<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>SWS: SE Once More Into the Void: The Beacon (Part 1 &amp; 2)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-se-once-more-into-the-void-the-beacon-part-1-2/7485</link>
    <description>*This two-shot is part of a celebration of 4 years of the*  ***Star Wars Saturday***  *games series, brought to you by members of the Gauntlet RPG Community.*

&quot;Once, we fought for the Republic - the Clone Wars, they call it now. We did a lot of things, not all of them pretty, but the worst of it was the job on Agurran. Nice little world in the Mid Rim. Boring, actually. Until the Cult of the Shining Void under their leader Tey&#39;ha took over, broke the planet off from the Republic and followed a philosophy of control through fear and strength through hate. The controlled the entire population by a Beacon that emitted a low hum of anxiety and seething resentment, powered by a kyber crystal so corrupt that it had cracked and was bleeding dread.

We did it, back then. Barely, but we disabled the Beacon, dismantled the cult and threw Tey&#39;ha down a deep chasm. The Republic was just about to install a democratic government and help the people of Agurran find peace when it became the Empire. Now, we all had other problems during that time - hell, we have other problems now. But it seems that the Cult of the Shining Void is back, and they may well try to install another of their infernal beacons - not on a backwater world this time, but somewhere close to the Core. They need to be stopped. Are you with me? One last time?&quot;

This is a two-shot of Jamila Nedjadi&#39;s game Once More Into the Void, slightly tweaked for Star Wars. It is strongly suggested that you sign up for both games, but it is not a requirement. You will have to sign up separately for the second game.

**CW: Violence, betrayal, intimacy**

Session 1: [date=2021-12-04 time=11:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;]: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MlfOJnpfJRQHHSCOBfG

Session 2: [date=2021-12-05 time=11:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MlfOZKRtpqo1reTO0Cz

**Duration**  : Two 3-hour sessions

**Breaks**  : 1 every hour

**Venue**  : GM’s Zoom

**Recording**  : Nope, unless someone wants to and everyone else agrees.

**Safety**  : Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, and open-door policy. This game will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 18:15:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-se-once-more-into-the-void-the-beacon-part-1-2/7485.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>SWS: SE Once More Into the Void: The Beacon (Part 1 &amp; 2)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>This two-shot is part of a celebration of 4 years of the</em>  <em><strong>Star Wars Saturday</strong></em>  <em>games series, brought to you by members of the Gauntlet RPG Community.</em></p>
<p>"Once, we fought for the Republic - the Clone Wars, they call it now. We did a lot of things, not all of them pretty, but the worst of it was the job on Agurran. Nice little world in the Mid Rim. Boring, actually. Until the Cult of the Shining Void under their leader Tey’ha took over, broke the planet off from the Republic and followed a philosophy of control through fear and strength through hate. The controlled the entire population by a Beacon that emitted a low hum of anxiety and seething resentment, powered by a kyber crystal so corrupt that it had cracked and was bleeding dread.</p>
<p>We did it, back then. Barely, but we disabled the Beacon, dismantled the cult and threw Tey’ha down a deep chasm. The Republic was just about to install a democratic government and help the people of Agurran find peace when it became the Empire. Now, we all had other problems during that time - hell, we have other problems now. But it seems that the Cult of the Shining Void is back, and they may well try to install another of their infernal beacons - not on a backwater world this time, but somewhere close to the Core. They need to be stopped. Are you with me? One last time?"</p>
<p>This is a two-shot of Jamila Nedjadi’s game Once More Into the Void, slightly tweaked for Star Wars. It is strongly suggested that you sign up for both games, but it is not a requirement. You will have to sign up separately for the second game.</p>
<p><strong>CW: Violence, betrayal, intimacy</strong></p>
<p>Session 1: <span data-date="2021-12-04" data-time="11:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-12-04T10:00:00Z UTC">2021-12-04T10:00:00Z</span>: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MlfOJnpfJRQHHSCOBfG">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MlfOJnpfJRQHHSCOBfG</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <span data-date="2021-12-05" data-time="11:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-12-05T10:00:00Z UTC">2021-12-05T10:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MlfOZKRtpqo1reTO0Cz">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MlfOZKRtpqo1reTO0Cz</a></p>
<p><strong>Duration</strong>  : Two 3-hour sessions</p>
<p><strong>Breaks</strong>  : 1 every hour</p>
<p><strong>Venue</strong>  : GM’s Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Recording</strong>  : Nope, unless someone wants to and everyone else agrees.</p>
<p><strong>Safety</strong>  : Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, and open-door policy. This game will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-se-once-more-into-the-void-the-beacon-part-1-2/7485/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-se-once-more-into-the-void-the-beacon-part-1-2/7485/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 18:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7485-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-se-once-more-into-the-void-the-beacon-part-1-2/7485.rss">SWS: SE Once More Into the Void: The Beacon (Part 1 &amp; 2)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
