<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>How to run Wet Hot American Summer RPG?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717</link>
    <description>I tried posting this on r/rpg a while back but didn&#39;t get any response. Not sure if I&#39;ll have any more luck here or not, but it&#39;s worth a shot.

I kickstarted Wet Hot American Summer last year and have read it several times, with a plan to run it for some friends who don&#39;t have much experience with role-playing games but absolutely love the movie and TV series. The problem is, for some reason, I just cannot grok what my role actually is or how the game works. I get how things are structured in terms of the day being broken apart but the game is so light on actual mechanics that I feel lost. And it is not that I am new to running role-playing games. I have a lot of experience running Dungeons &amp; Dragons 5th edition, Dungeon World, Monster of the week, and a few others. And I have read through many more, a lot of them PBTA games but not all. And I&#39;m not sure I&#39;ve ever had this problem before where I just cannot wrap my head around how the game actually works in play.

Does anyone have any thoughts? I&#39;m particularly interested in hearing from people who have run or at least played the game. My friends that I was going to run it for have been bugging me since it&#39;s been like a year now and I really am excited to give it a shot. I just want to make sure that I actually do a good job and then I have a handle on what my role is, what the players&#39; roles are, and the actual mechanics of the game. I did watch an actual play video on YouTube from the game&#39;s creators, but frankly it didn&#39;t help much.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 01:57:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>How to run Wet Hot American Summer RPG?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, I think that seems like a fair assessment, unfortunately. I got the impression from the actual play video that it’s more a (very, very loose) structure for improvisation than an actual game. Which is … fine, I guess. It is what it is. But not something I’m particularly stoked about trying to run. I’m afraid this is just going to be a novelty item on my RPG shelf, and I’d rather that not be the case, you know?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 01:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-717-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717.rss">How to run Wet Hot American Summer RPG?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to run Wet Hot American Summer RPG?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dunadhaigh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dunadhaigh">@dunadhaigh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hmm, the fact that the game was designed by comedians, only one of whom had previous experience with RPG design (and that was on a game that seems to exist just for laughs), it may simply be that the game isn’t particularly well-designed. The Kickstarter, for instance, didn’t seem to communicate any of the mechanics whatsoever.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 01:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-717-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717.rss">How to run Wet Hot American Summer RPG?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How to run Wet Hot American Summer RPG?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I tried posting this on r/rpg a while back but didn’t get any response. Not sure if I’ll have any more luck here or not, but it’s worth a shot.</p>
<p>I kickstarted Wet Hot American Summer last year and have read it several times, with a plan to run it for some friends who don’t have much experience with role-playing games but absolutely love the movie and TV series. The problem is, for some reason, I just cannot grok what my role actually is or how the game works. I get how things are structured in terms of the day being broken apart but the game is so light on actual mechanics that I feel lost. And it is not that I am new to running role-playing games. I have a lot of experience running Dungeons &amp; Dragons 5th edition, Dungeon World, Monster of the week, and a few others. And I have read through many more, a lot of them PBTA games but not all. And I’m not sure I’ve ever had this problem before where I just cannot wrap my head around how the game actually works in play.</p>
<p>Does anyone have any thoughts? I’m particularly interested in hearing from people who have run or at least played the game. My friends that I was going to run it for have been bugging me since it’s been like a year now and I really am excited to give it a shot. I just want to make sure that I actually do a good job and then I have a handle on what my role is, what the players’ roles are, and the actual mechanics of the game. I did watch an actual play video on YouTube from the game’s creators, but frankly it didn’t help much.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 20:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-717-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-to-run-wet-hot-american-summer-rpg/717.rss">How to run Wet Hot American Summer RPG?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
