<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104</link>
    <description>What do you think the next generation of PbtA (Powered by the Apocalypse) games will look like? Personally, I think the drifts in the structure of the designs are the most interesting and where it seems to be trending, rather than different dice being used or rethinking playbook design (though that&#39;s happening too).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 23:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="45" data-topic="104">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/dolan/40/464_2.png" class="avatar"> Dolan:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>wish this was an industry standard practice.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>If by “industry standard” you mean “in replacement of” f2f games, I’m not sure I am in solidarity with you there. I only play in person games. I totally support online only games and mechanics, but hope they don’t become the industry standard in place of face to face. Definitely though every rule book should include a chapter or section on how to play or enhance the game for online play. Or even visa versa (games mostly focused on online play have a section on f2f play).</p>
<p>If I misunderstood your position, forgive me.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/71">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/71</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 23:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-71</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That is definitely in my to play if I ever get the chance list.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/70">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/70</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 18:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-70</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Toby]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/toby">@Toby</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="68" data-topic="104">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/deckard/40/2412_2.png" class="avatar"> Deckard:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I just learned of <strong>Jinkies</strong> - a Scooby -Doo style game. This sort of investigation is what I am looking for but for a more serious game. As GM, I love the idea of “playing to find out” and <strong>Monster of the Week</strong> requires the mystery be prescribed ahead of time.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Inspectres <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/InSpectres" rel="nofollow noopener">https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/InSpectres</a> is not PbtA and not especially serious, but it does handle the investigation side of things in the way it sounds like you’re after: the GM doesn’t invent the mystery, and instead the players assemble it from clues they invent as they go along.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/69">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/69</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 17:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-69</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/shane">@shane</a></p>
<ul>
<li>There are several duo games (although Ironsworn is the only duo playable PbtA game, I think) Then, there is virtually every other rpg, which are ideally built for 4 - 5 players with or without GM. I would love to see an rpg that runs best with 3 players (with no GM / sharing GM responsibilities), particularly in PbtA where the game mechanics focus / impact relationships.</li>
</ul>
<p>*Truncheon World was a bad example.  To be more clear, I would like to see more PbtA games where the rules are maybe more concise (Between 20 and 80 pages) for the GM and the rest of the rules fit on 1 simple 2 sided player aid and a 2 page character sheet for each playbook.  I enjoy learning and running new games… It feels<br>
a bit much sometimes then for a GM to have to learn all the GM rules AND teach every player facing rule to players before play can start.  One of the reasons I enjoy Dungeon World and Apocalypse World so much is because MOST of the rules fit on the playbooks and the rest is generally something you can look up if it comes up.  Still, if the rules can be complete without lookup, that is clearly better.</p>
<p>*<strong>Monster of the Week</strong> is an investigation game…but it fell flat with me and my group. Looking back.  I am not sure why.  Personally, I would be more interested in a cleaned up version of <strong>We Used to Be Friends.</strong>…maybe <strong>Noir World</strong> does this well?  I haven’t gone through that one yet.  Maybe all I need is the <strong>Codex: Moonlight.</strong>  I will check that out.</p>
<p>Before someone mentions it I know there is <strong>City of Mist</strong> that handles investigations but that one is WAY heavier on the crunch than I am interested in at the moment.</p>
<p>Edit: I just learned of <strong>Jinkies</strong> - a Scooby -Doo style game.  This sort of investigation is what I am looking for but for a more serious game. As GM, I love the idea of “playing to find out” and <strong>Monster of the Week</strong> requires the mystery be prescribed ahead of time.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/68">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/68</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 20:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-68</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="66" data-topic="104">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/deckard/40/2412_2.png" class="avatar"> Deckard:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>a PbtA that works best with 3 people</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Do you mean three players or two players plus MC? I personally feel that <em>most</em> pbta games run best with the former.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="66" data-topic="104">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/deckard/40/2412_2.png" class="avatar"> Deckard:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>more succinct PbtA rules - (e.g more Truncheon World less Dungeon World)</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is a bit confusing since Truncheon World only includes the GM facing rules. (It is basically the DW DMG.)</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="66" data-topic="104">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/deckard/40/2412_2.png" class="avatar"> Deckard:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>a PbtA game focused on investigating</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>AFAIK Monster of the Week is investigation focused, no? Also I would recommend <a class="mention" href="/u/sinisterbeard">@SinisterBeard</a>’s supplement <em>Apocalypse by Moonlight</em> in Codex: Moonlight - it is a guide for running investigations with pbta games.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/67">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/67</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 12:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-67</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/alexi_sarge">@Alexi_Sarge</a>… Ironsworn can be played GM-less using the “oracles”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there are a bunch of great ideas above. As for my own ideas I would like to see,. I have just a few to add:</p>
<p>*a PbtA that works best with 3 people<br>
*more succinct PbtA rules<br>
*a PbtA with a Civil War motif<br>
*a PbtA game focused on investigating and playing to find out<br>
*PbtA using a maps to create and document the location - a la Stonetop <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/discern-realities/episode-60" rel="nofollow noopener">Stonetop on Discern Realities</a> but on a bigger scale</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/66">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/66</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 04:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-66</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I have to say that this is one of the two advantages of playing by forum.  The forums often have ways to hide spoilers and point them to only the appropriate players (assuming players want to abide by them) .  The other advantage is you can really delve into detail and world building without slowing down the game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/65">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/65</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 19:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-65</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Exactly!  Legacy looks AMAZING but also complicated with lots of setup required.  I have downloaded this quickstart!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/64">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/64</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 19:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-64</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OnlyAnAlligator]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/onlyanalligator">@OnlyAnAlligator</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was more referencing the idea of playbooks that each have they’re own completely unique movesets with no common set of basic moves, while you’re more talking about the opposite direction, design-wise – generalizing PBTA moves to produce a unitary system. A unitary system, though, still enforces a shared space in so far that everyone needs to go through the same mechanical hoops to accomplish the same thing. Like, looking at DnD, I would argue that even though you don’t have a “move” for punching a guy in the face, the manner in which a character punches a guy in the face doesn’t particularly vary across classes. What will vary is the quality of the roll and modifiers that improve or worsen the outcome unique to the character. I think your answer certainly approaches parts of the question I brought up, though. the notion of the conversation and the way that it helps unify the experience. The idea I BELIEVE <a class="mention" href="/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> brought up (they can correct me if I misinterpreted). seems like it would also bring a unique set of its own design challenges to the table, though.</p>
<p>Anyway, I don’t want to hijack this discussion with a thread on one idea, so I’m personally going to leave it there for now.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/63">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/63</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-63</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JasonT]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasont">@JasonT</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="61" data-topic="104">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/onlyanalligator/40/1877_2.png" class="avatar"> OnlyAnAlligator:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>How do you enforce the idea that characters share a world when there’s no shared move set that determines how the world outside of the playbooks work?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Maybe I misunderstand the question, but RPGs were doing this for decades before there was Apocalypse World, no? Even if we stick just to PbtA games with no basic moves, though, I think the answer can be seen in World of Dungeons 1979, and World of Dungeons Turbo: Breakers, both by the same designer. In the former, everybody is expected to have a general idea  of how the world works because it invokes a commonly known fictional touchstone (in that case, D&amp;D). In the latter, which has a more unique setting/premise, players are expected to read the game text (or have it summarized by another player) to get a sense of what the world expects of them. The rules don’t enforce it in play; “social contract” does, as it’s understood that everybody should be on the same page to have a good time together.</p>
<p>Edit to add: Sorry, it feels like I may be “mansplaining” this, though I don’t mean to. I’m interested in the question, though, and wonder if I just missed something.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/62">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/62</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-62</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OnlyAnAlligator]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/onlyanalligator">@OnlyAnAlligator</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m wondering how a game with no basic moves would work, less from a mechanical perspective and more from a fictional perspective. It strikes me that it would take more effort on the part of players to keep their characters from spinning out into they’re own little subworlds only loosely connected to each other. Taking an example from Apocalypse World, every playbook but maybe one can open their mind to the psychic maelstrom. The move establishes a fact about the setting that unites what can be a disparate bunch of protagonists as clearly existing in a shared world. How do you enforce the idea that characters share a world when there’s no shared move set that determines how the world outside of the playbooks work?</p>
<p>The question isn’t a critique disguised as a rhetorical question, to clarify. I’m genuinely interested to hear thoughts on that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/61">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/61</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 09:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-61</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/shane">@shane</a> - <em>Night Witches</em> is without a doubt the most intense oneshot I’ve ever played and the book describes explicitly how to do it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/60">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/60</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-60</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t know if there is one that emphasizes texting, chatting,  etc., but it has shown up extensively in Urban Shadows games I’ve played, and in Sig I played a journalist who live-tweeted events at the table. In character chats in online games can be fun.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/59">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/59</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 16:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-59</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Big_Hammers]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/big_hammers">@Big_Hammers</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thank you &lt;3 This post must be greater than 20 characters.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/58">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/58</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 16:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-58</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s not official. <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1p5dFGIZ3y4elqWS4Oi4e3HS_J1BowXjy/view" rel="nofollow noopener">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1p5dFGIZ3y4elqWS4Oi4e3HS_J1BowXjy/view</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/57">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/57</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 16:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-57</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Big_Hammers]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/big_hammers">@Big_Hammers</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="23" data-topic="104" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/shane/40/186_2.png" class="avatar"> shane:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I was pulling my hair out last night trying to find <em>Blades Against Darkness Turbo</em> last night - but had forgotten the <em>Turbo</em> part!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I can’t seem to Google this up. Has it been taken down or maybe was a backer-only thing?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/56">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/56</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 16:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-56</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Chris_Mitchell]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chris_mitchell">@Chris_Mitchell</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>“Games with no basic moves, all the moves for each playbook are in that playbook.”</p>
<p>I asked Vincent about this in 2010 at GenCon when the game was still in the preapocalypse, and he told me that Luke Crane told him that games needed fiddly bits.</p>
<p>I think he was messing with me.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/55">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/55</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 02:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-55</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Michael]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/michael">@Michael</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Sundered Land is great for forums and text threads.  I’ve played by text a few times and really enjoyed it.  I also participated in a Twitter thread game that Meg Baker started, and that was pretty cool.</p>
<p><a href="http://lumpley.com/index.php/anyway/thread/722" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://lumpley.com/index.php/anyway/thread/722</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/54">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/54</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 11:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-54</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Is there a PbtA game embracing modern communication channels like e. g. chat, Text, WhatsApp?</p>
<p>I could imagine this would open up a new kind of experience having ongoing sub- or side conversations without other players /GM noticing.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/52</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 19:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jon">@Jon</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Not everyone wants the future of PbtA to shift deeper into micro-genre storygames, so while those excite me, there’s room for another direction they can go down simultaneously.  People like the chess game part of RPGs - player skill, discovering system nooks that you can use to improve your character, and tactics. Maybe not Pathfinder level tactical crunch, but <em>some</em> depth.</p>
<p>It’s exciting seeing player tactics in the Forged in the Dark games.  There’s a lot of “players discussing the most optimal new crew advance” play in Blades, for instance. There’s resources management, crafting rules, and other juicy trad mechanics there. And it’s skill-based, without moves.</p>
<p>Another trad-ish direction I’ve seen PbtA sensibilities invade is in Cipher system games. They have a GM role similar to Apocalypse World, but power trees, magic items, and a very “dungeon crawl” feel (even Invisible Sun to some degree).</p>
<p>I’d love to see PbtA gamerunning philosophy invade the granddaddy of all RPGs and get Incorporated into something like D&amp;D, whenever they roll out 6th edition (probably not for at least another 3+ years). We have the McElroys playing MotW and Adam Koebel running D&amp;D for Roll20. There’s a growing awareness of the value of reactive GMing among D&amp;D bloggers, too.</p>
<p>To me, the GM instructions are what make PbtA special. I want to see the PbtA style spread everywhere.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/51</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 19:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Maezar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maezar">@Maezar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>GM-full. Hehehe. Oh,by the way, hi everyone! <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/metal/6.png?v=6" title=":metal:t6:" class="emoji" alt=":metal:t6:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/50</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 02:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dissonance]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dissonance">@Dissonance</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Let me show you a Moth-Light character sheet …</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/1X/f58b7e1536edfedc0cfe0771f91b6924a3bebe92.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/z2bQb3JwMiNGPOhlirAc02PPzYC.jpeg?dl=1" title="image" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/1X/f58b7e1536edfedc0cfe0771f91b6924a3bebe92_2_500x500.jpeg" alt="image" data-base62-sha1="z2bQb3JwMiNGPOhlirAc02PPzYC" width="500" height="500" srcset="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/1X/f58b7e1536edfedc0cfe0771f91b6924a3bebe92_2_500x500.jpeg, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/1X/f58b7e1536edfedc0cfe0771f91b6924a3bebe92_2_750x750.jpeg 1.5x, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/1X/f58b7e1536edfedc0cfe0771f91b6924a3bebe92_2_1000x1000.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/1X/f58b7e1536edfedc0cfe0771f91b6924a3bebe92_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">image</span><span class="informations">1440×1440 294 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/49</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 02:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’d be surprised if there wasn’t a lot of back-flow from Forged in the Dark stuff towards it’s PbtA progenitor. Probably more focus on flexible Move mechanics, and a more highly developed meta-game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/48</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 16:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yochaigal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yochaigal">@yochaigal</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Not sure if you’re aware, but One Shot World is a hack of Dungeon World meant for one shots. I’m curious if there are other games out there <em>made</em> specifically for one shots, though.</p>
<p>Full disclosure: I made it. But it is free, so whatever.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/47</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 01:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Future Of PbtA Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Stentor_Danielson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stentor_danielson">@Stentor_Danielson</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m designing a PbtA game right now, and one of my plans is to include a free Gauntlet-style character keeper along with the playbook downloads on my website.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104/46</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 20:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-104-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-pbta-games/104.rss">The Future Of PbtA Games</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
