<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride recordings</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-synhamm-bride-recordings/4075</link>
    <description>A four session series unfortunately curtailed to 3 by illness ...

*Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride (1/3)*
with ... Alexis, Sabine, Blake &amp; Cody ...
We return to Synhamm to find Iamon, called &#39;Giant Killer&#39;, chafing under the weight of his growing reputation.  Meanwhile, Aedwen, Outlaw and lost daughter of a character from another series is just trying to get by; Ragnus, the Hammer of the Gods, seeks those who took his loved ones; and Casudius, a Monstrous Revenant, cursed to walk the earth for offending the Roman gods at a wedding, just wants to put true love on the right path ... and then there are outlaws ...

https://youtu.be/b34US5pT8HM

*Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride (2/3)*
with ... Paul, Sabine, Blake &amp; Pawel ...
After last session&#39;s confrontation with the Fenland Outlaws, a more pressing challenge threatens Synhamm.  Princess Manugia of Elmet must either be handed over to Synhamm&#39;s nemesis, King Beda, or spirited away to her betrothed in Mercia, and safety, after her father&#39;s Kingdom is absorbed by the most powerful Saxon King, Edwin of Northumbria.  Iamon &#39;Giant Killer&#39; confronts the Eorl&#39;s son over who should lead the Princess&#39; escape, while Aedwen the Outlaw and and Bull the Commoner (with his mule &#39;Donkey&#39;) will accompany them.  Goderic, the Saxon Mystic, is on a mission from Woden to ensure that &#39;the love that threatens Synhamm must be properly directed ...&#39;; and after summoning spirits sees the attraction between Manugia and Iamon ... he will go, too ... and then there are outlaws ...

https://youtu.be/gTrV-C6uMRU

*Eotenweard - the Synhammm Bride (3/3)*
... with Sabine V, Paul; Blake &amp; Alexi ...
We skip foward to the group reaching the lands of Aethelbert of Mercia, the Princess&#39; betrothed, where she takes control of her life and flees North to find any survivors of her father&#39;s dynasty.  The characters pursue ... as does Aethelbert ... who turns out to be a much different foe than anticipated.
Our Commoner displays a talent for matchmaking; our Monster Hunter agonised over what he might offer a Princess; a Priest from her past offered succour and then summoned the flames of St Michael; while our Outlaw defended the innocent ...
... and there&#39;s the hint of a happy ending ...

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i6WV9WVt00o</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 14:07:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-synhamm-bride-recordings/4075.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride recordings</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A four session series unfortunately curtailed to 3 by illness …</p>
<p><em>Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride (1/3)</em><br>
with … Alexis, Sabine, Blake &amp; Cody …<br>
We return to Synhamm to find Iamon, called ‘Giant Killer’, chafing under the weight of his growing reputation.  Meanwhile, Aedwen, Outlaw and lost daughter of a character from another series is just trying to get by; Ragnus, the Hammer of the Gods, seeks those who took his loved ones; and Casudius, a Monstrous Revenant, cursed to walk the earth for offending the Roman gods at a wedding, just wants to put true love on the right path … and then there are outlaws …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="b34US5pT8HM" data-youtube-title="Eotenweard: The Synhamm Bride (1/3)" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
<p><em>Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride (2/3)</em><br>
with … Paul, Sabine, Blake &amp; Pawel …<br>
After last session’s confrontation with the Fenland Outlaws, a more pressing challenge threatens Synhamm.  Princess Manugia of Elmet must either be handed over to Synhamm’s nemesis, King Beda, or spirited away to her betrothed in Mercia, and safety, after her father’s Kingdom is absorbed by the most powerful Saxon King, Edwin of Northumbria.  Iamon ‘Giant Killer’ confronts the Eorl’s son over who should lead the Princess’ escape, while Aedwen the Outlaw and and Bull the Commoner (with his mule ‘Donkey’) will accompany them.  Goderic, the Saxon Mystic, is on a mission from Woden to ensure that ‘the love that threatens Synhamm must be properly directed …’; and after summoning spirits sees the attraction between Manugia and Iamon … he will go, too … and then there are outlaws …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="gTrV-C6uMRU" data-youtube-title="Eotenweard: The Synhamm Bride (2/3)" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
<p><em>Eotenweard - the Synhammm Bride (3/3)</em><br>
… with Sabine V, Paul; Blake &amp; Alexi …<br>
We skip foward to the group reaching the lands of Aethelbert of Mercia, the Princess’ betrothed, where she takes control of her life and flees North to find any survivors of her father’s dynasty.  The characters pursue … as does Aethelbert … who turns out to be a much different foe than anticipated.<br>
Our Commoner displays a talent for matchmaking; our Monster Hunter agonised over what he might offer a Princess; a Priest from her past offered succour and then summoned the flames of St Michael; while our Outlaw defended the innocent …<br>
… and there’s the hint of a happy ending …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="i6WV9WVt00o" data-youtube-title="Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride 3/3" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-synhamm-bride-recordings/4075/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-synhamm-bride-recordings/4075/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 14:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4075-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-synhamm-bride-recordings/4075.rss">Eotenweard - The Synhamm Bride recordings</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
