<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fundraiser for Evey Lockhart</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fundraiser-for-evey-lockhart/7843</link>
    <description>Hey all, I&#39;m [raising funds for Evey Lockhart](https://www.gofundme.com/f/evey-and-family-need-help). You might know that Evey is a prolific and talented writer/designer of weird, sad, queer old-school stuff. She was celebrated in 2015 as winner of the One Page Dungeon Contest, then took ENnie silver for her contributions to Trilemma Adventures. She’s gone on to make books like Very Pretty Paleozoic Pals and the disturbing “Wet Grandpa” with the Melsonian Arts Council.

[![evey|690x460](upload://k5UkIczNKSHKD8n8s3WQndowMwl.jpeg)](https://www.gofundme.com/f/evey-and-family-need-help) 

You probably don’t know that most of her writing happens on an old laptop in a van: **Evey and her family are homeless**, and have been for a couple of years.

The pandemic has sucked for everyone, to put it mildly—but being trans, homeless, and disabled in the southern US with all this going on is an unrelenting stress. Evey’s been scraping from day to day this whole time, getting it done for her kids as best she can.

Nobody deserves to live under this kind of pressure. If, like me, you’ve been sheltered from the worst of the pandemic, you can make a huge difference in her life with a [couple of clicks](https://www.gofundme.com/f/evey-and-family-need-help). If you can only spare a few bucks, even that provides immediate relief from stressing where the money for the next meal or place to stay is coming from. If all you can do right now is help spread the word before the algorithm eats this, that’s awesome too.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:56:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fundraiser-for-evey-lockhart/7843.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Fundraiser for Evey Lockhart</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Michael_Prescott]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/michael_prescott">@Michael_Prescott</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hey all, I’m <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/evey-and-family-need-help" rel="nofollow noopener">raising funds for Evey Lockhart</a>. You might know that Evey is a prolific and talented writer/designer of weird, sad, queer old-school stuff. She was celebrated in 2015 as winner of the One Page Dungeon Contest, then took ENnie silver for her contributions to Trilemma Adventures. She’s gone on to make books like Very Pretty Paleozoic Pals and the disturbing “Wet Grandpa” with the Melsonian Arts Council.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/evey-and-family-need-help" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/8/8cd676ede717a9db51277ea0a2be211b60512b35.jpeg" alt="evey" data-base62-sha1="k5UkIczNKSHKD8n8s3WQndowMwl" width="690" height="460"></a></p>
<p>You probably don’t know that most of her writing happens on an old laptop in a van: <strong>Evey and her family are homeless</strong>, and have been for a couple of years.</p>
<p>The pandemic has sucked for everyone, to put it mildly—but being trans, homeless, and disabled in the southern US with all this going on is an unrelenting stress. Evey’s been scraping from day to day this whole time, getting it done for her kids as best she can.</p>
<p>Nobody deserves to live under this kind of pressure. If, like me, you’ve been sheltered from the worst of the pandemic, you can make a huge difference in her life with a <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/evey-and-family-need-help" rel="nofollow noopener">couple of clicks</a>. If you can only spare a few bucks, even that provides immediate relief from stressing where the money for the next meal or place to stay is coming from. If all you can do right now is help spread the word before the algorithm eats this, that’s awesome too.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fundraiser-for-evey-lockhart/7843/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fundraiser-for-evey-lockhart/7843/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 21:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7843-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fundraiser-for-evey-lockhart/7843.rss">Fundraiser for Evey Lockhart</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
