<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650</link>
    <description>Shall we share tips about creating videos for kickstarter?

If you have created one recently

- what software do you use?
- record in one go or use several tracks?
- choosing what to say and what not to say?

If you have looked at some recently,

- did you watch through to the end?
- what makes a good video?
- what makes a bad video?
- ideally what do you want from a video?

Cheers!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 01:11:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SPGNems]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/spgnems">@SPGNems</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thank you thank you!</p>
<p>I’m very fortunate to have a little acting experience, and more importantly a bunch of actor/film people friends who have been a great help with these projects, and the talking heads approach is so much easier - I think a lot of people see that stat about 70% of successful projects having videos and read that to mean 70% of projects with videos succeed and so get a “Anything is better than nothing” mindset, which is completely understandable, KSs encourage a very symbiotic FOMO after all!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/32</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 01:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I really like this approach, I completely agree that talking heads style videos are not really engaging, I find I can read a lot faster than most people talk, so I get very impatient listening to someone describe something that also has a full write-up right below it.</p>
<p>I think the “in game” video works as a more effective version of the intro fluff that a lot of games have. Combining some elevated reality visuals with dialog feels much more authentic to a roleplaying experience than a big wall of text with illustrations.</p>
<p>I don’t think it’s possible for every game, but I would love an intro akin to the video Valve produced for the first Left 4 Dead; it’s a perfect encapsulation of what happens in game and actually teaches you how to play without breaking fiction.</p>
<p>Welcome to the community by the way! Glad to have you here.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/31</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 23:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SPGNems]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/spgnems">@SPGNems</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One thing I like to suggest to folx is trying to have some fun shooting the video in a way that sets it apart from the usual “Look at camera, talk about game” ones you get most often.</p>
<p>For me, that usually means recording something silly, in-universe and, uh, “involved”. Obviously not everyone has access to the skills and resources to make something like, say, the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/sandypuggames/americana-1?ref=user_menu" rel="nofollow noopener">Americana</a> or <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/sandypuggames/disposable-heroes-0" rel="nofollow noopener">Disposable Heroes</a> videos but the<a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1930759690/orc-stabr" rel="nofollow noopener">Orc Stabr video</a> got a lot of comments and helped with selling the whole charm of the project while basically just being me dressed up in $10 worth of costume makeup, grunting at my friends phone camera.</p>
<p>Maybe this is colored by my own tastes - a basic “look at the camera and talk about the game” video gets me turned off real quick, and I’ll make choices based on the content of the page, but a creative video with some clever hook or something that shows off the game in a fun way? Really does influence me a lot.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 15:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think this point is Very important!  In any investment, you want to see and hear from the people involved.  It just feels like a more authentic investment.  Without the video, I would be less inclined to Kickstart something.</p>
<p>That said, the only point in a Kickstarter video that gets me excited to buy is the enthusiasm and dedication shown in the video.  Not the mechanics, not a dull how to video.  I want to see the creator super excited.  If not, the creator then a playtester that loves it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/29</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 20:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’d say 95% of the time I don’t watch the video. Really the only times I do is if I am friends with the person and just want to watch what they did. For me at least a video has never had an impact on my backing an RPG on Kickstarter.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/28</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 21:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jacob_Wood]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jacob_wood">@Jacob_Wood</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For my first two Kickstarters, I used PowerPOint to patch together some graphics and voiceovers. Actually, on my first one, I didn’t even own a webcam or microphone yet (this was 2012) and I used my screen reader + Audacity to record some robo text.</p>
<p>The result wasn’t spectacular, and there a few people who complained, but the campaigns were still ultimately successful so I’ll take it.</p>
<p>I think my third campaign was just a talking head video. My wife asked me a few interview questions off-camera and I answered them on-camera. I sounded uncomfortable and that’s because I was. Still, the campaign was a success. Not a huge success, but it was for a sourcebook for an existing game so I didn’t expect huge numbers anyway. I think I patched that together using Windows MovieMaker.</p>
<p>I’m working on my fourth KS campaign now for <em>Survival of the Able,</em> and this thread crossed my radar at an interesting time. I’m currently trying to decide whether to even bother with a video at all.</p>
<p>Third Eye Games hasn’t been doing videos for their campaigns lately, and they still hit $10k+ most of the time. I’m sure much of that is attributed to their large built-in following though.</p>
<p>It seems odd to me that so many of you won’t even watch a video but insist on there being one. IMO, it’s that kind of double-standard which makes tthis so difficult.</p>
<p>Consider that many gamers and game designers are either socially awkward or have a bonafied social anxiety. It can be difficult for them to get on camera and talk to people. That doesn’t make their game any worse and it doesn’t say anything about their ability to finish a project. Sure, they can try to patch some things together using PowerPOint and some graphics, like I did for my first campaign, but that is an <em>entirely</em> different skill set.</p>
<p>Then you have people like me, who are legally blind and don’t work well with certain types of software. I can use PowerPOint well enough because Microsoft products are generally very accessible. Adobe Premier, Final Cut, Vegas, and similar programs are typically  not. Even with Windows Movie Maker, I had to ask my wife to do the edits for me because cutting video on a timeline is just a huge challenge.</p>
<p>So that leaves me with a dilemma. My wife is a busy person who doesn’t always have time to do things like that, and it really isn’t her skill set either. Do I wait around until she has the time to help? Do I spend money to hire someone else, which is money I have to add to the campaign’s goal so I can recoup that cost? All for a video nobody’s going to watch? Do I slap together a worthless PowerPOint because nobody’s going to watch it anyway, but everyone’s going to expect something? Or do I just not bother with the whole thing and risk having people turn away because there is no video that they wouldn’t even bother watching if there was?</p>
<p>I would seriously challenge everyoneto re-think theirstandards and assumptions. Don’t mistake a lack of a video for a lack of care. Like I said, Third Eye Games doesn’t always use videos and they consistently deliver on their projects. Others lack the skill set or physical ability to put together a video, and the investment in learning how or hiring help isn’t necessarily worth it. By continuing to insist on there being a video you won’t even watch, you’re perpetuating a stereotype and giving room for ablism to thrive.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/27</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 16:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Malrex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/malrex">@Malrex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I had 0 interest in making a video…but I did one. I watched a few other videos as examples and I found them sorta boring…So to get one done, I just put together some art and pictures of my layout and maps…and umm…forced my wife to do the narration because her voice sounds better than mine (in my opinion) and talk about the adventure… The result is a sardonic narration with complete dispassion…which oddly…I thought was hilarious and I think might hold people’s attention? I have no idea. Ill let you know how it goes after August 9th…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/26</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 21:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For anyone curious to see how my video turned out, you can see it here (under 2 mins!)</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lonely-courage/a-cool-and-lonely-courage?ref=nav_search&amp;result=project&amp;term=Lonely%20courage" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Kickstarter</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/388;"><img src="https://ksr-ugc.imgix.net/assets/025/056/093/a766d8dcc38d0ad656b79db9d18478b3_original.jpg?ixlib=rb-2.1.0&amp;crop=faces&amp;w=1552&amp;h=873&amp;fit=crop&amp;v=1557268111&amp;auto=format&amp;frame=1&amp;q=92&amp;s=fef92029deac98cc94ee10d75f32026b" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lonely-courage/a-cool-and-lonely-courage?ref=nav_search&amp;result=project&amp;term=Lonely%20courage" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">A Cool and Lonely Courage</a></h3>

<p>A table top story game about the heroic women of the SOE in occupied France for 2-5 players.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/25</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 21:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BeckyA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m the same I almost never watch KS videos but if there isn’t a video I’ll always pause and possibly reconsider my pledge.</p>
<p>I think there are clearer ‘rules’ on what not to put in a video:</p>
<p>Don’t make it longer than 3 mins (pref 1.5 mins).<br>
Don’t ‘sell’ your game by saying how it is like “just like Call of Cthulhu but better”.</p>
<p>Because I think that it is the missteps which will cost you sales (including the misstep of not having a vid) rather than the things you include which will gain them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/24</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 07:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SinisterBeard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sinisterbeard">@SinisterBeard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, that’s basically it. It shows effort.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/23</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 19:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rabalias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is how I justify the dichotomy to myself. You want me to invest in your game but you couldn’t even get it together to create a three-minute video. Why should I trust that you’ll get it together to finish your game?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 19:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SinisterBeard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sinisterbeard">@SinisterBeard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes, 100% this. I’ve taken time to look at failed Kickstarters, and they mostly have either no video, or a terrible video.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 19:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SinisterBeard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sinisterbeard">@SinisterBeard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I also don’t really watch Kickstarter videos. HOWEVER, I judge the hell out of Kickstarters that don’t have them. They look unprofessional. Weird dichotomy.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 19:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@wordman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/wordman">@wordman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve backed over a thousand Kickstarters. I can count the videos I’ve watched on one hand, and those I remember on none.</p>
<p>Here’s the thing about video: it allows you the creator to control the pace at which information is given to me. That’s great, for you. I, however, have no interested in you controlling the pace I’m consuming information. Nothing about that helps me. Reading does.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 15:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It is interesting that there is some data to suggest that kickstarters with videos tend to fund more than kickstarters without videos. Source: <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/blog/how-to-make-an-awesome-video" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.kickstarter.com/blog/how-to-make-an-awesome-video</a> says 50% vs 30%.</p>
<p>I don’t think that is necessarily showing a causal relationship (have video = more funding!). I suspect that it is more a case of a video being a marker for a range of things which together contribute to the funding of the kickstarter.</p>
<p>That linked page is from 2012 of course. I’d love for Kickstarter to provide some more current evidence on the importance (or otherwise) of video usage - after all, they must have all the data!</p>
<p>Cheers</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/18</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 08:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It feels to me that it is a bit of a hygiene factor - doesn’t necessarily sell the kickstarter, not often watched, but it does send a message that care is being taken to cross the t’s and dot the i’s.</p>
<p>End result - I’m working on mine at the moment. Nothing flashy, but hopefully enough to make it worthwhile for those who do care for it.</p>
<p>Cheers</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/17</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 19:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@TabletopDuck]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/tabletopduck">@TabletopDuck</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m also going to throw out that videos aren’t terribly necessary in our industry. Campaigns like UVG and Swordsfall didn’t use any and did fine. I recently also launched a campaign with no video and a fairly small following and we’re doing really really good. Just food for thought.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/16</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 06:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@GeorgeA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/georgea">@GeorgeA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I just saw that, too! That was a really tight one-take KS video!</p>
<p>For RPGs and Larps, I’ve definitely noticed that Banana Chan makes good Kickstarter videos, and I especially like the work she did on Star Crossed. Her portfolio is here: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5nTQc2TjJscN0pby7q0PNXububTDyyhl" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5nTQc2TjJscN0pby7q0PNXububTDyyhl</a></p>
<p>Slightly further afield, C. Spike Trotman’s Iron Circus Comics has been putting up short, dialog-less, punchy, motion graphics and art heavy videos that’d be really easy to emulate for RPG book or zine-folks that have already paid their artists: <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/profile/ironspike/created" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.kickstarter.com/profile/ironspike/created</a></p>
<p>I actually just shot and edited my first Kickstarter video! My friends Ceridwen and Kylene hired me to to make a video for their Larp event when there was just over 2 weeks left in their campaign (there’s 5 days left now!!). I tried very hard to follow <a class="mention" href="/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a>’s last bullet point and keep it under 3 minutes, but they ended up posting the first release candidate I sent them rather than doing another round of feedback to help me kill another 2 to 4 darlings.</p>
<p>I’d love constructive criticism, or on the flipside to talk about the production!<br>
<a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/locrpg/flight-of-corvus-a-larp-event-in-the-catoctin-moun/description" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/locrpg/flight-of-corvus-a-larp-event-in-the-catoctin-moun/description</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/15</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 22:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So I just watched the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/camdon/one-childs-heart" rel="nofollow noopener">One Child’s Heart KS video</a>. I thought it was really good. It was short, it told you about the game, it told you why the game was important, it put a face on the game and made it personal.</p>
<p>I was going to back it anyway, but if I wasn’t, this video might have got me there.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/14</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 14:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Some really helpful input here from people BTW, thanks for putting time to put fingers to keyboard on this - hopefully it will be helpful for everyone who ends up considering a video for kickstarter <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 18:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Re: twitter poll I also didn’t take into account I’d only get four questions to ask! I knew that I wouldn’t get anything like a statistically interesting volume of answers, but was still a little interesting.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/12</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 18:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BeckyA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m not sure I have much to add.</p>
<p>Basically I think that if you have a vid it makes the page look more professional and gives people the option to see your face if they want to.  Now, lots of people don’t watch vids - BUT having the option of watching a vid is still something I look for even if I don’t then watch the video.  So it is worth having a video even if people don’t watch it.</p>
<p>I think the video for Bite Me! was played around 900 times (around 250 more than the number of backers I had).</p>
<p>Also your poll didn’t take into account something that expect is super common - which is people who watch the first 30 secs make their decision to buy based off that and then don’t watch the rest.  I suspect that accounts for most watches.  So say all the important stuff really early!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/11</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 16:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rabalias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I use iMovie, because it’s what I’ve got.</p>
<p>I generally record a few takes, then cut and paste the best bits into the finished version. I’ll be adding bits of visuals like the art etc into the video, so I can easily make it look seamless.</p>
<p>I tend to write myself a little script, but not necessarily stick religiously to it. I’ve found that I come across pretty wooden, but better if I’ve got someone on the other side of the camera who I talk to.</p>
<p>My patented content generation method is this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make sure you get across the basic sales pitch in the first 15 seconds. That should be enough that the watcher is grabbed and wants to know more.</li>
<li>Make sure that if they stick around for the first minute, they get enough additional detail about what the game is about to be converted. Situation and/or setting first, and then perhaps a bit about the mechanics. But remember most people are grabbed by flavour, not by rules.</li>
<li>The rest of the video is for people who really want to know all about it. Talk about the art, talk about stretch goals, all the extra bits and bobs that might sell someone who is on the fence.</li>
<li>It’s nice if people get visuals, not just your face talking at them, so interweave illustrations from the game, snapshots of the layout, pop quotes from people who liked it (playtesters, fellow designers, whoever). Just anything to add a bit of visual interest and make the game feel more real. Honestly, I don’t know if people are that fussed about seeing the designer talk on camera at all - though I always do include this, myself.</li>
<li>Don’t go over 3 minutes if you can help it. If you haven’t sold them by 3 minutes, you probably aren’t going to, and you risk them forgetting to do the thing they came here for: click on the “back” button.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now you obviously can hardly say anything in 3 minutes, and that’s the point: you focus in on the really important stuff. But you can make more videos with details of specific things, if you want to. My honest experience is that most people probably won’t watch them, but if you feel like you really need to talk about the detailed mechanics on camera, then that’s what I’d do. This means you’ve got something else to share as well, which is always nice.</p>
<p>Now that’s all my view as a creator. As a punter, I basically don’t watch videos. They are not for me at all. I find it annoying to have to sit with my eyes on the screen for a fixed amount of time rather than consume at my own pace. I actually find it slightly baffling that people want videos rather than text. But with that said, I know (as a creator) that having a video statistically increases your chance of success. And if you don’t have one then I notice (as a customer) that you’ve failed to make one, which makes me wonder what other things you aren’t going to get around to. So as a customer, I’m basically looking to see if you’ve got one, nothing more.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 11:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So here are my thoughts on Kickstarters and KS videos.</p>
<ol>
<li>If I got to your Kickstarter page by being someone I already know and follow, I’ll probably watch your video, to completion. But because I know you, not because it will give me insight into your Kickstarter. I am probably backing your project, just at what level.</li>
<li>If I got to your Kickstarter page from getting a link from someone I know, I’ll probably watch your video to get a general idea of your project, and what you think makes it stand out. I’ll probably watch it to completion, unless it’s offensive or extremely boring. If I don’t know you, I probably won’t back you just on your video, but it might get interested enough to read the longer text and the backer levels. Video’s at this level to me, are sort of a low level test. You can lose me here, but it’s extremely hard to win me just on the video.</li>
<li>If I got to your KS page from some other place, I’ll watch your video, but I’ll be doing a bunch more research on who you are and what the people I do know and trust think of your products and reputation so far. If you have no rep yet and there is no other information I can find, I will likely pass. If you have a negative rep, I will pass. If you have any sort of positive rep, I’ll take a closer look and see if it’s something that would interest me. If you have a demo I might look at that. I might have KS remind me about it 48 hours before the end. It’s a lot harder for me to back these projects (but not unheard of), and usually the video is just an opportunity to lose me.</li>
</ol>
<p>What does that mean in terms of tips for videos? For me:</p>
<ol>
<li>Short, concise and informative.<br>
a. General overview of project<br>
b. Why it is important to you<br>
c. Why does this stand out</li>
<li>Don’t be bad. No video is better than a bad or offensive video.<br>
a. Don’t be boring<br>
b. Don’t be funny, unless you are really sure your jokes are going to land with all of your intended audience. Jokes that don’t “land”, are a quick way for me to stop watching and closing that tab.<br>
c. Production quality matters, because, for me, videos are mostly an opportunity to lose me and not to gain me. I interpret any problems I see in the video as a foreshadow of potential problems down the line. This is largely unjust, as whether or not you can properly light, edit, or produce a video has little to do with most projects I back.</li>
</ol>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/9</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 23:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tips for kickstarter videos</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m running a tiny poll on twitter at the moment, and I’m surprised at the number of people who wouldn’t watch a video at all. There was certainly evidence in 2009 that kickstarters with videos were more likely to fund but (a) I’ve not seen something more recent and (b) that might just reflect all-round care and attention which the kickstarter creator was applying.</p>
<p>What I think I’ve been seeing so far is</p>
<ol>
<li>Be short and sweet. Shorter is better than longer.</li>
<li>It is the opportunity to put a human face to the creator of the game, and to sell the idea</li>
</ol>
<p>I’d certainly be interested in understanding what others have gleaned though.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> has just run a successful kickstarter; I wonder if she might drop by with words of wisdom?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650/8</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 22:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1650-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/tips-for-kickstarter-videos/1650.rss">Tips for kickstarter videos</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
