<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>GCOG Knave: The Waking of Willowby Hall, Sunday 17th October 14:00BST</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-knave-the-waking-of-willowby-hall-sunday-17th-october-14-00bst/7494</link>
    <description>Hi, a spot has opened up to play Knave: The Waking of Willowby Hall this Sunday, 17th October 14:00 BST (UTC+1) for GCOG.

It&#39;d be great if you could join us!

https://gauntlet-con.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjZb8E4t5q_c_wjj7ja

*The manor of Willowby Hall is under siege by a giant, enraged at the theft of his magical goose. The band of thieves has taken shelter within the manor&#39;s crumbling walls, cowering with their ill-gotten poultry as the building shakes itself apart. But something else is stirring. The giant&#39;s rampage is slowly awakening a Death Knight from its black slumber, and once it rises it will call on the bones of the manor&#39;s old residents to drive out the intruders.*

*Will the party loot the manor of its ancient relics, or succumb to the blades of its skeletal guardians? Who will make off with the goose and its golden eggs? Will anyone survive the giant&#39;s onslaught? The only way to find out...is to play.*</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:45:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-knave-the-waking-of-willowby-hall-sunday-17th-october-14-00bst/7494.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>GCOG Knave: The Waking of Willowby Hall, Sunday 17th October 14:00BST</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@gareththegeek]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gareththegeek">@gareththegeek</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi, a spot has opened up to play Knave: The Waking of Willowby Hall this Sunday, 17th October 14:00 BST (UTC+1) for GCOG.</p>
<p>It’d be great if you could join us!</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-con.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjZb8E4t5q_c_wjj7ja" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-con.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjZb8E4t5q_c_wjj7ja</a></p>
<p><em>The manor of Willowby Hall is under siege by a giant, enraged at the theft of his magical goose. The band of thieves has taken shelter within the manor’s crumbling walls, cowering with their ill-gotten poultry as the building shakes itself apart. But something else is stirring. The giant’s rampage is slowly awakening a Death Knight from its black slumber, and once it rises it will call on the bones of the manor’s old residents to drive out the intruders.</em></p>
<p><em>Will the party loot the manor of its ancient relics, or succumb to the blades of its skeletal guardians? Who will make off with the goose and its golden eggs? Will anyone survive the giant’s onslaught? The only way to find out…is to play.</em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-knave-the-waking-of-willowby-hall-sunday-17th-october-14-00bst/7494/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-knave-the-waking-of-willowby-hall-sunday-17th-october-14-00bst/7494/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7494-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-knave-the-waking-of-willowby-hall-sunday-17th-october-14-00bst/7494.rss">GCOG Knave: The Waking of Willowby Hall, Sunday 17th October 14:00BST</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
