<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Wool of Bat (Fridays in September, 8PM EST)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/wool-of-bat-fridays-in-september-8pm-est/7278</link>
    <description>
Being a witch isn&#39;t as fun as it sounds. Sure, there’s flying around on a broomstick, talking to spirits, learning dangerous secrets man was not meant to know, dancing naked under a full moon (if you’re into that sort of thing)… but then, there are _people_. And they always want your help. If you can fly a broomstick, someone wants you to get their kid&#39;s kite down from a tree. If you&#39;re on a first-name basis with _one_ malevolent spirit, everyone thinks you can exorcise their creaking floorboards. And then there are the constant requests for love potions and messages for dead relatives.

Worse: You&#39;re not the only one with magical powers, and the others range from terrifying creatures from other planes to your fellow witches, who have *no idea* what they’re doing. Who knows what trouble they could cause, fiddling with the balance of power?

Worst of all: Sometimes, once in a blue moon, you might need their help.

_Wool of Bat_ is a No Dice, No Masters hack where you play a fractious not-coven of witches, and elements of the world they live in. It&#39;s inspired by Terry Pratchett’s Discworld and Tiffany Aching books, but a general knowledge of fairy tales is probably all you need for context.


### Details
**Platform:** Streamyard, with Jitsi or Discord as a backup option. I&#39;ll email a link to the video call beforehand.
**Recording:** This session will be recorded. With players&#39; permission, the video and/or audio may be posted publicly afterward. I can obscure your face or cut out content on request.
**Attendance:** Joining all sessions is recommended but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.
**Breaks:** We&#39;ll aim for a break at the top of each hour, or when requested.
**CW:** The tone is usually pretty light and humorous, but there&#39;s potential for darker subjects. Especially body horror (turning people into other things), PvP violence, and mind control.
**Safety:** This game will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html), and we&#39;ll use Script Change tools and Lines and Veils. There will be *at least* Veils on torture, sexual assault/coercion, and graphic gore.

### Sessions
- [date=2021-09-03 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNO8zFH-2bX_dtvkI
-  [date=2021-09-10 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNXSojKwy4j0uAfvg
- [date=2021-09-17 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNgXdAt9kHLyxc5YR)
- [date=2021-09-24 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxO6x9zkyzmD2jtCK0</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 03:07:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/wool-of-bat-fridays-in-september-8pm-est/7278.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Wool of Bat (Fridays in September, 8PM EST)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bethany_H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bethany_h">@Bethany_H</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Being a witch isn’t as fun as it sounds. Sure, there’s flying around on a broomstick, talking to spirits, learning dangerous secrets man was not meant to know, dancing naked under a full moon (if you’re into that sort of thing)… but then, there are <em>people</em>. And they always want your help. If you can fly a broomstick, someone wants you to get their kid’s kite down from a tree. If you’re on a first-name basis with <em>one</em> malevolent spirit, everyone thinks you can exorcise their creaking floorboards. And then there are the constant requests for love potions and messages for dead relatives.</p>
<p>Worse: You’re not the only one with magical powers, and the others range from terrifying creatures from other planes to your fellow witches, who have <em>no idea</em> what they’re doing. Who knows what trouble they could cause, fiddling with the balance of power?</p>
<p>Worst of all: Sometimes, once in a blue moon, you might need their help.</p>
<p><em>Wool of Bat</em> is a No Dice, No Masters hack where you play a fractious not-coven of witches, and elements of the world they live in. It’s inspired by Terry Pratchett’s Discworld and Tiffany Aching books, but a general knowledge of fairy tales is probably all you need for context.</p>
<h3>Details</h3>
<p><strong>Platform:</strong> Streamyard, with Jitsi or Discord as a backup option. I’ll email a link to the video call beforehand.<br>
<strong>Recording:</strong> This session will be recorded. With players’ permission, the video and/or audio may be posted publicly afterward. I can obscure your face or cut out content on request.<br>
<strong>Attendance:</strong> Joining all sessions is recommended but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.<br>
<strong>Breaks:</strong> We’ll aim for a break at the top of each hour, or when requested.<br>
<strong>CW:</strong> The tone is usually pretty light and humorous, but there’s potential for darker subjects. Especially body horror (turning people into other things), PvP violence, and mind control.<br>
<strong>Safety:</strong> This game will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>, and we’ll use Script Change tools and Lines and Veils. There will be <em>at least</em> Veils on torture, sexual assault/coercion, and graphic gore.</p>
<h3>Sessions</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<span data-date="2021-09-03" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/New_York" data-email-preview="2021-09-04T00:00:00Z UTC">2021-09-04T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNO8zFH-2bX_dtvkI" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNO8zFH-2bX_dtvkI</a>
</li>
<li>
<span data-date="2021-09-10" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/New_York" data-email-preview="2021-09-11T00:00:00Z UTC">2021-09-11T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNXSojKwy4j0uAfvg" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNXSojKwy4j0uAfvg</a>
</li>
<li>
<span data-date="2021-09-17" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/New_York" data-email-preview="2021-09-18T00:00:00Z UTC">2021-09-18T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNgXdAt9kHLyxc5YR" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxNgXdAt9kHLyxc5YR</a>)</li>
<li>
<span data-date="2021-09-24" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/New_York" data-email-preview="2021-09-25T00:00:00Z UTC">2021-09-25T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxO6x9zkyzmD2jtCK0" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MgxO6x9zkyzmD2jtCK0</a>
</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/wool-of-bat-fridays-in-september-8pm-est/7278/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/wool-of-bat-fridays-in-september-8pm-est/7278/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 03:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7278-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/wool-of-bat-fridays-in-september-8pm-est/7278.rss">Wool of Bat (Fridays in September, 8PM EST)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
