<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bump in the Dark: Iron Country Autumn</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-iron-country-autumn/8283</link>
    <description>&gt; *The year is 1994 and the landscape of the Ontonagon Peninsula is dotted with rusting monuments to its history, abandoned headframes slouching like defeated giants. Shaft mining didn&#39;t last long in the grand scheme of things, but still they stand, reminders of a proud but dangerous history when the region known as &quot;Iron Country&quot; felt like the new frontier, the air alive with possibility, the danger of the mines proof of a delicate balance between the land and its people -- the land gives and the land takes, and such is the way of things.*
&gt; 
&gt; *These days, the people of Iron Country are facing down different dangers. Not just the indifferent forces of deindustrialization and a ruined economy, but dark dangers. The kinda shit people don&#39;t want to believe when you talk about it out loud. And that&#39;s where you come in. You&#39;re here to stop it. To come up against what goes bump in the dark, and make it stop bumping.*
&gt; 
&gt; *Are you up to the task?*

This is a 4 session, month-long series of my game  *Bump in the Dark*, a  **Forged in the Dark**  TTRPG about community, chosen family, and beating the shit outta monsters. The game is focused on tense investigations and action-packed showdowns, with regular folk caught in the middle. Using the  **Redacted Materials**  investigation system from  *External Containment Bureau*  and inspired by  *Brindlewood Bay*, you&#39;ll find clues, put together the pieces, and face off against monsters of your own design while the factions of Iron Country seek to harness the dark powers of the void. Downtime rules have been tweaked to highlight your connection to the community and the other hunters ... and up the drama, just like in the media that inspired the game.

No prior experience is required; rules will be taught at the table.

**Content Warning:**  The game focuses on investigation, combat, and interpersonal drama with horror elements. It defaults to a gritty tone with potentially difficult content such as violence, class struggle, and interpersonal/intraparty conflict. The game features paranormal, demonic, and psychological horror. Additional themes include found family, othering, redemption, and sacrifice. Think of Buffy or Supernatural with an R rating. Romance can be included if desired, but is not a required part of the game.

**Attendance**: Attending each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. RSVP Open Access Time is Sunday, August 7 at 2 PM Central Time. One seat is saved for Jesse A. and another is saved for Michael Elliott.

**Venue and Safety Tools**: We will use Streamyard for our sessions. Players can expect an email about a week before the first session with necessary links and resources. Please check your spam folders if you do not receive anything. Sessions will run up to three and a half hours with a ten minute break at the one-hour mark and a five-minute break at the two-hour mark. Sessions will be recorded but posted publicly only with everyone&#39;s enthusiastic consent. The [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) and [Open Door Policy](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/tools-of-the-table.html) will be in effect and safety tools will include [Lines and Veils](https://rpg.stackexchange.com/questions/30906/%20what-do-the-terms-lines-and-veils-mean), the [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg), and elements of [Script Change](https://briebeau.com/thoughty/script-change/). After the session, players will be invited to participate in an optional debrief using [Stars and Wishes](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/stars-and-wishes).

* [date=2022-10-06 time=19:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 1/4](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jUeXLc2xoJtTj9Yhe)
* [date=2022-10-13 time=19:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 2/4](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jUxp290ZwZi6ZXgxb)
* [date=2022-10-20 time=19:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 3/4](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jV4hJsPp8E0T-bnji)
* [date=2022-10-27 time=19:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 4/4](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jVK-ALM_kqXoKgNQ_)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 19:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-iron-country-autumn/8283.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bump in the Dark: Iron Country Autumn</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p><em>The year is 1994 and the landscape of the Ontonagon Peninsula is dotted with rusting monuments to its history, abandoned headframes slouching like defeated giants. Shaft mining didn’t last long in the grand scheme of things, but still they stand, reminders of a proud but dangerous history when the region known as “Iron Country” felt like the new frontier, the air alive with possibility, the danger of the mines proof of a delicate balance between the land and its people – the land gives and the land takes, and such is the way of things.</em></p>
<p><em>These days, the people of Iron Country are facing down different dangers. Not just the indifferent forces of deindustrialization and a ruined economy, but dark dangers. The kinda shit people don’t want to believe when you talk about it out loud. And that’s where you come in. You’re here to stop it. To come up against what goes bump in the dark, and make it stop bumping.</em></p>
<p><em>Are you up to the task?</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a 4 session, month-long series of my game  <em>Bump in the Dark</em>, a  <strong>Forged in the Dark</strong>  TTRPG about community, chosen family, and beating the shit outta monsters. The game is focused on tense investigations and action-packed showdowns, with regular folk caught in the middle. Using the  <strong>Redacted Materials</strong>  investigation system from  <em>External Containment Bureau</em>  and inspired by  <em>Brindlewood Bay</em>, you’ll find clues, put together the pieces, and face off against monsters of your own design while the factions of Iron Country seek to harness the dark powers of the void. Downtime rules have been tweaked to highlight your connection to the community and the other hunters … and up the drama, just like in the media that inspired the game.</p>
<p>No prior experience is required; rules will be taught at the table.</p>
<p><strong>Content Warning:</strong>  The game focuses on investigation, combat, and interpersonal drama with horror elements. It defaults to a gritty tone with potentially difficult content such as violence, class struggle, and interpersonal/intraparty conflict. The game features paranormal, demonic, and psychological horror. Additional themes include found family, othering, redemption, and sacrifice. Think of Buffy or Supernatural with an R rating. Romance can be included if desired, but is not a required part of the game.</p>
<p><strong>Attendance</strong>: Attending each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. RSVP Open Access Time is Sunday, August 7 at 2 PM Central Time. One seat is saved for Jesse A. and another is saved for Michael Elliott.</p>
<p><strong>Venue and Safety Tools</strong>: We will use Streamyard for our sessions. Players can expect an email about a week before the first session with necessary links and resources. Please check your spam folders if you do not receive anything. Sessions will run up to three and a half hours with a ten minute break at the one-hour mark and a five-minute break at the two-hour mark. Sessions will be recorded but posted publicly only with everyone’s enthusiastic consent. The <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> and <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/tools-of-the-table.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Open Door Policy</a> will be in effect and safety tools will include <a href="https://rpg.stackexchange.com/questions/30906/%20what-do-the-terms-lines-and-veils-mean" rel="nofollow noopener">Lines and Veils</a>, the <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">X-Card</a>, and elements of <a href="https://briebeau.com/thoughty/script-change/" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change</a>. After the session, players will be invited to participate in an optional debrief using <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/stars-and-wishes" rel="nofollow noopener">Stars and Wishes</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<span data-date="2022-10-06" data-time="19:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-10-07T00:00:00Z UTC">2022-10-07T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jUeXLc2xoJtTj9Yhe" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 1/4</a>
</li>
<li>
<span data-date="2022-10-13" data-time="19:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-10-14T00:00:00Z UTC">2022-10-14T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jUxp290ZwZi6ZXgxb" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 2/4</a>
</li>
<li>
<span data-date="2022-10-20" data-time="19:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-10-21T00:00:00Z UTC">2022-10-21T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jV4hJsPp8E0T-bnji" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 3/4</a>
</li>
<li>
<span data-date="2022-10-27" data-time="19:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-10-28T00:00:00Z UTC">2022-10-28T00:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8jVK-ALM_kqXoKgNQ_" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 4/4</a>
</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-iron-country-autumn/8283/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-iron-country-autumn/8283/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 19:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8283-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-iron-country-autumn/8283.rss">Bump in the Dark: Iron Country Autumn</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
