<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Good First Time LARPs?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993</link>
    <description>I&#39;ve been slowly starting / growing a regular play group over the past few months, and it&#39;s gotten to the point where we have more people interested in playing than can fit comfortably in a typical TTRPG system. Meanwhile, I&#39;ve also been looking to try out more LARPs. I played my first few at Big Bad Con last year, and they were fun as heck. Since LARPs seem better suited to playing with 7-10 people at a time, I&#39;m thinking I can solve both my &quot;too many players&quot; and &quot;haven&#39;t played enough LARPs&quot; problems at the same time. The only hitch: I don&#39;t have any idea what LARPs are good!

Anyone have suggestions for 7-10 player LARPs, especially ones that might be friendly to people new to RPGs at large? Preferably ones that can fit in a 3-4 hour time frame?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 02:46:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Good First Time LARPs?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sam">@Sam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>These are all great suggestions! Excited to read a bunch of larps over the weekend to see what stands out. Sign was already on my short list (as one of the like 3 larps I’ve read before), On Display looks intriguing, and someone I asked offline also recommended We Are Roommates Now. I really like the sound of Tribunal, though I think we’ll be on the short side of players / won’t want to get that intense off the bat.</p>
<p>A bunch of these other suggestions look great for a “2nd or 3rd time around” list. Strange Gravity - love me a Star Trek.</p>
<p>I’ll be sure to report back with what I decide on. Thank you to everyone so far!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 02:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1993-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993.rss">Good First Time LARPs?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Good First Time LARPs?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s so exciting to introduce people to live action play! New people are the best players, always. You’ll have a great time. I’d suggest finding a couple of games that sound really fun to you personally, and then letting your group choose the one that fits their mood and comfort level.</p>
<p>Seconding <em><a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/202647/Strange-Gravity-BUNDLE" rel="nofollow noopener">Strange Gravity</a></em> for that size group. Maybe not for your first larp, though.</p>
<p><em><a href="http://leavingmundania.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/tribunal_02.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">The Tribunal</a></em> will sort of work with 8-10 and is designed for 12. It’s a good first larp if people are on board for some intensity.</p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/152644/Still-Life?manufacturers_id=8663" rel="nofollow noopener">Still Life</a></em> is a great first larp and scales well to any size group. It’s simple and fun and, at its best, a little thought-provoking. The rules say up to 10 but I’ve run it with 20. Needs a facilitator.</p>
<p><em><a href="http://www.goldencobra.org/pdf/2016/WeAreRoommatesNow_Gorman.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">We Are Roommates Now</a></em> is great for up to 8. It is silly and delightfully simple.</p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/149064/Will-That-Be-All" rel="nofollow noopener">Will That Be All?</a></em> mentioned above is a lovely game for 6-10.</p>
<p><a href="https://thornygames.com/pages/sign" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>Sign</em></a> is my favorite “first larp” and a beautiful experience, but it is for 4-7. Play it anyway, it is great. Benefits from a facilitator.</p>
<p>All of these games take about two hours, more or less, to play. Maybe three on the outside.</p>
<p>You might also strike gold (see what I did there?) by trolling through the archives of the <a href="http://www.goldencobra.org/archives.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Golden Cobra Challenge</a>, which is full of interesting short freeform larps.</p>
<p>I could recommend some of my own if you want as well.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 13:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1993-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993.rss">Good First Time LARPs?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Good First Time LARPs?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Strange Gravity</em> by Jay Treat, if you also want an exercise in distributed authority. This is essentially Star Trek: The Next Generation: The Larp. There is no MC, and all GM-like roles are distributed to players based on their role on the ship. This is a hard game.</p>
<p><em>Symbiosis</em> by Sarah Lynne Bowman, if memory serves. That feels right. This is a game about growing up and developing new emotional capabilities.</p>
<p><em>Tribunal</em>, written by <a href="https://nordiclarp.org/wiki/J._Tuomas_Harviainen" rel="nofollow noopener">J. Tuomas Harviainen</a>, English version done with the help of Jason Morningstar. This is a game about the mechanism of oppression.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 12:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1993-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993.rss">Good First Time LARPs?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Good First Time LARPs?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@LarpWellington]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/larpwellington">@LarpWellington</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If you’re after theatre-style with pre-designed characters, these are my suggestions</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="http://www.paracelsus-games.com/theatrical-experiences/on-display" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>On Display</em></a> by Paracelsus Games is only 6 players (and an NPC for half an hour), but it is a perfect beginner’s theatreform. The character sheets are simple, yet flavourful. I have a review of it <a href="https://www.rpg.net/reviews/archive/17/17056.phtml" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/144589/The-Face-of-Oblivion?src=Gauntlet" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>The Face of Oblivion</em></a> by Cat Pegg (6-8 players) is a tense larp about how people confront a crisis. Review <a href="https://www.rpg.net/reviews/archive/16/16321.phtml" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>
</li>
<li>
<em>Hamlet</em> by Shifting Forest Storyworks (8 players). Chuck the rules, there’s a pretty good game under them.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once people are feeling more comfortable, I would highly recommend <a href="http://www.paracelsus-games.com/theatrical-experiences/howling-fire-theomachy" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>Howling Fire Theomachy</em></a> by Paracelsus (8 players). It has longer character sheets, but they are well worth it.</p>
<p>On the freeform side, I quite like <em>Will That be All</em> by Graham Walmsley, and <em>Arsenic &amp; Lies</em> looks good. But I’m more a theatre-style person.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for more, there’s a list <a href="https://wiki.rpg.net/index.php/LARP_Scenarios" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a> which is regularly updated, and I can answer questions about quite a few of them.</p>
<p>(Disclosure: I write larps. None of the above are by me. If you’re interested in the stuff I do, here’s my <a href="https://www.patreon.com/larpwellington" rel="nofollow noopener">patreon</a>).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 08:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1993-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993.rss">Good First Time LARPs?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Good First Time LARPs?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sam">@Sam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve been slowly starting / growing a regular play group over the past few months, and it’s gotten to the point where we have more people interested in playing than can fit comfortably in a typical TTRPG system. Meanwhile, I’ve also been looking to try out more LARPs. I played my first few at Big Bad Con last year, and they were fun as heck. Since LARPs seem better suited to playing with 7-10 people at a time, I’m thinking I can solve both my “too many players” and “haven’t played enough LARPs” problems at the same time. The only hitch: I don’t have any idea what LARPs are good!</p>
<p>Anyone have suggestions for 7-10 player LARPs, especially ones that might be friendly to people new to RPGs at large? Preferably ones that can fit in a 3-4 hour time frame?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 07:16:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1993-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/good-first-time-larps/1993.rss">Good First Time LARPs?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
