<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662</link>
    <description>At this point, many people have played and/or run Hearts of Wulin, an upcoming wuxia melodrama game by @edige23 and @Agatha. The purpose of this thread is to collect feedback for Lowell and Agatha, as well as to discuss the game in general. What did you like about the game? What excites you? What left with you questions? What other recommendations do you have? 

Please be respectful with your feedback or when commenting on the feedback of other participants in the thread. 

If you&#39;d like to learn more about Hearts of Wulin, check out the info page right here: 

https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/hearts-of-wulin.html</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 07:20:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chuangdangjianghu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chuangdangjianghu">@chuangdangjianghu</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This helps a ton. This connects a lot of dots about how to leverage the rules system to fit different types of action. While I’ve read a lot of PbtA rules, my actual play time has largely been D&amp;D and other more simulationist systems so sometimes the jump can still be hard. This totally makes sense though, and I appreciate it.</p>
<p>This game is so cool!!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/64">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/64</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 07:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-64</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So let me run through how I’ve handled these details and give some options.</p>
<p>First: Poison. Yes, poison’s a classic element-- and you’ll notice the Deadly Venoms move actually deals with that. Generally that’s used when an NPC gets poisoned. If someone chooses that move, then I try to have several different kinds of poisoners and poisons. That’s handled pretty much fictionally.</p>
<p>Poison can also be part of the fictional descriptor-- a player could have that as part of how they describe their style, though that would seem like a more corrupt or unorthodox approach, but I can imagine a reformed villain as PC trying to use that for good.</p>
<p>If Poison’s an element of an foe, how can you use that. The easiest part of that is as part of the fictional positioning-- that’s how they’re fighting an dealing damage. In this case the damage is quick and can be dealt with after the scene, so it functions as any other weapon, though more sinister. But Poison’s also a cool add-on for a Hard Move or a cost (for Duel or Overcome vs. a Poisoning foe). You have a couple of options: a) have the player mark an element, but note that they cannot clear it until they go to see someone who can treat it. b) give them an ongoing effect-- like they’re sleepy or blinded until they can get a cure. Then future hard and soft moves can revolve around that. Alternately, “You’ve been poisoned and will die in three days, unless…” is also a great hard move which presents some new story options and choices.</p>
<p>If you want to make a poisoning foe more threatening, you can borrow a step from the Fantastic section and have players mark an element when they engage a foe. If you do this, make sure the players know beforehand so they can make that choice or come up with a way to counter it. If you have someone Study a poisoning foe for scale, you might also add in that their character realizes that if they fight their foe, the poison’s a real challenge-- and that a 7-9 result on a Duel will have a specific effect rather than player choice.</p>
<p>Again that presents this as a thread, but one the player’s aware of. The only time I’d surprise a player with a poison effect would be on a hard move.</p>
<p>*I’d handle neigong injuries much the same way. In this case I might offer as a cost or impose as a hard move that they can’t use on of their playbook moves until it’s taken care of. These kinds of effects are classic for PCs narrating how they want to reduce the scale of a foe. It’s a good way to frame the things they learn using the New Technique move.</p>
<p>So, generally again these are details of the fiction which we can roll into the narrative rather than having a large set of sub-systems.</p>
<p>Meridian manipulation also falls into this class. It can be a New Technique or perhaps it’s an Overcome move done to affect the opponent’s scale for someone else. This is a good Hard Move if done against a PC-- perhaps until they get that cleared up, foes which would normally be on their scale will be above.</p>
<p>The rules are written broadly enough to let you roll those fictional details into your descriptions: of combats, foes, strikes, techniques, etc.</p>
<p>I hope that helps a little.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/63">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/63</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 16:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-63</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chuangdangjianghu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chuangdangjianghu">@chuangdangjianghu</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The rulebooks finally got sent out! I just finished it and love it. No clue when/how I’ll get to play (life isn’t easy for TTRPGers in China!), but still, awesome stuff.</p>
<p>I had some questions for how people might use the rules system to deal with certain story elements that are extremely common in wuxia, but whose mechanical resolution I’m not quite sure how to manage.</p>
<ul>
<li>Poison! Poison is a huge part of wuxia stories. My gut says that this should be treated narratively, rather than mechanically? But poisoning is such a huge part of so many wuxia stories, and doesn’t get too much treatment in the rules. Am curious how people deal with it at the table!</li>
<li>How to deal with “neigong” type injuries. Again, these come up a ton in wuxia stories…where for whatever reason, someone needs special intervention or they will die (condor heroes) or be incapable of wugong (<a class="mention" href="/u/edige23">@edige23</a>’s beloved laughing in the wind is a classic example of this!). I imagine again it can just be a plot thing, where it makes sense…it could perhaps even be rolled into the process of gaining scale? But also, these really are super common in the stories, so curious.</li>
<li>How to deal with meridian manipulation. This sort of thing is also super common…there are many characters in wuxia that don’t necessarily have amazing wugong, but they’re really good at hitting meridians to disable much stronger foes (protagonist of Handsome Siblings is an example, but meridian stuff is super common). For this I imagine it could be seen as “another type of attack”? Like, use the normal combat, but even for a stronger foe, if you get an outcome where you escape, perhaps your escape is because of meridians. But it’s also common to have situation where you “get the drop” on someone and use meridians to incapacitate them etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m familiar with pbta systems but am not an expert, so I imagine there might be some well tread ways to expand rules systems to deal with things like this that I just don’t know. I appreciate the patience!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/62">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/62</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 15:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-62</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joecrak]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joecrak">@Joecrak</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I haven’t gotten to play Coeur de l’Epee, but I see and share many of your feelings in regards to HoW.</p>
<p>Inner conflict, especially, the 7-9 feels like 1-9 is nothing but hard moves.</p>
<p>More often than not, I mark an element, because running away pretty much ends a scene, and rarely in a satisfactory note.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/61">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/61</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 04:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-61</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Pawel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/pawel">@Pawel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I had the pleaseure to playtest 3 sessions in recent run by Alun of Coeur de l’Epee setting for HoW.<br>
I have played HoW before and I enjoyed it every time, but in Coeur de l’Epee I had major problem with moves and fiction. Also everyone else enjoyed the game greatly, so I might be the odd one.<br>
Here is my issues and feedback.</p>
<ol>
<li>Inner Conflict move 7-9 result is missing an ending.<br>
“On a 7-9 you must either flee the scene or mark an element (your choice).” if you mark an element then what? you pull through or not?<br>
The most common of what I see in other games would be to add “On a 7-9 you must either flee the scene or mark an element (your choice) <strong>to take 10+ result</strong>.”</li>
<li>Inner Conflict as a whole. I hardly call it a move, any move in PbtA game resolves something, even Defy Danger resolves some peace of fiction, Inner Conflict doesn’t resolve anything. As such I see it as a resistance roll, you roll in order to avoid bad outcome with 10+ adding nothing to the fiction. What I would love to see is for the move having a clearly defined stake - why do you roll this move? what is at stake? In some games Defy Danger sort of moves have this as part of the move description “say what you are trying to avoid”.<br>
Why it doesn’t resolve anything? Because it is so unspecific. Something happens in fiction on a 6- as GM makes a move. Something happens at 7-9 if you flee the scene. Nothing happens at other results - you keep it together or maybe mark an element, but this also has no fictional outcome.</li>
<li>Inner Conflict as an XP farm. In the game I played in 50% of PC XP was from this move. On a miss it awards even more XP. As such it is clearly written as the most used move. I’m not sure if it is a good design to have one move marked such obviously as XP farm.</li>
<li>Inner Conflict trigger. “face to face with emotional turmoil and pressure from an entanglement or personal issue” is so not concrete and open to interpretation. Let me illustrate it with an example. There is a King’s party (in Coeur de l’Epee) and my character is secretly in love with one of the women at the court, a big dance is starting and I want to ask her for a dance. When should I roll the move? Before I ask her for a dance or as we dance? I expect the game rules to inform me with a fictional trigger.</li>
<li>Inner Conflict result ‘flee the scene’ doesn’t fit Coeur de l’Epee setting. I’m not well versed in original HoW setting, but I’ve seen most of source material for Coeur de l’Epee - Musketeers, Man in Iron Mask etc. Characters in those movies do not ‘flee the scene’ but they make a fool from themselves and become source for gossips at the court, they lose reputation. That would be more fitting result in my opinion for this setting.</li>
<li>Players should be somehow rewarded for engagin with another player Entanglement that targets them. (this reward XP could possible replace the XP from Inner Conflict)</li>
<li>Hearts and Minds 7-9 results are not successes. They are a hard punch in the face and they are great ideas for 6-, but they are not a success with a cost, 7-9 should be a success with a cost -&gt; they agree, but overreact.</li>
<li>Bonds. They are weird, really weird. I understand that you seek to make them more mechanical than Hx or DW Bonds, but they are weird and they play weird. When a Bond can be used - anytime? So I’m dueling someone, I burn a bond on my father and I get a +1? does it make any sense?</li>
<li>What does it mean to have an element mark? Why there is “Obsessive, Disdainful, Uncaring” written and a place to write a condition? should I pick one that fits the fiction and use it as a cue for my roleplaying?</li>
<li>Face to Fate reads “On a 6- mark XP and the GM gains a soft move from fate for later use”. GMs job is to be doing soft move all the time, a 6- should either give GM permission to do a hard move or just say GM gets a move, but that’s quite obvious, anyway it should not be only a “soft” move.</li>
</ol>
<p>What is good in the game?<br>
EVERYTHING else. I love Entanglement. I love factions. I love scale of enemies.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/60">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/60</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 08:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-60</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I am looking forward to putting the ‘Coeur de l’epee’ stretch goal setting on the Gauntlet Calendar as soon as it’s available.  I feel I can embrace Wuxia as a player but I still lack the confidence to run it.  Swashbuckling Musketeers though … That I can do!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/59">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/59</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 10:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-59</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There’s some ideas for handling Xianxia in there-- both about how to shift the fiction and some mechanical add-ons you can use to help simulate things like The Untamed (which is great), Ice Fantasy, or Martial Universe.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/58">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/58</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 02:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-58</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m curious how the system would work for wuxia adjacent genres. I’m generally skeptical of xianxia, but I just watched the untamed and…quite enjoyed it. But it has a lot of complexities that I’m not sure how HoW would handle! (Or if it even should)</p>
<p>I like how HoW handles combat a lot, because ironically, wuxia isn’t really about the combat, and the stronger person usually wins in a direct confrontation. But in xianxia, people have a much more complicated array of powers…it gets into exalted territory honestly. So I dunno!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/57">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/57</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 19:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-57</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just finished watching 天龙八部 (half gods and semi devil’s, I think?). 1997 version, the classic good stuff.</p>
<p>Hoping we get some exciting hearts of wulin news sooner than later. I need wuxia roleplaying melodrama in my life <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/56">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/56</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-56</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think the key is to explain what makes a good or bad entanglements. Here is my attempt at an example, though the game designers can no doubt do this more consistently with the rules. But I think the key is to explain entanglements in terms of goals and contextualize why romantic entanglements might be particular good/common in light of that. My attempt:</p>
<p>In the wuxia genre, these entanglements are generally romantic. Romantic entanglements are often good catalysts for interesting drama because they can create interesting contradictions, they can get people to make decisions they otherwise wouldn’t – decisions they’d only make when love is on the line. That said, in the wuxia genre there are also non-romantic entitlements, and we want to support players who are interested in non-romantic themes. That said, a good entanglement is one which will put the character into a bind, which will potentially drive the character to make serious decisions with serious ramifications. Would this entanglement potentially lead to the character disobeying their master, leave a revenge unavenged, or in some other way violate personal and social codes? Perfect! A less useful entanglement is one that let’s the player off the hook, that doesn’t challenge them, that lets them easily satisfy everyone.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/55">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/55</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 16:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-55</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Maybe something along the lines of “It is strongly encouraged to have one of these entanglements be romantic or familial, especially for players new to the game.”</p>
<p>That turns it into a bit more of a “best practice” than a rule, and also broadens the space a little.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/54">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/54</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 16:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-54</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for the welcome, <a class="mention" href="/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a>! I guess I’ve been lurking waiting for hearts of Wulin updates. I’m a huge wuxia junkie and am really excited about this take on the genre. I don’t have many chances to play games ATM but am hoping I can get a pbf going of HoW once the final rules come out!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/53">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/53</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 12:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-53</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Welcome to the Forums <a class="mention" href="/u/jco">@jco</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/52</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 11:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree on the entanglement thing - familial stuff in particular is very important in most of the C-Dramas I have watched and there are lots of fun ways to be hidden relatives owing some deep filial debt.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/51</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 22:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I 100% support entanglements not having to be romantic. I think it will make the game better at no cost (people can still choose the romantic route if they want!).</p>
<p>A question, as I saw in the Kickstarter update that the rules are finalized: what meaty stuff is in the final rules that’s not in the playtest packet, out of curiosity? I’m particularly interested in whether or not you’ve fleshed out the rules for longer term play. The playtest packet is oriented towards one shots and very short campaigns (understandably!), I’m curious how the full rules will adapt to longer campaigns (which is what I’m interested in)</p>
<p>Keep up the good work!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/50</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 02:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sorry, <a class="mention" href="/u/cinphoria">@Cinphoria</a>. I was referring to anyone who wanted to do that, but I understand and agree with your assessment that I messed up, and edited that phrase out. Sorry again.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/49</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 17:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Cinphoria]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cinphoria">@Cinphoria</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Jim - painting marginalised people as “insisting” and being on the outside and an exception and drawing attention to themselves because they want to play a character who’s like themselves is the exact attitude I’d like to see explictly erased in modern tabletop roleplaying games.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/48</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 22:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It seems to me like it’d be easy enough to allow a player to frame their other entanglement around family or friendship instead with a request to other players to leave them out of their own romantic Entanglements. (Though it occurs to me that there are even Romantic entanglements of the ‘we’re meant to be together but XXX wants to keep us apart’ where XXX could have familial or friendship reasons for that…)</p>
<p>I’d maybe worry that <em>everyone</em> doing so would constitute actual premise drift, but even then the Inner Conflict mechanic is probably robust enough to handle it without any hacking.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/47</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 18:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes it is. I had the chance to sit down with Agatha at Gen Con and we spotted some things we want to adjust, particularly a few moves. I will try to get another iteration out for use in the next several weeks.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/46</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 13:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s certainly a good point-- and I’ll keep that in mind as we work on the Entanglement sections.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/45</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 01:55:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Cinphoria]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cinphoria">@Cinphoria</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The wuxia genre is built on tropes, and many of those tropes are problematic. While some of the tropes are interesting to incorporate to confront and examine, some, I feel, are unnecessary for us to capitulate to as they only serve to exclude groups of people.</p>
<p>The one I’m concerned with here is the core concept of the romantic entanglement. While romance is a prominent element of wuxia fiction, the instruction that each character must choose a romantic entanglement says to players that someone categorically cannot play an aromantic character. I believe that it wouldn’t take away from the feel of  the genre to change this to a love entanglement of any kind - romantic, platonic, familial, etc, and would fix a gap in the wuxia genre that denies and excludes the existence of aro and ace people.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/44</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 22:31:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/edige23">@edige23</a> <a class="mention" href="/u/agatha">@Agatha</a> Is the packed dated 4/23 the latest playtest version? I’m going to start a campaign in the next couple months and want to make sure I have the latest. Thanks!</p>
<p>PS: I’m also a kickstarter backer.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/43</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That sounds great. I would probably suggest though on the character sheet not saying explicitly how many moves to choose (other than the role) - just say something like “discuss with your GM how many moves to take and when.” Otherwise the players are going to already start making those choices in their heads…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/42</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 22:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Our plan has been to offer some dials and guidelines to GMs about how to tuned the game based on the number of sessions: entanglements, experience mechanics, # of moves.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/41</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin Discussion</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yay Necro-thread! I’ll follow up with something related to what <a class="mention" href="/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> noted: specifically that the Moves chosen are pointers to the GM (and TBH other players, but they are less likely to think of them as such) as to what the player wants to see in the series. Now, you’ll notice I used the word “series” there. I feel that taking the time to choose Moves during chargen (beyond the Role) wastes time and can end up locking players into useless abilities if you are playing a oneshot (and possibly even a twoshot depending on what the GM has planned).</p>
<p>If you have three or more sessions (and perhaps two for experienced GMs) you as the GM can set up situations to really show off those moves that work within the story.</p>
<p>I don’t know if this goes in the chargen rules or on sheets or in a teaching guide (which I think are frickin awesome) or in the GM section… Maybe something in the beginning of session move wherein you can pick a different move if it hasn’t been used yet (though that could throw off the GM’s planning…)?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662/40</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 18:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1662-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-discussion/1662.rss">Hearts of Wulin Discussion</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
