<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534</link>
    <description>This may just be a personal shibboleth, but every time I see questions in forums and theories on blogs about a &quot;Big Bad Evil Guy&quot;, it frustrates, saddens and vaguely infuriates me. The idea that what every campaign needs to work is some kind of reoccurring villian who always escapes is just frustratingly pointless and seems to provide endless encouragement or justification for GM misbehaviour. 

I&#39;m not even opposed in principle to reoccurring arch-antagonists, but treating every campaign like an 80&#39;s kids cartoon designed to sell action figures and so requiring some kind of Skeletor who is constantly thwarted until a finale feels stultifying, restrictive and an excuse for antagonistic GMing.

Thank you for listening to my rant.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 23:24:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaerdaph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thinking about this more and going back to basics, it’s <em>conflict</em> that’s at the center of any story. The BBEG is just [and I really hate the archaic, sexist phrases man vs. man, man vs. nature etc. so I’m going to go with] protagonist vs. antagonist. But that’s not the only type of conflict found in stories and by extension, this should apply to RPGs as well.</p>
<p>So there could be RPG adventures and settings that feature protagonist vs. nature, or vs. the environment, vs. society, vs. machine, vs. fate, even vs. themselves as the central conflict.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/34</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 23:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaerdaph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Another option to the BBEG could be an intangible, underlying evil force that drives and unifies everything, and the PCs can’t really confront it outright or fully understand its nature. Examples would be the Dark Powers from the Ravenloft campaign setting (or the similar Red Death from the Masque of the Red Death Gothic Earth setting) and The Evil Way from the CHILL RPG. Such a force adds a layer of depth to what would otherwise be a monster of the week type setup.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/33</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 23:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@gartsalrisa]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gartsalrisa">@gartsalrisa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/gus.l/40/1716_2.png" class="avatar"> Gus.L:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t mean to be a jerk, but this sounds pretty condescending to ones players “they won’t enjoy my game or become invested in it unless I spoon feed them narrative beats…”</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I agree that “spoon feed” can be read as dismissive. I can also attest that a less colloquial version of the same statement–e.g. “some players do not enjoy my game or become invested in it unless they are provided vivid, identifiable, narrative beats to work with”–is absolutely true. It’s not my preferred environment at the table by a fair margin, but I have friends who are smart, clever, respected, completely devoid in expertise with cartoons who immediately become frustrated and/or bored when there is not an adventure path with a targetable adversary. <em>Why</em> that the case is to some degree irrelevant: They know the style of play they enjoy and what aspects they find entertaining.</p>
<p>Along those lines…</p>
<aside class="quote no-group">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/gus.l/40/1716_2.png" class="avatar"> Gus.L:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’d argue BBEGs [in TRPG campaigns] are an artifact of: 1. “Adventure Path” design. 2. Increasingly complex mechanics 3. Conscious design choices to emulate videogame narrativism/genre 4. Streamed actual play: its time constraints, need for consistent actual and serialization.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Streamed play is not a contributor to the preferences of the example table I just mentioned–I say this with a fair amount of confidence since only two of us have even watched any streamed play (well, unless the other folks are refusing to admit it.) That said, based on the experiences implied in your posts <a class="mention" href="/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a>, I can imagine in many situations streamed play is a contributor in the way you posit. Meanwhile, I’d argue that “adventure path design” and “videogame narratism” are the same apect, when it is a contributor. And I am interested to hear more about how you think complex mechanics would foster a predilection toward use of BBEG.</p>
<p>But I also think one key contributor is missing: Some (maybe many, or maybe even most) players like having a BBEG. They enjoy it. It brings them pleasure. To tease out why is to tease out why you see a BBEG so often in so many other media. The game system or adventure module is not shaping their play as much as the play they prefer is attracting them to the system or adventure module. The players are choosing to play that way.</p>
<p>The people at the table always have more of an effect on the style of play than the rules and notes, yah? If I read you correctly, you’d have no problem if a BBEG emerged organically from gameplay, but you bristle at the idea that a preordained BBEG be the center of all interaction. I’m right there with you. I personally lose interest quickly when a I feel a BBEG is present as a trope, a crutch, or McGuffin’s Steward. My mind wanders quickly when I feel like a party is being shepherded through a series of set pieces toward an obligatory end spectacle. But I know for a fact that sometimes when that happens the person to my left and to my right is having a very different experience, that they feel they are being given a framework of opportunities to indulge in the experiences they like (battle tactics, problem solving, rolling lots of funny-shaped dice, speaking in outrageous accents). The table above shows up for the set pieces, emergent themes feel arbitrary to them. The good news is that they have a GM (not me) who groks this groove and everyone has a swell time.</p>
<p>None of this negates the passionate dismay <em>you feel</em>. You very much do not dig implementations of a certain approach. I hear you. It is not my experience, but I would definitely be frustrated if I felt like one specific, personally-unsatisfying style of play was choking out other options. I may be optimistically reading between the lines, but it <em>seems</em> like you have opportunities to play at tables that enjoy the same aspects as you do. I hope that is the case! And if it isn’t, I am confident you can find some opportunities here in this community!</p>
<p>Dig this thread!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/32</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 21:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I haven’t said it can’t in fact I’ve suggested two situations when it can:</p>
<p>A) When one is focused on genre emulation of a genre where a specific cliche is powerful. E.g. comic book villians.</p>
<p>B) when one has brought the players into the metanarrative through mechanics specifically aimed at genre emulation and playing with genre.</p>
<p>Yet I’ve also suggested that neither of those exist in the common places where the BBEG theory of design is most popular (contemporary trad play) and that even when there are reasons to do so the trope often forces antagonistic GMing and abrogation of player choice to maintain a predetermined narrative, which seems a high cost.</p>
<p>It’s not really a question worth asking in this space though, given this is a PbtA forum about narrative play. I might as well go to Dragonsfoot and talk about when and how illusionism is useful.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/31</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Why can’t the answer be “sometimes”?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 17:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>On Moriarty and Holmes I think you are onto something. The popularized Holmes of cartoons and movies - a stock character of the detective v. Doyle’s own work which plays more on the unease caused by the then novel anonymity of urban life.</p>
<p>At the core of this discussion though is the questions “Are TTRPGs genre fiction?”, “Is TTRPG design genre fiction design and TTRPG writing genre fiction writing?”, and “Under what circumstances are TTRPG designers well served by emulating the narrative tropes of genre fiction?”</p>
<p>I don’t think I have to clarify my positions on these questions, but they are very different then the question of where the BBEG trope comes from.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/29</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 15:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think this is a VERY good point.  Good versus evil, good guys versus a BBEG are simpler narratives that people have enjoyed for maybe thousands of years.   There is something satisfying in this sort of narrative for most people.  I think it largely reflects our wishes to be a hero archetype.  The easiest way to show a hero archetype generally is to showcase the opposite theme in a foil…the BBEG.  A hero is is defined by the theme / morality they show.  Therefore, the puporse of the BBEG should display the opposite morale / side of the theme.</p>
<p>That said, storytelling has become more detailed and complicated as people as a whole have become literate (generally the last 100 years).  Perhaps it is an overused narrative tool but it is certainly a popular one.  This is especially true in rpgs where players often overlook complicated plots in favor of morality tales.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 15:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jacob_Wood]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jacob_wood">@Jacob_Wood</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="26" data-topic="2534">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jesseabe/40/206_2.png" class="avatar"> Jesseabe:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Moriarty isn’t a BBEG in the Doyle stories. He appears in 2 out of tens of the stories. He is described in outsized language, yes, but that’s just one sentence in the entire corpus of Holmes stories. I suspect his role as outsized, recurring villain is a product of film.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Thanks for your insight. As a common person who only casually follows Sherlock Holmes, I actually wasn’t aware of this.</p>
<p>I think it does speak to my point, though. If he’s not as prevalent in the novels as he is in the films, why is he he so widely known amongst laypeople? What about that one villain has captured the imagination of others so much that he has become legendary, despite not being as significant as we give him credit for?</p>
<p>There’s a very strong link between character / hero fiction and arch nemesis / BBEG-type characters</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 12:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jesseabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jesseabe">@Jesseabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just a side note, because it irritates me and has been repeated a few times in this thread<br>
Moriarty isn’t a BBEG in the Doyle stories. He appears in 2 out of tens of the stories. He is described in outsized language, yes, but that’s just one sentence in the entire corpus of Holmes stories. I suspect his role as outsized, recurring villain is a product of film.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 05:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Also sorry to double post but I still strongly, strongly reject that the presence of BBEGs is because of video games or something. I think that is just a coincidence with when video games came about and when RPGs were developed…but I think that video games in fact are drawing from older storytelling traditions. Moriarty! So to think this is some sort of modern affliction on storytelilng is, IMO, completely off base. Read Chinese wuxia (pre-video game!) fiction, there is a ton of “we have the chance to kill the big bad but guess what, we’re not going to or we can’t because of (convenient reason X)”. Buffy did not invent that.</p>
<p>Edit: I should clarify that I do think video games as a genre (and things like comics, movies) have certainly influenced this sort of storytelling, and made it more of an expectation for many game players. But I don’t think they invented it at all, and I don’t like that line of thinking because I think again it sort of sells short the storytelling utility of a BBEG (even if I think there are other sorts of interesting stories!). As <a class="mention" href="/u/jacob_wood">@Jacob_Wood</a> mentioned, the key is to understand what people who use it or expect it want it for. I guess you can also just throw out the idea of any sort of planned narrative but…that seems like a broader debate!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 05:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think both <a class="mention" href="/u/jacob_wood">@jacob_wood</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> bring up great points. I quite agree with jacob around the utility of the BBEG, I also agree with Gus that there is a lot to examine in DND, though I think that warrants a longer post. Here, though, I just want  want to focus on one thing: I do not think it is “condescending” at all. I mean, I guess it depends on how it is executed. But I have played D&amp;D with lots of nice people who wanted to play, well, a game. And I think this is something that a lot of people in TTRPG spaces have little respect for. Everything is all about collaborative storytelling, narrative, etc. As if caring about the story just sort of was inherent to playing an RPG. Now, I bet for everyone who posts on the gauntlet, when they sit down to play a game, they are already engaged. They want to tell a story. They’re willing to take “suboptimal” choices to tell a good story. They’re engaging with the system and the story to maximize creative fun.</p>
<p>But…not everyone plays these games that way. I’m not saying it’s right or wrong, but I’ve had some really great sessions of D&amp;D and Dungeon World that were built around a sort of grand vision of a story. I think there are a lot of reasons that this is the case, and I think a balance must be struck, but I think that it’s doing a serious dissservice to both RPGs, GMs, and players to say that that sort of storytelling is condescending or bad. This is independent of colonialist, racist, etc themes, though of course one can examine why the two might appear together etc etc.</p>
<p>Many players just want to control their character, and sort of see what happens. They want to play through a movie, a choose your own adventure where they will be tested and ultimately experience amazing, dramatic things. There are lots of ways to get there, and some might argue that the PbtA style approach can facilitate a lot of investment and ultimately drive things to a satisfying ending. But like…a lot of people really enjoy that final showdown with the BBEG, they enjoy seeing the intricately laid plot laid bare, they enjoy finding out how it all fits together. Lots of people enjoy games like that. They sit down and think: ooh! I wonder what the GM is going to throw at me!</p>
<p>In the games I run these days I have tried hard to get people to see it as a more collaborative storytelling exercise, encouraging them to see it as a chance to get invested in the world…create interesting factions, NPCs, etc. Some people love that. Some people…just can’t get into it at all. Maybe you don’t want to play RPGs with those people, I don’t know. But I mean, I’ve had people who wanted a “traditional D&amp;D” type game with narrative beats and all that who still ended up doing things that were fun and memorable and made for a good story.</p>
<p>I think many people in the RPG community focus on the RP and forget the G aspect. Some people enjoy games where it’s all just RP facilitated by a little G, but sometimes, having some G can actually be very satisfying.</p>
<p>FWIW I don’t like to play D&amp;D anymore because I don’t like that it’s all about combat combat combat, I hate murder hobos, and I agree there is some deeply problematic stuff (I despise D&amp;D style “races”), but I feel like a lot of people on the gauntlet have this sort of “narrative reigns supreme” sort of view and I think it is in fact quite condescending to the many many people who want to engage in RPGs as games and not The Next Great American Novel, in session form.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 05:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t mean to be a jerk, but this sounds pretty condescending to ones players “they won’t enjoy my game or become invested in it unless I spoon feed them narrative beats…”  I also don’t think there aren’t genre (supers, Saturday morning cartoon emulation)  and mechanical (games with strong shared narrative or scene based structure) reason to include narrative beats - but they are no panacea.</p>
<p>Again the issue is not reoccurring villains or players developing antipathy towards, and hence engagement with the setting, the thing I hate is the assumption that there must be a reoccurring villain and that conflict with that villain, culminating in climactic confrontation make up a necessary and ideal aspect of campaign design.  This leads to illusionism and GM fiat antagonistically used to protect the villain (and story) from the players and by necessity invalidates and disfavors player choice.</p>
<p>In novels, movies and most videogames the user of the medium consumes the story passively. With TTRPGs one of the draws of the medium is that the user (player) is not passive, but active - with an authorial role.  My own opinion is that any game that help emphasize player choice is doing what TTRPGs can uniquely accomplish, rather then simply emulated other forms of entertainment.  Now I am open to the idea that this can be accomplished by inviting players into the meta aspects of the game - using mechanics and ethics of play where goals and success are themselves measured by how well the story produced hit genre specifics and narrative beats.  In these sorts of games BBEGs are perhaps forgivable, depending on genre, but in games where the player is inhabiting a role, as opposed to a authoring the meta narrative I can’t see a function for them because they imply predetermined narrative.</p>
<p>I also don’t think It’s an accident that this kind of adventure path thinking predominates in contemporary traditional play where the question of D&amp;D’s colonialist and racist taint are currently being debated.  If your game relies on forced narratives and predetermined evils, scenes and structures, it has no room for moral decisions by the players and without moral play the assumptions and underlying, perhaps unexamined, prejudices of the setting creators will be never face a challenge.  Player decision and moral interrogation allows counternarratives and player interaction with these assumptions however - and for this reason (among numerous others) I take a strong stand against illusionism and anti-choice mechanics and design.</p>
<p>So Jacob, I’ve gone beyond your point, and perhaps used your post as a straw man for my own takes about narrative and choice in TTRPGs - for that I apologize.  I do think that these questions are important to TTRPG theory at least (which may be the antithesis of important?), and that there’s a lot to be learned by interrogating them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 02:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jacob_Wood]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jacob_wood">@Jacob_Wood</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>After giving this a bit of thought, I noticed one common element in BBEG stories is that it usually creates a stronger connection between the protagonists and the villains. Even when reading advice articles about why one should have their BBEG show up from time-to-time and pester the players, that advice is being given because it helps forge a  stronger emotional bond with the enemy. The more you hate them, the more satisfying it is to defeat them.</p>
<p>This really isn’t new at all. Sherlock Holmes has an arch nemesis who serves as his own BBEG. Super heroes, action movie stars, and fantasy characters have all had similar counterparts for about as far back as their genres have existed.</p>
<p>So to retire the BBEG trope, we need to ask ourselves: in what other ways can we make the heroes invested in the story? Particularly in long-term campaign play, but in shorter campaigns and one-shots as well.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/22</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 19:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is very common and successful in comics. The Joker, Lex Luthor, Magneto?  Hence, movies are doing this commonly over the last decade.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 22:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I recently finished this episode (from 2018) about villains, BBEGs and adversaries. I found it quite insightful. Interestingly, I watch currently the 3rd season of Gomorrha - a series about neapolitanian mafiosi. So this came at the right moment. One question the podcast rose is what a setting without a villain looks like. And one possible answer is: like Gomorrha.</p>
<p>What I find fascinating from a mechanical point of view: there are no clear protagonists; at least not in a traditional sense. After watching three seasons - the fourth is on my list - there are persons with more screentime, so from that they must be something like the protagonists. To give you an impression: you start watching and are presented some persons with very deep detail and the relation to others and think: “oh, this is the story of these guys”. The very next moment, they are shot. “Oh. But then it’s about… No. Dead too”.<br>
And the same goes for the antagonists. There is no clear evil adversary: In the end they are all evil - nobody is safe. It’s the mafia. Everybodies influence is limited by the gunshot.</p>
<p>It’s literally AWs “looking through crosshairs” on screen.</p>
<p>And it’s not the way George RR Martin does it. It’s not this long buildup of relationship between audience and character. There is always a kind of distance between audience and characters. One does not identify with the characters but somehow still relate to them. There is no Toni Soprano.</p>
<p>I am sorry if this actually sounds like a review for the series <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/smile.png?v=9" title=":smile:" class="emoji" alt=":smile:"></p>
<p>But I wanted to share the podcast episode on “how to have no BBEG” and have interesting sessions and a good example of story writing for screenplay which shows that this could really work well.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="/uploads/default/original/2X/c/c8410f830627a41aec33870fead175f3082224e2.png" class="site-icon" width="" height="">
      <a href="https://9littlebees.com/mab016-all-things-villainous/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">9littlebees</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="/uploads/default/original/2X/4/409e5fcab97129d1bba61aff809272f7a5e44304.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="" height="">

<h3><a href="https://9littlebees.com/mab016-all-things-villainous/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">16: All Things Villainous • 9littlebees</a></h3>

<p>In Episode 16, Liam is joined once again by guest host Shawn to discuss villains. Themes include examining what makes a villain, the point of having a villain in your campaign, and the difference between enemies and villains.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 18:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’d say expanding the design choices of post 1990’s WotC and later edition D&amp;D (and PF) to cover all of D20 and then arguing that a mechanical solution cribbed from a very different tradition of play is required is both overstating the issue and creates it’s own problems.</p>
<p>If the problem with BBEG narrative in contemporary-trad games is that they stifle player choice and show contempt for player goals (which is my problem with them - not BBEG as aesthetic choice) by writing a narrative and then bending all actions toward it, the source of that narrative means little. It is perhaps marginally less irksome if you had a say in how the adventure path is written and if the final boss is a beholder, dragon goddess or liche, but it’s not saving the game from being a repetitive linear series of combats and maybe skill tests.</p>
<p>With the exception of the Hickmans, classic campaigns and adventures rarely include an explicit BBEG character, and they certainly don’t expect conflict with it to occur in a predictable manner.  You might kill B2’s Evil Priest in your first session, but maybe the minotaur or the Bugbear slavers are the real important leaders of the Caves of Chaos?  Even classic campaigns that include evil masterminds (Lloth in the G &amp; D series comes to mind) don’t structure encounters with these powers in a novelistic or filmic way.  D20 and a lack of session 0 aren’t the issue. Nor are BBEGs an unintended consequence of d20 mechanics.</p>
<p>I’d argue BBEGs are an artifact of: 1. “Adventure Path” design. 2. Increasingly complex mechanics 3. Conscious design choices to emulate videogame narrativism/genre 4. Streamed actual play: its time constraints, need for consistent actual and serialization.</p>
<p>BBEGs are purely a design choice, a useful enough one maybe if your combat mechanics and character building to optimize for them are the major source of fun in your game, the locus of play, and both the complexity of encounter creation and amount of play time devoted to tactical combat require design that more quickly from combat encounter/scene to combat encounter/scene.  Otherwise, outside a tactical combat or warfare context (maybe a narrativist genre-emulation one) they are a problem.</p>
<p>As an aside, the first thing I can think of using the BBEG is the Hickmans “Ravenloft”, and its worth noting that it represents an effort to shift genre from fantasy adventure to (camp?) horror, as well as showcasing thier growing interest in genre emulation/narrativism over simulationism/exploration play.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 14:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think why it’s so prevalent in the d20 fantasy spaces is those games have no formalized relationship mechanics. When the GM is thinking about campaign design, they don’t have any mechanical input from the players on what kinds of characters they want to interact with, and based on DnD’s more adversarial GM vs. player nature I think it’s somewhat expected that the first character the GM thinks of is going to be the ultimate adversary, and like you said, many of the published modules embrace this design.Also for games like DnD, where the GM is controlling many more characterless NPCs (in the form of mooks and minions) I think it might also be a draw for the GM to want one or two “big” characters that they operate, and an arch-villain gives that character a lot more agency in the world than a friendly cleric or guildmaster does, as the latter only exist to move the players’ story forward</p>
<p>This is kind of an aside, but I’ve been thinking recently about how there is a deep wealth of research on how language effects how we think. That is to say, the way in which we are able to express ourselves also shapes the ways in which we respond and analyze feedback. I think we can apply this thinking to roleplaying games in that if we read the options a text gives to the players to interact with the world, we can trace how it  consciously and subconsciously influences how the players respond to and want to act on the world.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/18</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 12:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree that in many D&amp;D and co type spaces, the BBEG trope is super common and taken for granted. I also think that it’s good to get away from.</p>
<p>That said, I also agree with <a class="mention" href="/u/gartsalrisa">@gartsalrisa</a> – I think you’re underselling how common this trope is in media, and to go further, I think it’s important to understand why. Before that, I’ll just say that I use BBEG fairly loosely, I mean it can be someone as conniving and all encompassing as Skeletor, But I think you know the evil grand vizier who is scheming to bring the kingdoms to war etc etc counts, even if they’re not quite as powerful. Just to get on the same page.</p>
<p>I think BBEGs were common before video games. Sauron, for example. And TV shows like Buffy and whatnot. I think they exist because they make it easy to motivate epic fantasy plots. Have you ever tried to run a game of courtly intrigue? It’s hard! Really hard! But knowing there’s this one being sort of playing chess behind the scenes simplifies a lot. Plus, it has an implied structure that is quite straightforward and fits well with traditional expectations of epic fantasy, as well as tradition leveling systems (which again existed before video games). With a BBEG, you get the drama of an unbeatable enemy – who eventually, through leveling and scheming and experience, you bring down. This is super satisfying to groups that want an epic fantasy campaign, because the investment in the foe as such is emergent from the gameplay itself. You have someone to focus your frustrations on, then eventually take down.</p>
<p>Compare that to what someone above said – various factions, then see where people go. This is a good approach to and is probably what I’d choose if I were running a DND type game these days. That said, when power and allegeniances and all that are diffuse, it’s going to take more work to get people to be invested in this side vs that said. It’s easy to want to take down the evil lich king. But it takes more work to get them to identify with faction 1 of 15, with the various shared of grey involved. Not hard or anything, it’s just a different kind of game with much less obvious pacing.</p>
<p>TLDR: BBEGs provide a classic, approachable type of drama that lends itself well to traditional epic fantasy arcs. I agree we can and should get away from that, but by understanding it’s strengths we can make sure we are still creating interesting stories that players will readily relate to!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 09:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s a popular enough topic of discussion in Contemporary Traditional (5E D&amp;D, PF) spaces, and seems especially popular among the fans and followers of streaming actual play, which makes sense given the performative nature and strongly GM narrative focus of that medium.  Likewise I’d say that several of the WotC module tomes have embraced the idea.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 23:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Something I learned from the intro adventure in <strong>Feng Shui 1ED</strong> is that you can have a BBEG, but you only meet its henchmen. So it doesn’t matter what you do with one of it’s arms, the head will always remain. A lot of roleplaying games expands on this and create entities that will affect the worlds in a (for the characters) negative way. <strong>Mutant Chronicles</strong> got its five apostles that affects the opposition in each adventure, or (an example for better suited for this forum) the fronts in <strong>Apocalypse World</strong> could be said to be the heads of each type of henchmen.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 19:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@RenoGM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/renogm">@RenoGM</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Interesting topic. In nearly 40 years of playing RPG’s I’ve never run across this. I’ve seen, and used, reoccurring characters, had organizations with powerful leaders, and had a bid bad behind a specific scheme, but I’ve never seen a single nemesis being used as the ultimate foil across an entire campaign ala Skeletor. Of course I’ve seen this as the primary model in video games but do many people employ this to tabletop campaigns?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 19:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think it works the other way around:<br>
If one is looking for a recipe which works everytime, he could take BBEG and he has something to build upon. It is a relative easy understandable format. It is like the template for Columbo with Peter Falk: Easy to consume, easy to understand, only little deviation from the principle, worked for 69 episodes. What more do you want?</p>
<p>Of course not everybody is a Columbo fan.</p>
<p>If somebody is new to the hobby or is looking for a last minute idea, why not use the BBEG pattern?</p>
<p>OTOH having more player agency is something which is a bit more demanding on the players as well as on the GM.</p>
<p>Of course, if you are into Columbo True detectives might not be what you are looking for.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 22:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@gartsalrisa]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gartsalrisa">@gartsalrisa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> it is likely that I am both following different forums and blogs than you and am not as sensitive to the topic, because the concept of BBEG does not occupy a noteworthy portion of TRPG discussion in my experience. But I am unambiguously convinced that you are not a fan! Or at least, not a fan of specific implementations of the idea.</p>
<p>Given that, as noted repeatedly above, the concept of a re-occurring antagonist is is prevalent-unto-nigh-ubiquity in stories of all genres, it seems uncharitable to narrowly associate it with children’s cartoons. Would it be fair for me to assume that your passion is coloring your rhetoric?</p>
<p>In your examples, you seem to equate BBEG with railroading–you specifically seem to consider “plot armor” as a defining characteristic of BBEG. Is this based on personal experience?</p>
<p>Good news: I am not preparing an enterprise that attempts to change your mind on the matter! But I am surprised to see that someone would be saddened and infuriated by that sort of play, so I am trying to learn why you find it so distressing (as opposed to, say, it being a style of play that is simply not entertaining for you.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/12</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 20:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The issue isn’t reoccurring villains, it’s the assumption and design that a specific villain will reoccur and the level of illusionism and railroading that then typically go into making that villain escape from player efforts to stop them.</p>
<p>As a matter of genre emulation I can certainly see how it would work out (Say if you were emulating 80’s Saturday Morning Cartoon Fantasy - playing a Master of the Universe or GI Joe system with specific mechanics related to foiling Cobra Commander/Skeletor) but as a general principle it’s something that grates immensely.  It grates not because a rivalry between PCs and an NPC forms, or because some foe returns after escape - but because the way it tends to be discussed is as an inevitability to force on the game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/11</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 18:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curufea]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curufea">@Curufea</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I only recently came across the acronym. I’m used to nemesis or recurring villain and they’re tropes of pulp and superhero genres which also tends to be games where heroes are expected to not be killing, so it’s relevant to have recurring villains.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534/10</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 07:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2534-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-hates-it-the-assumption-of-the-bbeg/2534.rss">I hates it... The assumption of the BBEG</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
