<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068</link>
    <description>Do stress and anxiety limit your participation in the hobby? It could be when it come to play games or to participate at events but it can also be when you try to create gaming material. 

I accumulate a lot of stress and anxiety due to my precarious financial situation and how it limit my transition, I often feel in a dead end and it strongly affect me emotionally. I often have a hard time playing in online games sessions because too many things worries me. The stress due to my limited transition often undermine my self confidence and make it very hard for me to participate in gaming or art events, like yesterday I cancelled my participation to Gauntlet Con because the combined stress of my personal life and the event is just too big for me to handle. 

This even affect my personal projects. Yesterday I nearly deleted my Comet Crawl project and other things I was working on because I felt that I will never be able to finish anything. There is a strong demand for my art but I have to refuse a lot of commissions because they inject too much additional stress. I also often had to refuse to work on interesting projects because of this, like during the G+ era, Patrick Stuart offered me to illustrate a whole book for him, kind of like Silent Titans but I had to refuse due to stress, I also had to back down from illustrating the Garden of Ynn (I was so enthusiastic for this one). I so often feel hindered and limited by how stress and anxiety affect that I sometime think of disengaging totally from the hobby or even from art. What is frustrating is that I often better periods where I handle stress better and I start having hope and get enthusiastic again about running games and working on projects and then I get a anxiety spike and I have to abandon nearly everything again.

I guess that what I am trying to say is that some creative people have important personal barriers of entries into the hobby, both as participants and as creators. I often isolate myself because of this, because I feel guilt over not being functional, because I imagine that everyone else are functional, participate to events, publish books and realize beautiful projects all the time. 

I don&#39;t have much solutions but because of how I felt yesterday and the things I had to cancel again, I wanted to at least offer a testimony and to bring some awareness.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 02:14:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Tuirgin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/tuirgin">@Tuirgin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-post="33" data-topic="3068">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/shane/40/186_2.png" class="avatar"> shane:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I “trap” myself into doing the thing. I throw something up on the calendar before I can overthink it…</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is something that is beginning to work for me. Regular repetition begins to take the edge off, but any disruption to that regularity can put me right back at needing to outwit my anxiety again.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/34</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 02:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One part of the Gauntlet culture that I would love to see propagate is: you don’t need to be a great (or even good) GM to run games on the calendar, but you <em>should</em> want to grow as a GM. As long as it is clear to those involved that the GM isn’t just “phoning it in” Gauntlet players are going to do their utmost to make the game a success. In my experience the players <em>want</em> the GM to succeed and will support them to make it happen.</p>
<p>Now with that said I will tell you I struggle similarly to you. I put a lot of stress on myself in these situations and it leads me to not run that often. But I have over time also come to the personal realization that in general I have barely any external evidence for my concerns: no one has said I suck a GM, feedback I get makes sense, people continue signing up for my games, etc.</p>
<p>Finally I’ll say what my “solution” to this is (which you and others may or may not make use of): I “trap” myself into doing the thing. I throw something up on the calendar before I can overthink it, people sign up, and at that point it becomes a <em>fait accompli</em>. I am committed and I just have to do the thing. Then the embarrassment of cancelling overrides the fear of doing a bad job. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>As I said though: I feel you <em>big time</em> on this and totally understand if it hampers your engagement with The Gauntlet. Absolutely <em>zero</em> judgements made about how anyone handles this very real struggle.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/33</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 12:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@_ry]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/_ry">@_ry</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Perfectionism - if the players don’t love it, what’s the point? I’m just wasting everyone’s time -the fear of rejection time means if I can’t run something great I don’t play. Since I’ve had kids (a decade) it’s been hard to play at all, and it’s that standard that is holding me back more than anything.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/32</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 01:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="30" data-topic="3068">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jimlikesgames/40/250_2.png" class="avatar"> JimLikesGames:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Like, I’d rather not do feedback, if it’s all the same, and if we don’t do some kind of formal pre-game social introductions as part of setup, it’ll mess with my head all game.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’ve tended to find feedback less than useful lately also. I think I’d prefer more of a debrief or a focused question from DM or player, “Hey, I tried X and I wasn’t sure how it came across. Thoughts?”</p>
<p>Regarding pregame intros: you mean the players introducing themselves to each other?  That’s something that actually makes me very anxious because I’m horrible at intros. That said,  if it makes others feel more comfortable to game,  I’m all for it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/31</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 19:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I often vacillate on whether social anxiety limits my participation in the hobby, or if my participation is <em>predicated</em> on anxiety. Like, I did sports all through adolescence into high school and hated just about every second of it, and got a degree in theater, and found much of the community and certainly most of the business associated with it frequently unbearable, but RPGs have given me most of what I like about both with <em>so much less</em> of the associated trauma.</p>
<p>I have often wondered if the overvaluation, especially in Indie gaming spaces, of creation over ‘mere’ play and facilitation drives folks to try and publish when a lot of them (including me) would be happier just participating. I’ve got the issue of having been a retailer for nearly three decades, so my anxiety and comfort is <em>hugely</em> context-dependent. Situations that feel like work allow me to go into ‘at work’ mode, so I can often get through stuff that might shut me down outside of that context.</p>
<p>My worst gaming-related panic attacks have come from two sources: large-cast LARPs, where you can’t breathe and relax when the spotlight isn’t on you and there’s no guarantee a mediator is present for everything; they’ve been universally destructive to me and I can’t imagine ever playing one again. The other is, maybe oddly, maybe not, in the space that surrounds the game as opposed to the game itself. Like, I’d rather not do feedback, if it’s all the same, and if we don’t do some kind of formal pre-game social introductions as part of setup, it’ll mess with my head all game. My worst Gauntlet game was with <em>lovely</em> people, but they all assumed we knew each other and the story and the game so they just jumped in and started playing, and it… wasn’t good. No one was being in any way deliberately obnoxious or exclusive, but man, online makes it MUCH harder to read the subtle social cues that can say ‘you are welcome and we’re glad you’re here’.</p>
<p>Anyway. You have value as a player. You have value as a facilitator. You don’t need to write a game to be ‘worthy’ of participating in the hobby. Your passion is sufficient.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:52:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For what it is worth, your crowd funding post is GREAT!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Evlyn_M]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Anxiety is anxiety, all issues are valid.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I see.  That is quite the struggle. I hope you can find the energy to get the makeup on and go on more walks than you do now.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a Comet Crawl sounds awesome!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I experience my anxiety and depression as indeed being limiting to my participation in the hobby.</p>
<p>I noticed that before a Larp event my social phobia kicks in. It may range from mild anxiety, a flight response that I am able to overcome up and panic attacks that I can handle (quivering, shaking) up to experience panic attacks along with nightmares month before the event takes place. Its the reason why I had to drop out of Convention of Thorns despite having tickets and really wanting to go. More usual I might confide to some friends, co-larpers or the organizers about being quite scarred and insecure.</p>
<p>In regards to tabletop rpg I tend to get quite unwell briefly before games, yet usually I force myself to get down. I do somewhat panic before running a game at a convention. Which mostly expresses itself by procrastinating preparation up to the last minute. As well as as “last minute buys” because I forgot tokens for my players or stuff.</p>
<p>The most frustrating part, next to skipping larp, is blogging and writing stuff.<br>
Between days at work it happens a lot that I fall into a hole which sees me doing nothing. Sleeping, eating, maybe video gaming or watching YT vids but doing really nothing more. Which if I am on vacation without travel might lead as well as the roof crashing down onto me into a nervous break down.<br>
Doing the crowdfunding collection on a schedule helps, though on some weekends I just can’t do them because I procrastinated to much. Which hits me hard when I notice that I “lost” a project because of it (ended to early).<br>
Thus the last break was me really not feeling well, including Sunday.<br>
Which doesn’t annoy me as much as the fact that I am neglecting my WODnews.blog as well as article series. For my WoD news I planned - and got topics - to produce one to five articles a day, which worked fine last year, but this year, not at all.<br>
For my articles, I started several series, but haven’t concluded them because after one to four articles, anxiety puts up a severe road block. I know what I want to write, I actually written it on some occasion but I can’t open it, finish it and release it.<br>
Same even more drastically happens for fan content that I planned. Got it outlined perfectly. Can’t get it started. Without having a lack of free time.</p>
<p>It intersects with other challenges of life, whether its staying focused at work or keeping the apartment in a shape I approve off (where I had a rude awakening without anyone else being involved, when I woke up and looked around and was “It’s terrible”).</p>
<p>I haven’t got a solution yet. I do constantly try to go against it.<br>
I do got meds prescribed (Escitalopram) and I do try to get some therapy - which is like really difficult.<br>
Positive reinforcement does help to feel better, and does occasionally spur me into activity, yet I did notice that I happened to use it as an excuse and part of my lack of activity.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My issues are relatively minor in comparison to what many others struggle with, but yeah, there are some limitations.</p>
<p>My ftf gaming group has six people in it, two of whom run games regularly and three more (including me) who do so occasionally. All of us have some level of social anxiety, which means getting off that email about booking a new time to play when the last one didn’t work out? It often takes weeks before one of us breaks through enough to get it done. It’s ridiculous, but that’s how it goes. (At least we don’t have to call each other up on the phone the way we did 15 years ago… <em>shudder</em>)</p>
<p>I have similar issues with signing up for something here, compounded by anxiety connected to booking up events far in advance. I’ve had periods when I haven’t had nearly enough time to myself because of social commitments, and that’s made me very gun shy about filling up my calendar.</p>
<p>As for creative work, I’m terrible at finishing what I start. I don’t know if it’s fear of rejection or that I’m very deadline driven or something else, because at work I can crank stuff out and not care what anyone else thinks, but my own projects I do for fun at best get to a state of being nearly done before I start to slide off and move on to something else. I’m trying hard to make myself finish a couple of projects that are getting close, but when I try I just feel drained and I either move on to one of the new shinies or just waste time doing something else. But these are all things I’m doing for fun and not part of my regular income so it’s not that big a deal.</p>
<p>So yeah, relatively minor issues but they do limit me.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Evlyn_M]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is more a question of my sense of self, like it is my identity that is at stake. I mean I had to do multiple coming out, I transitioned in my personal life and at work (without passing), so I am used to going on and moving forward while not caring about what people think of me. It’s simply not practical for me to spend two hours to femme up to take a walk and going out as a man hurt me more than anything. Due to my late transition I just don’t have the option to go out without makeup, the result is too masculine, it is not myself and this cause me too much dysphoria.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 06:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I know this is easy to say and harder to do but why care what people think you look like if it helps you?   Don’t get me wrong… I understand the problem.  I deal with some psoriasis and anxiety and bouts of depression. Mine is likely a simpler case but I just refuse to allow any opinions from stopping me from going to swimming pools and going outdoors.  It is hard to start but usually I feel better when I get past the door.  Part of how I do this is to only pay attention to people I respect. No one else’s reactionz to me matter much at all. Part of a self defense mechanism I suppose but I find it works pretty well</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 05:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Evlyn_M]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For Comet Crawl I have a pre written frame (the Soft Horizon system) but I need to rewrite it in my own words and to craft my own random tables. But yes it would be easier for me just to produce illustrations and to let someone else write about them.</p>
<p>I can handle small projects as I have published zines but working on a project big enough to be considered a book is different. I have accumulated so many failures that the thought of working on a big project is now scary as I anticipate the emotions that I associated with failing. But still I can overcome these emotions with some support. But long projects also imply that my motivation will eventually have to survive through a anxiety attack or a period of depression (often triggered by my low income transition).</p>
<p>When I am told “publish anything, it don’t matter, people will like it”. This discourage and demotivate me. Since my self esteem is very low I often feel like I need to over perform to make something good.</p>
<p>(about taking walks)<br>
I used to like to take walks to lower my stress but now that I need to wear makeup to go outside it became complicated for me to do so. I need to put on my makeup face to look a bit like a woman or to hide my breasts to pass as a man. One option is not very practical while the other is uncomfortable and  make me feel shame.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 04:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Good point!  Almost every large project is completed by breaking it into parts</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 03:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JasonT]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasont">@JasonT</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I can relate to a lot of this.</p>
<p>I know it won’t work for everybody, but one of the more helpful strategies I’ve found for personally fulfilling creative output, at least, is to aim to complete smaller projects. It makes sure I don’t have enough time to get too anxious about them and quit in frustration. I know I need a longer term strategy if I ever want to get anything longer done, and of course this doesn’t address other sources of anxiety at all, but it’s something.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 03:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@disquisition]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/disquisition">@disquisition</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I definitely feel this. One of the main reasons I joined the Gauntlet community is I wanted to play more games but I haven’t been able to get myself to sign up for anything yet. I have a hard time doing anything with new people and it really limits my ability to participate in the hobby despite the fact that the act of playing itself really helps my anxiety.</p>
<p>For me: Exercise helps. Getting outdoors helps (especially getting outside the city). Playing games with my home group helps. Any positive social interaction helps (but of course there’s no way to guarantee a social interaction will be positive going in). I used to meditate 3+ times per week, and that helped a lot, but it’s been a while since I’ve maintained that habit. I haven’t tried medication, mainly because my anxiety makes it difficult to contact doctors and set up appointments, but I am working on it because so many people have told me that medication has helped them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/18</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 16:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This seems topical:</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/d8a87cc08cdeff7dd9af4bfe5710a0477d6de8be.png" class="site-icon" width="150" height="150">
      <a href="https://gnomestew.com/gaming-with-anxiety/" target="_blank" title="02:00AM - 09 September 2019">Gnome Stew – 9 Sep 19</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/444;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/3ba6e4c12547c188a1ccff973ce11ed5acd75dd5.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://gnomestew.com/gaming-with-anxiety/" target="_blank">Gaming with Anxiety</a></h3>

<p>I pull up to the house, park out front (not t0o early, I hope), and sit for a moment. I consider briefly taking off again, I’m pretty sure that no one saw me. I’ve known Ken for several years, but that doesn’t take away the gnawing feeling of being...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/17</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Johnstone]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/johnstone">@Johnstone</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For me, I’d say it’s mostly depression that keeps me from engaging more, although depression-related social anxiety has made conventions harder in recent years. I also shelved a game I was working on because I knew some people’s reactions would cause me problems, and that was a source of some anxiety too.</p>
<p>Evlyn, it seems like the projects you mentioned mostly involve you illustrating a book that’s already written? Which is a big job and understandably stressful. Do you find it easier to draw first and have someone else write about it after? That’s how I do the monsters for my Patreon. My artist Nathan gives me whatever he wants to draw and I have to figure out what it is, which puts most of the pressure on me instead of him. Whereas most of the rpg industry seems to be focused on writers first and getting illustrations for those words second.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/16</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@GerwynWalters]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gerwynwalters">@GerwynWalters</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes yes yes,   so much so it caused me to take a step back from the gauntlet entirely for a few months.</p>
<p>I suffer social anxiety when around people i dont know and when overloaded with stimulus.  I find playing with people i dont know incredibly stressful and the whole lack of “table talk” and banter in most games on the gauntlet means i dont get the opportunity to just get to know folk meaning that i find a lot of the games on the gauntlet less satisfying than traditional FtF games.</p>
<p>As an ST I find the whole method of setting up the game stressful and anxiety triggering,  getting the character keepers done,  writing the fluff for the firebase site posting the game waiting to see who will sign on.   ending emails out, which is why my comms almost always come at the last minute in games i’m running.</p>
<p>One of the biggest issues i have with running games if the sheer lead time in between posting them and actually doing them.   invariably my mood will nosedive at some point during the 4-6 weeks between a game being posted and play starting.</p>
<p>Ironically, I have less problems with anxiety when playing larps than i do with running them.  Running them my paperwork is again always last minute as i do multiple rewrites or struggle to get the words down where as when i’m playing i can be as confident as anybody because, thats not me being confident… thats the character being confident.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 19:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@funkaoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/funkaoshi">@funkaoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What does participation need to look like, for you, to be satisfying. People love your art. I bet people would have enjoyed your half finished comet crawl, even if the last page said, “now you make up the rest”. But, maybe that’s not enough for you, which is fine. I just think it’s important to figure out if you are making things difficult for yourself because you worry about expectations no one else has about your work or output.</p>
<p>My work is stressful and busy sometimes, so RPGs and warhammer are an outlet to relax. We all need breaks or we will burn out. If you are working constantly you won’t be able to do anything useful. Sometimes it is OK to waste time, because it’s not actually a waste.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 12:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It makes Total sense!  I have battled with general anxiety plenty in the last 10 years.  Mostly that is under control for me until my ADHD distracts me so much that I can’t get anything requiring detailed work done for a time. (I work with data while my hobbies are boardgames and tt-rpgs so details are most of my life). Then, I stress about what I could have gotten done during that time.</p>
<p>Related specifically to rpgs, I have dropped out of GMing games at conventions because I did not feel prepped enough.</p>
<p>I also have started many rpg projects and writing projects but generally get anxious about finishing any of them.  I have never had anxiety prevent me from playing in an rpg session even with strangers though so it could certainly be worse.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 03:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SeanGomes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seangomes">@SeanGomes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="7" data-topic="3068">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/calris/40/2028_2.png" class="avatar"> calris:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>For me a major contributor to anxiety and stress is feeling guilt about what I think I should be doing with my free time.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is me all over. I often beat myself up about “wasting my evening” when I could have been writing or designing. The logical part of my brain usually wins out. Full-time job, full-time dad (as much as possible given aforementioned full-time job), I need to unwind, etc. But the creative/critic? That jerk gets cruel, some days.</p>
<p>For me, part of how it relates to <em>social</em> anxiety is that I used to run a small but dedicated community, and every time I didn’t have anything to show or anything to discuss I felt like I was letting everyone down or being boring. I felt the duty to always be “on”, if that makes sense.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/12</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 03:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="7" data-topic="3068">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/calris/40/2028_2.png" class="avatar"> calris:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>For me a major contributor to anxiety and stress is feeling guilt about what I think I should be doing with my free time.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I feel this <strong>so</strong> hard. I end up wasting so much time trying to figure out what I should be doing with my free time - what the optimal thing to do is… I just end up not making the decision for fear of choosing incorrectly. For fear of regretting my decision.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/11</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 01:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@luoyun]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/luoyun">@luoyun</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I am living with post-traumatic stress disorder. I guess in one sense, anxiety affects everything I do, but with respect to TTRPGs…</p>
<p>I take medication and attend biweekly talk therapy. Both are essential to my function, but sometimes, especially in intensely social interactions with strangers, it’s not enough. In an anxious state, I am withdrawn in my story-telling and in my engagement with the game in front of me. It’s not a one-for-one ratio of good to bad, but it happens enough that I feel at least somewhat limited.</p>
<p>I can’t speak to the creative side of things because I do not design games, but if the way I treat my academic work is any indication, I can see anxiety affecting that, too.</p>
<p>In my experience, providing an open forum to discuss such things is one of the best things a community can do. It lessens the stigma.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/10</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 23:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I medicate for my anxiety-- I hadn’t even realized how bad it was until Sherri pointed it out to me. I still have problems at cons unless I have at least one close friend with me. I can handle things when I’m in a structured environment, but outside of that I have problems. The anxiety creeps up in little ways, like putting off emailing people who I vaguely know but need to contact. Once I get stuck in that loop, it is hard to get out.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068/9</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 17:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3068-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/is-anxiety-limiting-your-participation-in-the-hobby/3068.rss">Is anxiety limiting your participation in the hobby?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
