<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vaesen: The Haunting of Huddunge</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vaesen-the-haunting-of-huddunge/5650</link>
    <description>https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MDGk5imJS8JS7fQ1yn8

![](https://resources.mynewsdesk.com/image/upload/c_limit,dpr_1.0,f_auto,h_700,q_auto,w_690/pxwdwp5oajmz08vii06o.jpg)

*Sirs and Madams of the Society,*

*I write to you in the greatest distress. I have recently returned from the village of Huddunge, and something is terribly awry there. The priest has abandoned the church, the villagers refuse to come out of their houses, and the few hours I spent there I felt a dark presence following my every step.*

*As fellow Seers I hope you will have the courage I did not, and venture to discover and drive out whatever dark creature has invaded Huddunge.*

*With regrets of bearing such dark news,*

*Erik Forsmark, Assistant Härad Scribe of Väsby Fögderi*

**Vaesen**  is a gothic horror game set in a mythic version of 19th century Scandinavia, focusing on creatures from Scandinavian folklore - trolls, ghosts, the Neck, giants, fairies, wood wives, and lindworms among many others. The player characters are capable but ultimately relatively ordinary people who have suffered some trauma that have given them the Sight, the ability to percieve the supernatural for what it is. The setting is loosely based on historical Scandinavia, but period details should be taken as inspiration for fun play and discarded if they don&#39;t enhance the experience. It may also be worth noting that this is not an urban fantasy or steampunk setting - the characters are mostly limited to normal human capabilities, and while technology won&#39;t necessarily conform exactly to historical levels neither will it be fantastical.

The game uses Free League&#39;s dice pool system as seen in Mutant: Year Zero, Forbidden Lands, Coriolis, Alien, and Tales from the Loop.

No knowledge of the setting or system is needed to play. Characters will be created at the start of the session.

This is a one-shot session to try out the system and setting. I have not run or played this game before (though I have played a couple of Free League&#39;s other games), and it is also my first time running a game here on the Gauntlet.

We will use Streamyard to play. A link will be sent out by mail at least half an hour before the start of the session. This session will not be recorded or streamed publicly.

[The Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in effect for this game.

We will use the X-Card and Lines &amp; Veils as safety tools, along with a discussion about tone and the setting in general. The Open Door policy will also be in effect.

Note that this is a horror game so there will be content in that vein, but the most important goal is that everyone should have a good experience.

For the first 48 hours, please only sign up if you&#39;re close to the GMT time zone (basically Europe or Africa) or if you have played with me before - as this is my first time running a game on the Gauntlet, having a familiar face or two in the game would be comforting.

The all-access time for this event is [date=2020-07-30 time=22:00 format=&quot;LLLL&quot; timezone=&quot;Europe/Stockholm&quot;]

An e-mail with a link to the character keeper will be sent out roughly a week before the game.

[date=2020-08-15 time=18:00:00 format=&quot;LLLL&quot; timezone=&quot;Europe/Stockholm&quot;] → [date=2020-08-15 time=22:00:00 format=&quot;LLLL&quot; timezone=&quot;Europe/Stockholm&quot;]</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 19:43:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vaesen-the-haunting-of-huddunge/5650.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Vaesen: The Haunting of Huddunge</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MDGk5imJS8JS7fQ1yn8" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MDGk5imJS8JS7fQ1yn8</a></p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://resources.mynewsdesk.com/image/upload/c_limit,dpr_1.0,f_auto,h_700,q_auto,w_690/pxwdwp5oajmz08vii06o.jpg" title="" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="https://resources.mynewsdesk.com/image/upload/c_limit,dpr_1.0,f_auto,h_700,q_auto,w_690/pxwdwp5oajmz08vii06o.jpg" alt width="370" height="500"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename"></span><span class="informations">519×700</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
<p><em>Sirs and Madams of the Society,</em></p>
<p><em>I write to you in the greatest distress. I have recently returned from the village of Huddunge, and something is terribly awry there. The priest has abandoned the church, the villagers refuse to come out of their houses, and the few hours I spent there I felt a dark presence following my every step.</em></p>
<p><em>As fellow Seers I hope you will have the courage I did not, and venture to discover and drive out whatever dark creature has invaded Huddunge.</em></p>
<p><em>With regrets of bearing such dark news,</em></p>
<p><em>Erik Forsmark, Assistant Härad Scribe of Väsby Fögderi</em></p>
<p><strong>Vaesen</strong>  is a gothic horror game set in a mythic version of 19th century Scandinavia, focusing on creatures from Scandinavian folklore - trolls, ghosts, the Neck, giants, fairies, wood wives, and lindworms among many others. The player characters are capable but ultimately relatively ordinary people who have suffered some trauma that have given them the Sight, the ability to percieve the supernatural for what it is. The setting is loosely based on historical Scandinavia, but period details should be taken as inspiration for fun play and discarded if they don’t enhance the experience. It may also be worth noting that this is not an urban fantasy or steampunk setting - the characters are mostly limited to normal human capabilities, and while technology won’t necessarily conform exactly to historical levels neither will it be fantastical.</p>
<p>The game uses Free League’s dice pool system as seen in Mutant: Year Zero, Forbidden Lands, Coriolis, Alien, and Tales from the Loop.</p>
<p>No knowledge of the setting or system is needed to play. Characters will be created at the start of the session.</p>
<p>This is a one-shot session to try out the system and setting. I have not run or played this game before (though I have played a couple of Free League’s other games), and it is also my first time running a game here on the Gauntlet.</p>
<p>We will use Streamyard to play. A link will be sent out by mail at least half an hour before the start of the session. This session will not be recorded or streamed publicly.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">The Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> will be in effect for this game.</p>
<p>We will use the X-Card and Lines &amp; Veils as safety tools, along with a discussion about tone and the setting in general. The Open Door policy will also be in effect.</p>
<p>Note that this is a horror game so there will be content in that vein, but the most important goal is that everyone should have a good experience.</p>
<p>For the first 48 hours, please only sign up if you’re close to the GMT time zone (basically Europe or Africa) or if you have played with me before - as this is my first time running a game on the Gauntlet, having a familiar face or two in the game would be comforting.</p>
<p>The all-access time for this event is <span data-date="2020-07-30" data-time="22:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/Stockholm" data-email-preview="2020-07-30T20:00:00Z UTC">Thursday, July 30, 2020 8:00 PM</span></p>
<p>An e-mail with a link to the character keeper will be sent out roughly a week before the game.</p>
<p><span data-date="2020-08-15" data-time="18:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/Stockholm" data-email-preview="2020-08-15T16:00:00Z UTC">Saturday, August 15, 2020 4:00 PM</span> → <span data-date="2020-08-15" data-time="22:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/Stockholm" data-email-preview="2020-08-15T20:00:00Z UTC">Saturday, August 15, 2020 8:00 PM</span></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vaesen-the-haunting-of-huddunge/5650/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vaesen-the-haunting-of-huddunge/5650/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 19:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5650-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vaesen-the-haunting-of-huddunge/5650.rss">Vaesen: The Haunting of Huddunge</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
