<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737</link>
    <description>This might be weird to say on the Gauntlet, given the nature of the business, but I think there are people drawn here for reasons other than the hangouts, and regardless, I think it&#39;s interesting to discuss perhaps the different gaming experience provided by one-shorts vs more campaign oriented games. In particular, I&#39;m curious if anyone else believes that the popularity of one-shots has skewed in anyway the direction that new games in the PbtA-verse are taking.

I&#39;ve played a number of one-shots in various systems, and I mean, it&#39;s not bad! But I find that knowing things will end produces a very different type of gaming experience. It&#39;s not bad per se, just different...people can really lean into the drama, make destructive decisions (not trolling, just you know, dramatic), can really just push hard on the system. The downside is, well, that in my experience sometimes that can get out of hand, or just sort of get a bit ham-fisted in a way that I personally don&#39;t enjoy. With more campaign oriented play people are encouraged to get more invested in the longer-term arc of their character, which I personally enjoy quite a bit.

Obviously logistically, one-shots are great. They&#39;re great for people who struggle to play regularly, and they&#39;re great for game designers, since it&#39;s much easier to test in a bunch of one shots than in a bunch of campaigns. Take Hearts of Wulin, for example. I&#39;m really excited about seeing the full rule book whenever it drops, but I can&#39;t help but be worried that it&#39;s optimized for a 1-3 session experience because that&#39;s where the bulk of the playtesting was. I&#39;m curious if anyone else has any thoughts on how the feedback loop might influence designs. For example, in the &quot;crunchy systems&quot; thread, people discussed character advancement a little bit. One complaint I&#39;ve seen levied against PbtA games in general on other forums is that advancement isn&#39;t that excited...this could be an outgrowth of one-shot culture, because in that case, advancement isn&#39;t super common like it is vs in a game specifically oriented around campaigns.

And of course, the discussion about one-shots goes way beyond PbtA of course, those games just happen to be popular and pretty fleshed out. A lot of the game design that happens at least that I see on Twitter etc is for very short games...200 word games, 1 page games, and so on. I personally find these games clever as an intellectual endeavor, but hard to get invested in.

I just want to caveat:
* I&#39;m not saying pbta is bad
* I&#39;m not saying you can&#39;t play a campaigns in pbta
* I&#39;m not saying nobody plays campaigns
* I&#39;m not saying character advancement is non-existent in pbta
* I&#39;m not saying game creators don&#39;t consider campaigns at all (though for 200 word games etc I think many do not)

I&#39;m just discussing where people might fall on the one-shot/campaign spectrum, and discussing whether or not these preferences have influenced game design in our milieu.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 20:47:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/tuirgin">@Tuirgin</a>  Regarding these “long term moves”, or simply character arcs, reading Chuubo’s quest is good inspiration.</p>
<p>The general idea in Chuubo’s that I try to imitate in my design is this : instead of a chain of conflicts, make a mesh of them. That is, like in a TV series, allow conflicts to be in an intermediary state of “being soon resolved”.</p>
<p>I believe this overlapping of actions makes the “dramatic tissue” robust and adjustable to the local conditions at the table and in the fiction. It’s not just a question of when or how we resolve a question, but also : what aesthetical choices direct the weaving of the various themes and dramatic threads.</p>
<p>This doesn’t have to be long or slow at the table. It’s a question of diversity, diversifying resources (as in BitD, where you can dig for romance, credits, politics, etc.) and scales (as in the following example).</p>
<p>Fast playing months of a relationship or slow-motionning through a round of glances are possible in a game, only, both are not equally possible depending on the system you use. Speaking of long term play is often speaking of a system that only uses “lego blocks” moves. Theoretically, systems with better maneuverability allow competent players to build a beautiful (?) form in little time. In practice, this precision in story building is not everyone’s fun.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/49</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 20:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’d rather leave a game wanting more than thinking “Thank goodness we’re finally done with that.” which, alas, has been my sensation after several campaigns.  On the other hand, it was also my sensation after a one shot of classic Traveller, and similarly a one shot of The Dark Eye, so clearly one-shots aren’t immune from this.</p>
<p>Anyway, one of the fun things about one shots is that you don’t HAVE to stop (well, unless it was a con game).  If you play a oneshot and everyone goes “That was AMAZING! I really want to go back and see what happens next!” it’s usually a possibility that you can do just that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/48</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 16:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@funkaoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/funkaoshi">@funkaoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think one shots can be fun, and at a convention are a good way to play a game when you might not have been able to do. But, I also feel most games become more interesting the more time you invest with them. The choices you make each session become more meaningful. You end up caring about the characters more. With a lot of OSR games people start of playing generic adventure person that will slowly evolve through sessions into an actual character. I think campaign play is often the most compelling aspect of an RPG. And the RPG games I look back on most fondly have all been parts of longer campaigns.</p>
<p>Trying to make games that work as compelling one shots seems like a good goal, because people often don’t have the time to play a long campaign. A lot of D&amp;D adventure I have seen in recent years seem built with the idea you could play them in a convention sized slot. (Basically everything from DCCRPG for example.) Many indie games seem built this way as well. I think games that purposefully try and come to a nest conclusion work better here. Otherwise you just leave wanting more. Maybe not the worst way to feel after a game, though.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/47</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 11:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="35" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/rickard/40/1793_2.png" class="avatar"> Rickard:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Can you give an example of how you get invested in a longer-term arc? Because I noticed a tendency myself that people just start to play themselves after a few sessions.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Sorry, I’ve been reading this thread and really enjoying it, I guess I’ve been somewhat sheepish to contribute too much since others have quite a bit of experience and are saying very smart things!</p>
<p>For me, I really enjoyed building a shared history, and then sort of playing to that. Often, a mix of chemistry, chance, and stats can take your character in a way you didn’t expect. I once played a paladin in DW who, due to a mix of factors, started heavily skirting his code (a sort of bad lieutenant type) in a way I never would have expected when I made the character. And then as we played, it was fun to sort of tie what was happening to the shared history of the game. Being able to sort of create that together can be very satisfying. In my experience, people don’t just play themselves…I feel like over time their character builds up history and then they can play to that. There are a lot of factors.</p>
<p>I do also think that real character advancement mechanics can be pretty fun and exciting. This relates to another thread on crunch I made but I think it’s relevant. I’m trying to get into a VTM game and am making a character and you know, I have to make a lot of compromises, which feed into my character…as I level, I’ll have to choose what I care about, and the mechanics can serve to crystallize that. Do I want to be a better killer, or a better schmoozer? That will reflect the needs of the chronicle, as well as the character he’s proven to be and the character he wants to be. And then with that change, he will get more competent, which in turn will change how the narrative moves.</p>
<p>I find that stuff all very fun!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/46</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 15:56:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/rickard">@Rickard</a>, it’s funny, because I just referenced <em>Imagine</em> a few posts above. I’m well aware of that game, as well as your various thoughts about kishotenketsu and story structure. But I’m glad you wrote that; I think it will be very interesting reading for other participants of the thread. Thanks!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/45</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 18:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Wanted to give this thread some time for <a class="mention" href="/u/jco">@jco</a> to respond on my question because I’m really curious how we differ when it comes to starting to “feel” for the characters.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="36" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/paul_t/40/1825_2.png" class="avatar"> Paul_T:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Have you written anywhere about your approach to creating “slow play” in one shots, and what enables it?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>In all honestly, I haven’t given this enough thought but I really want to sit down with some people in the Swedish game design collective and discuss this face to face.</p>
<p>I can’t recall asking you if you played <a href="https://www.urverkspel.com/vara-spel/oevriga-projekt" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">Imagine</a>. I talked about Freytag’s pyramid in my last post but it’s not like all games/sessions need to follow that narrative structure.</p>
<p>Imagine is based upon <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dBmIkEvEBtA&amp;t=61s" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">kishotenketsu</a>, and that narrative structure is about finding the mood and to reflect about the situation (making you think). Compare this to the Western narrative structure about the conflict. Every time, that I can recall at least, when we had moments of slow play in traditional games, it always brought forth a mood. Someone having a scene sighing over a letter; people helping out dropping tidbits of information to set the atmosphere in a scene; the slow pace in horror games where the game master had us scare ourselves about what could lurk in the shadows.</p>
<p>So … mood and contemplation, instead of conflict? Where “introduction, development, twist, conclusion” are used instead of the pyramid’s “exposition (introduction), rising action, climax, falling action (return), dénouement (reveal)”. Well, both have introduction which connects to what I said in my previous post about the danger of skipping it. I really love the introduction scenes for each character in <strong>Dogs in the Vineyard</strong>, to give an example of how it can be done. I would like to see more of that in other games.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/44</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 16:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a>:  Suddenly, this week tautological was used at work.  People were confused.  I said here is an example…</p>
<p>“A longer research study takes more time.”</p>
<p>Thanks for helping me look smart in the office.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/43</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 15:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m not sure if it is explicit about the structure, but everything else about Monster of the Week, from the prep guidelines on down, drives the game towards an episodic format – it’s clear that the idea of “Some time passes between missions” is a thing since the healing rules basically say “If some time has passed since the last mission, remove all harm, otherwise, remove one.”</p>
<p>But it never quite comes out and SAYS that things are episodic, unless I am forgetting something.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/42</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 13:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="40" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/paul_t/40/1825_2.png" class="avatar"> Paul_T:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>the only games I’m aware of that do episodic storytelling within a larger structure explicitly are, somewhat oddly, older games</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I am about 2/3 done with <em>Monster of the Week</em>, and I feel like it explicitly is about shorter episodes in a larger whole (I’m about to start the chapter on Arcs).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/41</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 04:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s a great post, and I love the reference to <em>Understanding Comics.</em></p>
<p>The “negative space” in roleplaying can be a really powerful tool, whether between sessions or not, to hint at and bring about character development or to create a sense of progression or depth when it comes to plot, setting, or theme. Rickard Elimaa’s <em>Imagine</em> plays with this on a very short scale in a way that’s really lovely.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/samr">@SamR</a>, the only games I’m aware of that do episodic storytelling within a larger structure explicitly are, somewhat oddly, older games.  <em>Primetime Adventures</em> (which has you plan out the “season”, episode by episode, and assign character “Screen Presence” accordingly) and <em>In a Wicked Age…</em>, which does so much more organically and in surprising ways.</p>
<p><em>S/lay w/me</em> also has an interesting sort of structure for episodic, long-term storytelling.</p>
<p>I agree that it would be great to see more design in this space!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/40</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="37" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/samr/40/631_2.png" class="avatar"> SamR:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>each session is a complete story, but they all connect and build a larger narrative. I want one-shots with <em>sequels.</em></p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>My brain is making the connection to Scott McCloud’s <strong>Understanding Comics</strong> (or was it Reinventing Comics?) in which he talks about how the panel structure is also using the space between panels to tell a story. From a design view, the shape of panels dictates and is dictated by the negative space around them. From a narrative view, the info not included in panels is as important as the info included; you can swing the view across huge distances, back and forward in time, or create ambiguity for the reader to inject meaning into.</p>
<p>If we consider the “panel” of a ttrpg to be a session, than we can think of the space between panels as the parts of the game not actively played, either between sessions or as travel/downtime skipped over during play. One option would be as <a class="mention" href="/u/tuirgin">@Tuirgin</a> quoted above me, using the “negative space” to frame the subsequent session. If we want to get really experimental, we could structure a series of oneshots like the individual drill downs that occur in <strong>Microscope</strong>, allowing for incredibly disjointed one-shots that tie into an overarching narrative. If we break the one-shots apart so that they do not need to correspond chronologically we can play out stories where unexplained phenomena/relationships/artifacts are teased out in order of importance. Stories similar to the narratives of <strong>Holes</strong>, <strong>Cloud Atlas</strong>, or say <strong>Futurama</strong>.</p>
<p>I think the technology for these concepts probably already exists, but to my knowledge nobody has married them into crunchier systems yet.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/39</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Tuirgin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/tuirgin">@Tuirgin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="37" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/samr/40/631_2.png" class="avatar"> SamR:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>One of the things I find really intriguing right now, as a designer, is what I see as an under-explored space: Games designed for campaign play that have the session structure of a one-shot game.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> touches on this in his thoughts on further developing <a href="https://spoutinglore.blogspot.com/2018/07/homebrew-world.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Homebrew World</a> for <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DungeonWorld/comments/cb39uj/online_version_of_homebrew_world/etfi735" rel="nofollow noopener">campaign play</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>My eventual plan for this is a framework where:</p>
<ul>
<li>Each adventure is hard-framed at the beginning and the end, as it’s own “episode”. So, like, as the first adventure ends, we’d epilogue or otherwise wrap things up, but specifically NOT follow the PCs back to town or find out “what happens next.”</li>
<li>The second/next adventure would be framed much like the first: in media res, at the door to the next dungeon, in the middle of the next interesting situation. Lots of Q&amp;A to establish what they’re doing here, etc.</li>
<li>Use semi-standard “love letter” style moves to help determine what happened between adventures. These would serve to (mostly) reset gear (and maybe XP), to support longer-term character development and the pursuit of longterm goals, and to give the sense of a world living and breathing and moving between sessions. The options would be stuff like  <strong>Squander Riches</strong>  or  <strong>Make Things Right</strong>  or  <strong>Dig Into a Mystery</strong>  or  <strong>Pursue a Goal</strong> . The outcomes of these moves would help launch the next adventure, possibly providing motivations and details. (This will, I think, be the hardest part to pull off well.)</li>
</ul>
<p>The end result would, if done correctly, feel like a collection of classic adventure short-stories. You don’t see where Conan goes off to at the end of one adventure, or how he got where he is at the start of the next. That’s all established off-camera and (maybe) revealed later.</p>
</blockquote>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/38</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 17:35:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SamR]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/samr">@SamR</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Recently I’ve been playing more one-shots or 2-3-shots, and haven’t played a proper long campaign of anything for a while. (And my only long campaigns have been various editions of D&amp;D.)</p>
<p>I’ve been finding the one-shots much more satisfying, for many of the reasons that others have already said. I feel like I’m getting a complete and satisfying story, while so many of the longer campaigns I played felt like they never got around to the good part. I often found myself excited to sit down for a session, only to leave disappointed — 4 hours and that’s all we have to show for it? I definitely think part of it was D&amp;D — it’s easy to get bogged down in combat and minutiae, and there aren’t a lot of interesting mechanics for character drama or growth that isn’t tied to power.</p>
<p>One of the things I’ve noticed, as someone with a TV-writing background, is that one-shot games have a set structure. Everyone at the tables knows, whether the game is designed for one-shots or not, that the story ends at the end of the session. So you can parcel out story in a way that makes sense for the game and builds toward a satisfying conclusion. You get a very movie-like arc.</p>
<p>On the other hand, games that are built for long-term campaign play tend to punt on session structure. So while long-term campaigns ostensibly feel like a long-running beloved TV series, they rarely have the sort of episodic rhythms that even heavily serialized shows have, building a satisfying arc with an intriguing conclusion, etc.</p>
<p>One of the things I find really intriguing right now, as a designer, is what I see as an under-explored space: Games designed for campaign play that have the session structure of a one-shot game. For example, I’d love to see more games that are designed to feel like, say, the MCU — each session is a complete story, but they all connect and build a larger narrative. I want one-shots with <em>sequels.</em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/37</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 17:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="35" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/rickard/40/1793_2.png" class="avatar"> Rickard:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Since a few years back, I become fond of the <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/a-tribute-to-slow-play-culture/1874/33">slow play </a> for one shots and, when playing collaborative storytelling</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Thanks, Rickard! I was very happy with that post.</p>
<p>Have you written anywhere about your approach to creating “slow play” in one shots, and what enables it?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/36</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 15:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="1" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jco/40/2199_2.png" class="avatar"> jco:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>With more campaign oriented play people are encouraged to get more invested in the longer-term arc of their character, which I personally enjoy quite a bit.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Can you give an example of how you get invested in a longer-term arc? Because I noticed a tendency myself that people just start to play themselves after a few sessions.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="1" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jco/40/2199_2.png" class="avatar"> jco:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>The downside is, well, that in my experience sometimes that can get out of hand, or just sort of get a bit ham-fisted in a way that I personally don’t enjoy.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I agree with this. Most of the Forge games I played (<strong>Kagematsu</strong>, <strong>My Life With Master</strong>, <strong>Fiasco</strong>, etc.) were mostly about setting up <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dramatic_structure" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">Freytag’s pyramid</a> in every scene, where you introduce a problem and solve it in the same scene; rinse repeat. It gets boring because the whole structure becomes transparent to me, and the overall arc is just one adrenaline shot after another. The continuous hunt for The One Roll, in every scene, that makes or breaks the whole outcome.</p>
<p>Since a few years back, I become fond of the <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/a-tribute-to-slow-play-culture/1874/33" data-bbcode="true">slow play</a> for one shots and, when playing collaborative storytelling, I noticed that the stories we were really engaged in had the same structure with a few scenes that introduces the characters, a few scenes that sets up any kind of trouble, a few scenes that have the characters go at each other, and a few scenes to stitch together everything – Freytag’s triangle. Whenever we skipped the introduction part, the story turned bad because no one was really invested in their character/story, even if they created them.</p>
<p>But we also need slower moments within each segment (ex. rising action, climax) of the pyramid. A comedy show doesn’t consist of an hour of good jokes, because we would just raise the bar of what’s “good”, so it needs its slow play – the down period that makes the good jokes become great.</p>
<p>That said, I can get all this in a one shot (4-6 hours), but I need enough time to get invested in everything. I’m also more about creating good stories together with my friends nowadays, than acting in character. And when it comes to that, I can even get really invested in a story within an hour. So much that the story still lingers in my head for months, but that’s because the focus of my games is to make the participants think and create engagement through that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/35</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 08:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@empowermint]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/empowermint">@empowermint</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One of the frustrations I have with very long-running campaigns is that I have difficulty remembering the characters and story in between sessions. I need to take copious notes and revise them before sessions in order to follow along. The joy of the one-shot is that I can hold it all in my head at once and manipulate my character (and often other threads too) into a satisfying conclusion.</p>
<p>Having said that, in retrospect it’s the long-running games which I tend to remember most clearly. Not specific moments of the game, especially after a few years, but I remember all my characters and what they were like to play. I have played many, many one-shots - easily 80+ sessions at this point - and I only remember the characters I played from maybe two or three of them.</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>It might be helpful to distinguish between character advancement and character development. Advancement: the numbers get bigger, they learn new skills, they fight bigger monsters. Development: by overcoming or succumbing to their flaws, they becoming a different person.</p>
<p>I think it’s broooadly true to say that games optimised for short-term play are more likely to be interested in development, while those optimised for long-term play are better at advancement. I’m not sure it would be possible to do satisfying character development in a truly long-term or open-ended context. I am not aware of any successful examples of this from fiction: there are certainly very long character arcs (the Fool trilogies by Robin Hobb come to mind) but they all have a bounded nature.</p>
<p>Soap operas are the only truly open-ended form of fiction we have. If you watch how the characters develop in them, it tends to be that once a character has their climax and finally changes for the better (or worse) they leave the show. Sometimes they fade out of the story for a while and come back basically as they were before, ready to do their character arc again. (This is called the ‘character reset button’ in the UK.)</p>
<p>In an RP context, I don’t think I’d really want to continue playing that much once my character story was resolved—either by rolling a new character or resetting my development.</p>
<p>I’ve been enjoying some bounded miniseason campaigns recently (we aim for four sessions, then add more if needed to conclude). These tend to have strong character development, at least as I play them. But I would be really interested in an indie-space game which attempted to do character development on a very long-term scale.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My only long campaign of non D&amp;D was a DW campaign that I think went about 10 sessions. By the end, some characters were hitting 7-8th level. They pretty much succeeded at everything. I’m pretty sure that was on me to adjust the challenges they were facing. I assume they had fun - they said they did.</p>
<p>Someone up-thread mentioned maintaining a mechanical power curve that still also held interest. While more moves can be fun; I think there’s also an opportunity with some games (AW may be the best at this from games I have read) for the PCs to branch out politically and socially; ie take over the world.</p>
<p>I can imagine Freebooters of the Frontier having an Epic Level game, after the Freebooter has gotten his 10,000 silver pieces. For example, turning from a freebooter to a Freeholder or something. Completely shifts the game however from an homage to old school emergent play into something more like what I imagine Pendragon or Legacy Life among the Ruins are like.</p>
<p>Not sure if that’s something <a class="mention" href="/u/jasonlutes">@jasonlutes</a> has any interest in exploring though.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/33</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 03:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree that there isn’t necessarily a link between “Traditional RPG” and “Designed to run for a really long campaign” – though I definitely think Trad RPGs have a greater percentage of games designed for that length, partially because very, very few indie/experimental/whatever you want to call them games design for this.  That certainly doesn’t mean that Trad RPGs never design for shorter game lengths, however.</p>
<p>In fact, I think it’s worth the historical call-out that a lot of the reason you see a so many newer games designed for the one shot/short campaign format is precisely because the designers of those games found the pacing and amount of “character moments per hour” in older games to be lacking.  This isn’t some sort of elitist “Ptui, Grognards. I bite my thumb at you!” movement, this is a reaction to lived experience.   Of course, part of this reaction is ALSO the “I don’t have time in my busy adult life to play a game that lasts for years.”  So there is also the element of “If I can’t play a long game, I want to jam all the character stuff I can into a short game.” here.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/31</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 17:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@technoskald]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="18" data-topic="3737">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/airk/40/2435_2.png" class="avatar"> Airk:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>With those caveats, I find that my preference is for “short shots” or mini-campaigns – somewhere between 3 and 10 sessions. This works well for most systems – I just finished a Ryuutama campaign that produced beautiful results in about 10 sessions – and it feels like this is where most of the PbtA games that I like are positioned as well (Also recently finished an 8 session Monster of the Week game, and we actually had to speed up advancement slightly to feel like we were getting a ‘full game’ in that time frame – definitely not ‘optimized for a one shot’.)</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I tend to like shorter “campaigns” as well - some of my favorite experiences have been games we intentionally planned for 4-10 sessions, regardless of system. I’ve had 10-session D&amp;D 5e campaigns that were incredibly memorable, for example: we explored a particular story arc with room for a few small side stories to explore characters’ specific backstories.</p>
<p>In fact, regarding systems, I’d point out that some “traditional” games excel on this. As an example, take a look at Call of Cthulhu: adventures typically run for a handful of sessions (maybe 1-4), at the end of which it’s understood that many of the PCs will be unable to continue for various reasons.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/30</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 17:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I generally pride myself on a large vocabulary but tautological was a new one for me!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/28</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 14:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I like the approach mentioned by <a class="mention" href="/u/calris">@calris</a> of scheduling a block up front (3-8 or whatever sessions), then checking in about the next block. New game? No time? Etc. I want to try to do that!</p>
<p>I also do want to try one shots again, as while I still think certain systems lean this way or that, people do make the most different. When I’m not in China I should give the gauntlet Hangouts a try…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 06:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Gus,</p>
<p>It’s funny how we seem to get into these debates with regularity lately. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>I can clarify on this point:</p>
<p>Of course, there is always greater investment in characters and more development when the games are longer in duration. That is fairly tautological: spend more time with characters you love, and you will be more attached to them. Of course!</p>
<p>It’s like watching a several seasons-long tv show, compared to a single movie: you will feel more shock and more “feels” when a character you’ve watched for years croaks. Of course.</p>
<p>What I’m talking about is, rather, a matter of efficiency: how much of this can we get <em>per unit of time</em>?</p>
<p>Although this metaphor is no longer true in the television/movie world, I think you and I are both old enough to remember when this was pretty much always the case:</p>
<p>Yes, in a long running tv show, you will get more emotional attachment and more character development.</p>
<p>But a high budget movie, although it’s shorter, can be of much higher quality. More work is put it into it and it’s all very focused; better writing, better editing, more care.</p>
<p>In this analogy, a two-hour Hollywood film creates much more impact than two one hour episodes of a typical tv show.</p>
<p>The effect <em>per unit of time</em> is more dramatic.</p>
<p>Again, everything depends on the game being played, and the players. I agree that most typical trad gamers, playing a typical trad game, won’t get much out of a one shot. But that’s just because they’re used to things moving very slowly; a single session of a long running campaign will be just as lacking in impact (anyone who’s ever sat in on a single session in the middle of a long running campaign can see what I mean - unless you happen to luck out and show up for a particular climactic session, you’ll probably be bored).</p>
<p>Hopefully that clarifies what I’ve seen in my experience. (I’ve seen it go either way, basically, depending on the attitude of the players and their skill set.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/26</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 05:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Gus brought up the observation that one shots are unsatisfying because of a lack of character development, whereas long term campaigns are far more interesting.</p>
<p>This is very true in a sense; certainly, the longer the game, the more room there is for development and evolution.</p>
<p>However, in practice I often see the opposite trend. There is a sort of flip side to this observation:</p>
<p>In one shots (with games designed for that!) I see dramatic character development take place regularly. (Again, consider something like <em>Witch</em> or <em>Dog Eat Dog</em>, which reliably produces personal epiphanies and character transformations in every game.) In many “indefinite duration” campaigns, on the other hand, I see people shy away from development and evolution and stall progress in every way possible.</p>
<p>The result is that (in my experience) good short form games see a lot more character development <em>per unit of time</em> than the typical open ended campaign.</p>
<p>The best games are campaigns where everyone treats each session as a potential ending point or one shot, but the game continues due to sustained interest and enthusiasm. That’s like the best of both worlds, when it can be pulled off.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 05:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I also agree that the PbtA angle is irrelevant here (although the game poems and 200-word RPGs and “nanogames” might be!).</p>
<p>While I know that some exist, I’ve yet to play any PbtA game that plays as a one shot. AW and anything based on it even says “it doesn’t get good until session 6 or so!”. I’ve tried running one shots with popular PbtA games, and it requires hard work and modification to make that work. (Compared to games that are intended as one shots, like Fiasco or Witch: the Road to Lindisfarne.)</p>
<p>However, it’s also true that the typical AW campaign isn’t designed to run as “long” as a typical D&amp;D game. It seems to me that D&amp;D is designed to play out over 40-150 sessions, while AW and games based on it might look more like 10-50 sessions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 04:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is actually a really interesting topic, and very relevant to any gamer, since we’re constantly trying to arrange games of various lengths.</p>
<p>My most successful games, like many here, have been “short campaigns of limited duration”. Perhaps in the 2-3 to 10-12 session range. Having a sense of duration going into it makes a huge difference (more on this below!), as I find campaigns of indefinite duration tend to encourage bad play habits (everyone working hard to delay the progression of the game, such as keeping mysteries hidden, tends to make the games slow and ungainly and fail over time).</p>
<p>A lot of this depends on the people involved, though. I’ve seen a play culture among trad gamers, in particular, where long-term, open-ended campaign play is seen as “true gaming”, and anything less is considered a throwaway hobby or a lark. As a result, these players don’t approach short-form games with seriousness, investment, or skill, and, predictably, they are always “ham-fisted” and silly or incoherent. (A self fulfilling prophecy!)</p>
<p>On the other hand:</p>
<p>My main “conversion moment” came when I was part of a gaming club in university. We had some ongoing long term campaigns, and an experiment where each weekend a different player ran a one shot.</p>
<p>After two years of this it was hard not to notice how much BETTER the one shots were than the long term campaigns. The long term games would have great material over time and great moments, but individual sessions were often letdowns. In the one shot series, however, each GM tried to outdo the others, and the players came in with full commitment. You only had one session that year, so you really had to make it count! Those games were amazing!</p>
<p>So, in that environment (even though these were also trad gamers), the opposite tendency soon developed.</p>
<p>Overall, the motto “run every session as though it were a one shot” seems like a great discipline.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737/22</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 04:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3737-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/looks-nervously-both-ways-anybody-else-not-like-one-shots-very-much/3737.rss">*looks nervously both ways* anybody else...not like one shots very much?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
