<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Girl By Moonlight: Brink of the Abyss (Wednesdays at 8:30 PM PDT)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-by-moonlight-brink-of-the-abyss-wednesdays-at-8-30-pm-pdt/8713</link>
    <description>Link: https://app.playabl.io/games/176

For the latter half of June through to July, I&#39;ll be running a series of Girls by Moonlight using the At the Brink of the Abyss playset. Girls by Moonlight is a magical girl roleplaying Forged in the Dark about characters fighting against doom with the aid of magical powers and some fancy transformation animations.

The At the Brink of the Abyss is specifically focused on characters fighting for a world worth saving from an encroaching evil that threatens to destroy it. The protagonists might be flawed, but they&#39;re ultimately heroic, and even the darkest villains have the possibility of being redeemed. Good touchstones for the tone include Sailor Moon as well as She-Ra and the Princesses of Power.

The game will take place over zoom, and will be recorded, although I will only post the recordings with everyone&#39;s enthusiastic consent. As always, we will be making use of The Open Hearth&#39;s Open Door Policy, the x-card, script change, and line and veils. One seat has been reserved for Mona.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 17:19:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-by-moonlight-brink-of-the-abyss-wednesdays-at-8-30-pm-pdt/8713.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Girl By Moonlight: Brink of the Abyss (Wednesdays at 8:30 PM PDT)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OnlyAnAlligator]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/onlyanalligator">@OnlyAnAlligator</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Link: <a href="https://app.playabl.io/games/176" rel="nofollow noopener">https://app.playabl.io/games/176</a></p>
<p>For the latter half of June through to July, I’ll be running a series of Girls by Moonlight using the At the Brink of the Abyss playset. Girls by Moonlight is a magical girl roleplaying Forged in the Dark about characters fighting against doom with the aid of magical powers and some fancy transformation animations.</p>
<p>The At the Brink of the Abyss is specifically focused on characters fighting for a world worth saving from an encroaching evil that threatens to destroy it. The protagonists might be flawed, but they’re ultimately heroic, and even the darkest villains have the possibility of being redeemed. Good touchstones for the tone include Sailor Moon as well as She-Ra and the Princesses of Power.</p>
<p>The game will take place over zoom, and will be recorded, although I will only post the recordings with everyone’s enthusiastic consent. As always, we will be making use of The Open Hearth’s Open Door Policy, the x-card, script change, and line and veils. One seat has been reserved for Mona.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-by-moonlight-brink-of-the-abyss-wednesdays-at-8-30-pm-pdt/8713/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-by-moonlight-brink-of-the-abyss-wednesdays-at-8-30-pm-pdt/8713/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 17:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8713-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-by-moonlight-brink-of-the-abyss-wednesdays-at-8-30-pm-pdt/8713.rss">Girl By Moonlight: Brink of the Abyss (Wednesdays at 8:30 PM PDT)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
