<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706</link>
    <description>The definitive list! (Definitely not the definitive list. Drop more of your favorite duets in replies.) Compiled mostly with @bccook and @transalaskan, with suggestions from a few others.

We&#39;ve got three categories: Feels, Murder, and Other (which is currently, basically, Space).

**Feels**

* [*183 Days*](https://www.drivethrucards.com/product/144510/183-Days) — Two psychics navigate their relationship
* [*The Bite*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/190812/The-Bite) — You&#39;re trapped in a room with your companion, who may or may not have been bitten by a zombie. What stories do you tell each other to delay a decision?
* [*Breaking the Ice*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/80426/Breaking-the-Ice) — A couple goes on their first three dates
* [*By the General&#39;s Hand*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/246216/By-The-Generals-Hand) — A letter-writing combat game in which the course of an ever-changing war plays out in the form of correspondence between two generals and their loved ones back home. 
* [*Dead Friend*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/234653/Dead-Friend-A-Game-of-Necromancy) — One dead friend and one living struggle to reconnect and abjectly fail at letting go.
* [*Message*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/255136/You--I-Roleplaying-Games-for-Two) — Two chatbots have an hour-long talk using words harvested from your very own real-life emails.
* [*Neighborly*](https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1LrNVuyZzb2Hs2sC95Dnd0iDXoWw6CO8aCYft897VvPA/edit?usp=sharing) — The evolution–or devolution–of the relationship between two next-door neighbors.
* [*One Missed Call*](http://www.lessthanthreegames.com/blog/tag/one-missed-call/) — A long distance relationship either falls apart or comes together over a series of phone calls.
* [*Our Mundane Supernatural Life*](https://storybrewersroleplaying.com/freegames/) — One Normal and one Supernatural live a day of their shared life together.
* [*A Single Moment*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/174365/A-Single-Moment) — The story of how two samurai have come to odds, and what bitter end awaits them.
* [*Starcrossed*](https://bullypulpitgames.com/games/star-crossed/) — A game about really, really wanting to, when you really, really can&#39;t.
* [*Sympathy and Admiration*](https://bccook.itch.io/sympathy-and-admiration) — Figure out who your copilot really is on the inside while punching monsters
* [*Tumbling*](https://sidneyicarus.wordpress.com/tumbling/) — Laundromat meet cute. The slow evolution (or not) of the relationship between two strangers.

**Murder**

* [*De Profundis*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/84298/De-Profundis-Second-Edition) — play out a Lovecraftian horror story via letter exchange. Meant to be played over a period of days/months.
* [*The Hour Between Dog and Wolf*](https://www.errantknightgames.biz/thbdaw) — One of you plays a serial killer, the other the person hunting them.
* [*The Knife*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/237146/The-Knife) — One of you is a future murder victim, the other the person who will kill them.
* [*Murderous Ghosts*](https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/225162/Murderous-Ghosts-a-Party-Game) — Pit your guts, wits, and luck against your opponent&#39;s twisted, bloody imagination. Can you escape the murderous ghosts?

**Other**

* [*Mars Colony*](http://www.tckroleplaying.com/marscolony/) — Political science fiction (in space!) about a cult of personality.
* [*Mars Colony: 39 Dark*](http://www.tckroleplaying.com/39dark/index.html) — Political science fiction (still in space!) about a resistance leader and the forces working against them.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 19:46:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s not specifically a duet game, but <a href="https://www.ironswornrpg.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Ironsworn</a>’s cooperative mode would work very well with two players.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/39</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 19:46:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I feel like that’s not a GMLess/Full game. It’s a standard GM/PC game with the standard distributions of responsibility and power.</p>
<p>It’s a duet game, yes, but Cthulhu Confidential and Night’s Black Agents: Solo Ops (both great) are also disqualified here, I would think.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/38</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 19:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would like to recommend <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/rpg/618/dirty-world" rel="nofollow noopener">A Dirty World</a>. It is not specifically two player but as it is noir and most noir stories focus on only one or two characters AND this game is GM-less, I think it could work well for two players.</p>
<p>Mythic <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/rpg/1510/mythic-role-playing" rel="nofollow noopener">Mythic rpg</a> is a very rules light game where you just ask Yes / No questions and estimate how likely something is to happen, then roll on a simple chart.  The updated version apparently has done away with the chart and the GM simulator can not be done by buying a set of cards (which at first look are complicated).  Still, I LOVE this GM simulator to prevent my writing from becoming too boring, and running two player games.</p>
<p>Added:  A Dirty World. This game is not specifically 2 player BUT I suspect it works best with 2 or 3 players.  It is GM-less and noir narrative focused though so I think it fits for a recommendation.  Hardboiled detective and femme fatale story - check;. Detective and informant - check;  even Jessica Jones type stories - check.  I gotta get in game of this now…</p>
<p>‐--------‐--------‐<br>
Edited: The two below work great as 2 players games with one running the game as GM</p>
<p>Dr. Who also works well with 2 players when the GM plays The Doctor as an NPC. <a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/rpg/4241/doctor-who-roleplaying-game" rel="nofollow noopener">Doctor Who Role Playing game Through Time and Space</a></p>
<p><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/rpg/2534/wushu-open" rel="nofollow noopener">Wushu Open</a> is also a good choice for a railroady 2 player game.  The mechanics are such that 2 players or 5 players just means you don’t have to adjust much at all.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/37</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 18:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-post="29" data-topic="706" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/brushmen/40/1642_2.png" class="avatar"> brushmen:</div>
<blockquote>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-post="12" data-topic="706">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/yoshi/40/169_2.png" class="avatar"> yoshi:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’d love to know if you played them what that experience was like.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Tobie Abad’s <em>A Single Moment</em> is very similar to Jim McClure’s <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/202679/Reflections-A-Game-of-Dueling-Samurai" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>Reflections</em></a> (I can’t say the former completely inspired the latter), with the former having more crunch than the latter. <em>A Single Moment</em> has rules to “force/reward” more give-and-take in the build-up of the two former friends’ relationship (token economy) as well as the final back-and-forth during the duel (gambling with dice pool built from the token economy), while <em>Reflections</em> relies on the players more to go as deep as they want (1 single roll, no token economy, only a point tracker). But I felt the crunchier system can easily get in the way of the improvised storytelling, unless both players have mastered the rules, then maybe <em>A Single Moment</em> helps with the improvisation because of the give-and-take structure (help your opponent’s character so as to gain valuable token, or help your own character so as to gain better fictional positioning). <em>Reflections</em> is easier on the cognitive load, but doesn’t necessarily play faster because sometimes both players have to decide when to finish a scene if it looks like neither could accomplish their scene objective narratively. The base game for both plays out a tragedy, but in the appendix both have a “romcom” hack.</p>
<p>The link for <em>One Missed Call</em> above doesn’t work for me at the moment, but it sounds like a similar game by David Zerbst, <a href="https://200wordrpg.github.io/2018/rpg/2018/05/28/ToEraseandReRecordPressThree.html" rel="nofollow noopener"> To Erase and Re-Record, Press Three</a>. David was/is on the StoryGames Discord and sent me his longer document upon request, and I play-by-chat it with someone. The built-in X-card mechanism felt novel to me at the time. My gut says the emotional core of this game may be “hope”. But it’s probably dependent on the players.</p>
<p><em>Mars Colony</em>, in the “Influences” section of the rulebook, talks about the “feelings of personal failure,” which I presume could be the emotional core of the game, but when I played it with someone who didn’t let failed rolls (consequently narrative setback) get to him, it nearly came out a “perfect victory” for the protagonist. So, your mileage might vary?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I enjoyed A Single Moment. The game mechanics were simple and pushed the both players to create the story.   The give and take mechanic works pretty well to keep the conversation going back and forth. The combination of very heavy improv with minimal prompts and only 2 players for 60- 90 min game is pretty exhausting though . It assumes though that the other player will not just give in to total collaboration and instead tries to take control of the narrative.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/36</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 17:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="27" data-topic="706" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/yoshi/40/169_2.png" class="avatar"> yoshi:</div>
<blockquote>
<p><em>How we are like Storm</em> by Jackson Tegu is another duet game. It’s a game about two people who have been apart for 10 years and great distance coming back together. As one player describes the landscape the other paints/draws the landscape on the speakers arm. It is also about anticipation, and reflection on how each character has changed the course of the other, and ruminating on “how alike a storm we are”.</p>
<p>Then you swap roles and who is speaking and who is painting/drawing flips. The game ends when the painted landscapes meet at your held hands.</p>
<p>I have a copy but haven’t played it yet. Someday. As far as I can tell it’s not currently available. Possibly reaching out to Jackson might let you know when or how you can get a copy.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This game sounds like a great idea!  It is also one of the few possibly fun themed games that could be used as a direct form of therapy.  There are SO many people that have not seen their parent, sibling, or best friend for years and want to reconnect.  If this is done well, it could create a nice structure to roleplay this scene out before they do it for real.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/35</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 16:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You could most certainly play FtQ with two players.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/34</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 02:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@technoskald]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I haven’t played it, but apparently there are some Call of Cthulhu modules designed expressly for this sort of play, such as <a href="http://www.unboundbook.org/?p=82" rel="nofollow noopener">Monophobia</a>. My son asked me to run one of these for him; our experiments in D&amp;D 5e have improved but were ultimately unsatisfactory.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/33</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 17:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ll second the vote for <em>S/lay w/Me</em>. It’s an excellent game for this!</p>
<p>Another game that’s really great for two players is <em>Showdown</em>, by Seth Ben-Ezra.</p>
<p>I believe this is the official link:</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/137649/Showdown/../../../themes/dtrpg/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/137649/Showdown" target="_blank">drivethrurpg.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:386/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/c/c9d24b0792c20f5faa7a940ee1753de4ad621277.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/137649/Showdown" target="_blank">Showdown - Dark Omen Games | DriveThruRPG.com</a></h3>

<p>Don't forget to purchase the add-on deck of cards! (Cards are not required to play, but make the experience much ni</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Finally, I’m not 100% sure about this, but wouldn’t <em>For the Queen</em> work well as a two-player game?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/32</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 23:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Tacoforce]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/tacoforce">@Tacoforce</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I want to try this (lonesome world) sometime!</p>
<p>I don’t think I’ve seen anyone mention Ironsworn. It does some really neat things with tone and uses a solid structure to facilitate one on one, gmless, and solo play. Highly recommend checking it out.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/31</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bccook]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bccook">@bccook</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="https://lessthanthreegames.itch.io/one-missed-call" rel="nofollow noopener">Here’s an updated link for One Missed Call!</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/30</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 15:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brushmen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brushmen">@brushmen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-post="12" data-topic="706">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/yoshi/40/169_2.png" class="avatar"> yoshi:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’d love to know if you played them what that experience was like.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Tobie Abad’s <em>A Single Moment</em> is very similar to Jim McClure’s <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/202679/Reflections-A-Game-of-Dueling-Samurai" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>Reflections</em></a> (I can’t say the former completely inspired the latter), with the former having more crunch than the latter. <em>A Single Moment</em> has rules to “force/reward” more give-and-take in the build-up of the two former friends’ relationship (token economy) as well as the final back-and-forth during the duel (gambling with dice pool built from the token economy), while <em>Reflections</em> relies on the players more to go as deep as they want (1 single roll, no token economy, only a point tracker). But I felt the crunchier system can easily get in the way of the improvised storytelling, unless both players have mastered the rules, then maybe <em>A Single Moment</em> helps with the improvisation because of the give-and-take structure (help your opponent’s character so as to gain valuable token, or help your own character so as to gain better fictional positioning). <em>Reflections</em> is easier on the cognitive load, but doesn’t necessarily play faster because sometimes both players have to decide when to finish a scene if it looks like neither could accomplish their scene objective narratively. The base game for both plays out a tragedy, but in the appendix both have a “romcom” hack.</p>
<p>The link for <em>One Missed Call</em> above doesn’t work for me at the moment, but it sounds like a similar game by David Zerbst, <a href="https://200wordrpg.github.io/2018/rpg/2018/05/28/ToEraseandReRecordPressThree.html" rel="nofollow noopener"> To Erase and Re-Record, Press Three</a>. David was/is on the StoryGames Discord and sent me his longer document upon request, and I play-by-chat it with someone. The built-in X-card mechanism felt novel to me at the time. My gut says the emotional core of this game may be “hope”. But it’s probably dependent on the players.</p>
<p><em>Mars Colony</em>, in the “Influences” section of the rulebook, talks about the “feelings of personal failure,” which I presume could be the emotional core of the game, but when I played it with someone who didn’t let failed rolls (consequently narrative setback) get to him, it nearly came out a “perfect victory” for the protagonist. So, your mileage might vary?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/29</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 12:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My game <em><a href="http://halfmeme.com/Threeforged2015/1577s3.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">The Policy of Truth</a></em> is a two player game. One player is an Iraqi asset of American intelligence in Baghdad in 2004 and the other player is their American handler. I don’t know which of your categories it would fall into. It will make you feel something, and that something is bad, and there will certainly be some murder.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 14:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>How we are like Storm</em> by Jackson Tegu is another duet game. It’s a game about two people who have been apart for 10 years and great distance coming back together. As one player describes the landscape the other paints/draws the landscape on the speakers arm. It is also about anticipation, and reflection on how each character has changed the course of the other, and ruminating on “how alike a storm we are”.</p>
<p>Then you swap roles and who is speaking and who is painting/drawing flips. The game ends when the painted landscapes meet at your held hands.</p>
<p>I have a copy but haven’t played it yet. Someday. As far as I can tell it’s not currently available. Possibly reaching out to Jackson might let you know when or how you can get a copy.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 15:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I created a game called Lonesome World, a Powered by the Apocalypse Western-themed one-on-one game. It’s been through a few play tests and holds up pretty well. The bones are there, but development is on hiatus as I strategize about handling the problematic aspects of late 19th century America.</p>
<p>Rules Summary, Playbooks, and other materials here: <a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1g-0371OWpPn6odYLjl3xHKmu89tozaxB" rel="nofollow noopener">https://drive.google.com/open?id=1g-0371OWpPn6odYLjl3xHKmu89tozaxB</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 20:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Nickwedig]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/nickwedig">@Nickwedig</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="http://nickwedig.libraryofhighmoon.com/2011/03/fortune-cookies-and-nuclear-war/" rel="nofollow noopener">I made this microgame for two players</a> a long time ago, about political negotiation and bluffing. It’s made to be played in a Chinese restaurant, where you have to reach a consensus with your sworn enemy over the course of a single meal, or the entire world will be destroyed. (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuban_Missile_Crisis#Drafting_response" rel="nofollow noopener">Based on a true story.</a>)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 11:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My upcoming game A Cool and Lonely Courage is designed to play well as a two player GM-less game, although it can be used with up to 5 players. Kickstarting soon! Information here</p>
<p><a href="https://planesailinggames.com/a-cool-and-lonely-courage/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://planesailinggames.com/a-cool-and-lonely-courage/</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/24</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 22:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bccook]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bccook">@bccook</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Having played these two Emotional Mecha Games, I want to recommend <em><a href="https://casskdesigns.itch.io/breach" rel="nofollow noopener">Breach</a></em> by <a class="mention" href="/u/cass">@Cass</a> and <em><a href="https://merthurlin.itch.io/rev-your-engines" rel="nofollow noopener">Rev Your Engines</a></em> by Maayan Priel.</p>
<p><em>Breach</em> is all about a Mech and its Pilot making a decision about what to do when the rules of engagement conflict with camaraderie. It uses a deck of cards to make the decision impossible and its final move is gutting.</p>
<p><em>Rev Your Engines</em> brings big scale mechæmotion down to the anime rivalry schoolyard level. Choosing from its nine prompts becomes a lot more difficult when each of them is on a tic-tac-toe board that will determine which one of you comes out on top.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/23</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 16:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@klintron]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/klintron">@klintron</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For the sake of completion: <em>S/lay w/Me</em> by Ron Edwards. I haven’t played it or read it.</p>
<p>There’s also <em>Cthulhu Confidential</em>, the duet Gumshoe system game, which I guess isn’t really GMless.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 04:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mcbacon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mcbacon">@mcbacon</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This looks pretty cool- the idea of a potentially malevolent entity persuading its way towards release reminds me very much of that AI box experiment thing. Was that an influence?</p>
<p>Also, I like the inversion variant you list at the back, with the human courting the terror. Pretty neat how that shifts the tone entirely with only the slightest mechanical change.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 03:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@harpydora]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/harpydora">@harpydora</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My absolute favorite TTRPG currently is a two-player game called <a href="https://roswellian.itch.io/random-access-histories" rel="nofollow noopener">Random Access Histories</a>. It would go in the “other” section, probably. It’s about a sentient mecha and their neural-linked pilot, and it’s very good. It’s also pretty easy to do in a play-by-post format, as I’ve done that several times.</p>
<p>Also, in the spirit of self-promotion, I wrote a 2-player game (though it has 3- and 4-player variants) about an eldritch god trying to tempt a human into summoning it. It’s called <a href="https://harpydora.itch.io/things-eldritch-and-terrifying" rel="nofollow noopener">Things, Eldritch and Terrifying</a> and it also would go in the “other” section.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 01:23:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thorsten]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thorsten">@thorsten</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I just got the GO from my girlfriend to play Dragon/Dragonslayer with her. It’s going to be intense.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/19</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 20:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@atminnie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/atminnie">@atminnie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Would a game designed for one GM and a solo player/protagonist count as specifically intended for 2?</p>
<p>I think it would, in which case games like  <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/127180/Scarlet-Heroes" rel="nofollow noopener">Scarlet Heroes</a> would apply, right? I have not run this one, but whenever I look into duet games, I tend to be intrigued by the concept.</p>
<p>Since it’s classic sword and sorcery, I suppose it would fit under the Murder category.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/18</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 20:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@thorsten]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thorsten">@thorsten</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Dragon/Dragonslayer by Wendy Gorman.</p>
<p><em>This is a game for two. One of you is a Dragon, the other, a Dragonslayer.</em></p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://200wordrpg.github.io/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://200wordrpg.github.io/2016/rpg/finalist/2016/04/05/DragonDragonslayer.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">200wordrpg.github.io</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:400/225;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/1X/cf37baa26ac8368965069673cce1a90025032975.gif" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://200wordrpg.github.io/2016/rpg/finalist/2016/04/05/DragonDragonslayer.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Dragon/Dragonslayer</a></h3>

<p>Wendy Gorman</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/17</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 18:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/52369/sweet-agatha" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>Sweet Agath</em>a</a>, also noteworthy because you physically destroy the game as you play. Super interesting and cool.</p>
<p>I’ve played <em>Dogs in the Vineyard</em> one on one and it is pretty intense and fun.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/16</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve played Connection Lost from the <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/255136/You--I-Roleplaying-Games-for-Two" rel="nofollow noopener">You &amp; I collection</a> , about an astronaut going down with their damaged satellite and the other person this astronaut is talking to during the last hour before the satellite will be destroyed by entering the atmosphere.</p>
<p>That was a very intense game (I was the astronaut) about dying and facing the stark reality of death.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706/15</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 23:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-706-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/recommendations-two-player-gm-less-full-rpgs-duets/706.rss">Recommendations: Two-Player, GM-less/full RPGs (&quot;Duets&quot;)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
