<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Haunted West (PbtA): Ghosts Of The Prairie</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/haunted-west-pbta-ghosts-of-the-prairie/7999</link>
    <description>**NUMBER OF SESSIONS:**  4

**DURATION:**  3 hours

**NUMBER OF PLAYERS:**  4 (A seat is reserved for Lowell)

**CONTENT WARNING:**  This is a game set after the Civil War in the American Midwest, which means it will occur in an era and environment where colonialism, imperialism, racism, and genocide were policies explicitly endorsed and carried out by the government, military, and private citizens. Right was almost exclusively determined by might/capitalism. Saloons often had brothels, so alcohol and sex workers may be part of the game. Characters might use or abuse drugs. Violence was common.

However, Haunted West is a game which explicitly works against the prevailing attitudes of the time, and none of those attitudes will be used to try to shock players. This is just the historical reality of the time, and the players can choose how or whether to engage with it. Haunted West is also a Weird West game, so the supernatural will be involved in some way.

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

Angel Falls was once the far edge of the frontier, protected by elements of the 9th Cavalry, stationed at Fort Wilcox. It was a buffalo boomtown, and smelled like it. When the western wind came across the plains, it brought the stench of uncountable distant corpses rotting in the prairie heat.

But that was then. Now, Angel Falls is all but a ghost town. The general store still supplies the few subsistence farmers who try to stick it out, but the barber&#39;s chair is empty most days. The Bugle &amp; Bison saloon is still open, but the piano bench is empty whenever someone comes calling on Red Molly. Preacher Jack decided the town&#39;s name was an omen and lit out for a place where he might actually find something like a congregation, thus depriving the Bugle &amp; Bison of its best customer.

The few people here are tired and weary, too broke to leave for better prospects. But at least Angel Falls is quiet. Usually. Lately, there have been rumbles on the horizon, storms that look to be forming and dissipate just as quickly. For those able - or willing - to pay attention, it&#39;s obvious that  *something*  is coming.

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

**SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:**  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet&#39;s Community Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html

**RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:**  04/06/2022 15:00 Central Time

**SET UP INFO:**  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the game.

**BREAKS:**  2 five minute breaks

**RECORDED:**  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.

**PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:**  No experience required, rules will be taught.

**Session 1:** https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWD6E_pKaWECuKtjv
**Session 2:** https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWhmwSEJeNRXUXyAf
**Session 3:** https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWy-icB6yJVa2CSEK
**Session 4:** https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqXBbPBFoHMtk2njwI</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 22:27:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/haunted-west-pbta-ghosts-of-the-prairie/7999.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Haunted West (PbtA): Ghosts Of The Prairie</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>NUMBER OF SESSIONS:</strong>  4</p>
<p><strong>DURATION:</strong>  3 hours</p>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF PLAYERS:</strong>  4 (A seat is reserved for Lowell)</p>
<p><strong>CONTENT WARNING:</strong>  This is a game set after the Civil War in the American Midwest, which means it will occur in an era and environment where colonialism, imperialism, racism, and genocide were policies explicitly endorsed and carried out by the government, military, and private citizens. Right was almost exclusively determined by might/capitalism. Saloons often had brothels, so alcohol and sex workers may be part of the game. Characters might use or abuse drugs. Violence was common.</p>
<p>However, Haunted West is a game which explicitly works against the prevailing attitudes of the time, and none of those attitudes will be used to try to shock players. This is just the historical reality of the time, and the players can choose how or whether to engage with it. Haunted West is also a Weird West game, so the supernatural will be involved in some way.</p>
<hr>
<p>Angel Falls was once the far edge of the frontier, protected by elements of the 9th Cavalry, stationed at Fort Wilcox. It was a buffalo boomtown, and smelled like it. When the western wind came across the plains, it brought the stench of uncountable distant corpses rotting in the prairie heat.</p>
<p>But that was then. Now, Angel Falls is all but a ghost town. The general store still supplies the few subsistence farmers who try to stick it out, but the barber’s chair is empty most days. The Bugle &amp; Bison saloon is still open, but the piano bench is empty whenever someone comes calling on Red Molly. Preacher Jack decided the town’s name was an omen and lit out for a place where he might actually find something like a congregation, thus depriving the Bugle &amp; Bison of its best customer.</p>
<p>The few people here are tired and weary, too broke to leave for better prospects. But at least Angel Falls is quiet. Usually. Lately, there have been rumbles on the horizon, storms that look to be forming and dissipate just as quickly. For those able - or willing - to pay attention, it’s obvious that  <em>something</em>  is coming.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:</strong>  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet’s Community Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a></p>
<p><strong>RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:</strong>  04/06/2022 15:00 Central Time</p>
<p><strong>SET UP INFO:</strong>  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the game.</p>
<p><strong>BREAKS:</strong>  2 five minute breaks</p>
<p><strong>RECORDED:</strong>  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.</p>
<p><strong>PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:</strong>  No experience required, rules will be taught.</p>
<p><strong>Session 1:</strong> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWD6E_pKaWECuKtjv" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWD6E_pKaWECuKtjv</a><br>
<strong>Session 2:</strong> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWhmwSEJeNRXUXyAf" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWhmwSEJeNRXUXyAf</a><br>
<strong>Session 3:</strong> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWy-icB6yJVa2CSEK" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqWy-icB6yJVa2CSEK</a><br>
<strong>Session 4:</strong> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqXBbPBFoHMtk2njwI" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MzqXBbPBFoHMtk2njwI</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/haunted-west-pbta-ghosts-of-the-prairie/7999/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/haunted-west-pbta-ghosts-of-the-prairie/7999/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 22:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7999-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/haunted-west-pbta-ghosts-of-the-prairie/7999.rss">Haunted West (PbtA): Ghosts Of The Prairie</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
