<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>New Fantasy World SRD (Dramatic Fantasy PbtA)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-fantasy-world-srd-dramatic-fantasy-pbta/8601</link>
    <description>Hey all. I saw this fly under the radar, so I wanted to share that the new **[Fantasy World SRD](https://fantasyworldrpg.com)** has been released under CC-BY -- being a strong proponent of libre licensing, it makes me very happy that the publisher decided to go with the most free CC license.

It contains, unlike the old free wiki, the full text of the PDF and print editions of Fantasy World. There are also now ready-to-print [PDF playbooks](https://fantasyworldrpg.com/downloads/Downloads.html). I&#39;m not too fond of the playbook layout myself, but they are reasonably functional.

*Disclosure: although I helped @Alessandro_Piroddi with some of the scripting and website shenaningans for this wiki, I&#39;m not involved with the game&#39;s design or its commercial aspect, I only help because I like the game, and it&#39;s released under CC-BY, so this benefits the community at large.*</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 18:55:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-fantasy-world-srd-dramatic-fantasy-pbta/8601.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>New Fantasy World SRD (Dramatic Fantasy PbtA)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Froggy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/froggy">@Froggy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hey all. I saw this fly under the radar, so I wanted to share that the new <strong><a href="https://fantasyworldrpg.com" rel="nofollow noopener">Fantasy World SRD</a></strong> has been released under CC-BY – being a strong proponent of libre licensing, it makes me very happy that the publisher decided to go with the most free CC license.</p>
<p>It contains, unlike the old free wiki, the full text of the PDF and print editions of Fantasy World. There are also now ready-to-print <a href="https://fantasyworldrpg.com/downloads/Downloads.html" rel="nofollow noopener">PDF playbooks</a>. I’m not too fond of the playbook layout myself, but they are reasonably functional.</p>
<p><em>Disclosure: although I helped <a class="mention" href="/u/alessandro_piroddi">@Alessandro_Piroddi</a> with some of the scripting and website shenaningans for this wiki, I’m not involved with the game’s design or its commercial aspect, I only help because I like the game, and it’s released under CC-BY, so this benefits the community at large.</em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-fantasy-world-srd-dramatic-fantasy-pbta/8601/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-fantasy-world-srd-dramatic-fantasy-pbta/8601/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 23:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8601-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-fantasy-world-srd-dramatic-fantasy-pbta/8601.rss">New Fantasy World SRD (Dramatic Fantasy PbtA)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
