<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gauntlet Con: Seeking Diverse GMs</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088</link>
    <description>Gauntlet Con is an entirely online convention that&#39;s going into its third year. This year the con will take place from Thursday, October 24 to Sunday, October 27 in Eastern Daylight Time. We have many excellent GMs from across the globe. This year, we&#39;ve already scheduled over 170 game sessions from 75+ GMs.  We&#39;ve been looking at the diversity of the GMs on our current Gauntlet Con schedule, and we want to expand both the number and diversity of GMs for this year&#39;s con. Specifically, we&#39;d like to add 15 games by GMs who are people of color, queer-identified/LGBTQIA, people with disabilities, or women. We&#39;re very interested in expanding this number of games by recruiting GM who ***aren&#39;t already on the calendar*** (though GMs who are already on the calendar are certainly welcome to check in about adding games as well).

If you are person of color, LGBTIA+ person, person with a disability, and/or woman who has an interest in running games in the following categories, we&#39;d like to hear from you:

* Powered by the Apocalypse &amp; Forged in the Dark Games
* Storygames
* OSR Games and Adventures
* Stand-alone games from designers who are independent, small press, or self-published

***Like all of our GMs, you are welcome to bring and run their own systems, settings, and scenarios, including materials still in playtest.***

GMs from across the globe and across timezones are definitely welcome. We plan to run games beginning at 4 AM US Eastern on most mornings and finish the day with games that start at 11:30 PM US Eastern.

If you are interested, please reach out to @RichardRuane or @yoshi on The Gauntlet Forums.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:57:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Announcements</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Gauntlet Con: Seeking Diverse GMs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@RichardRuane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/richardruane">@RichardRuane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just a reminder that we’ve still got a couple of days open to add games to the schedule. If you’re interested in this or know someone who might be, reach out!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3088-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088.rss">Gauntlet Con: Seeking Diverse GMs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gauntlet Con: Seeking Diverse GMs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@RichardRuane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/richardruane">@RichardRuane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Gauntlet Con is an entirely online convention that’s going into its third year. This year the con will take place from Thursday, October 24 to Sunday, October 27 in Eastern Daylight Time. We have many excellent GMs from across the globe. This year, we’ve already scheduled over 170 game sessions from 75+ GMs.  We’ve been looking at the diversity of the GMs on our current Gauntlet Con schedule, and we want to expand both the number and diversity of GMs for this year’s con. Specifically, we’d like to add 15 games by GMs who are people of color, queer-identified/LGBTQIA, people with disabilities, or women. We’re very interested in expanding this number of games by recruiting GM who <em><strong>aren’t already on the calendar</strong></em> (though GMs who are already on the calendar are certainly welcome to check in about adding games as well).</p>
<p>If you are person of color, LGBTIA+ person, person with a disability, and/or woman who has an interest in running games in the following categories, we’d like to hear from you:</p>
<ul>
<li>Powered by the Apocalypse &amp; Forged in the Dark Games</li>
<li>Storygames</li>
<li>OSR Games and Adventures</li>
<li>Stand-alone games from designers who are independent, small press, or self-published</li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>Like all of our GMs, you are welcome to bring and run their own systems, settings, and scenarios, including materials still in playtest.</strong></em></p>
<p>GMs from across the globe and across timezones are definitely welcome. We plan to run games beginning at 4 AM US Eastern on most mornings and finish the day with games that start at 11:30 PM US Eastern.</p>
<p>If you are interested, please reach out to <a class="mention" href="/u/richardruane">@RichardRuane</a> or <a class="mention" href="/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> on The Gauntlet Forums.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 03:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3088-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-con-seeking-diverse-gms/3088.rss">Gauntlet Con: Seeking Diverse GMs</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
