<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gauntlet Reading Club: DIE/The DIE RPG (Saturdays in April)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-die-the-die-rpg-saturdays-in-april/8593</link>
    <description>Link: https://app.playabl.io/games/45

To celebrate the release of the ***DIE RPG*** , the Gauntlet Reading Club will be reading volume one of Kieron Gillen and Stephanie Hans&#39;s ***DIE*** , then playing a run of the game created to emulate the drama of a bunch of estranged roleplaying friends getting transported into their gaming group&#39;s old stomping grounds.

**Content Warnings for DIE: Depictions of violence, parental loss and mind control.**

*DIE is a pitch-black fantasy where a group of forty-something adults have to deal with the returning unearthly horror they barely survived as teenage role-players. If Kieron’s in a rush, he describes it as “Goth Jumanji.” That only captures a sliver of what you’ll find in oversized debut issue—where fantasy gets all too real.*

Session 1 will be a book discussion group for volume 1 of *DIE* . During the run, we&#39;ll be drawing on the thematic inspiration of *DIE* rather than specific plot points, and will have a discussion on tone and content before play, as well as establishing Lines &amp; Veils to provide a comfortable play experience.

We&#39;ll be using Zoom to discuss and play, but the sessions will only be recorded and posted publicly with everyone&#39;s enthusiastic consent.

This game will take place under the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) and the safety tools [Script Change ](http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m) and [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg) will be in use. I will aim to get in touch with participants through either the Gauntlet Slack or email a week in advance of the game to confirm attendance and provide play materials. A seat has been reserved for a player from off-gauntlet.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 01:00:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-die-the-die-rpg-saturdays-in-april/8593.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Gauntlet Reading Club: DIE/The DIE RPG (Saturdays in April)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OnlyAnAlligator]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/onlyanalligator">@OnlyAnAlligator</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Link: <a href="https://app.playabl.io/games/45" rel="nofollow noopener">https://app.playabl.io/games/45</a></p>
<p>To celebrate the release of the <em><strong>DIE RPG</strong></em> , the Gauntlet Reading Club will be reading volume one of Kieron Gillen and Stephanie Hans’s <em><strong>DIE</strong></em> , then playing a run of the game created to emulate the drama of a bunch of estranged roleplaying friends getting transported into their gaming group’s old stomping grounds.</p>
<p><strong>Content Warnings for DIE: Depictions of violence, parental loss and mind control.</strong></p>
<p><em>DIE is a pitch-black fantasy where a group of forty-something adults have to deal with the returning unearthly horror they barely survived as teenage role-players. If Kieron’s in a rush, he describes it as “Goth Jumanji.” That only captures a sliver of what you’ll find in oversized debut issue—where fantasy gets all too real.</em></p>
<p>Session 1 will be a book discussion group for volume 1 of <em>DIE</em> . During the run, we’ll be drawing on the thematic inspiration of <em>DIE</em> rather than specific plot points, and will have a discussion on tone and content before play, as well as establishing Lines &amp; Veils to provide a comfortable play experience.</p>
<p>We’ll be using Zoom to discuss and play, but the sessions will only be recorded and posted publicly with everyone’s enthusiastic consent.</p>
<p>This game will take place under the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a> and the safety tools <a href="http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change </a> and <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">X-Card</a> will be in use. I will aim to get in touch with participants through either the Gauntlet Slack or email a week in advance of the game to confirm attendance and provide play materials. A seat has been reserved for a player from off-gauntlet.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-die-the-die-rpg-saturdays-in-april/8593/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-die-the-die-rpg-saturdays-in-april/8593/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 01:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8593-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-die-the-die-rpg-saturdays-in-april/8593.rss">Gauntlet Reading Club: DIE/The DIE RPG (Saturdays in April)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
