<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Dark - Fiorina 161</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-fiorina-161/5054</link>
    <description>A session of **Alien Dark**, my game of alien horror inspired by Chtulhu Dark (Graham Walmsley) and Alien RPG (Free League), run as part of the first **Gauntlet Community Open Gaming (GCOG)** weekend ... the crew of the USCSS Lake discover a simple survey mission has secrets ... 

Burned out XO Fayne &amp; Navigator Arroyo investigate a rogue beacon on the far side of the mothballed ore refinery complex while Chief Engineer Smithson and the Lake&#39;s Science Officer, Johanson, get on with the survey they are being paid for. Fayne and Arroyo find a deserted scavenger shuttle and a body killed in a way ex-Marine Fayne can&#39;t explain. Meanwhile, Captain Jackson, left minding the ship is surprised when &#39;something&#39; boards the Lake. By the time the teams get back she&#39;s missing but Johanson, driven by a desire to know more, follows a blood trail to find &#39;something&#39; wrapped around her face. The Company rep. joins her and gets too close to a large ovoid organic thing ... 
Meanwhile, hyped-on-uppers Smithson is having an episode while Fayne tries to hold the crew together. That&#39;s when Arroyo gets an offer from Weyland-Yutani that would solve all her problems ... We end on a Mexican stand-off between the tough Fayne, protective Johanson, desperate Arroyo and hyped Smithson ... A great pilot episode leaving the network begging for more ...

https://youtu.be/VfiTPYiK5eM</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 12:56:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-fiorina-161/5054.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Alien Dark - Fiorina 161</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A session of <strong>Alien Dark</strong>, my game of alien horror inspired by Chtulhu Dark (Graham Walmsley) and Alien RPG (Free League), run as part of the first <strong>Gauntlet Community Open Gaming (GCOG)</strong> weekend … the crew of the USCSS Lake discover a simple survey mission has secrets …</p>
<p>Burned out XO Fayne &amp; Navigator Arroyo investigate a rogue beacon on the far side of the mothballed ore refinery complex while Chief Engineer Smithson and the Lake’s Science Officer, Johanson, get on with the survey they are being paid for. Fayne and Arroyo find a deserted scavenger shuttle and a body killed in a way ex-Marine Fayne can’t explain. Meanwhile, Captain Jackson, left minding the ship is surprised when ‘something’ boards the Lake. By the time the teams get back she’s missing but Johanson, driven by a desire to know more, follows a blood trail to find ‘something’ wrapped around her face. The Company rep. joins her and gets too close to a large ovoid organic thing …<br>
Meanwhile, hyped-on-uppers Smithson is having an episode while Fayne tries to hold the crew together. That’s when Arroyo gets an offer from Weyland-Yutani that would solve all her problems … We end on a Mexican stand-off between the tough Fayne, protective Johanson, desperate Arroyo and hyped Smithson … A great pilot episode leaving the network begging for more …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="VfiTPYiK5eM" data-youtube-title="GCOG Alien Dark: Fiorina 161" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-fiorina-161/5054/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-fiorina-161/5054/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 12:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5054-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-fiorina-161/5054.rss">Alien Dark - Fiorina 161</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
