<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392</link>
    <description>So I&#39;ve decided to go ahead with my idea to hack *The Between* to run a Delta Green style Cthulhu game, an idea I discussed on the Discord a little. Posting here will let me keep a more concise log of the design process. I&#39;ve only begun faffing about with the rule set, so this will start of as some disjointed ideas that will (hopefully) coalesce over time into a playable game. The core goal is to explore what Delta Green would look like run with the Brindlewood Bay mystery mechanics, and given the same cinematic/character-focused treatment you get in *The Between.* So to start, some rough ideas about reskinning/hacking bits of *The Between*...

**Hargrave House** - this will get split into a couple of things. First, there will be a home base of some kind that will expand (be explored) as the game progresses. There will also be safe houses, which will double for HH when the team is travelling. I wanted to keep the geographical reach of the game bigger than TB, but I&#39;ll design it as a sliding scale so individual GMs can pick how big they want they game to be.

**The Mastermind** - will play a very similar role, and could be an individual or a Cult-like organization. These Masterminds probably will have supernatural or occult powers.

**Character Occlusion** - this part of the Between fits perfectly and is going to stay. The agents come to the cell as mysteries, holding back their histories and personal lives as bulwarks against the Mythos. As their characters get revealed, and as they use masks, they are using up what is termed Sanity in CoC games. 

**Abilities** - play roughly the same roll. The names may change.

**Janus Mask** - as I mentioned above, this plus the Vulnerable move and Conditions are what will stand in for Sanity. This will take some actual hacking, obviously, but the moving parts are there. The actual mask mechanic won&#39;t change (i.e. standard plus one per threat etc)

**Day - Night cycle** - this will also stay, although I may whack it about a little. Day is for recon and the like, while night is more straight OPs. SO the danger levels stay the same. I may toss in some bits from FitD to make this hum like I want it to in terms of position and effect. I would like to keep &#39;the day&#39; as the basic play unit. If time needs to be elided, for travel say, it can happen outside that framework.

**Playbooks** - one of each per game, and will be designed to cover broad competencies. So have the tech guy, the face, the heavy, that sort of thing. The custom moves will be designed to help cover for the broad range of skill competencies those sorts of characters would have in a CoC game. Essentially, they&#39;ll be good at what they&#39;re supposed to be good at.

**Unscenes** - this is where I&#39;m changing it up. Rather than exploring london, the unscenes will be how the players explore &#39;their&#39; mythos. The probably won&#39;t be connected to the threat at hand, but they will be generally connected to that particular game&#39;s brand of weird. I want each game on this hack to build it&#39;s own mythos, essentially. The unscenes and how the players answer the questions will be how that gets done. Echoes in the Night will work about the same way as it does in the Between, hopefully.

That&#39;s the basics anyway. I&#39;ll have to see how the pieces fall together. I&#39;d to hear everyone&#39;s ideas about how they&#39;d port their favorite bits of Delta Green, or do things completely differently.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 16:28:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>OK, the Legend playbook is in the bag, so back to DG. I’m currently trying to decide when to set the hack. The modern day default involves a lot of computers, which I’m not super keen on having to write rules for, so I was considering a 80’s or more likely 90’s setting.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/28</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 16:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s really cool, thanks for sharing. This hack of mine has been put on the back burner for a bit. I have a Sci-Fi/Horror hack of Trophy Gold that needs to get finished now that I bought art for it, and I got roped into some playbook design for Ghosts of El Paso that I really should finish. Then I’ll be back. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/grinning.png?v=9" title=":grinning:" class="emoji" alt=":grinning:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/27</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 07:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Scott_Beattie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/scott_beattie">@Scott_Beattie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Love it,  I’ve done a PBTA Delta Green which I’m happy for you to take apart and repurpose bits out of, especially on the combination of procedural traits for an agency oriented model.  <a href="https://blackethical.itch.io/aichmophobia" rel="nofollow noopener">https://blackethical.itch.io/aichmophobia</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 04:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I like this tech. I’ve been looking to do a DG game (actually Fall of DG that takes place in the late 60’s early 70’s) that’s not either default DG or Gumshoe. I look forward to your first alpha/beta version.</p>
<p>The Between setting is only lukewarm for me, but the rules sound cool. This DG version seems more in my wheelhouse.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/25</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 04:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In the Between, there is a part of the dusk phase where the players use Paint the Scene Moments to describe Hargrave House one room at a time, so over the course of sessions the picture of that games particular version of HH becomes clearer and clearer. Each room has a prompt or two to help direct things. For example, the prompts for The Reception Hall are:   <em>Do you feel unsettled or at home when you enter Hargrave House? What do you perceive in the reception hall</em>  <em>that reinforces this feeling?</em>  There are 13 rooms in HH that get described in this way, one per Day cycle. This is a small moment in the grand scheme of things, but it adds great flavor to the building that houses the group.</p>
<p>I really wanted to keep something like this in Liminal Dark, but have been struggling to figure out how to do it. I have at last settled on a scaffold that might work for a Delta Green version of HH. I didn’t think that the Cell’s home base would be physically as big as HH, which is a Victorian Mansion, so I had to go a little further than just rooms, so here’s what I cam up with. Instead of rooms there are three different kinds of things that get this Paint the Scene Treatment like HH does.</p>
<p>First, the Office, which is what I’m calling the Cell’s home base (it’s also interchangeable with the phrase Cell to describe the group as whole for which the PCs work). The Office has 5 parts: The Front Company, the Office, the Armoury, the Lab, and Records (or Library). Each of these will have prompts much like the rooms of HH.</p>
<p>Second, Secure Storage, which is the Green Box or whatever your particular flavour of DG calls the place where they store the dangerous shit. Here we won’t be talking about rooms, but rather strange objects. There will be five basic prompts which give a type of object, and the players will take turns filling in details. A very preliminary list of objects would be things like books, specimens, weapons, masks, etc. The players fill in details such as  <em>What is it? What’s unsettling about it? What case is it from? Who worked that case? How did the case resolve?</em> ​</p>
<p>Third, Agency Assets, who are NPCs the occasionally work for the Office. These might be game-useful, but in this instance serve more to exemplify the sorts of people the Office has working for/with them, which in turn helps define what the overall feel of the Cell is. Each NPC gets a series of prompts as well, things like name, specialty, quirks, reputation, and that sort of thing.</p>
<p>The basic cycle is to go Office - Secure Storage - NPC until there are no more prompts, which in this case I’m thinking will be about 5 of each, so 15 Day cycles.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/24</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 19:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A little more granularity on the harm-conditions-masks playloop. My overarching goal here is to keep mechanical additions inside that loop, rather than having negative consequences fall into a completely separate mechanical category or playloop.</p>
<p>So two tracks, one for harm and one for stress, more or less BitD style. You use Stress in-game to push rolls and resist conditions, and recover it using the Vulnerable move (small amounts) and also an after-threat move (a new thing) that clears a larger amount. Harm is taken for bodily harm, either in combat or as a consequence, and will require some kind of basic equipment list, probably listing harm and some basic weapon tags much like MotW. Harm can be healed using the Rest move (new) and also as an after-threat move. Both the harm and stress tracks result in a condition if filled, at which point they clear. The Condition track remains the same as the between, so everything moves toward eventual mask use.</p>
<p>The notion of an After-Threat phase occurred to me as the right design space to add a limited sort of downtime phase to the game. There will be a After-Action report with some attached mechanics, and each character will be able to choose one or two actions from a range. The healing and tress clearing ones comes at the expense of additional training and asset acquisition (just to name a couple of things I thought of). Successful resolution of a threat gives advatage one roll in this phase, while unsuccessful resolution results in disadvantage on one roll, although you won’t be forced to use that second roll.</p>
<p>Unsuccessful threat resolution you say? Why yes, I reply. Delta Green is all about secrecy, and I think this hack needs a cover or secrecy mechanic. When you do things that threaten your cover or operational secrecy, you fill the clock. If the clock fills before you resolve the threat the Agency pulls you out and sends in a rendition team. Sad trombone. I think the clock will be relatively short, maybe six segments, but I also think there will be a move to repair cover, but at the cost of not taking day (some?) Day actions. I need to make sure this doesn’t end up being a death spiral, but I like the idea. It’ll work a lot like Heat in Blades, but without the incarceration bit, and it will add another kind of consequence the GM can use for7-9 and 6- results in some cases.</p>
<p>Anyway, this is what I thought about on my walk home from work today.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 22:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I guess it depends on the mechanic? In the case of this particular game, I probably will explain the connection between the masks and conditions insofar as together those represent the slow erosion of self and mental security that is the result of confronting cosmic horror. Replacing Sanity as a mechanic was one of my goals for the hack and The Between offers a pretty awesome way to to do that.</p>
<p>Unless by intention you meant play loops, which I’m always transparent about. In this case I think players need to know what their choices are when it comes to spending and refreshing resources.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/22</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 11:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One side question out of sheer curiosity (no-one-true-way) : do you explain the “intention behind the mechanics” before the game begins or do you explain mostly the mechanics and let the players experiment with them and discover their meaning ?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/21</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 06:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, I meant the GM inflicts the condition based on fictional positioning or whatever, as a consequence.</p>
<p>Refresh is key, and there’s a little more going on there than just the white room mechanics. The Between  is by design a short run game, specifically designed to play through X threats and 1 Mastermind. Yeah, you can extend but then mostly you need to house rule stuff anyway. I want this hack to be a little more long term campaign-y, so how I set the refresh is critical. I definitely want to keep the Vulnerable move to clear conditions, I think that interacts very well with the 'no real names" aspect of Delta Green play. The character’s history emerges slowly over play. So on the RP side its fabulous.</p>
<p>One option is to also allow the V-Move to clear stress instead of a condition. That likely won’t be enough by itself. The Between connects Vice to the V-Move though, so the idea of indulging a vice took me right to BitD where that is a stress management tool. I need more mechanics there for sure.</p>
<p>In either case I want the fictional details to matter. I don’t dislike mini-games but that’s not what I’m after in this case (or for this hack really). I might not even call it stress, but regardless from a fictional standpoint you’re essentially exchanging position for effect.</p>
<p>Edit: Additionally, I’m also noodling around with the idea of using stress to resist conditions, also somewhat like BitD</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>OK, you seem to have a handle on things here.<br>
I am a bit weary of GM facing mechanics, but in fact I don’t see how conditions are GM facing. Oh, you mean : GM has to think of something to inflict the Condition. Right, that’s easily shared with the whole table.<br>
As with any resource, refresh is important. The tactical choice between Stress and Condition is interesting but it is also very divergent. I mean, it doesn’t mean much for the character and yet it directs their actions… Something I find elegant is : clear the condition by rolling at disadvantage (“playing” the condition) once or twice. So you give this for that and the economy stays within bounds. It’s not the best idea, but in a certain playstyle it’s important that the player embrace the fictional details, while in others resource management is a mini game in itself, and I am not sure what you like best.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m trying to approach this, to start, from a playloop management perspective. I have the Between playloops already, since that’s what I’m hacking, so the decision is when and where to insert new mechanics and whether or not to remove something at the same time. I think, overall, that the result is going to be mostly the addition of mechanics. In the case of stress I’ve moved away from the dark die idea above toward a something like the FitD model.</p>
<p>So the conditions remain the same, but each character has a 5 or 7 pip stress track. a PC can check a box. take a stress, and get advantage on a role. Stress past the boxes checks a mask much like conditions past three. They could still end up with a condition from the role. So conditions end up as the GM facing mechanic while Stress is the player facing one, and the two need to be balanced.</p>
<p>To help with balance I think I’ll expand the Vulnerable move - it keeps it’s condition clearing feature as written, but will also function like Indulging Vice in FitD. Probably Dawn phase you state that indulged your vice last night and roll 2d6, with the roll determining how much stress is cleared (or something like that, the exact roll there isn’t a thing yet). Or, alternatively, just stress reduction have be a different choice of mechanical output for a vulnerable scene. But you can’t clear both a condition and stress in one go, so there’s a choice that matters there.</p>
<p>So the play loop of Conditions - Vulnerable - Mask Use is still in play, but some additional depth.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/18</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, more design space than just 3 conditions then a mask might be in order. I might go with a harm or a corrption track along side conditions. Something… Im looking at a bunch of mechanical options, including the stress system from Alien.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/17</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 16:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree coming up with another condition on the fly is risky. For cognitive lightness, you could name a specific harm category this badness goes to, always the same. Corruption, personal affairs, social pushback, etc. Then whether this jauge communicates with others depends on your thinking.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 08:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just a small note today. I’m hacking away at a push-for-advantage mechanic to use in here. It involves a dark die, like Cthulhu Dark. So you decide to push and roll 2 white d6s and a black d6, You count success as normal for advantage (highest 2 of the 3), but if the black is highest, which is a 1 in 4 chance, there will be additional badness of some kind. The existing mechanics for <em>The Between</em> don’t really suggest an obvious ‘badness’. Piling on another condition isn’t really a good option there IMO, since a condition was already on the table as a part of a roll involving risk. So the trick now is to figure out what widgets I need to add to perhaps make harm a little more granular than it currently is in <em>The Between</em>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 21:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So, some thoughts about conflict and how that may (or may not) influence the design here. After some thinking and pondering I settled on two primary kinds of conflict that will drive the rest of my design choices. This is where, I think anyway, that the impetus to break away from a straight reskin of <em>The Between</em> is going to happen. We’ll see how true that ends up being I suppose. The two main avenues or sites or areas of conflict for the game are going to be, first, the probably losing battle the agents are fighting against the crushing horror of the Dark (read here all the standard Cthulhu bits) but here I’m specifically and completely going to avoid any content related to mental illness. It’ll be more personal than that. Second, there is the conflict between the characters when it comes to ways and means, or, to put that another way, what they’re willing to do to push back against the Dark. So lets get a little more granular about what those two things might look like.</p>
<p>This is ostensibly a Delta Green hack, so the idea of maintaining a fortress of safety in one’s mind, a protective fortress built around the things that really matter to the agent, is going to be key. But the Dark is insidious, it worms it’s way in through the smallest gaps to poison everything the agent holds dear. So, in <em>The Between</em> the characters don’t talk about their pasts and I’m going to take that, and all the mechanical bits that entails, and keep 'em all, and maybe even double down on it in occasionally. Some reskinning and repurposing, but it’ll all be there. The bits that matter most here are conditions, the Vulnerable move, and the masks. Taken all together, those do a good job subbing in for what is, to be honest, a pretty out-of-touch approach in CoC that indexes sanity. I’m going to replace sanity with something more like mental privacy. The reasons the agents put themselves in harm’s way, whether that’s prior experience, loved ones, or whatever. The Vulnerable move will slowly show those reasons to the other players, one onion layer at a time. Conditions and a likely additional mechanic for bonds, will be the threads that connect the agent to those things she holds dear, things that will be poisoned and made dust one at a time by the slow creep if the Dark into their mind. The mechanics here don’t really change that much, but they get wrapped in some very different verbiage, and added in are couple of light mechanical touches that will nudge things in the right direction. The Masks mechanic will get bent toward this teleology, where the Mask of the Past will represent those touchstones the agent wants to protect, while the Mask of the Future will index the approaching doom that is an almost inevitable fate when one deals with the Dark. So as the agent gets and removes conditions, and is forced to use masks to survive certain death, what they value, what they hold sacred will slowly be laid bare.</p>
<p>Moving past this struggle to keep sacred things sacred is the notion that the agents will not always be in agreement about how to go about dealing with the Dark. Here, things get a little more nebulous from a design perspective as there are more balls in the air and I’m less sure which balls will end up being caught. The mechanics in play here, at least to begin the discussion, are the Dawn questions and a variety of bits that factor into the playbook, which I I mentioned in a post above, is going to be a core book with at least two bolt on parts, one for character archetype, and one for the character’s speciality or MOS. A notion that sums up this collection of mechanical widgets is that of the Crooked versus the Straight. Based on Char Gen choices, a character ends up somewhere on that spectrum and, at least I think at this point, probably somewhat specifically one or the other. The Straight are the white knights, agents who will get their hands dirty up to a point, but have very hard lines about certain sorts of things like collateral damage and a range of criminal activities. Crooked characters will be more on the ends justify the means side of things, and generally far more willing to break laws and sacrifice potential innocents in the fight against the Dark. FVrom a mechanical standpoint, this will be reflected in the Dawn questions, the questions answered for XP and advancement. The plan there is to make a range of those questions incompatible between Crooked and Straight characters. The idea is not to invoke or precipitate a full blown PvP blood letting, but rather to provide just enough mechanical heft to get players on both sides of an argument, and for the idea of means and ends to something that not only gets talked about but that actually matters in a mechanical way. The ideal end result here is a team that doesn’t agree about ways and means, but has enough of a common goal for there to be regular give and take on how things get done. I think that provide the right level of frisson.</p>
<p>I don’t actually have my notes for this in front of me. but those are the highlights. Let me know what you think.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/14</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 23:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ok. Moving on in the design process, following some Lumpley priciples. There will be one playbook, the agent, which essentially gives access to the basic moves and some basic equipment and permissions. You’re an agent and you can do agent things. It essentially defines baseline play. Those playbooks will be modified by (I think) at least two things, a character archetype (like Greenhorn etc above) and a specialty, like Hitter or Hacker, that gives access to improvements and modifiers to the basic moves, both in terms of success but perhaps more importantly in terms of results. So sure, any agent can do some light hacking, but the Hacker will get better results and be better suited to tacking really difficult targets. Those specialities will also serve as the basic permission for gear - so there’s base gear that everyone gets, and then you get access to some specific cool stuff because of your role. I may go so far as to also have the specialty influence what sort of contacts you have, at least to start.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/13</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 15:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would indeed think the agents in this hack would be broadly competent in the way you describe. The notion of special moves was to index a specialty, not general training. So sure, anyone can hop on a laptop and do agent stuff, but the tech person (insert better playbook name here) has some room to succeed more often, in different ways, or to a greater degree than everyone else. The idea is not at all to try and pigeonhole a PC into one area. For general tasks, any agent will do, but for a really important tasks, you get the specialist. I like how that impacts spotlight movement.</p>
<p>You do bring up an excellent point though, agents in genre to often index particular character archetypes. The list you provided would also be a great way to differentiate characters. For example, using a Brindlewood model, with one base agent playbook, a player might get to choose and personality type and a specialty to differentiate their PC. That could work very well.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/12</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 16:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@broin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/broin">@broin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>When I’ve run ‘agents’ in the past, I’ve found their skillsets must overlap by necessity. Mulder and Scully both fire guns, drive cars, and can interrogate. GURPS Black Ops was notable for this, where the agents are very competent at everything, and world-class at their specialities.</p>
<p>It might be interesting to divide up playbooks by role in the team (and genre conventions) rather than skills. So you’d have the Wildcard, the Stoic, the Greenhorn, the Cynic, the Cursed.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 14:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m not familiar with it, but it’s on my list now. Thanks!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 23:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sandy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sandy">@Sandy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That sounds good, I’ll be interested to see what you come up with. Have you seen Alun Rees’ Against The Dark Conspiracy? It has a somewhat similar but distinct approach to equipment that might be useful to look at.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 22:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is a question I’m thinking about a lot. My temptation right now is to have different  playbooks for different ‘types’ of agent. My goal there was to have custom moves that cover the main skill set of that agent. That said, the Brindlewood model would do that just fine if it’s only one move, so it’s going to be a process of finding out how much I want or need the functionality of the characters to depend on bespoke playbooks.</p>
<p>Mask of the past is something I’m unsure about. I don’t know that there’s enough juice in the archetypes (as I’m thinking of them now) to make that really hum. It may end up just being an exposition of character background and motivation unconnected to archetype, but I would like it to be punchier than that, so we’ll see.</p>
<p>On a related note, some of my initial thoughts about equipment play in here. I don’t want crunchy extensive lists of equipment, nor do I want the acquisition of equipment to be a core part of game play. I’ll probably make what DG would term ‘common’ equipment auto-add, perhaps limited by one per dawn phase or some such. In the middle we have fairly common but illegal stuff like silencers, false papers, or some kinds of black hat hacking software, and then finally we have very rare or very illegal things like a copy of the Necronomicon or high end military equipment. For the latter two I’m looking at a normal 2d6 roll, with failure, clock ticks, and success as the basic ladder for 6-/7-9/10+. The size of the clocks and magnitude of consequences are what differentiate the two levels.</p>
<p>The reason this plays in here is I was also thinking of connecting the acquisition of certain sorts of gear (and/or services) to the playbooks, or at least some of the playbooks. Your mercenary type is more like to be able to get her hands on a rocket launcher while the face is more likely to be able to get false papers, that sort of thing. If I go that direction it mitigates for multiple playbooks, and the connections those bonuses represent are an opportunity to add colour and people to the agents background (tell us who got you those false papers and why they don’t like you much, etc). I’m also considering that kind of background of connection as part of the consequences - the worse the roll the more problematic the connection will be. So things like on a 6-, you fail to acquire the item and tell us who you contacted and what previous betrayal has made them angry enough to cause you problems down the road.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/8</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 21:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sandy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sandy">@Sandy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I like this idea a lot, and have been thinking of trying something similar.</p>
<p>I’m curious about how you’d handle characters - separate playbooks, or something more like Brindlewood Bay with a basic character sheet with picklists and once defining move to distinguish them? I’m interested because I wonder what the Mask of the Past (or equivalent) would look like - are there fictional archetypes to build them from, the way there are for The Between?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 21:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Reading this panic behaviour list gives me the creeps. Good job !<br>
Letting go (fluids) is common but less “photogenic”.<br>
CW seems appropriate.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/6</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 17:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Fenris-77]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/fenris-77">@Fenris-77</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s a good list. I think the conditions will be a key element in making the hack ‘feel’ right, so I may expand them a little from what’s in the Between.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deodatus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deodatus">@Deodatus</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I have this saved list from somewhere (???), you could turn them into conditions of fear:</p>
<ul>
<li>they can’t speak</li>
<li>they can’t understand speech</li>
<li>they can’t do anything requiring focus (e.g. casting spells, forming an escape plan)</li>
<li>their hands stop working and they drop what they’re holding</li>
<li>they can’t move</li>
<li>they can’t let go of something (a railing, someone’s hand)</li>
<li>they can’t look, or they can’t look away</li>
<li>they shut down completely and their perception is flooded by something trivial (e.g. the smell of their jacket)</li>
<li>they stop breathing out</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7392-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hacking-the-between-for-a-delta-green-style-experience/7392.rss">Hacking The Between for a Delta Green style experience</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
