<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125</link>
    <description>We&#39;ve all had the experience of reading through a shiny new RPG and stumbling across a really cool little mechanic which perfectly encapsulates a genre or has intriguing depth to it or feels really original. What are some examples you&#39;ve seen?

A couple for me:
* In Troika, an OSR game, the order of inventory matters. When trying to retrieve something in a hurry, you have to roll under the item&#39;s position in the list. This makes inventory management, a usually arithmetic staple of the OSR into thinking about item practicality which is cool

* In Dead World, a wild west reskin of Apocalypse World, Open Your Brain is replaced by the following. It perfectly encapsulates the scene of a character showing their personal philosophy to the world, which feels so very western

&gt; When you indulge your vices and your mind is besotted with your particular pleasures (booze, opiates, whores, gambling, violence, righteous anger), you gain revelatory insights amidst all this squallor. Roll+will and pontificate, in brief or in full, about the nature and truth of things. On a hit, the MC will seize on something you’ve said and elaborate on your insight. On a 10+, they’ll straight-up tell you something you hadn’t realized before. On a 7-9, they’ll hint at the answer to something that’s been vexing you. On a miss, some truth will set you free, but not this truth. No, this truth is gonna shove you right back into the mud.

* In Fellowship, a LotR inspired PbtA game, NPC followers are used like resources. They each have a trait or two (e.g. the hunting bird has Eagle Eye and Go For The Eyes) which they can use once per unit of adventure. This allows a companion to be incredibly useful but never outshine the players

* And despite it being old hat, of course I have to mention Apocalypse World&#39;s GM agenda, principles and moves. The idea of formalising the GM&#39;s role and responses is a really cool one.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:52:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I like a lot of mechanics but use very few. Among those I don’t use, I find “rolling under a TN but using the result for effect magnitude” very elegant.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/53">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/53</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 10:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-53</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Dogs in the Vineyard</strong> makes everyone behaves like assholes, even if that wasn’t their intention in the first place.</p>
<p><strong>Don’t Rest Your Head</strong> has some cool subsystems that interact with each other. You can do stuff, but the drawback in the end will come back and haunt you. Desperate choices for the win.</p>
<p><strong>Svart av kval, vit av lust</strong> is what <strong>Vampire: tM</strong> should have been. No dice, only stones, in a collaborative storytelling game, where the Beast in each vampire will try to mess it up for the human side (other participants controls the Beast). To resist the Beast, you take a stone. There are a clear hierarchy, where older vampires will always win over younger vampires. Summoning the Beast, however, can make younger vampires win in a brutal way against the elders, but any participant can take a stone away from a vampire to have their Beast refuse to help them. All in all, this means that younger vampires will walk through a flood of blood if they want to achieve their goals.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/52</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 08:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>FYI.  For anyone interested…</p>
<p><a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/258593/Forbidden-Lands-Core-Game?term=Forbidden+Land" rel="nofollow noopener">Forbidden Lands</a> core rules are free for a few hours more today.</p>
<p>Updated: The sale is over now.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/51</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@HeadOfTheGoat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/headofthegoat">@HeadOfTheGoat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I adore the way <em>Past</em> cards work in Zombie World. Essentially, you get assigned a past, a history, for your character, and that past comes with a perk or special move. Your <em>Past</em> card starts facedown; only you know what it is, but you don’t get that special perk. Everyone starts Zombie World as strangers, and so nobody knows each others’ pasts.</p>
<p>Each <em>Past</em> card also a condition to “unlock” it—some narrative beat you must complete in order to be able to use your special perk. When you have that story moment, you flip your card over and reveal your past, and thus gain the benefits of your <em>Past</em>.</p>
<p>Say, for example, my character is a Priest. The Priest perk is something along the lines of “When you <em>Calm Someone Down</em>, use Soul [interpersonal stat] instead of Steel [nerves/guts stat] while invoking a higher power.” It’s a pretty good perk, in the same way that any of those substitute-X-for-Y-while-Z moves are pretty good.</p>
<p>In order to unlock it, though, I have to fulfill this requirement (ish, I’m paraphrasing): “In a moment of weakness, profess your faith to your another character as a means of finding strength.” And then I flip my card, and the whole table knows I was—or am—a Priest.</p>
<p>The game builds in specific narrative requirements to unlock specific mechanical benefits. Super good design all around.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/50</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 15:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MKAdams]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mkadams">@MKAdams</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="48" data-topic="2125">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jacob_wood/40/2554_2.png" class="avatar"> Jacob_Wood:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>In <em>COntinuum</em> , a time-travelling game, you can reach for just about any item you need and then retroactively declare that you put it there for yourself sometime in the past. For example, you can reach into a planter box and pull out a pistol, which you declare you had stashed there yesterday for just such an occasion.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Ah, a game using the the rarely seen <em>Bill &amp; Ted’s Excellent Adventure</em> rules of time-travel.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/49</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jacob_Wood]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jacob_wood">@Jacob_Wood</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In <em>COntinuum</em>, a time-travelling game, you can reach for just about any item you need and then retroactively declare that you put it there for yourself sometime in the past. For example, you can reach into a planter box and pull out a pistol, which you declare you had stashed there yesterday for just such an occasion.</p>
<p>During character creation in the same game, everyone gets to roll a bunch of dice and multiply by some ludicrous factor to get a hefty amount of wealth. It’s said that you used your time travelling powers to get your one big score and assumes everyone has already done that before the game starts.</p>
<p>In <em>Killshot,</em> a cinematic game where you play as assassins, there’s a really cool initiative mechanic. Each side (players vs. NPCs usually) gets a certain number of actions to use between all members of the team. You can use actions yourself or pass the torch to one of your team members who also pulls from the same action pool (IIRC).</p>
<p>The cool thing though is that if you’re pressing an attack, you can often keep getting actions until you miss. If you miss an attack, the enemy gets to steal the initiative and push back using their own actions.</p>
<p>It’s hard to describe without the rulebook in hand, but the result is a very cinematic combat in which one side keeps punching until they make a mistake, then the other side takes advantage of the opening.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/48</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 12:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MKAdams]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mkadams">@MKAdams</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>HERO System’s <strong>Presence Attack</strong> is best mechanic I’ve ever seen, with the closely related <strong>Characteristic Effect Dice</strong> being a close runner up.  The Presence Attack rules are the most satisfying way I’ve found of mechanizing the disparity between player social skill and character social skill without overly disrupting the pure pleasure of actually role-playing social encounters.</p>
<p>If you’re unfamiliar with the HERO System, characters have six Primary Characteristics (“CHA”), each with a base of 10 and a range of 0 to 20.  The Characteristics are your standard D&amp;D array:  Strength, Dexterity, Constitution, Intelligence, Ego (“Wisdom”), and Presence (“Charisma”).</p>
<p>The attributes are used primarily determine a <strong>Characteristic Roll</strong> ((CHA/5)+9 or less) and <strong>Characteristic Effect</strong> ((CHA/5)d6).  So if a character has a Presence (“PRE”) of 10, then they have a Roll of  11- and an effect of 2d6.</p>
<p>When a character wants to influence another character (an NPC), they can use an PRE-based Interaction skill (which has a base roll equal to their PRE Roll), or they can use a PRE Attack.  To perform a PRE Attack, the player rolls their PRE Effect and compares the result to the target’s PRE.  If the result equals or exceeds their PRE, they are influence.  For every  +10 they beat the target’s PRE, the more profound the effect they have is.</p>
<p>As an example, let’s say Bob (PRE 13, Roll 12-, Effect 2½d6) approaches a woman (PRE 10) at a bar and attempts to flirt with her.  This is a PRE Attack, so he rolls his dice.  He gets an 11.  The woman has a mild, but positive response to his approach, giving him the opportunity to build on his success.  Had he rolled a 9, she’d roll her eyes, grab her drink, and move to another section of the bar.  If he rolled a 40 (a +30 effect, not possible for Bob), then the woman would instantly fall madly in love with him and be unable to live without him  (sometimes you can impress someone a little <em>too</em> much).</p>
<p>There are of course ways to increase you PRE Effect roll – a positive reputation, a striking appearance – and the GM can apply bonuses to the dice for the quality of the player’s narrative, the appropriateness of the act.  For example, the GM might give Bob +2d6 in the above example because the whole reason the woman is sitting at the bar is she’s hoping someone like Bob will approach her, and is thus amenable to being chatted up.  He might apply a -2d6 penalty if Bob tries to chat up a woman while, say, a gunman is shooting up the bar.  Read the situation, Bob.</p>
<p>The reason I love this mechanic so much is that its super easy to integrate it smoothly into role-playing. There’s a natural rhythm to conversations, and generally there are very clear “turning points” where the reaction of the NPC is going to determine the outcome of the interaction.  For example, let’s say the player’s “Party Leader” is talking to a Local Noble Lord, and trying to convince the Lord to render aid.  This could be reduced to a single die roll, a pass/fail skill check, but that’s dull and robs me of the chance to give this Lord any personality.  So instead, we role play the interaction, and whenever the player says something that challenges the Lord’s assumptions and inherent position, I call for a PRE Attack.  This gives me a metric by which I can decide which way the Lord is leaning based on the PC’s argument, without shutting down the RP.  And thus the Lord is either slowly swayed to the PCs position after multiple successes, or hardens his own position after multiple failures.</p>
<p>Related to this is the whole concept of Characteristic Effects.  Every attribute can be turned into dice of effect.  This can be used in so many different ways.  For example, I’ve run sessions where a player and an NPC were both trying to convince a group of scholars of the truth of a proposition – it was a debate over the fundamental nature of dragons, IIRC – and rather than a pass/fail check, I had each character roll the INT Effect, going back and forth, until one or the other passed a benchmark.  This gamifies the debate, creating a sense of excitement and anticipation – will our friend, the PC, shut down his opponent and prove his thesis, or will he be demolished by his opponents superior rhetoric?  Each die roll increasing the tension, until finally resolution.  Likewise, I’ve had players roll DEX Effect to determine how impressive their dancing or a display of weapons skills is.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/47</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 05:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Zombie Cinema</strong>, where you can add dice to a roll to support someone. This is a mechanic for active listening, so you will still be interested in the scene, even if your character isn’t in it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/46</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 05:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Pendragon</strong> mechanic, where what you roll is how good your roll is. Compare this to rolling d20, subtracting what you rolled from your skill value. (Talking BRP, not d20)</p>
<p>Flipping dice, where you roll d100 (with 2d10) and then have the option to flip the number around, from 23 to 32 or 94 to 49. <strong>Warhammer 1ED</strong> flips the dice to see where you hit your opponent.</p>
<p><strong>Unknown Armies</strong>, of course, is using both Pendragon/Blackjack mechanic and flipping dice. A good example of a brilliant rule system.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/45</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 05:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Scariest mechanic:  The central mechanism in Dread is amazing, even if it isn’t always done well.</p>
<p>Best generic mechanic for any game:  advantage / disadvantages to the +1/-1 mechanism</p>
<p>Funniest rpg rule:  In the mini game Clerics (where you play Clerics trying to save your dumbass party run by the GM from themselves), there is a hilarious rule that states, as a cleric you can suggest what the other party members do., in response,  the GM ahould play those characters in the opposite way.</p>
<p>Best PbtA game specific moves:<br>
-Cramped quarters for Uncharted Worlds -  I suspect this predated the Stonetop version to create interparty tension between the action</p>
<p>-Wild Jumps-  This move is So helpful to prevent murder hobos in space And to introduce any random setting or space monsters or hooks into a story.  Characters about to die due to a bad jump?  No problem, rescue them in exchange for a mission to pay off the debt… And easily get the players to buy into the deal!</p>
<p>Comrades - Cradle a dying comrade - if this can’t pull out an emotional response, no PbtA move can.</p>
<p>For one shots -<br>
Tags in Lady Blackbird / Uncanny Echoes<br>
AW 2nd Ed - “love letters” - flashback with mechanics</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/44</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 04:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@noah_t]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/noah_t">@noah_t</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>At the moment, I can’t stop thinking about…</p>
<p>The Arrival’s “Offer someone a cigarette” move in <em>Dream Askew</em>. The themes of scarcity and community, the disparities between the queer enclave and the society intact are folded together so perfectly in those four words.</p>
<p>The way the “Fall in love / Fall out of love” moves are strong or weak moves, depending on a character’s position in the community in <em>Dream Apart.</em></p>
<p>The Discovery Phase in <em>Swords without Master.</em> When there isn’t a clear conflict imperiling the rogues, the game enters the Discovery Phase, and the players take turns describing their characters interacting with new people, discovering new worlds. Then, they ask the GM a loaded question about their discoveries:</p>
<p><em>I know a ship that will take us as far south as we wish. What vile price will the captain ask of us?</em></p>
<p><em>I push open the door to the castle kitchen. What sight causes me to stop dead in tracks, my heart frozen in my chest?</em></p>
<p>You keep discovering new things and asking loaded questions about them until a new conflict appears that propels the rogues to action. It’s a wonderful way for the story to find new directions after the tension has gone out of an action scene.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/43</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 21:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@elStiko]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/elstiko">@elStiko</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I love this, reckon I’ll make six narrow cards which look like logs for the campfire, for players to flip and ask of the player on their left, or something…I’ve never had time for camp scenes and always wanted a mechanic to help me engineer them!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/42</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 05:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>These mechanics are all descended from Apocalypse World’s “workspace” move. It’s a powerful one; some would argue that the workspace move is THE fundamental move in AW (or PbtA games in general), and with good reason. I’m glad to see it being put to use in other games.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/41</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 04:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SamR]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/samr">@SamR</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The games share a designer (Sage Latorra) so I wouldn’t say it’s out of the question. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/40</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 03:55:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@technoskald]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The choices in <strong>This Is All True</strong> look a <em>lot</em> like those in the <strong>Ritual</strong> move for Wizards in Dungeon World. Maybe they had a common ancestor? In any case, I agree that it says really interesting things about the world.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you draw on a place of power to create a magical effect, tell the GM what you’re trying to achieve. Ritual effects are always possible, but the GM will give you one to four of the following conditions:</p>
<ul>
<li>It’s going to take days/weeks/months.</li>
<li>First you must  _______.</li>
<li>You’ll need help from _______.</li>
<li>It will require a lot of money</li>
<li>The best you can do is a lesser version, unreliable and limited</li>
<li>You and your allies will risk danger from   _______.</li>
<li>You’ll have to disenchant  _______ to do it.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/39</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 03:34:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SamR]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/samr">@SamR</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just rediscovered this one, from <em>A Storm Eternal</em>, that I love:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>This Is All True</strong><br>
The rulings laid out here are all true. The Ancients are unknowably powerful. Permanently marked harm can’t be healed. A new age will come. These are all facts.</p>
<p>Until they’re not. At some point a player will want to break the rules. They’ll want to face an ancient as equals, or heal permanent harm, or something stranger. This is all possible, but we don’t know how.</p>
<p>How is up to you. When a player wants to do something that doesn’t seem possible, tell them yes, but (choose one or more):</p>
<ul>
<li>The best they can do is a lesser version</li>
<li>It’ll cost them _______ to do it</li>
<li>They’ll have to gain knowledge of how from _________</li>
<li>First you must _________</li>
<li>You’ll need help from __________</li>
<li>You’ll risk danger from ____________</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>It so elegantly captures the game’s theme of a world that is shifting into a new age, sets up thrilling stories with climactic moments, and maybe even says something deep about the world. Plus it has a meta quality that I find irresistible.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/38</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 21:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SamTung]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/samtung">@SamTung</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The ORE games (Wild Talents, Godlike, Nemesis, Reign) had a great d10 dice pool mechanic to determine where on a the body a character was hit, and had damage categorized into “shock” and “killing” damage.  It was a quick way to get specific damage that might cause varying degrees of problems/drama as opposed to generalized hit points that could be easily healed.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/37</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Two things that come to mind:</p>
<p>(1) In <strong>Stonetop</strong>, there’s a move called <em>Keep Company</em>. The text of the move is:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you spend a stretch of time together (on the road, in camp, etc.) and you or the GM calls for it, take turns asking one of the following questions of a PC or NPC in camp.</p>
<ul>
<li>What do you do that’s annoying/endearing?</li>
<li>What do I do that you find annoying/endearing?</li>
<li>Who or what seems to be on your mind?</li>
<li>What do we find ourselves talking about?</li>
<li>How do you/we pass the time?</li>
<li>What new thing do you reveal about yourself?</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>This move was so good that we’ve essentially ported it to every other party-based game we play. It’s an incredibly effective ways to build interesting relationships and introduce new facts. It’s also a great way to shine the spotlight on folks that haven’t been as active to ensure that every member of the group is protagonized.</p>
<p>(2) Someone previously mentioned <strong>Troika’s</strong> inventory system. <strong>Torchbearer</strong> has something pretty similar (which is where I first saw it): the system makes tracking inventory, light sources, food/water, etc. interesting by giving most player actions an indirect <em>time cost</em>. It blew me away that you could make the kind of bookkeeping that always seemed to slow down D&amp;D feel compelling and interesting, and also use it to make exploring dungeons feel dangerous even when they are deserted.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/36</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 03:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just thinking back, I played a hack of <em>Dream Askew</em> that outlined just how cool the regular moves are. Just having these actions on the sheet, these “you can always do this” things. Because positioning them in the design allows them to be drivers  of narrative. When you do these actions, they’re actions that <em>mean</em> something, so even though you can always do them, you should be thoughtful about when you do them, because they hold power, and you have to think about how you use that power.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/35</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The flashback mechanic in Blades in the Dark. I love playing out intricate plans but I’ve been in games where we’d spend one whole session planning for every two sessions playing and while it can be fun it can also feel like a huge waste of time. (And there I wasn’t even the GM, for whom in my experience long planning sessions are much worse.)</p>
<p>As a GM, I love the monster design and encounter building guidelines in D&amp;D4E. I ran a combat heavy campaign that wen’t to level 14 or so, and with the exception of one or two encounters every single combat I ran was fun, tense, and exciting for the players and fun for me to run as the GM. I never had to worry that I had picked enemies that were too dangerous or that a creature that was supposed to be a tough opponent would be a pushover, because the challenge ratings just work. If I want to give the players a tough fight they will probably win, I can give them that by following the guidelines and then try as hard as I can to beat them with what I’ve got. I never need to hold back or fudge because the balance is already there. It gives me exactly what I want for a combat focused game where tactics and player skill are part of the fun.</p>
<p>I also love the playbooks in Beyond the Wall. I’m not sold on old-school D&amp;D as such, but <em>man</em> those playbooks. They illustrate character archetypes, they give you hooks, they create character connections, and they set up the setting. Yes, this is standard for PbtA games, but with the random tables everything becomes so quick and easy.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/34</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 12:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@stevendj]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stevendj">@stevendj</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I played a game at Origins called Lead and Gold, which had a Dialogue Card system I haven’t seen before. The premise is that we’re five bank robbers holed up in a safe house after a failed heist. Our leader is dead, and one of us tipped off the cops. We have to figure out who and eliminate the rat, or we’re all going to jail. It’s a character-driven set piece, not a deduction game: there’s no way to actually figure out who the rat is (although one player does have a card telling them that they’re the rat). So the game is just a paranoia-fueled conversation in which we all try to ferret out the rat. The twist is that the players all have Dialogue Cards, which we can pass to another player, and the other player has to follow the instructions on the card. (For example, “Insult somebody, then apologize.”) Works really well to keep the conversation going, since even the expectation of a possible lull will prompt people to slide a card to someone. And in the end, of course, the guns come out, and one of us ends up dead—although, in our case, it turned out not to be the rat.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/33</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 01:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jagash]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jagash">@Jagash</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There are so many, brilliant mechanics, but a couple that come to mind…</p>
<p><strong>Dream Askew / Dream Apart</strong> weak moves include a number sub-optimal social decisions that relate to the playbook’s internal conflicts. Showing vulnerability or insecurity might be one character’s weak move, while acting without consideration for other’s might be a different character’s flaw. This expresses fundamental character challenges in a compelling yet subtle way.</p>
<p><strong>Spire</strong> has a delightful fallout system, whereby you slowly accumulate stress during play, and then you roll based on your stress levels to see if it results in fallout. If you do get fallout (which are narrative/mechanical consequences), you reduce your stress. The fact that the fallout increases in severity means there’s a delightful incentive for you to hope that you fail early, and feel an increase of tension if you <em>succeed</em> in avoiding fallout because you know it’s coming. It replicates some of the emotional dynamics of Dread, but with dice.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 12:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Vincent_Eaton]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/vincent_eaton">@Vincent_Eaton</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One of my favorites is the Shiver from Fear move in Bluebeard’s Bride, where if the GM sees that a player is unnerved by what’s going on, they ask the player what they’re afraid of, and then show them how the reality of the situation is so much worse.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/31</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 11:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I really like when tokens gives natural boundaries of rule mechanics or otherwise helps any kind of bookkeeping. I adore how colored paper clips are used in <strong>Deadlands</strong> to mark wounds or keep track of bullets. I tend to use that in almost everything I do. <strong>Shadows over Camelot</strong> uses a normal die to keep track of health points, which gives a natural limit of max 6 HP. I like the notion of rolling to get better, which makes the die cap how high a skill can be raised.</p>
<p>I also like graphic design that clearly tells something, like how the dots on the character sheet on <strong>Vampire the Masquerade</strong> tells, and limits, the players on how good they can be at something. I think the Swedish game <strong>Rotsystem</strong> (rot = root) has circles that you fill in for skills, but later on the circles are split in half and quarters, which tells the players—in an easy way—that it costs more to raise those skills. I also think the design of the character sheet for <strong>D&amp;D4</strong> had some really good design thoughts, merely how they used arrows and plus signs between squares to show, in a clear way, how any kind of calculation is done.</p>
<p>I used that when I designed my own <strong>D&amp;D4</strong> character sheet. Here you can also get an example of how a paper clip can be used:<br>
<aside class="onebox pdf">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://erebaltor.se/rickard/charsheet_4pages_dnd4.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">erebaltor.se</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <a href="https://erebaltor.se/rickard/charsheet_4pages_dnd4.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><span class="pdf-onebox-logo"></span></a>
<h3><a href="https://erebaltor.se/rickard/charsheet_4pages_dnd4.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">charsheet_4pages_dnd4.pdf</a></h3>

<p class="filesize">283.61 KB</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/30</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 10:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m going to combine all these mechanics … to make the best game evah!!!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125/29</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 19:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2125-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-the-best-most-interesting-mechanics-youve-seen/2125.rss">What are the best/most interesting mechanics you&#39;ve seen?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
