<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905</link>
    <description>For me it was GM-ing and managing to surprise a player whose GM-ing I greatly admire.  Hearing him say &#39;Pardon me ... did you say ...&#39; was a real lift.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:47:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Evlyn_M]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was running a cyberpunk game for a friend and he rolled a trans man character, somehow it felt good for me to share him parts of my personal experience when I described him stuff through a trans person point of view. It was the first time this ever happened to me, being able to use my personal experience as a trans person in a RPG game to describe the world. It was not much, just small details there and there but I don’t know, it made the game session more interesting for me. I think that the sci-fi setting helped me a bit to approach this lightly.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/11</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:47:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sam">@Sam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>GMing Blades for a party of two. They get asked by the Gray Cloaks to go hide a spooky “don’t let it touch your skin” artifact in the Billhooks’ lair (a butcher shop), then go back a week later and retrieve it, no questions asked. Crew agrees, and Hix (not normally the planner of the two) immediately has a plan. He walks right in there, asks to use the bathroom, stuffs the artifact down the toilet, and then makes a Wreck roll.</p>
<p>Crits.</p>
<p>So he comes out of the bathroom apologizing profusely, all the Billhooks on site vacate the premises, and they board up the bathroom door. A week later Hix comes back, apologizing again and again, and offers to fix the toilet up for free. They’re not happy to see him but allow it. Rolls himself a Tinker.</p>
<p>Crits.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Arden’s been using all this bathroom time to chat up the head of the Billhooks. Takes him out to a nice Skovlan restaurant, they make out in the alley while they’re waiting on the food, and long story short now he’s one of Arden’s Friends, and the crew is friendly with the Billhooks.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 08:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In my ongoing 5E dungeoncrawl set in “The magical lands of Feary” the party of former wedding caterers, distant “wood fey” cousins and changeling descendants has decided to remake themselves as hardboiled fixers. They have this endearing combination of ruthless pragmatism and utter terrified (admittedly two are ‘rabbitmen’ former bandits) fecklessness.</p>
<p>In this weekend’s session they wrapped up their infiltration of a Redcap briar fortress, using some wild schemes (recruiting giant crow allies, disguising themselves as town militia, overfeeding the giant spider cavalry mounts to make them torpid, poisoning the well, wedging shut the barracks doors) while running about commando style - and amazingly avoiding and distracting patrols - they find themselves face to face with the tower’s lord, their assassination (overreaching - he’s the cousin of their royal patron and they weren’t told to assassinate him, just disrupt his mortal stealing scheme) target.  They’re all ready to go when the Redcap noble predictably grows in size - and keeps growing - suddenly they find themselves facing a giant sized forest spirte made of root burls and dried heartsblood.  The party fires an arrow and spell or two but then just decides to flee.</p>
<p>Pursued by the rallying defenders (somewhat hampered by the party’s past efforts) the adventurers are justifying their change of plans and keep running down the spiral stairs, past the entry level into the caves below the briar.  They manage to get a few doors between themselves and the angry redcaps, the spiderknechts are especially peeved as thier mounts are bloated and unwilling to ride, and decide that rather they need to both escape and burn the entire place down.  The rest of the session was spent creating an elaborate trap involving the fortress booze store and broken furniture, and arguing with a magic postern gate that would only believe logical fallacies. Eventually the party no true Scotsman’s the door open with “You can’t be a real gate, because a real gate must open as well as remain barred” and flees, leaving behind fuse burning to the wine cellar.</p>
<p>They also didn’t steal anything valuable - they were so into their self imposed commando mission and didn’t want to risk theft being noticed, so no XP.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 07:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AviatrixCat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/aviatrixcat">@AviatrixCat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Running Lady Blackbird, and Vance heads the Owl to Nightport to meet his ex-wife, who wanted him to leave the Empire years ago when he didn’t want to, but was so done with him that when he went renegade she had no use for him. I grab the name list and come up with Jezebel as just the right name for her. Vance’s player says she’s in the Crimson Sky pirates.</p>
<p>So they hit Nightport and Vance goes to a bar and orders the drink that’s actually a code word. “Love to serve that to you,” says the barkeep, “But things are quiet now. One of the capos opened up a nightclub, and now Everybody goes to Jezzies’.”</p>
<p>What follows is twenty minutes of me riffing on a Lady Blackbird-style Rick’s Cafe Americain, down to a guy named Ugarte selling a possible imperial navigation document into the scatters, a goblin harpsichordist named Samel, and Jezzie’s entry line: “Of all the skytch saloons and all the gin joints in the Wild Blue, you had to walk into mine.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/8</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 20:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@stevendj]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stevendj">@stevendj</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In The Spectaculars, our support group/neighborhood watch tracked a group of bank robbers to their warehouse hideout. Our top priority is not to get the cops involved, so we decide to approach openly, carrying bags of take-out, and see if we can peacefully resolve the situation through talk. The metas invite us in, my teen hero Spÿwn flies down dramatically from a nearby rooftop with his costume billowing gently, flashing finger-guns at their lookout, and immediately asks Timberwolf, the one with a cool cybernetic wolf companion, for a selfie. GM describes how she sighs and strikes a pose with the wolf. “Great. I immediately tweet that out.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/7</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 18:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Silva]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/silva">@Silva</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Playing Undying.</p>
<p>We (three players) spent the whole night scheming against the Princeps to overthrow him. We had everything planned - who would be new the Princeps, new Patricians, the new hunting grounds division, etc.</p>
<p>On the final showdown we have the Princeps and his pawns cornered. The win seems guaranteed. Every player put firsts forward with hidden amounts of Blood wagered to the fight (GM included, representing the Princeps). Then, at the GM signal, everybody opens it up simulataneously. We add the values and it’s an easy win for us.</p>
<p>Except…</p>
<p>One player wagers on the Princeps side, describing his character turning on us in the fight. A betrayer. He turned sides at the last moment, it seems. We lost the fight, the two losing players (me included) becoming Pariahs.</p>
<p>It came so out of nowhere, and in the right timing, that it was marvelous. Even the GM was taken completely by surprise. One of the best sessions we had ever for sure.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/6</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 18:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was running a <em>Monster of the Week</em> one shot recently, and one of the players was playing the Divine and had chosen the following Mission:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The  End  of  Days  approaches.  Your  role  is  to  guide  these hunters and ensure it comes to pass.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I couldn’t pass this up, so it turned out the underground lair of the Monster (an ancient wolf spirit and its werewolf children) contained one of the seals of the Apocalypse.</p>
<p>We ended up in a three way stand off between the Divine (who wanted to open the seal), the monster (who wanted to destroy everyone who had seen the seal), and the hunters, who just wanted to get out of the situation.</p>
<p>Everyone had a great time and it made me wish that I was local so we could keep going with this story.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 17:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Nickwedig]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/nickwedig">@Nickwedig</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We made characters for a game of Sig, and the players have a duty to pair up and create NPCs for me (the GM) to pay. I have a large group of people, and it’s noisy, so I mostly help the players nearby figure out their NPC, then work around to the far side of the table.</p>
<p>The first ones are fine: He’s a talking frog that’s the captain of the city watch. Cool. And a fire elemental priest of sorrow, and a paranoid librarian. All pretty typical for how the game works.</p>
<p>Then we get to Blarrk. Blarrk is a giant flying tumor with hundreds of eyes. Once every hour, he shouts prophecies and unwelcome truths in the town square. They couldn’t decide if Blarrk had one huge shouty mouth, or one thousand tiny whispering mouths, so they rolled a die. (They got one big shouty mouth.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 14:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We’re playing Basic D&amp;D and these crystal karate robot dudes who have been harassing our settlement ask to parley. “I should go,” my guy says, “I’m the leader of the settlement and I have the highest charisma among us.” Someone points out that we have all used charisma as a dump stat, but it is agreed that I will go parley. I can be diplomatic, I promise.</p>
<p>Our tense delegations meet. It’s time for subtlety, diplomacy, give-and-take. “Stop harassing us or we will murder every last one of you and turn you into jewelry” I say.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 13:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Well I was playing a dark ages England game recently!</p>
<p>As the town came under attack my vengeful warrior dude jumped down on the enemies battering ram and roared at them, it was stupidly heroic (which was great since I mostly MC I haven’t got to be a heroic player for some time)</p>
<p>I fully expected some beefy warrior to kick my butt but my gambit paid off, one of my comrades did some keen arrow shots to show these dogs whom they were messing with <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 10:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For me it was GM-ing and managing to surprise a player whose GM-ing I greatly admire.  Hearing him say ‘Pardon me … did you say …’ was a real lift.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 09:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2905-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/most-enjoyable-moment-in-a-recent-game/2905.rss">Most enjoyable moment in a recent game</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
