<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Troika! Cardo y Blancmange [One-Shot in Spanish]</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/troika-cardo-y-blancmange-one-shot-in-spanish/8515</link>
    <description>![Troika! Cardo y Blancmange](upload://8w3aPMuMYMqzqLeX0rg9FTOhmXz.jpeg) 

**Information in english can be found further down.**

Este es un One-Shot de **Troika!** un juego que combina ciencia ficción y fantasía en un multiverso lleno de situaciones extrañas y a veces absurdas. En esta sesión vamos a explorar el famoso hotel *Cardo y Blancmange* , un lujoso hotel en el centro de la ciudad de Troika, que tiene su festival anual el *Festín de la Quiliarca* un evento que simplemente no te puedes perder.

Este juego está orientado la comunidad hispanoparlante de The Gauntlet, tanto nativos como hablantes de español como segundo lenguaje, para quienes puede ser una buena oportunidad para practicar.

The Blancmange &amp; Thistle es la aventura incluida con Troika Numinous Edition y un punto excelente para conocer el juego. Durante la sesión generaremos personajes y cubriremos la mayor parte de las reglas básicas.

Contenido: violencia, criaturas extrañas e insectos gigantes, alcohol y sustancias.

Un lugar está reservado. Vamos a usar Google Meet para las sesiones. Le voy a escribir a les participantes con los links necesarios. La sesión va a durar un máximo de tres horas. Me gustaría grabar la sesión y voy a confirmar con les participantes al inicio y final de la sesión. El [Código de Conducta de The Gauntlet](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) será empleado, así como las herramientas de seguridad Lines &amp; Veils y X-card.

-------------------------------

This a One-Shot for **Troika!** a science-fantasy game set in a multiverse of weird and even absurdist situations. In this session we will explore the famous *Blancmange &amp; Thistle* , a luxurious hotel in the center of the city of Troika, that is hosting their annual *Feast of the Chiliarch* and you simply must attend the party!

This game is aimed at the spanish speaking Gauntlet community, both native speakers and spanish as a second language, could be a good opportunity to practice.

The Blancmange &amp; Thistle is the adventure included with Troika Numinous Edition and it&#39;s an excellent starting point to get familiar with the game. During the session we will generate characters and go through most of the basic rules.

Content: violence, weird creatures and gigantic insects, alcohol and other substances.

A seat is being saved. We will be using Google Meet for the sessions. I&#39;ll be writing participants a week ahead of the game with pertinent links. The session will last a maximum of three hours. I would like to record the session but I&#39;ll confirm at the start and ending of the session. The [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in play, together with Lines &amp; Veils and X-Card as safety tools.

[date=2023-01-19 time=19:00:00  format=&quot;LLLL&quot; timezone=&quot;America/Mexico_City&quot;] → [date=2023-01-19 time=22:00:00  format=&quot;LLLL&quot; timezone=&quot;America/Mexico_City&quot;] [One-Shot](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NIhxK87H2fxJutzUmAH)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 19:05:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/troika-cardo-y-blancmange-one-shot-in-spanish/8515.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Troika! Cardo y Blancmange [One-Shot in Spanish]</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@darkade]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/darkade">@darkade</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/3bb0e61a02ce0949825004aa2bba42bf37dceb3d.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/8w3aPMuMYMqzqLeX0rg9FTOhmXz.jpeg?dl=1" title="Troika! Cardo y Blancmange" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/3/3bb0e61a02ce0949825004aa2bba42bf37dceb3d.jpeg" alt="Troika! Cardo y Blancmange" data-base62-sha1="8w3aPMuMYMqzqLeX0rg9FTOhmXz" width="690" height="388" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/3/3bb0e61a02ce0949825004aa2bba42bf37dceb3d_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Troika! Cardo y Blancmange</span><span class="informations">800×450 231 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
<p><strong>Information in english can be found further down.</strong></p>
<p>Este es un One-Shot de <strong>Troika!</strong> un juego que combina ciencia ficción y fantasía en un multiverso lleno de situaciones extrañas y a veces absurdas. En esta sesión vamos a explorar el famoso hotel <em>Cardo y Blancmange</em> , un lujoso hotel en el centro de la ciudad de Troika, que tiene su festival anual el <em>Festín de la Quiliarca</em> un evento que simplemente no te puedes perder.</p>
<p>Este juego está orientado la comunidad hispanoparlante de The Gauntlet, tanto nativos como hablantes de español como segundo lenguaje, para quienes puede ser una buena oportunidad para practicar.</p>
<p>The Blancmange &amp; Thistle es la aventura incluida con Troika Numinous Edition y un punto excelente para conocer el juego. Durante la sesión generaremos personajes y cubriremos la mayor parte de las reglas básicas.</p>
<p>Contenido: violencia, criaturas extrañas e insectos gigantes, alcohol y sustancias.</p>
<p>Un lugar está reservado. Vamos a usar Google Meet para las sesiones. Le voy a escribir a les participantes con los links necesarios. La sesión va a durar un máximo de tres horas. Me gustaría grabar la sesión y voy a confirmar con les participantes al inicio y final de la sesión. El <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Código de Conducta de The Gauntlet</a> será empleado, así como las herramientas de seguridad Lines &amp; Veils y X-card.</p>
<hr>
<p>This a One-Shot for <strong>Troika!</strong> a science-fantasy game set in a multiverse of weird and even absurdist situations. In this session we will explore the famous <em>Blancmange &amp; Thistle</em> , a luxurious hotel in the center of the city of Troika, that is hosting their annual <em>Feast of the Chiliarch</em> and you simply must attend the party!</p>
<p>This game is aimed at the spanish speaking Gauntlet community, both native speakers and spanish as a second language, could be a good opportunity to practice.</p>
<p>The Blancmange &amp; Thistle is the adventure included with Troika Numinous Edition and it’s an excellent starting point to get familiar with the game. During the session we will generate characters and go through most of the basic rules.</p>
<p>Content: violence, weird creatures and gigantic insects, alcohol and other substances.</p>
<p>A seat is being saved. We will be using Google Meet for the sessions. I’ll be writing participants a week ahead of the game with pertinent links. The session will last a maximum of three hours. I would like to record the session but I’ll confirm at the start and ending of the session. The <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> will be in play, together with Lines &amp; Veils and X-Card as safety tools.</p>
<p><span data-date="2023-01-19" data-time="19:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="America/Mexico_City" data-email-preview="2023-01-20T01:00:00Z UTC">Friday, January 20, 2023 1:00 AM</span> → <span data-date="2023-01-19" data-time="22:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="America/Mexico_City" data-email-preview="2023-01-20T04:00:00Z UTC">Friday, January 20, 2023 4:00 AM</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NIhxK87H2fxJutzUmAH" rel="nofollow noopener">One-Shot</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/troika-cardo-y-blancmange-one-shot-in-spanish/8515/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/troika-cardo-y-blancmange-one-shot-in-spanish/8515/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 19:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8515-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/troika-cardo-y-blancmange-one-shot-in-spanish/8515.rss">Troika! Cardo y Blancmange [One-Shot in Spanish]</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
