<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581</link>
    <description>I have noticed something interesting after listening to the [Death on Reik Fear of Black Dragon episode](https://discourse.funtimers.club/t/fear-of-a-black-dragon-death-on-the-reik-part-1/1575). @jasoncordova mentioned that the module feels very *pastoral*, which I understood means it was unlike the OSR feel he is used to.

Now, I have grown up on Death on Reik and Warhammer Fantasy Roleplay 1ed in general, so this is pretty much my old school gaming experience. When I stumbled upon OSR as a movement somewhere in early 2000s I understood it through this lens. When I read new OSR materials I run them in a similar manner, very mundane and grimdark. I often cut out combat encounters so the game would not be that combat focused. I mean, there is still magic and monsters, but they are the exception rather than a rule...

What I am getting at is that I think I was not running the same OSR as people who have grown up with D&amp;D. The themes are similar, but the overall feel of the game might be different. I find it really curious.

So here&#39;s my question to you - what do you understand by OSR? How do you play/run such games? Let&#39;s skip mechanics here and focus on themes and &quot;feel.&quot; Is your OSR about heroes saving the day (even if they are not super powered like in contemporary D&amp;D)? Is it vagabonds wandering from place to place in a more pastoral manner, stumbling upon adventure while knee deep in mud? Maybe it is something else? 

It would also be great if you shared what was your first RPG system, and maybe where are you from (country is plenty if you don&#39;t want to share personal info)... I sense some correlation here.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 03:34:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bryan_Mullins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bryan_mullins">@Bryan_Mullins</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/diyanddragons">@diyanddragons</a><br>
What’s at least a little funny, for me. Is that MY OSR is…and will continue to be people like you.</p>
<p>Along the way, I met these amazing peoples. The “scene” for me will always be these unique people good and bad.</p>
<p>But my memory of it … my story about it will be of the time I’ve spent reading your blog posts or interacting with you in various spots. Camaraderie like playing games with Gus &amp; Ram, or <em>HOURS and HOURS</em> of listening to Jason while driving or mowing or washing dishes. Or that time that Stewart made a Rainbow OSR logo.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/56">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/56</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 03:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-56</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@diyanddragons]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/diyanddragons">@diyanddragons</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve been very on the fence about “Voice” vs “Exit” as responses to developments I don’t like within the OSR. As <a class="mention" href="/u/humza_k">@Humza_K</a> says above, ask me again in a week and I might have a different answer. But lately every new development in OSR-land pushes me more toward “Exit”.</p>
<p>I mean, I’m not leaving my blog, or quitting Gauntlet (in fact I’m glad I joined), and I’m still interested in “old school style” rules and adventures, but I think recently my ambivalence toward “the OSR” has turned to rejection, and at the moment, I’m not sure what it would take for me to go back.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/55">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/55</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 22:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-55</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My experience with SWORDDREAM was that it’s its own thing, seemingly devoted to rules lite experimentation and with some anti-D&amp;D bias.  I support its efforts, but  it is not a place I feel comfortable, and I don’t want to intrude on someone else’s thing.</p>
<p>All in all I am likely just nostalgic, at my age the nostalgia comes pretty easily.  It is also likely that I am just not part of the more community minded TTRPG places.</p>
<p>Now 5E I can talk about at length (after running it for 6months).  It can be bent towards the playstyle I like, location based, exploration and resource management … but … it pushes back. Fiercely. The sharp power curve is hard to wrestle with and the combat in it is designed to increase in complexity and importance with level.  Worse the combat is weighted towards discrete encounters and isn’t very ‘swingy’, making it hard to get through a combat without the PCs being worn down and in need of retreat/rest.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/54">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/54</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 20:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-54</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Totally fair!  I was just pointing out that the label OSR was not originally and is not to most gamers new to the hobby or OSR, considered political.  My  example is that you use the acronym frequently, so it at least is often used without the context of toxic right wing associates. You have no argument from me that associating with a creep and his ilk is unpleasant.  I just think the term is more broad.  Apparently, I missed the period in gaming when OSR became associated with extreme right-wing politics.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/53">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/53</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 18:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-53</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Humza_K]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/humza_k">@Humza_K</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <ol>
<li>
<p>I completely agree with <a class="mention" href="/u/diyanddragons">@diyanddragons</a> re: what I <em>don’t</em> want to see in my gaming spaces.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I think that <a class="mention" href="/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> is correct re the scattered feeling that’s hitting almost all the OSR spaces, with a few exceptions (that unfortunately tend towards the spaces I’m least interested in).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I don’t think that the situation is hopeless for creating spaces and scenes discussing our particular blends of trad gaming, though. The SWORD DREAM discussion is still pretty early, but there <em>are</em> people latching on and working in those spaces - including new people who haven’t been part of the scene before! (And as Anne notes, many of those jams are 100% creative interchange and open documents for people.)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>I also see existing non-shitty creators gearing up to continue to make good stuff. Melsonian Arts Council is going strong – I think Troika and Luka’s SEACAT are going to be pretty solid breakout systems – and there are new folks coming in and taking their first steps into the design space.</p>
<p>The commercial aspect is still there, but there continue to be pushes back against that, community creation events, and the like.</p>
<p>Shit’s wobbly, and there’s lots of work to be done, but I think there’s still some hope.*</p>
<p>*Of course, this feeling fluctuates. Talk to me in a week and I might be “fuck it burn it all down,” ngl.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/52</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasoncordova]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasoncordova">@jasoncordova</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just diving in real quick to say I don’t get into conversations like this. They always end badly for me!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/51</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@diyanddragons]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/diyanddragons">@diyanddragons</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I understand what you mean about missing the feeling of there being a “community” or “scene” that one could belong to. As <a class="mention" href="/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> mentions, Sword Dream might offer one such place, but at the moment it feels more like “a thing I have heard of” than “a thing I am participating in.” Then again, that might be as simple as writing an “I am in Sword Dream now” post on my blog.</p>
<p>I think there is still quite a bit of free sharing going on. Maybe less than the time you’re thinking of? Most of the pdfs on most of the <a href="http://Itch.io" rel="nofollow noopener">Itch.io</a> “jams” I’ve seen have been free or pwyw, they’re just being hosted on <a href="http://itch.io" rel="nofollow noopener">itch.io</a> rather than being hosted directly on anyone’s blog.</p>
<p>In terms of running the kind of resource-focused, exploration-focused games you’re interested in, I can tell that 5e isn’t perfect, but it seems like not so far off either. The exhaustion and rest mechanics, in particular, seem like additions to 5e that actually facilitate resource management during exploration.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/50</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:42:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>To be fair, was not asking about the politics of OSR, which many of us outside publishing no little about. As such, I think it would be nice to consider this thread not a loaded question, which is what the forum requests.</p>
<p>On a side note, if <a class="mention" href="/u/jasoncordova">@jasoncordova</a>  is using the term OSR all over his Fear of Black Dragon podcast. I don’t think the acronym is fully political.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/49</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 16:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@funkaoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/funkaoshi">@funkaoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think people are too quick to cede something they helped build. The OSR is a lot of things and a lot of people. Everyone people are complaining about now were also loud and active from what feels like the early days of the scene. I think you can choose to shrug your shoulders and move somewhere else—which to be fair is totally valid. Sometimes you don’t want to bother with reforming anything. Or you don’t want to be adjacent to stupid people. Who has time for that? But! You can also be loud and try and make space for the people you like. Which has been my tack this whole time. Why give up the thing you like to fucking Pundit or whomever else?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/48</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 15:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m with you 100% Anne, though that might not be good company, and it’s very disheartening seeing something one has given time and creative energy to sort of rot away - though I suppose one could say that about my country and profession currently as well.</p>
<p>I’m not sure what the post-OSR looks like, or if one even needs it. It’d be nice to feel a kinship and community, and it’d be nice to offer up a project or two to one. At the same time I can play my campaign around my kitchen table and discover how 5E just won’t quite work without the YDIS lads and all the other citizens of the internet raising my gorge. Wandering about the ruins one notices a same sort of loneliness in most of the former “OSR” scenes and places: fracture, disconnection and a dying away of mutuality.  So I don’t think it’s just you or I feeling a sense of exile - I think the worst people of the OSR are feeling scattered as well.</p>
<p>One of the things that made 2011 - 2015 old-school blogging and online play good was the way that creators shared and built off each other while cheering one another’s projects without taking things too seriously.  So much now is about publishing and locking down specifics and ideas under one’s name and brand.  Every 2 page mini-game gets published and every little hack is another game.</p>
<p>I don’t know how the frission and guarded nature of the current classic game space can be remedied, while making it welcoming for people who aren’t middle-aged white guys, but if you want to figure it out I will cheer you on even if I’m too curmudgeonly to build any sort of community myself.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/47</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 14:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Love the evocative name, completely disagree with the ethos being proposed. I don’t think it’s <em>bad philosophy</em>, but if you want to create a movement meant to separate and allow others to move on from OSR, you can’t pitch the baby out with the bathwater (although a more appropriate analogy from what I read is the author wants to trash bathtubs altogether). Yes, there is inherent danger in creating ingroup/outgroup mentality when you create a “community”, but it’s a little self defeating to say “here’s this new movement, nobody runs it, don’t brand it, don’t exclude people from it”. That’s not a movement, that’s just a label you can give people you approve of.</p>
<p>I don’t want to sound like I’m harshing the vibes, I really like the actual genre SWORD DREAMS espouses, but I don’t think aggressively resisting community is the way to actually make it stick.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/46</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 13:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@technoskald]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="44" data-topic="1581">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/radmad/40/2161_2.png" class="avatar"> Radmad:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Maybe it would be prudent to create a separation from what OSR represents right now,</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is effectively what SWORD DREAM is. See for example <a href="https://graverobbersguide.blogspot.com/2019/06/a-sword-dream.html" rel="nofollow noopener">this post</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/45</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 11:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Labels and identity are important for creating a philosophy/group to engage with. Maybe it would be prudent to create a separation from what OSR represents right now, something like “Classic Revival” or “New Players Old Games” to rally around both as a more welcoming title (I get what “OSR” is trying to evoke but hey, that’s loaded language for a lot of people) and as an escape avenue for people who like OSR principles but not OSR people.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/44</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 10:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@diyanddragons]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/diyanddragons">@diyanddragons</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m not sure what “my OSR” is right now. I feel utterly alienated from what I think of as “the OSR”, but I’m not sure what or whom that leaves me with. Maybe Sword*Dream?</p>
<p>Let me stipulate that I know there is no “the” anything, that every group contains multiple factions competing to be the ones who get to offer the more official definition. But my impression of which faction is currently “winning” leaves me wanting absolutely no part of the OSR right now.</p>
<p>I don’t want to participate in a debate about whether Gygax or Arenson was better and/or more important, nor about which surviving friend, family member, or original player is the most legitimate inheritor of their glory.</p>
<p>I don’t want to play a game written by a self-described “supervillain” fascist, nor do I want to listen to people who’ll tell me that I ought to ignore the author’s fascism, or that “reaching across the aisle” to shake hands with fascists is the correct way to have a properly “civil discourse”. I don’t want to be told that any attempts to depict real-world diversity in a gameworld is an unwarranted intrusion of “politics into gaming”, nor do I want to listen to the self-described champions of “free speech” whose primary action in supposed-defense of this freedom is trying to silence anyone who criticizes them.</p>
<p>I’m not interested in talking about how much fun it is to play games by an artist who harassed dozens of people online and still managed to have an online persona that was less bad than the truth about his offline behavior. I’m not interested in trying to preserve the legacy of the publisher who gave that artist his biggest platform before, and who continues to flirt with supporting him even today. I get no enjoyment talking to people who still seem to be repeating the artist’s pet ideas and theories, or who appear to me to be trying to carry on his vision for the OSR even in his absence.</p>
<p>Those, to me eye, are the biggest or most vocal or currently most successful of the factions claiming to represent the OSR.</p>
<p>One thing all this has done is massively increased my interest in people and games that fall outside those three groups. Finding time to learn and play them has been a challenge. But I’d rather do something new and different (even if the people doing it are also calling themselves OSR) than continue with what’s gone before.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/43</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 05:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<ol>
<li>The use of random tables and systems to generate unexpected scenarios</li>
<li>Emphasis on player exploration, discovery, problem-solving</li>
<li>Space for GMs to come up with their own consistent sets of rules/mechanics/rulings</li>
<li>Experimenting with system design to accomplish the above</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
<p>I agree wholeheartedly.   I suspect my OSR would be Beyond the Wall and Other Adventures…if I could get it to the table.</p>
<p>It’s odd because I always think of D&amp;D derivatives first but actually the OSR I play often now is Mothership.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/42</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 04:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>When I was around 12 some family friends gave me a copy of the 1st edition Dungeon Master’s Guide. I knew I was interested in D&amp;D but didn’t know anyone who played it, and didn’t have access to anyone who did (the internet wasn’t really a thing yet). I ended up being fascinated by it and attempted to “reverse-engineer” how to play D&amp;D without a Player’s Handbook (which meant a lot of crucial information was either incomplete or missing). I ended up running some games using my own AD&amp;D “reconstruction” before finally getting my hands on a 2nd edition Player’s Handbook and moving to a more traditional RPG experience.</p>
<p>The aspects of classic play (or old-school play or OSR) that resonate with me are:</p>
<ol>
<li>The use of random tables and systems to generate unexpected scenarios</li>
<li>Emphasis on player exploration, discovery, problem-solving</li>
<li>Space for GMs to come up with their own consistent sets of rules/mechanics/rulings</li>
<li>Experimenting with system design to accomplish the above</li>
</ol>
<p>I was never part of the G+ group nor ever in any of those scenes, but I do enjoy collecting and reading old modules, manuals, etc. from the late 70’s into the late 80’s. Apart from a historical interest, many of these old games are sources of inspiration and interesting ideas.</p>
<p>(I should add that I agree with those that have critiqued “OSR” as being politically or socially reactionary – it’s one of the reasons I don’t strongly identify with it.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/41</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 18:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>OSR is a label for something that I feel like I should attach myself to, but I can’t.</p>
<p>I started playing with the Mentzer Basic D&amp;D red box and Keep on the Borderlands. Unlike a lot of people in 1981, I didn’t learn by watching others play. I read the rules, figured out what worked, and DMed for a couple years before interacting with anyone who had played the game before. I “advanced” to AD&amp;D and started down a path of deep interpretation of the rules that would make a tax lawyer self-conscious. I combed through Dragon articles and advice books by Gygax for wisdom handed down from on-high.</p>
<p>And yet, my games made me unhappy.</p>
<p>I found the Forge about 20 years later and it rocked my world. I drifted away from D&amp;D but never entirely. I played every edition that came out. The Forge and Story Games taught me new ways to look at game play and game design. I played new kinds of games and learned new techniques from them.</p>
<p>Eventually, I took those techniques back to “traditional” games. I started playing story games less and started playing a lot more D&amp;D and Traveller. I started running 1981 Basic D&amp;D and Keep on the Borderlands at least once a year at conventions, faithfully to the rules, but informed by story game techniques to fill in the gaps.</p>
<p>The OSR movement took hold somewhere in there and I dug into it with deep interest. I was fascinated by its ability to take rules that were sitting on my shelf and smooth out the rough edges for me. Don’t like Descending Armor Class or no cleric spells at 1st level? There’s a ruleset that fixes that – maybe not in the same book though. I saw that folks had the same issues with the old rules that I had.</p>
<p>I originally approached OSR with a sense of nostalgia but quickly realized that there was no going back. I knew too much. I had embarked on the Hero’s Journey, crossed the threshold, and had become a different person. Also, I gained new respect for the old rules as they were. I didn’t need Labyrinth Lord; I had Mentzer Basic and it was just fine.</p>
<p>I’ve definitely embraced the OSR pathos in the Traveller world. When Mongoose locked down the Mongoose Traveller 1st Edition Open Game License and trademark stuff, a lot of publishers (not me) got the shaft, so they created Cepheus Engine so they could continue to publish their games. That ruleset inspired me to create my own CE stuff very much in the OSR vein.</p>
<p>In the D&amp;D universe, I’m still fascinated by the OSR but pretty turned off by the wave of gonzo in it. Also, I tend to hate <em>dungeons</em>, murder hobos, and the stench of colonialism. I also like slightly more complicated rulesets than OSR games often champion. I often feel like an outsider to fantasy OSR stuff, like it’s <em>not for me</em>. At the same time, the story games community (in general) isn’t producing games that really hit my sweet spot with a combination of rules complexity and long-term “campaign” play.</p>
<p>I guess there’s no “my OSR” for me.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/40</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 16:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I definitely could have been more clear. Sorry about that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/39</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 16:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@funkaoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/funkaoshi">@funkaoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>No worries. I’m probably reading too much into your post!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/38</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 16:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I didn’t call the OSR playstyle rubbish. What I played in middle school is absolutely NOT “OSR” – which is why I don’t have an OSR of my own.  Believe me, if you saw what I did with D&amp;D when I was 12, you’d call it rubbish too. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Apologies if that is out of place here.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/37</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@technoskald]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>When I see the term “OSR,” I interpret it in my mind as “broadly focused on emulating 0E/1E D&amp;D”. That’s still a spectrum, including folks who enjoy detailed exegesis of the original writings through games that try to examine what it looks like to take modern game design ideas and apply them back to those old rulesets.</p>
<p>In 2019, it’s <em>also</em> something of a code word for a community of grognards that are often (but certainly not always) a bit reactionary or even regressive. To be sure, the games themselves aren’t necessarily - or at least, not any more so than D&amp;D still has problems in need of decolonization. I think that’s why the semi-tongue-in-cheek label “SWORD DREAM” has come up, or at least the focus on “DIY D&amp;D”.</p>
<p>In my individual case, having been a teenager in the late 80s and early 90s in a conservative evangelical family, D&amp;D was pretty well ruled out very quickly when we tried to play AD&amp;D. Burned books, threats of shunning, etc. So we played GURPS and MegaTraveller and Avalon Hill wargames instead. Oddly enough, now I remember very little about how those games work. But we also tried designing our own games back then, and the idea that I don’t have to accept whatever some publisher gives me as the only way to play is what I still love when I think about DIY RPGs.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/36</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m really happy with most of the Sine Nomine, Kevin Crawford stuff I’ve bought. I’ve run a bunch of <em>Godbound</em> and I think it’s excellent fun. My other OSR experience has been MCC &amp; DCC which I found to be a mixed bag. I will say, having played the OS games back in the 1970’s, I like most of the OSR versions better because you don’t have to wonder if there’s actually rules you can play from in there.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/35</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@funkaoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/funkaoshi">@funkaoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If you don’t have an “OSR”, commenting in a thread asking people what their OSR is about seems pretty obnoxious. I think calling the play style rubbish and suggesting it’s predicated on nostalgia isn’t the best. There is certainly some part of the OSR most interested in trying to recapture how AD&amp;D should be played from first principles, but there is much more going on in the scene—as you note.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/34</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oh, it’s definitely a good idea for the OSR to have a term for itself, I just wish it had chosen a different one, that’s all.  I’m not attacking the style or the people, and maybe “secret handshake” is too dismissive – I just meant that it’s not descriptive in any sort of way.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/33</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 15:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s your OSR?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JasonT]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasont">@JasonT</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I hear you. I’m one of those players for whom the “old school” part doesn’t really mean anything—by the time I first played D&amp;D, it was already into its second  <em>“Advanced”</em>  edition (so fancy!), which was already more complex, mired in tradition, and user-unfriendly than I was really fond of. (Who on Earth thought the term “non-weapon proficiency” made more sense than just saying “skill”?) I honestly don’t even know how much of the modern OSR is really based on early play styles or, as one writer has suggested, it’s more of a <a href="https://rolesrules.blogspot.com/2019/06/post-osr-adventure-gaming-with.html" rel="nofollow noopener">“never-was school.”</a></p>
<p>All of that said, people use brand names and genre monikers because  <em>they’re useful,</em>  at least sometimes. I can’t be sure that everything that people describe as “OSR” will be of interest to me, but seeing that descriptor increases the odds that (a) it’s broadly compatible with a TON of other published and free material dating back roughly 50 years, and/or (b) it’ll be a GM’d game by an independent creator with more pared-down rules than most of what I’d see published for D&amp;D 5th edition. And that’s useful to me for filtering the massive influx of new RPG content on the internet every day, and sometimes, for describing my own work and hoping to connect with people with similar tastes.</p>
<p>But I would  <em>love</em>  to have a narrower term that describes rules and play style more than scene and tradition.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581/32</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1581-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-your-osr/1581.rss">What&#39;s your OSR?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
