<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122</link>
    <description>I have read a bunch of OSR theory and played a bunch of OSR games, and I have the following questions (some of which I have tentative answers to, some of which I do not).

(1) When people say that in an OSR game, we make decisions from the point of view of our characters, do they mean what our characters would do, or what would be in our characters&#39; best interests?

(2) To what degree is an OSR GM responsible for pacing, and what tools are they allowed to use in service of that end?

(3) To what degree can OSR games handle player-authored material without losing integrity of setting?  Does player-authored material threaten any other aspects of OSR play?

(4) To what degree can OSR games handle situations/characters/etc created specifically to target individual PCs and their interests without losing integrity of setting?

(5) If OSR games offer total freedom, why are they almost always about murderhobos wandering around and smashing pots in search of rupees?

I don&#39;t know if this is the optimal place to have this discussion, since I think most people here will bring the same assumptions that I do to these topics, but we&#39;ll see.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 13:42:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I have limited experience with OSR games, yet from my view based on a few sessions (DCC, Labyrinth Lord and another one):</p>
<p>(1) I did assume that decisions are made based on what is in the characters and groups best interest with justifications being reflected onto the character. Safe from critical situations the character is played as player assumes the character would act.</p>
<p>(2) From my understanding the OSR GM is seen to be responsible for setting up an adventure or scenario with whom the players can act by proxy of their character in an exciting way. Thus if there are pacing problems those might be attributed more to the players than the GM.</p>
<p>(3) Player authored material are integrated within the rule context and the group contract. When my chaotic cleric decided to first bellow a “kneel” at the foes and then proceed to attempt a speech converting them to her believe, it was between the rules (charisma) and the GM to see whether it succeeds.<br>
From my perspective the game style does ask for players to be creative and come up with stuff.</p>
<p>(4) I don’t understand how situations/characters/etc that specifically target individuel PCs are in conflict with the integrity of the setting?</p>
<p>(5) I can’t confirm the observation. Though I have literally neither observed a game nor heard of a game where player wander around and smash pots for rupees. I know that it’s something in the Zelda videogame series, yet never seen it outside of Zelda videogames.<br>
I did instead got the strong vibe from DCC that engaging in direct murderhobo’ing would lead to a fast and fatal tpk. Like, we barely survived our first encounter. Thus, when trying to rescue the people who paid us, we got creative with trying to avoid to battle 15 foes and their boss in a pit. Something that got me to ask whether there’s a big object/broken statue (there was, after a check) to throw down at the boss (which we excelled at).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/66">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/66</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 13:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-66</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@technoskald]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="63" data-topic="122">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/abacusmensch/40/2724_2.png" class="avatar"> AbacusMensch:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s a game focused on aiding the creation of a narrative, not the exploration of a given terrain, but I don’t know why it’s become so associated with “anything goes!”</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’m not suggesting that anything goes; all these principles have to be balanced against each other. Instead, I’m referencing things like “ask questions, use the answers” and “play to find out what happens”. Those things have some amount of tension with your prep. For me, they fit well together because those questions reminds me not to overprepare as I am inclined to do. Otherwise, there’s no room left for questions and finding out what will happen, since I’d have written it down in advance.</p>
<p>I’m not sure where “anything goes” comes from; perhaps you’re referencing something I’m unfamiliar with.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/65">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/65</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 02:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-65</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would say that “anything goes” is quite a misnomer here. But if it helps to get you a clear position to what you want it was nevertheless helpful.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/64">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/64</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 20:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-64</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AbacusMensch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/abacusmensch">@AbacusMensch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="54" data-topic="122">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/technoskald/40/1771_2.png" class="avatar"> technoskald:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>in PbtA, nothing’s “real” until it is said and established <em>during the game session</em> (with the players present).</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This notion seems pervasive, and I’m not sure when it became the accepted distinction.</p>
<p>Apocalypse World’s GM-facing rules include Agenda, Principles, Moves, and Always Say.</p>
<p>One of the things to Always Say is “What your prep demands.”</p>
<p>To me, it feels like the mechanics replace random tables with “lists of interesting things/places/people and what they want” (Fronts and Threats) and “lists of interesting small-scale outcomes” (the Moves).</p>
<p>It’s a game focused on aiding the creation of a narrative, not the exploration of a given terrain, but I don’t know why it’s become so associated with “anything goes!”</p>
<p>Maybe that’s how most people run it. I’ve always found my prep (of what people in the setting are up to now) to be essential, and bending it doesn’t make a better story. The world feels less real.</p>
<p>Despite their different approaches to gaming, I’ve always found that OSR and PbtA share similar tool sets and sometimes the same principles.</p>
<p>Thank you to everyone for your answers in this thread; an OSR approach looks more attractive to me than it ever has before.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/63">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/63</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 18:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-63</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Evlyn_M]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah it is like a second layer of more personal details.</p>
<p>You have the dungeon map and the rooms contents as a layer and then you have this additional layer generated by probing the players that you superpose over it.</p>
<p>When I use this technique with locations that are less personal I often send NPCs into the dungeon and ask questions about them, stuff like: “your cousin was part of the first expedition into the ancient tomb, did he ever came out?”</p>
<p>But I don’t use this technique all the time. Sometimes I only use it for the base camp and not for the dungeon itself. That said this discussion make me want to run a game just to experiment more with this. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/62">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/62</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 13:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-62</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think this is a player facing example of the distinction I’m making above about pre-prepped material as a skeleton for play.</p>
<p>Like you have the map of the old orphanage  (sounds like a great campaign starting location!) and the key, but rather then filling in all the necessary, unpredictable, unwritten, unwritable, but inevitable details you are having players fill in some in a concerted effort to create backstory linked to location history.   This sounds really useful in a haunted location, a ghost story, where some of the challenges are traditionally linked to the psychology of the characters.</p>
<p>Have you done it for a more traditional sort of location/genre? Say a ruined borderlands keep or ancient tomb?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/61">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/61</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 18:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-61</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Evlyn_M]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The answers the players gave me influenced the gameplay. Like if a player tried to open the kitchen door I could have asked: “when you were younger where did Sally used to hide the kitchen’s key?” Answer: “In a box under her bed with her favorite knife.” When they check under the bed I tell them that they key is in the box with a knife and a lucky coin that glow in the dark. Or I can ask what was Timmy afraid of after bed time? And use the answer a few rooms later. This don’t break how the players interact with the dungeon’s environment. I use the pre written dungeon as a canvas to paint on while we play. I really love GMing OSR like this as it keep me engaged as the GM.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/60">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/60</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 16:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-60</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeph">@Jeph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/shane">@shane</a>, of course nobody can claim that every OSR GM will run things that way, completely faithful to pre-committed material. Rather, the claim is this:</p>
<p>If we as a table <strong>agree to treat the pre-committed material as true and sacrosanct</strong>, we gain a strong foundation on which to play a game where the players’ choices feel concrete and real.</p>
<p>And this lets us experience facing a challenge, or pursuing a goal, as meaningful in a whole new way: we were able to do it because <em>we were able to do it</em>, not because someone else at the table thought it would be awesome, or make for a good story.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/59">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/59</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 18:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-59</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t think we need any of these ‘design principles’ to be 100%. I think it’s best to keep the moniker ‘OSR’ out of it because it’s pretty unclear what it meant back in G+ days and the idea that GURPS, Black Hack, 1981 Moldvay, and Dungeon World are all part of the same design space is too large a tent to be useful.  To me OSR was a scene, and is now a brand. To others it has different meanings.</p>
<p>We don’t need to litigate those meanings (subjective most likely) is we instead talk about “The design principles of pre-90’s exploration based ttrpgs”. There will still be outliers, but it’s likely easier to find them, there distinct meanings in this more neutral, less contentious descriptive label.</p>
<p>In my experience, for pre-90’s exploration focused ttrpgs there is a design principle of preferring that adventure creation is preparation - especially as it relates to physical and spatial issues.  The adventure location is mapped prior to play.  Even if procedural generation is used (and it is … as early as B1 ‘Search for the Unknown’ or the AD&amp;D DMG - arguably<br>
Booklet 3 Underworld &amp; Wilderness Adventures) it’s either meant to be prep (B1) or to simulate the unknowable (random encounters).</p>
<p>This emphasis is tied to issues of diagetic ‘fairness’ but maybe more because the GM is going to be busy arbitrating player schemes “You can’t jump a chasm … but can you pole vault it?” and making setting design decisions “How does Dragon the Greedy react to a bribery attempt involving a gilt painted wooden statue?”</p>
<p>On the fly content creation requires focus, GMing in general does, and your arbitration and general description effoets will get less of your focus when you are trying to decide the shape of the rooms off the next corridor or the how the geoup of urban hoodlums you just created relate to thectown in general.  Having setting ideas and maps written down or random generative tables prepared is a good solution to this.</p>
<p>Relatedly, because of an emphasis on simulation, or at least a principle disfavoring simple mechanical solutions  (e.g. even a best result on an acrobatics skill or such to leap the giant chasm will fail - unless combined with a fictional element and plan - like vaulting with a pole), the GM is expected to add to written/prepared work during play.  To what extent the GM does this is somewhat individual - but rarely impacts the core of an adventure and it tales GM time.</p>
<p>Lastly, without pre defined information and detail It’s harder for players to use fiction positioning to deal with obstacles. The better the details are described or known the better the player can engage them.</p>
<p>“You find a locked door” - How do I engage with this? How good a lock, how strong a door? As a player I’m limited to using a mechanical solution “I pick the lock” or “I force the door”. Alternatively I can interrogate the GM, ask about the door, It’s materials and complexity.</p>
<p>“You find a rusted steel door, locked with a new padlock on a thick steel chain” Now I have detail, and as a player can evaluate - that door sounds impossible to force, but maybe the lock or chain? Could tension and torsion pop the chain more easily?  It’s a new lock, it’s in use, who has a key? If I can pick that lock I could relock this door, creating a safe area, especially if I use my own lock?"</p>
<p>Obviously this is super simple, but when the GM is expected to create these details on the fly it’s helpful to have a basic idea of a location, its inhabitants and important first. It doesn’t only save GM attention for play, but it makes providing details easier as the GM knows what context they need to be coherent.</p>
<p>I guess this is a long-wonded way of saying that design principles exist to help ensure that your players are having fun - they’re best practices that make running the game easier.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/58">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/58</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 14:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-58</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BrianAshford]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brianashford">@BrianAshford</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Firstly, the GM shouldn’t be expecting the players to zag. The GM should have the situation prepared so that whatever the players choose to do, the GM can accommodate them. Obviously you can’t prepare for everything, so in the event that there players step outside of the prep the GM should impartially generate something appropriate. This is where random generators come in. It’s like wandering monster tables, it isn’t practical to track the movements of a dozen monsters which the PCs might encounter, so you abstract it with a dice roll instead. Books like Yoon Suin or the d30 Sandbox Companion scale that up to basically everything you might need.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/57">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/57</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 20:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-57</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I mean sure… But it doesn’t exist for the player characters until they experience it in the game session either. And are we 100% certain that no Old School GM changes anything once they have written it down in the big book? What if they are running a published module? Are they allowed to change things on the fly? (If not it seems like they are going to have a hard time not railroading their players when they zig when they expected them to zag.)</p>
<p>I kind of just keep coming back to the fact that in the end: it’s your table. As long as you and your players are getting what they want out of the sessions who the heck cares whether anyone is following any specific tenants?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/56">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/56</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 19:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-56</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You nailed it.  Thank you!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/55">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/55</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 19:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-55</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@technoskald]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/technoskald">@technoskald</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It sounds like the difference about tampering with the world is that, in PbtA, nothing’s “real” until it is said and established <em>during the game session</em> (with the players present). In OSR tradition, it’s “real” when the GM writes it down in their notes <em>during prep</em> (and thus could be shown to players if somebody questions it).</p>
<p>At least, that’s how I’ve been viewing it myself, and I think that might be what <a class="mention" href="/u/airk">@Airk</a> is saying.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/54">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/54</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 18:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-54</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BrianAshford]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brianashford">@BrianAshford</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The reason Evelyn’s wonderful orphanage concept works in an OSR context is that the history that the players were creating is not relevant in game terms. It adds to the atmosphere but doesn’t affect the tactics the players might use while Dungeoneering.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/53">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/53</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 17:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-53</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>As for “the game world is persistent and real” – I feel like OSR play hinges pretty strongly on the idea that the no one, the GM or the players, can “tamper” with the game world.  The “ideal” is the proverbial Gigantic Three Ring Binder Where Everything Is Written Down And Therefore True (Or at least, the module for the dungeon, or whathaveyou.).</p>
<p>I probably could have phrased it better – it’s the idea that “prep is binding” and the GM can’t change the world on the fly.</p>
<p>To be honest, this is one of the things that I struggle with the most about OSR ideals – it simply doesn’t make a lot of sense to me.  How, I ask myself, is something that is written in a binder any more real or binding than something the GM thought about during the session?  But in discussions with various people (Including Sandra, above) it’s become very clear to me that for some people the sanctity of prep is of utmost importance.</p>
<p>This ties back to the “GM as impartial referee” thing, I believe.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/52</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 16:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was mostly thinking of “Traditional play” at that point;  Doing it during play with people who are ok with that is fine, but unusual.</p>
<p>I think the only real core tenet that OSR insists upon in terms of “players shall not make up this content” is the actual specifics of the dungeon – I don’t think it’s possible to have a player-skill game where the players can decide where the traps are, after all.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/51</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 16:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I mean I think doing the standard DW fronts and grim portents thing pretty much does the trick, no? The world and it’s inhabitants should do their own things and progress as if the characters didn’t exist outside of what the characters <em>actually</em> do. Factions’ machinations should progress as time passes unless the PCs intercede, etc.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/50</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 12:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="47" data-topic="122">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/airk/40/2435_2.png" class="avatar"> Airk:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Not during “play” or at least, not during what people think of as “play”.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Could you expand on this? I’m assuming you aren’t saying that what <a class="mention" href="/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> did was incorrect since she is “constantly ask[ing]… questions and build[ing] on the… answers” which means it’s happening throughout a session?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/49</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 12:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yochaigal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yochaigal">@yochaigal</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Can you elaborate on “the game world as persistent and ‘real’” a bit? I’m starting an OSR/pbta hybrid soon, and I think this is the one bit I’ll struggle with as we play our campaign.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/48</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 10:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think at the end of the day it doesn’t actually matter to “OSR” games WHO builds the world.  “Traditionally” it would be the GM, during the dark hours of the night, writing page after page to put in their three ring binder of campaign notes.  Whatever, tradition.  The game works equally well and feels the same if the players invent the duchies and the towns and the major NPCs or whatever.  But it still needs to happen in the background.  Not during “play” or at least, not during what people think of as “play”.   I think you could literally use Microscope to create a world and then run an OSR game in it with the very people who created it.  I don’t see any conflicts there. It’s not how it’s “usually done” but that doesn’t matter.</p>
<p>I think the key tenets that need to be in place are:</p>
<ul>
<li>GM as impartial referee</li>
<li>The game world as persistent and ‘real’  – NO ONE really has the power to change what has been set down as “fact”</li>
<li>Player skill over character skill</li>
</ul>
<p>Aaaaand… that’s probably fundamentally it.  There are some other things that are USUALLY part of it – getting loot out of dungeons, high lethality combat, etc.  But I think driving at the core of the matter gives you the three bullet points above. And none of those three bullet points care who makes up the world.  Though it does care who draws the map for the dungeon.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/47</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 03:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Evlyn_M]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/evlyn_m">@Evlyn_M</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>When I run OSR games I constantly ask questions to the player characters and build on their answers. The game sessions still feel very OSR in their gameplay.</p>
<p>One of the more memorable OSR game I ran was a short dungeon about teenage adventurers coming back to dungeon delve in their now abandoned childhood orphanage. I ran the game in a OSR fashion, tracking resources, traps, random encounters, etc. But I also probed the character for memories and flash backs each time they entered a room and found stuff. By the end we really had a good idea of who these characters were and the game became more and more emotionally engaging. We were all moved after the final room encounter, I may have cried a bit. The game ended with taking mementos as loot (worth XP).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/46</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 01:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s great to see Sandra here, even if it’s “second-hand”!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/45</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/jeph">@Jeph</a> Please pass along my thanks to Sandra for this excellent response!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/44</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 02:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeph">@Jeph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>(3) To what degree can OSR games handle player-authored material without<br>
losing integrity of setting? Does player-authored material threaten any<br>
other aspects of OSR play?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Authoring material is fundamentally a different mode and mindset than<br>
running/exploring the material. This goes for GM as well as PC.</p>
<p>In other words, there is a severe split between creation mode (character<br>
creation or world creation) and actually playing/running the game.</p>
<p>Do not mix these “hats” at the same time.</p>
<p>Add in player authored material at creation time.</p>
<p>During Prep:</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/a/ad4a7984eaeb9f82d2373c8e1fc854f3a0780402.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/oJ0a97vIebxxInDTZPSIdRicBRU.png?dl=1" title="" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/a/ad4a7984eaeb9f82d2373c8e1fc854f3a0780402_2_690x407.png" alt data-base62-sha1="oJ0a97vIebxxInDTZPSIdRicBRU" width="690" height="407" srcset="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/a/ad4a7984eaeb9f82d2373c8e1fc854f3a0780402_2_690x407.png, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/a/ad4a7984eaeb9f82d2373c8e1fc854f3a0780402_2_1035x610.png 1.5x, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/a/ad4a7984eaeb9f82d2373c8e1fc854f3a0780402_2_1380x814.png 2x" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/a/ad4a7984eaeb9f82d2373c8e1fc854f3a0780402_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename"></span><span class="informations">1823×1077 169 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
<p>In my group, we haven’t yet hit the ceiling of what proportion of the<br>
material can be player authored but, on the other hand, we have been<br>
very careful with this. A temple here, a cult there, a family here, a<br>
bounty hunter there… We’re playing in a continent level sandbox and a<br>
the players have added like less than a hundred people to that<br>
continent and that’s been fine.</p>
<p>It’s important to</p>
<ol>
<li>do this during prep and not during play, and</li>
<li>don’t let the resolution of any challenge be player authored. Just<br>
the presence of elements.</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>(4) To what degree can OSR games handle situations/characters/etc created<br>
specifically to target individual PCs and their interests without losing<br>
integrity of setting?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As you (the asker) probably have realized, which is why you’re asking<br>
the question, is that altering the game world after seeing the<br>
characters somehow threatens the integrity of the game. I’ve called this<br>
the “No paper after seeing rock” principle in the past.</p>
<p>“No paper after seeing rock” (or “Paper→Rock” for short) is one possible<br>
solution to the “chasm width” problem. The chasm width problem is<br>
something that arose in GURPS.</p>
<p>GURPS has a very very complicated formula for how far characters can<br>
jump. They need to carefully invest points at character creation time to<br>
influence variables in that formula.</p>
<p>On the GM side, the GM can just make up whatever width of chasm they<br>
want. It’s 5 feet? It’s 15 feet? It’s 30 feet? It’s 2 feet? Up to you.</p>
<p>And what I thought as I pondered this is… isn’t this kinda dumb?</p>
<p>Because obviously good game design will lead to chasms jumpable some<br>
non-zero amount of time and unjumpable some non-zero amount of time.<br>
(Let’s for the sake of argument say that the perfect number is ⅔ of<br>
chasms are jumpable.) Because if they’re jumpable 100% or 0% of the<br>
time, why even have the jumping distance formula? Why not just say “You<br>
can jump all chasms” or “You can’t jump any chasm”?</p>
<p>(By the way, this is generally a complexity-reducing principle that, for<br>
example, Cthulhu Dark applies brilliantly. CD doesn’t need monster stats<br>
because, in it, monsters will always kill you if you fight them. For the<br>
purps of our particular game (whether it’s 2097e or whatever OSR game<br>
you have at hand), we usually do want a little more nuance than that.)</p>
<p>But deciding on chasm width arbitrarily after seeing the player<br>
characters is equally pointless. Because why should I dump points into<br>
being good at jumping if no matter how many points I dump in there, I’ll<br>
be able to jump around ⅔ of chasms?</p>
<p>So, two solutions.</p>
<p>One is to have a generative aspect of chasm widths, or, well, of<br>
challenge content in general. I.e. the chance of you jumping a<br>
particular chasm is generated by the rules. This is the route chosen by<br>
many post-90s challenge games like Three Sixteen (can you jump a given<br>
chasm? Well, just roll NFA) or D&amp;D 4e with its encounter budget system.</p>
<p>The other is the OSR way. The brilliant solution that is the whole<br>
raison d’être for OSR play: when you have sufficiently salient prep, you<br>
can arbitrate a multitude of unique situations fairly. I.e. if you have<br>
written down a chasm width, if you have committed to it before ever<br>
seeing the characters, you have the answer right then and there. You<br>
just know the chasm width because you have already committed to a chasm<br>
width.</p>
<p>And thus: Paper→Rock.</p>
<p>Obviously examining the PCs too closely means that you are seeing “rock”<br>
and can’t with good conscience create challenge elements (i.e. “select<br>
paper”).</p>
<p>So there is a workaround and that is to temporally displace any custom<br>
content. For example you (as GM) have created a PC-specific nemesis,<br>
maybe from the same cleric order as the PC or whatever. Do not “serve it<br>
up” as an encounter. (That’s a good OSR principle generally: never<br>
“serve up” encounters. Let encounters emerge from how the players are<br>
bouncing around in the big old pinball petri dish called the game<br>
world.) Instead add the nemesis to your encounter tables. You never know<br>
when it’s going to get rolled. This workaround has a ceiling. I’d say at<br>
around… maybe 10, 15 percent? If you keep rolling up a bunch of custom<br>
contents the world is going to start looking like it’s just a paper<br>
world created for the characters and the integrity of the game world<br>
itself takes a big toll.</p>
<p>This ties in to the second problem. Aesthetically. PC-specific content<br>
clashes with the idea of player-created characters exploring a very real<br>
place. I know we talked to bits on Story Games about how in Burning<br>
Wheel the challenge content is tailored to challenge specific “beliefs”<br>
and how awesome that is and… after experimenting with this stuff a<br>
bit…</p>
<p>it’s not so awesome. There is something magical in entering the UNKNOWN.<br>
Idk. So, aesthetically, I’d say the ceiling is lower than 10%. It’s<br>
something I want to be very careful about adding.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>(5) If OSR games offer total freedom, why are they almost always about<br>
murderhobos wandering around and smashing pots in search of rupees?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That hasn’t been my experience. We’ve had games about family and loss<br>
and desire and broken relationships and mended relationships and<br>
politics and and…</p>
<p>But.</p>
<p>OSR material is meant to be easily mashed up and recombined. Having a<br>
standard setup and milieu especially when it comes to goals and modus<br>
operandi is very useful in that regard.</p>
<p>Also, what makes OSR work compared to the typical “90s game” is the<br>
porte-monstre-trésor array. Places, problems, goals. And, agential<br>
search of goals rather than reactively answering the batphone.</p>
<p>For those two reasons, rupees is a fine goal.</p>
<p>It’s one that my particular play group usually have a hard time getting<br>
invested in which means that we usually go for other macguffins.<br>
Stopping murderers or ending evil soul sucking machines or exerting<br>
political influence or exploring the unknown.</p>
<p>(Also they want money to buy diamonds to use as components for spells<br>
because spells are cool and/or they want to Raise their loved ones or<br>
their old fave chars.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/43</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 21:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Five hard questions about OSR play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeph">@Jeph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I forwarded this thread to Sandra of <a href="https://idiomdrottning.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://idiomdrottning.org</a> aka <a href="http://story-games.com/forums/profile/2097" rel="nofollow noopener">2097</a> and she asked me to forward her reply here in turn, since she doesn’t have an account!</p>
<p>All that follows below is from her.</p>
<p>=======</p>
<blockquote>
<p>(1) When people say that in an OSR game, we make decisions from the point<br>
of view of our characters, do they mean what our characters would do, or<br>
what would be in our characters’ best interests?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is an ongoing debate in our own group as well as within the<br>
community.</p>
<p>What happened was that three consecutive parties stepped in the same<br>
party-killing trap. And I was like “What’s going on?” and they were like<br>
“But our new characters don’t know that the trap is there.”</p>
<p>This was a few years ago. It’s still a point of reference for when we<br>
talk about this in the group.</p>
<p>Since then, something they’ve started doing is to sometimes sort of<br>
nudge their character decisions towards a better outcome. For example,<br>
and this is an example from Tuesday’s game this week, the player knows<br>
very well that there are (at least) two rooms with water and one room<br>
with wine, and the location of those rooms. But the character is a<br>
kinda newish replacement character. The party hadn’t been annihilated so<br>
the player had his character was asking another player’s character “Are<br>
there any rooms with water up on level 2?” hoping to as quickly and<br>
relatively painlessly as possible “square the knowledge” between what he<br>
knew and what his character knew. (Unfortunately the player he asked is<br>
kind of a ditz and they didn’t remember any of the water rooms.)</p>
<p>That’s something I’ve observed as a consistent theme. The players want<br>
to ask quickly as possible “square the knowledge” between what the<br>
player knows and the character knows.</p>
<p>So the rule I’ve cooked up is this.</p>
<p>The degree to which they can do this vs the dungeon, vs the world, vs<br>
the challenge, is completely up to them. Challenge isn’t the sole point<br>
of our game but if there is a challenge aspect to the game, it becomes<br>
ridiculous to not then let players learn from their mistakes.</p>
<p>Similar to Rogue style video games (like Fatal Labyrinth) where the only<br>
thing you can bring with you from run to run is your own knowledge and<br>
experience.</p>
<p>I understand the tension between the two poles: defeating the challenge,<br>
and staying true to the character. My friend Jonatan Kilhamn once said<br>
“I want to win. But I want to win as the character.” I let the players<br>
choose freely from moment to moment how they want to resolve that<br>
tension when it comes to the challenge vs the world.</p>
<p>However.</p>
<p>When it comes to pvp situations, I’ve put my foot down. Here is another<br>
example.</p>
<p>A character is sneaking around in the forest trying to stealth on the<br>
party’s camp. He out-rolls their perception stats. But “Mr Meta” in the<br>
camp who just flubbed the perception says “But I still feel that<br>
something is going on. I want to look again more carefully” and I go “no<br>
way, Mr Meta!” (I don’t want to single out any one player, this is<br>
something that they’ve all done from time to time.) It’s the drive to as<br>
quickly as possible square character knowledge and player knowledge<br>
that’s at play again.</p>
<p>And the rule I have is: metagaming vs the world is allowed but not<br>
mandatory. It’s a long axis with many possible points of compromise and<br>
you can decide where you land on it from moment to moment. Metagaming vs<br>
<em>each other</em> is not allowed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>(2) To what degree is an OSR GM responsible for pacing, and what tools are<br>
they allowed to use in service of that end?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The DM needs to be much more hands off wrt pacing.</p>
<p>The playgroup needs to be in charge. Let them take their time and learn<br>
to be patient.</p>
<p>And, you can’t “cut”. The players want to be with their characters 24/7.</p>
<p>That said, there is a very powerful tool that the DM has available:<br>
the saliency time zoom principle.</p>
<p>Let things take the time needed to answer the questions we need to<br>
continue playing, but no more.</p>
<p>I.e. time passes quickly af when nothing happens. Fast-forwarding is<br>
different from cutting.</p>
<p>Please feel free to say “And a week passes, scratch rations please” or<br>
“It’s about thirty miles there, roll three encounter checks please” or<br>
“and you take the entire day to search the rooms. In one of the rooms<br>
you hear an unusual sound when tapping the wall, what do you do?”</p>
<p>(continued)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122/42</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 21:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-122-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/five-hard-questions-about-osr-play/122.rss">Five hard questions about OSR play</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
