<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bump in the Dark - Monster hunting, Forged in the Dark</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-monster-hunting-forged-in-the-dark/8059</link>
    <description>Hi all! I haven&#39;t been around much lately, in large part because I&#39;ve been busy at work on my game, *Bump in the Dark*! It&#39;s a lightweight FitD game with a flexible investigation system inspired by *External Containment Bureau* and *Brindlewood Bay*. You play as a hunter, someone who has dedicated their life to keeping regular people safe from the horrors of the darkness: cryptids, monsters, demons, and the nefarious factions vying to control the dark power of the void. It&#39;s a game about community, chosen family, and beating the shit out of monsters. I&#39;ve been having a lot of fun designing and running it, and I&#39;m super stoked to finally be able to share it with others. I&#39;d love for you to take a look and maybe even pick up a copy, and I&#39;m glad to answer any questions you might have about it!

You can find the game [here](https://jexjthomas.itch.io/bump-in-the-dark) and get updates on [Twitter](https://twitter.com/BumpDarkRPG).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 20:53:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-monster-hunting-forged-in-the-dark/8059.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bump in the Dark - Monster hunting, Forged in the Dark</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi all! I haven’t been around much lately, in large part because I’ve been busy at work on my game, <em>Bump in the Dark</em>! It’s a lightweight FitD game with a flexible investigation system inspired by <em>External Containment Bureau</em> and <em>Brindlewood Bay</em>. You play as a hunter, someone who has dedicated their life to keeping regular people safe from the horrors of the darkness: cryptids, monsters, demons, and the nefarious factions vying to control the dark power of the void. It’s a game about community, chosen family, and beating the shit out of monsters. I’ve been having a lot of fun designing and running it, and I’m super stoked to finally be able to share it with others. I’d love for you to take a look and maybe even pick up a copy, and I’m glad to answer any questions you might have about it!</p>
<p>You can find the game <a href="https://jexjthomas.itch.io/bump-in-the-dark" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a> and get updates on <a href="https://twitter.com/BumpDarkRPG" rel="nofollow noopener">Twitter</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-monster-hunting-forged-in-the-dark/8059/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-monster-hunting-forged-in-the-dark/8059/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 20:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8059-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-monster-hunting-forged-in-the-dark/8059.rss">Bump in the Dark - Monster hunting, Forged in the Dark</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
