<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>NGC Masks: Silver Animosity</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-masks-silver-animosity/6160</link>
    <description>New Gauntlet Comics Presents: Silver Stoat Imprint&#39;s SILVER ANIMOSITY run!

Masks Silver Age Shenanigans on Tuesdays in February at 1300/1 pm Central US time

PLEASE DO NOT RSVP TO THIS GAME FOR THE FIRST 72 HOURS IF YOU HAVE NOT EDITED THE NEW GAUNTLET COMICS WIKI BEFORE

It&#39;s the year 1970, right after that amazing moon landing discovered the Moonians on the dark side of Luna. The Moonians, as they are now known, came to Earth and shared several of their most advanced technologies to help advance science and now have ambassadors in New Gauntlet City. All was going well until someone stole some of their hypertech and has finally announced their intentions!

The Atavist Society for Pragmatic De-Evolution has decided that they are able to take their activities to the next level thanks to all the developments made in the world thanks to the combination of Earth and Lunar sciences. They say that humanity has come too far to be held back by primal traditions when they should be embracing the parts of the past that were glorious: The strengths, the ingenuity, the perfect parts without all the dross that held it back in the dark ages.

You are part of a group of super heroes who have to stand up to these Low Evolutionaries, a team that will go down in history as those who have stopped the creeping old world ways or who will have failed in the end.

This game will be like the old school Extra Large Special Issues versus the tradeback style of today. You will be introducing a new team to New Gauntlet Comics&#39; Silver Age and we will explore the fun of four color hyper science adventures with a splash of scientific fantasy that makes such a world fun and fantastic.

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfNlP7upf4hLTzQRD
Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfao27Wh5eiv0WGqj
Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfmAfLBWFNR12qB1l
Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfxOGT1LsQCw8iToZ</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 19:11:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-masks-silver-animosity/6160.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>NGC Masks: Silver Animosity</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Ferret]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ferret">@Ferret</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>New Gauntlet Comics Presents: Silver Stoat Imprint’s SILVER ANIMOSITY run!</p>
<p>Masks Silver Age Shenanigans on Tuesdays in February at 1300/1 pm Central US time</p>
<p>PLEASE DO NOT RSVP TO THIS GAME FOR THE FIRST 72 HOURS IF YOU HAVE NOT EDITED THE NEW GAUNTLET COMICS WIKI BEFORE</p>
<p>It’s the year 1970, right after that amazing moon landing discovered the Moonians on the dark side of Luna. The Moonians, as they are now known, came to Earth and shared several of their most advanced technologies to help advance science and now have ambassadors in New Gauntlet City. All was going well until someone stole some of their hypertech and has finally announced their intentions!</p>
<p>The Atavist Society for Pragmatic De-Evolution has decided that they are able to take their activities to the next level thanks to all the developments made in the world thanks to the combination of Earth and Lunar sciences. They say that humanity has come too far to be held back by primal traditions when they should be embracing the parts of the past that were glorious: The strengths, the ingenuity, the perfect parts without all the dross that held it back in the dark ages.</p>
<p>You are part of a group of super heroes who have to stand up to these Low Evolutionaries, a team that will go down in history as those who have stopped the creeping old world ways or who will have failed in the end.</p>
<p>This game will be like the old school Extra Large Special Issues versus the tradeback style of today. You will be introducing a new team to New Gauntlet Comics’ Silver Age and we will explore the fun of four color hyper science adventures with a splash of scientific fantasy that makes such a world fun and fantastic.</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfNlP7upf4hLTzQRD" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfNlP7upf4hLTzQRD</a><br>
Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfao27Wh5eiv0WGqj" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfao27Wh5eiv0WGqj</a><br>
Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfmAfLBWFNR12qB1l" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfmAfLBWFNR12qB1l</a><br>
Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfxOGT1LsQCw8iToZ" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNUfxOGT1LsQCw8iToZ</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-masks-silver-animosity/6160/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-masks-silver-animosity/6160/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 19:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6160-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-masks-silver-animosity/6160.rss">NGC Masks: Silver Animosity</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
