<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Neon City Overdrive - GF Camp</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041</link>
    <description>Hello! I am a cadet in Jim Crocker&#39;s awesome Game Facilitator Camp. Each camp participant is running a one-shot for the other cadets to give us hands-on experience creating the calendar event, making the announcement on Slack, and much more. So without further ado:

NOTE THAT THIS EVENT IS LIMITED TO PARTICIPANTS IN JIM CROCKER&#39;S GAME FACILITATOR CAMP

Neon City Overdrive is a game of cyberpunks and the near-future sprawl they run jobs in. It is a game inspired by the attitude, style, and action of Blade Runner, Snow Crash, Neuromancer, and RoboCop. It is a world of gleaming skyscrapers and crowded urban labyrinths where people eke out whatever existence they can claw from the next punk. It&#39;s a grim and gritty world of hard choices, high tech, and limitless danger dressed in chrome and lit in neon.

In this one-shot, we will create characters at the table and then take them on an action-packed job in a near-future San Francisco. Character creation is fast and the rules are intuitive. We&#39;ll be in and out in no time!

**Duration** : One 3 1/2-hour session
**Breaks** : Two breaks per session (5-10 mins each)
**Venue** : GM’s Zoom (link will be shared immediately the event)
**Recording** : Yes, but made public only with all players&#39; consent!
**Safety** : Lines &amp; Veils, Script Change, and Open Door Policy.

This game operates under the [Gauntlet Inclusivity Policy](http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html).

June 15 5:00 PDT: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MbFKYteeCd5LjDcQ6Fi</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 18:42:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Neon City Overdrive - GF Camp</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Beekzor]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beekzor">@Beekzor</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A spot has opened up for tonight’s –  <strong>June 15 at 5:00pm PDT  –</strong>  one-shot of  <strong>Neon City Overdrive</strong>  , a cyberpunk action RPG. Character creation is fast and the rules are intuitive. This was only open to participants in the Game Facilitator Camp - but now it’s open to all! Please join us!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 18:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7041-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041.rss">Neon City Overdrive - GF Camp</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Neon City Overdrive - GF Camp</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@StarDrive.Games]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stardrive.games">@StarDrive.Games</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thank you for bringing this game to my attention.  I love, LOVE, <strong>LOVE</strong> this theme!<br>
I have been thinking about making a synthwave inspired RPG.<br>
/80s freak<br>
//apologies for being offtopic a bit</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 20:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7041-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041.rss">Neon City Overdrive - GF Camp</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Neon City Overdrive - GF Camp</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Beekzor]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beekzor">@Beekzor</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello! I am a cadet in Jim Crocker’s awesome Game Facilitator Camp. Each camp participant is running a one-shot for the other cadets to give us hands-on experience creating the calendar event, making the announcement on Slack, and much more. So without further ado:</p>
<p>NOTE THAT THIS EVENT IS LIMITED TO PARTICIPANTS IN JIM CROCKER’S GAME FACILITATOR CAMP</p>
<p>Neon City Overdrive is a game of cyberpunks and the near-future sprawl they run jobs in. It is a game inspired by the attitude, style, and action of Blade Runner, Snow Crash, Neuromancer, and RoboCop. It is a world of gleaming skyscrapers and crowded urban labyrinths where people eke out whatever existence they can claw from the next punk. It’s a grim and gritty world of hard choices, high tech, and limitless danger dressed in chrome and lit in neon.</p>
<p>In this one-shot, we will create characters at the table and then take them on an action-packed job in a near-future San Francisco. Character creation is fast and the rules are intuitive. We’ll be in and out in no time!</p>
<p><strong>Duration</strong> : One 3 1/2-hour session<br>
<strong>Breaks</strong> : Two breaks per session (5-10 mins each)<br>
<strong>Venue</strong> : GM’s Zoom (link will be shared immediately the event)<br>
<strong>Recording</strong> : Yes, but made public only with all players’ consent!<br>
<strong>Safety</strong> : Lines &amp; Veils, Script Change, and Open Door Policy.</p>
<p>This game operates under the <a href="http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Inclusivity Policy</a>.</p>
<p>June 15 5:00 PDT: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MbFKYteeCd5LjDcQ6Fi" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MbFKYteeCd5LjDcQ6Fi</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 05:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7041-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/neon-city-overdrive-gf-camp/7041.rss">Neon City Overdrive - GF Camp</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
