<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sixth Ring: Dragon</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-dragon/6794</link>
    <description>@Judd  and I are back with a new episode of The Sixth Ring! This is a fantastic episode, with lots of great discussion and tips. The first segment is about how Trophy Gold has changed the play culture of Judd&#39;s D&amp;D group. The second segment is about Cat Evans&#39;s Last Night on Earth, a truly excellent Rooted in Trophy game that has strong World of Darkness vibes. The third segment continues our discussion of converting OSR modules, in particular strategies for dividing up the physical space of the dungeon in preparation to make sets out of it. The fourth segment is some dragon doodling. The last segment, as always, is our short-form actual play featuring the mannikin Wöd Dum. Check it out: 

https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/trophy-podcast/the-sixth-ring-dragon</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 16:21:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Announcements</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-dragon/6794.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The Sixth Ring: Dragon</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasoncordova]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasoncordova">@jasoncordova</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/judd">@Judd</a>  and I are back with a new episode of The Sixth Ring! This is a fantastic episode, with lots of great discussion and tips. The first segment is about how Trophy Gold has changed the play culture of Judd’s D&amp;D group. The second segment is about Cat Evans’s Last Night on Earth, a truly excellent Rooted in Trophy game that has strong World of Darkness vibes. The third segment continues our discussion of converting OSR modules, in particular strategies for dividing up the physical space of the dungeon in preparation to make sets out of it. The fourth segment is some dragon doodling. The last segment, as always, is our short-form actual play featuring the mannikin Wöd Dum. Check it out:</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/trophy-podcast/the-sixth-ring-dragon" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">THE GAUNTLET</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/dcf7d9ed7b61e484ccd66e0a362127a9445d772f.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="500" height="500" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/d/dcf7d9ed7b61e484ccd66e0a362127a9445d772f_2_10x10.png">

<h3><a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/trophy-podcast/the-sixth-ring-dragon" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">The Sixth Ring: Dragon</a></h3>

<p>The Trophy Podcast is a podcast by Jason Cordova, Judd Karlman, and Rich Rogers. </p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-dragon/6794/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-dragon/6794/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 16:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6794-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-dragon/6794.rss">The Sixth Ring: Dragon</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
