<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549</link>
    <description>It has recently come to my attention that my GMing runs...**dark**. I recognize that this is true of myself. I like Abercrombie. I like grim, gritty, and even grimdark (see Abercrombie).

But that&#39;s not necessarily what my players like and I don&#39;t want to ring the same bells over and over again either.

I would like my players to describe my games as **dramatic**, or **exciting**, or even just **fun**. Any of those would be better than **dark**. 

I know this kind of change is possible - but does anyone have any suggestions for how to go about it? Especially about how to fight existing tendencies and actively practice and learn new ones? I already tore down my entire trad GMing game and rebuilt it around fail-forward and player empowerment about 15 years ago and it was...tough. Exhausting. There were too many sessions that weren&#39;t enough fun while I was learning.

Anyone have any tips on making this easier? Faster? Or do I just say: 

&gt; Everyone, I&#39;m trying to reform my grimdark ways, based on your feedback. I&#39;m going to do my best but my instincts are all to find the worst thing that can happen and then crank that up and shove it in your faces and shout, &quot;Oh yeah? What are you going to do about THIS?&quot; Please understand that I may take longer than normal to decide on the results of actions as I seek to moderate outcomes, and please let me know if something has gone too deep into tragedy and we can retcon it ASAP.

Thanks in advance for your advice. From me and my beleaguered MASKS players!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 16:21:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> - yeah, the standout for me was when the players realized that the amorphous, amoeba-like aliens thought that they (The PCs) were inferior life forms (kind of disgusting, but also kind of cute - like the way I feel about snakes) because they were a solid, unchanging shape. Then the shapeshifter in the group shifted into an amoebic shape and the aliens fell all over themselves apologizing. They then presumed that the others were the shapeshifter’s <strong>pets</strong>.</p>
<p>It had some drama, but it was funny. The PCs got caught up in the confusion as I wanted, pieced together the problem, and solved it, but nobody got like…imprisoned or anything.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 16:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Congrats - glad it went so well</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 15:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Any particular really positive moments you enjoyed during the session?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/26</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 17:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h1>Followup: Results</h1>
<p>Hey everyone, thank you so much for your help - I just wanted to post a quick followup about what I tried and how it went.</p>
<p>I tried three things:</p>
<ol>
<li>I prepped light. Making a planet for their first proper session of Apocalypse Sonata I chose a confusing planet, and made it deliberately lighthearted.</li>
<li>I opened the game telling them I’d been thinking about this and asking for their help recognizing when things had gone too dark. I didn’t want to get as formal as an X-Card because this was explicitly not about not having to talk about what was edited out - it was about giving me feedback and that requires talking. So I asked them to just make a “time out” sign if anything was too much.</li>
<li>I put an index card on the table and wrote “DARK” on one side in black sharpie. I said, “When I go to the dark side, we’ll flip this card so the DARK shows. I can’t go dark again until we’ve flipped it over by doing something lighter, OK?”</li>
</ol>
<p>It went really well. The players expressed their gratitude that I was trying to change things and we ended up only flipping the dark side card for something a <strong>player</strong> contributed. We didn’t want to edit it out, we just wanted to vary the dynamic. Nobody called a time out on me and I felt like this was a change I could make <strong>without</strong> ruining my game for a year as with my transition to more narrative and player-facing play.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/25</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 17:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Try something new and silly as a one shot, and then get inspired by it. Some <a>Dungeons and Bananas</a>, some <a href="http://lookrobot.co.uk/doctor-magnethands/" rel="nofollow noopener">Dr. Magnethands</a>, a little <a href="http://www.memento-mori.com/rpg/inspectres" rel="nofollow noopener">InSpectres</a>, or dig into <a href="http://www.dangerpatrol.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Danger Patrol</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/24</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 07:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I really like that, <a class="mention" href="/u/aviatrixcat">@AviatrixCat</a>. I think seeing characters as tools for tone is a very, very important technique.</p>
<p>I dealt with this recently when running My Life with Master. I wrote a fair bit about the game here:</p>
<aside class="quote quote-modified" data-post="2" data-topic="2383">
  <div class="title">
    <div class="quote-controls"></div>
    <img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/paul_t/40/1825_2.png" class="avatar">
    <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/my-life-with-master-yukon-gold-rush/2383/2">My Life with Master: Yukon Gold Rush</a> <a class="badge-wrapper  bullet" href="/c/rpg-chat"><span class="badge-category-bg" style="background-color: #0088CC;"></span><span style="" data-drop-close="true" class="badge-category clear-badge" title="Chat about actual play of, prepping to play, and running of LARPs and RPGs.">RPG Chat</span></a>
  </div>
  <blockquote>
    I’ll add some more commentary here, and mention that comments, questions, and so forth are very welcome! 
… 
I found it very difficult to play the Master: always walking a line between portraying the villain and running the game in a fair and generous way. This game, like  Dog Eat Dog , blurs the line a little between the character and the player, and given the amount of power the Master has over the Minions, could easily become a pretty twisted power fantasy. I found it hard to be appropriately…
  </blockquote>
</aside>

<p>As you can see, I struggled with the incredibly dark and heavy-handed portrayal of the Master the game demanded of me. While it was occasionally exciting to consider twisted, diabolical plans, it was also emotionally wearying. So I found tremendous relief in the “overture” or “Connection” scenes. I made the Connections (human locals that are dear to the Minions) sympathetic, kind, innocent, and I played the scenes with them in warm tones and in a gentle key.</p>
<p>I also combined this with greater freedom for the players to contribute to the narrative. When the Master was involved, I framed hard and controlled the narrative. In Connection scenes, the players had freedom to frame the scene themselves and I tended to ‘say yes’ to whatever they offered.</p>
<p>Putting all that together, it was great to find relief from the heavy, dark, sadistic Master scenes in more warm-hearted and gentle Connection scenes, and a big part of that was the way I chose to play those characters. That balance between the dark and the warm really made the game work for me.</p>
<p>I hope that might be a source of inspiration for you, Jason! Perhaps it will spark a thought or an idea.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 18:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Someone who worked for me, and was worried he always managed people a little too roughly, had a block of wood made with a variety of leadership styles on each of 8 faces: confrontational to collaborative.  After every interaction with someone he managed he’d rotate the block as a reminder to respond differently to the next one.  I hadn’t thought about applying this on an RPG context until I read this thread.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/22</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 15:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AviatrixCat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/aviatrixcat">@AviatrixCat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A thing I did for a while last year was play a series of characters really <em>sincerely</em>. That is, they were what they said they were; it wasn’t that they lacked substance, but their substances wasn’t particularly obfuscated. I found that really helped me get into the space of all kinds of different characters, good and bad. That might be a thing to try; if you have good characters, make them <em>good</em>, not good by convenience but for reasons, reasons that are hard to corrupt. And if you have evil characters…well, they should have reasons too <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>There was a thing I noticed back when my meetup did Night Witches. We did the entire run of the game, from training to the end of the war. One of the GMs was pretty cognizant of how terrible the Soviet system was and so we lived in a crapsack world of constant pain from outside. Now, this can be fine: the queer reading of NW is about building your own community in the face of an outside world. But I had been reading “A Dance With Death,” a book of interviews with the actual Night Witches and what stood out to me was that they were a phenomenally high-morale unit: they did a grind any pilot would find overwhelming and did it night after night. So when I rotated into the GMs chair, I made a couple of characters that weren’t so…dark. The new Chief of Staff was an officer of the “my job is to keep you alive and flying” persuasion who was on the characters’ side as much as possible. And the new politruk was…an inexperienced woman who’d have been a better Komsomol camp counselor than hardcore commissar. She really believed in socialism and education. (I modeled her off the political officer interviewed in “A Dance With Death.”) I think having those two around helped; certainly at the end of my run, the PCs organized an off-the-books raid on a German prisoner train with the help of some sexy partisans to rescue the captain <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Glimmers of light and hope are why we can stand in the grimdarkness, I suppose.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/21</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 13:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Re SwM: I adore Epi and his writing but I would <em>highly</em> recommend finding an AP to watch or listen to to learn the game. (IIRC he did a series running it on Twitch…)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/20</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 01:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Very nice! I don’t think reading that game will give you much more in terms of tone; the only difference is that in the game, the tone switches based on a die roll.</p>
<p>It’s definitely worth finding some cues for yourself like these, whether it’s for prep or for play. You could also have a checklist of more specific things, like, “A kind and well-meaning soul”, which you check off when you include them in your prep or in a scene. “Someone develops a crush without ulterior motives,” stuff like that. It depends a fair deal on the specifics of your game and the particulars of how you tend to “get dark”.</p>
<p>Can you think of any instances of your game where you <em>tried</em> to make things less grim, but you feel the attempt didn’t work (either because you couldn’t follow through, or because you didn’t do it the way you had wished)?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/19</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I just replied to <a class="mention" href="/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> above with:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="16" data-topic="2549">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/j/c5a1d2/40.png" class="avatar"> Jason_Kottler:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I think I’m gonna make myself a card that’s black on one side and flip that side up when something has gone dark. It’ll remind me to produce a different kind of tension.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’ve got Swords Without Master haven’t gotten a chance to really read it yet. But it sounds like the kind of concrete tool I can apply at the table that will remind me and allow my players to help correct course if I go against the card, because they’ll know the state of the tone card.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/18</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Have you ever heard of Swords Without Master or Monkeydome?</p>
<p>Those games introduce “tone” as a variable, and some technique for switching it over.</p>
<p>You could make a “tone” tool for yourself, and engage it at certain times. For example, a card which says “Grim” on one side, and “Full of Hope” on the other. The rule is that you can’t flip over the card until you create or narrate something that fills that quality, and you can’t go against the quality while it’s face up, either. See if that kind of thing makes a change to your GMing; everything is worth a try!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/17</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 23:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="8" data-topic="2549">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/blakeryan/40/438_2.png" class="avatar"> BlakeRyan:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If something bad just happened, don’t follow it up with another.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I really like this idea. Vary the dynamic. I think I’m gonna make myself a card that’s black on one side and flip that side up when something has gone dark. It’ll remind me to produce a different kind of tension.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 23:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>OK, I’ve got that. A team of adult heroes who are friendly (mostly) and supportive (mostly) but also somehow are never around or effective when the kids are facing villains. I like the idea of clue cards!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/15</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 23:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Been playing indie games since the early 2ks, been asking leading questions for a looong time now. I love to incorporate my players’ input.</p>
<p>Recently been playing the <strong>living hell</strong> out of Dialect because it is so reliably amazing. Last time, I deliberately portrayed <em>The Innocent</em> to force myself to go against type. My friends will <strong>never</strong> GM. It’s not going to happen. But I am loving Dialect and plan to pick up Dream Askew next.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/14</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 23:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Another thing: Be a fan of your players, so let some NPCs be the fans of their characters. They’ve done something good? They accomplished something? Have an adult compliment them, or show them respect. Let someone write a nice blog article about them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 18:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Heidi_Schlottman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/heidi_schlottman">@Heidi_Schlottman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It sounds like you’ve become a pro at making your stakes matter by making them dark. (Not  a bad thing - I think a lot of people struggle with that!)</p>
<p>Since your goal is to make things feel lighter, rather than going for the grimmest stakes available, instead look for stakes that matter to the PCs <em>personally</em> but aren’t going to cause death, dismemberment, or insanity. That way you have investment and tension (which often is what amounts to “fun”) without the consequences having to be “And also your beloved companion is brutally removed from existence in front of you.”</p>
<p>Good news is, in Masks, this is especially easy since you’re playing teenagers who care about ALL SORTS OF THINGS that might not lead to grim ends. Prom night? Likes on Instagram? Attaining your dreams of getting accepted into your ideal college RIGHT NOW? That new pair of shoes or iPhone upgrade? All things that can cause the character to care, to chase things, and don’t have to go dark if they lose them or if you want to ramp things up a bit.</p>
<p>Look for character-invested stakes that <em>feel</em> like they life-or-death matter without <em>actually</em> life-or-death mattering.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/12</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 15:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The advice here has been spot on. My advice is pretty similar to what others said (<a class="mention" href="/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> in particular) but maybe this formulation will also be useful.</p>
<p>My suggestion is to make a list of ideas of scenes, twists, or story lines which you would consider <em>dramatic</em>, <em>exciting</em>, or <em>fun</em> (and in any case not <em>dark</em>). Don’t railroad people towards these, but just figure out for yourself what they look like and how you might get there from your story using the MC moves.</p>
<p>These can be large story arcs, complications from their alter ego, twists to their relationships (marriage, break up, problems at work, moving, etc.), teaming up with villains to do something non-villainous, visiting a new city, etc. They can also just be small scenes you think would be fun to try, e.g. superheroes at a party or a bar, what it’s like having to testify in court, being interviewed by the Super Society, etc. The important thing is that they seem interesting to you and that you can get used to seeing their <em>shape</em> and <em>feel</em>.</p>
<p>Going <em>dark</em> in a story is a little bit like eating sugar or a dessert in a meal. Characters often have tragic pasts, or experience loss, but these events are more significant and satisfying when they occur after other character and plot development (the nutritious meal). But once you get used to eating a lot of sweets all the time it’s hard to appreciate the other flavors and break the habit.</p>
<p>Since you’ve trained yourself to see ways to take stories in a dark direction this will likely be your impulse while running the game. To break the habit, you not only need to reign in this impulse (which it sounds like you’re doing) but also build a sense of where you <em>do</em> want to go, and practice seeing opportunities to get there.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/11</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 15:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Shortaaron]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shortaaron">@Shortaaron</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So the darkness arises from the complications, not the game’s genre? That seems like it would be hard to change. I like dark fiction; I get bored with novels where “everything is beautiful and nothing hurt.” It’s not that I don’t get satisfaction from other texts or that darkness is the only good mode, it’s just less emotionally impactful. I empathize here.</p>
<p>Maybe use that old DW complication roll table (or make your own) that has more moderate responses to the game. This way it’s not taking you extra time in-game and has some moderation built in. Or make a simple table with increasing intensity of consequences:</p>
<ul>
<li>broken finger &gt; mutated hand &gt; dismembered forearm.</li>
<li>hear a voice in your head &gt; sickening feeling like there’s something inside you &gt; your actions are no longer your own.</li>
</ul>
<p>I think “Trophy” does with “Conditions” growing in intensity as you encounter new rings, you might take a look at that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 15:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My advice would be to stop being the boss. Play some GMless, GMful, heavily collaborative games. Ask your friends to step up and run some games that you get to play. Cede your authority and embrace the group vibe while adding your own special darkness now and again.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 13:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If something bad just happened, don’t follow it up with another. Put in a mundane or lighter moment to mix up the tone.</p>
<p>Mundane stuff : visit from an old friend, asking them to share a childhood memory, seeing a theatre/movie with a sibling, a cat/dog/raccoon adopts them, friend of a friend heard about something they did and just wanted to say thanks (they’re also pretty cute).</p>
<p>Don’t mention paying bills or serious disease. If there is an injury, the temple/hospital can fix it-don’t mention payment.</p>
<p>Hobbies help, give them a few successes with it, and build up to them fixing that old car/forging that awesome blade/designing the royal dress. It will change how they see their character and how npcs see them.</p>
<p>Police/City Guard will cut them some slack if they are saving lives/fighting bad guys, you know like how heroes get treated by the cops in every 90 min action film.</p>
<p>Don’t forget things like nights at the club, birthdays, street parties, religious festivals (with non lethal contests like juggling, archery, singing, pottery)</p>
<ul>
<li>the heroes avoid the lycans by ducking down an alley and going through an unlocked door, the staff of the karaoke bar say Your in the door, you gotta sing!’<img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:">
</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/8</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 23:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ahhh there it is! I wanted to recommend CATS but couldn’t find a good blog post/website that talked about it. Maybe a good resource to link on The Gauntlet’s pages?</p>
<p>It can also be helpful to get analytical. You’ve cracked the formula on how to get your players in worse and worse situations, so how would you tackle the problem of how to celebrate the awesomeness of the characters? Honestly, just singling out moments where characters are doing awesome stuff and celebrating that both in the moment and after the fact (see: Stars and Wishes, <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/stars-and-wishes" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/stars-and-wishes</a> ) will start to build a feedback loop in your brain. If you’re excited to see players doing really fun, awesome stuff, that’ll actually help rewire your instincts along the way.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/7</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 23:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ll echo <a class="mention" href="/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> here: talk to your players. A great way to start that conversation is CATS:</p>
<p><a href="http://proleary.com/2016/04/25/the-cats-method-a-story-telling-game-opening-ritual/" rel="nofollow noopener">http://proleary.com/2016/04/25/the-cats-method-a-story-telling-game-opening-ritual/</a></p>
<p>From then on use safety tools like <a href="http://briebeau.com/thoughty/script-change/" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change</a> to let everyone (players and MC) pause things to point out when things are going darker than the agreed upon tone.</p>
<p>As someone who runs a periodic series called <em>Tragic Tuesdays</em> I can empathize. But I do so on The Gauntlet, so people decide to play or not. I don’t have a group where I am <em>the</em> GM. I tend to be someone who likes the extremes so on the other hand I’ll run Gonzo stuff to even things out.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/6</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OriJinal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/orijinal">@OriJinal</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think you can say that <em>and</em> try to incorporate some tips.</p>
<p>I used to have a darker style. For me, that grimness was driven in part because I thought it was my job to challenge <em>the players</em> as well as the characters. Then I sat down with one and asked them why they weren’t enjoying themselves. They answered “I think hard all day at work. When I play, I just want to kill some stuff and have a laugh.” That was illuminating for me. Talking to your players - what a concept.</p>
<p>I’ve also found some grimmer games are grim because the GM focuses on trying to realistically portray the setting as opposed to, say, trying to make the setting cinematic. So maybe look to what your inspiring fiction is - are you aiming for a real space game where a pin-prick to the oxygen tank spells doom or Legolas winning his way with ease through everything?</p>
<p>“Be a fan of the PCs” is, I think, the best advice. If you don’t want to see them come out the other side, maybe go back to char gen and work with the players so that they are more sympathetic?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Help Me Lighten Up</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Absolutely communicate with the players! They can help you manage tone very powerfully. Also, I highly recommend using content management tools to help with this (<a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/tools-of-the-table.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/tools-of-the-table.html</a>); <em>Lines &amp; Veils</em> is a good way to pre-emptively manage your content, for example, by setting your own Lines on dark elements you want to keep away from.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2549-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/help-me-lighten-up/2549.rss">Help Me Lighten Up</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
