<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hearts of Wulin: In the Court of Crimson Blades</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-in-the-court-of-crimson-blades/6658</link>
    <description>This is for a four-session run of the romantic melodrama game *, Hearts of Wulin* using the **Courtly Wuxia** variant ruleset, scheduled for 8:30pm US Eastern time on Thursdays in May. Prior experience with *Hearts of Wulin* or the Courtly Wuxia rules is not expected (rules will be taught during and throughout play). I will send out a group email about a week before the first session to confirm everyone&#39;s intent to play and to provide set-up and invitation details. A fourth seat is being held for Shane of the Gauntlet community. You are a courtly scholar-warrior or noble (or uncultured emissary from the distant edges of the kingdom) who must not only navigate deadly duels of romantic passion and honor, but also brave the equally threatening world of court politics and social maneuvering as you sip tea, write poetry, and employ cutthroat cloak-and-dagger tactics to win the ruler&#39;s heart--or claim their title as your own.

The game&#39;s initial set-up and inciting incident will be decided upon collaboratively at the beginning of play and during character creation, rather than set a priori by the GM. A set of example story starters will be sent to players prior to the first session to give everyone a sense of the sort of directions a game of court intrigue can take. Whether dealing with a power-scramble following an assassination, the threat of an army approaching the capital, or the disclosure of a political secret that threatens to change the empire forever, players will take the role of nobles, generals, members of the royal family, ambassadors, or any other number of courtly individuals, as they fight to win love, seize the throne, or take revenge for old wounds.

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9E3jyfJFrPDUJW4Ly

Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9Eq7Hi-t0vwM8Ipgu

Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9F8Xr5V8qOS8Mjhj5

Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9FXO6knEasATDABIP

**System :** Hearts of Wulin (Courtly Wuxia variant rules)

**Duration :** Four 3-hour sessions

**Breaks :** Short breaks at the top of each hour-ish (5-10 minutes)

**Venue :** Zoom

**Recording :** With permission from all participants before and after the session

**Attendance :** Attendance to all sessions is strongly preferred but not required.

**Safety :** Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.

This game will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the calendar posting and send me a heads-up. All-access sign-up opens on March 13, 1:00pm US Eastern.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 01:24:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-in-the-court-of-crimson-blades/6658.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hearts of Wulin: In the Court of Crimson Blades</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@David_S]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/david_s">@David_S</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is for a four-session run of the romantic melodrama game <em>, Hearts of Wulin</em> using the <strong>Courtly Wuxia</strong> variant ruleset, scheduled for 8:30pm US Eastern time on Thursdays in May. Prior experience with <em>Hearts of Wulin</em> or the Courtly Wuxia rules is not expected (rules will be taught during and throughout play). I will send out a group email about a week before the first session to confirm everyone’s intent to play and to provide set-up and invitation details. A fourth seat is being held for Shane of the Gauntlet community. You are a courtly scholar-warrior or noble (or uncultured emissary from the distant edges of the kingdom) who must not only navigate deadly duels of romantic passion and honor, but also brave the equally threatening world of court politics and social maneuvering as you sip tea, write poetry, and employ cutthroat cloak-and-dagger tactics to win the ruler’s heart–or claim their title as your own.</p>
<p>The game’s initial set-up and inciting incident will be decided upon collaboratively at the beginning of play and during character creation, rather than set a priori by the GM. A set of example story starters will be sent to players prior to the first session to give everyone a sense of the sort of directions a game of court intrigue can take. Whether dealing with a power-scramble following an assassination, the threat of an army approaching the capital, or the disclosure of a political secret that threatens to change the empire forever, players will take the role of nobles, generals, members of the royal family, ambassadors, or any other number of courtly individuals, as they fight to win love, seize the throne, or take revenge for old wounds.</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9E3jyfJFrPDUJW4Ly" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9E3jyfJFrPDUJW4Ly</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9Eq7Hi-t0vwM8Ipgu" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9Eq7Hi-t0vwM8Ipgu</a></p>
<p>Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9F8Xr5V8qOS8Mjhj5" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9F8Xr5V8qOS8Mjhj5</a></p>
<p>Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9FXO6knEasATDABIP" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MV9FXO6knEasATDABIP</a></p>
<p><strong>System :</strong> Hearts of Wulin (Courtly Wuxia variant rules)</p>
<p><strong>Duration :</strong> Four 3-hour sessions</p>
<p><strong>Breaks :</strong> Short breaks at the top of each hour-ish (5-10 minutes)</p>
<p><strong>Venue :</strong> Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Recording :</strong> With permission from all participants before and after the session</p>
<p><strong>Attendance :</strong> Attendance to all sessions is strongly preferred but not required.</p>
<p><strong>Safety :</strong> Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.</p>
<p>This game will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p>If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the calendar posting and send me a heads-up. All-access sign-up opens on March 13, 1:00pm US Eastern.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-in-the-court-of-crimson-blades/6658/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-in-the-court-of-crimson-blades/6658/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 01:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6658-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hearts-of-wulin-in-the-court-of-crimson-blades/6658.rss">Hearts of Wulin: In the Court of Crimson Blades</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
