<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Interesting games about forming and maintaining coalitions in a changing world?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892</link>
    <description>One of the options I&#39;m thinking about running is an interval/lead-in game for the next part of our campaign that is based around the idea of creating a new consensus between different political groups in a realm that has undergone a sudden seismic shift as a result of the current campaign. A chance for everyone to take a break from their characters and explore the world through some different sets of eyes and an opportunity to create an interesting ground for our storytelling.

Not sure whether we would run as one game for shaping the consensus - a &quot;meeting of the council&quot; type of scenario-  and another for maintaining/building on those decisions, one for both, or only play one or the other out. For the &quot;maintaining/building on it&quot; part my first thought would be to play *Kingdom* but there may be better options out there.

In terms of what I&#39;m looking for, something narrative-lead/low-crunch is ideal and it needs to be a game that can be played online by a group of five. Ideally something that plays out in a session or two and we have to be able to fit it reasonably easily into our established world, which is your classic fantasy kind of thing. 

Anyone got any suggestions that might work for this?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 02:14:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Interesting games about forming and maintaining coalitions in a changing world?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jesseabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jesseabe">@Jesseabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think this is a great opportunity to play some of Avery Alder’s games, if what you want to do is play out both the changes and the consensus building.  These games would work less well if you already know all the details of the changes.  With that introduction, you could definitely do this with The Quiet Year, playing out a year in a community that is undergoing/has undergone radical change.  It’s also a great premise for a no dice/no masters game like Dream Askew.  I don’t know if the game as written works for you, but a ton of derivatives have been made. google around you might find one you like.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 02:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2892-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892.rss">Interesting games about forming and maintaining coalitions in a changing world?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Interesting games about forming and maintaining coalitions in a changing world?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One of the options I’m thinking about running is an interval/lead-in game for the next part of our campaign that is based around the idea of creating a new consensus between different political groups in a realm that has undergone a sudden seismic shift as a result of the current campaign. A chance for everyone to take a break from their characters and explore the world through some different sets of eyes and an opportunity to create an interesting ground for our storytelling.</p>
<p>Not sure whether we would run as one game for shaping the consensus - a “meeting of the council” type of scenario-  and another for maintaining/building on those decisions, one for both, or only play one or the other out. For the “maintaining/building on it” part my first thought would be to play <em>Kingdom</em> but there may be better options out there.</p>
<p>In terms of what I’m looking for, something narrative-lead/low-crunch is ideal and it needs to be a game that can be played online by a group of five. Ideally something that plays out in a session or two and we have to be able to fit it reasonably easily into our established world, which is your classic fantasy kind of thing.</p>
<p>Anyone got any suggestions that might work for this?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 23:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2892-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/interesting-games-about-forming-and-maintaining-coalitions-in-a-changing-world/2892.rss">Interesting games about forming and maintaining coalitions in a changing world?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
