<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsterhearts 2: Kingsport 1876</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1876/2560</link>
    <description>**Kingsport is back for its one year anniversary!**
**Please give priority to players who have been in a Kingsport game previously. There is a newbie game in September.**

As the nation&#39;s centennial approaches, Kingsport is at the height of its powers: its merchants sail the world&#39;s oceans, its shipbuilders supply the vessels the young nation&#39;s commerce demands, and its fishermen have suspiciously large hauls. All around is activity, prosperity and an engine of activity.

If you&#39;re old enough for all that, of course. For Kingsport&#39;s adolescents, the summer looks like another long excuse in boredom punctuated only by routine chores. Perhaps the new Century Club being set up to organize the town&#39;s Independence Day celebrations will provide something to do. Although there are those strange lights people have seen hovering over Kingsport Head. And those strange circles that appeared in farmer Smith&#39;s crops...

Kingsport 1876 is the next chapter in the ongoing Kingsport series, which look at historical events in the context of HP Lovecraft&#39;s seaside New England town. I&#39;ll be running four Wednesday sessions in August 2019, exploring Gilded Age inequality, conspiracies, and some critical views of the American experience.

August 7th at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2NJEm59
August 14th at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2XV0duj
August 21st at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2LJlzV9
August 28th at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2LL8hY6

I&#39;m holding one spot for my frequent collaborator, the wonderful Seraphina Malizia. The total amount of Mythos content will be decided upon as a group. I&#39;ll provide the historical context as necessary.

This game will touch upon subjects including death, poverty, inequality, the unbridgeable gap between individual minds, and a certain amount of body horror.
Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. This session will be around 3 hours long, and I&#39;ll be recording it for inclusion in the Gauntlet video roundup. We will be using the X-card, lines and veils, and the open door policy. For more information on the Gauntlet&#39;s safety tools, please refer to our Inclusivity Policy on the website (http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:21:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1876/2560.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Monsterhearts 2: Kingsport 1876</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AviatrixCat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/aviatrixcat">@AviatrixCat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Kingsport is back for its one year anniversary!</strong><br>
<strong>Please give priority to players who have been in a Kingsport game previously. There is a newbie game in September.</strong></p>
<p>As the nation’s centennial approaches, Kingsport is at the height of its powers: its merchants sail the world’s oceans, its shipbuilders supply the vessels the young nation’s commerce demands, and its fishermen have suspiciously large hauls. All around is activity, prosperity and an engine of activity.</p>
<p>If you’re old enough for all that, of course. For Kingsport’s adolescents, the summer looks like another long excuse in boredom punctuated only by routine chores. Perhaps the new Century Club being set up to organize the town’s Independence Day celebrations will provide something to do. Although there are those strange lights people have seen hovering over Kingsport Head. And those strange circles that appeared in farmer Smith’s crops…</p>
<p>Kingsport 1876 is the next chapter in the ongoing Kingsport series, which look at historical events in the context of HP Lovecraft’s seaside New England town. I’ll be running four Wednesday sessions in August 2019, exploring Gilded Age inequality, conspiracies, and some critical views of the American experience.</p>
<p>August 7th at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2NJEm59" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2NJEm59</a><br>
August 14th at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2XV0duj" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2XV0duj</a><br>
August 21st at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2LJlzV9" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2LJlzV9</a><br>
August 28th at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2LL8hY6" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2LL8hY6</a></p>
<p>I’m holding one spot for my frequent collaborator, the wonderful Seraphina Malizia. The total amount of Mythos content will be decided upon as a group. I’ll provide the historical context as necessary.</p>
<p>This game will touch upon subjects including death, poverty, inequality, the unbridgeable gap between individual minds, and a certain amount of body horror.<br>
Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. This session will be around 3 hours long, and I’ll be recording it for inclusion in the Gauntlet video roundup. We will be using the X-card, lines and veils, and the open door policy. For more information on the Gauntlet’s safety tools, please refer to our Inclusivity Policy on the website (<a href="http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html</a>).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1876/2560/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1876/2560/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2560-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1876/2560.rss">Monsterhearts 2: Kingsport 1876</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
