<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsterhearts 2: Where Black Roses Bloom</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-where-black-roses-bloom/6625</link>
    <description>This is for a five-session run of *Monsterhearts 2* taking place in a Gothic Regency setting, scheduled for 8pm US Eastern time on Thursdays in April. Touchstones range from Jane Austen&#39;s upper-middle class idylls of pastoral romance to classic pre-Victorian gothic romances and horror tales. No familiarity with the game&#39;s touchstones or rules is necessary (rules will be explained before and throughout the game). I will send out a group email about a week before the first session to confirm everyone&#39;s intent to play and to provide set-up and invitation details. A fourth seat is being held for a guest from outside the Gauntlet community. You are a teenage monster staying at (or in the near vicinity of) a rural English Regency-era estate house who must not only navigate supernatural horrors and conspiracy, but also face equally threatening masquerade balls, garden parties, and countryside picnics.

*Shadowbrook Hall: home to one of England&#39;s oldest and most influential families. An idyllic haven offering respite from the hustle and bustle of London. A nostalgic refuge, where superstitious things like ghosts, vampires, and witchcraft could not possibly intrude.*

*That is, until you arrived.*

*In Monsterhearts 2: Where Black Roses Bloom, you have been sent to (or live at) Shadowbrook Hall, an estate house in early 1800&#39;s rural England. You may have any number of reasons for being here: a new servant, member of the reigning family, an intruding outsider, or the child of a family friend sent to pass the season in polite company. Our drama will emerge from the discoveries and conflicts that take place within and around the manor. While the setting is upper-middle to upper-class, characters are welcome to come from any social sphere.*

*Atmosphere, drama, and inclusivity will take priority over historical accuracy.*

﻿Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkX4zAGGOOlTD4Iji7

Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkXNwuuOLGaupskTzn

Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY-wuEpTFgamn2LAX

Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY4Mtb2cSoAcFvKLX

Session 5: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY9zk9cXtIeipZrCs

**System :** Monsterhearts 2

**Duration :** Five 3-hour sessions

**Breaks :** Short breaks at the top of each hour-ish (5-10 minutes)

**Venue :** Zoom

**Recording :** With permission from all participants before and after the session

**Attendance :** Attendance to all sessions is strongly preferred but not required.

**Safety :** Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.

This game will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the calendar posting and send me a heads-up. All-access sign-up opens on March 8, 1:00pm US Eastern.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 01:35:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-where-black-roses-bloom/6625.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Monsterhearts 2: Where Black Roses Bloom</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@David_S]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/david_s">@David_S</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is for a five-session run of <em>Monsterhearts 2</em> taking place in a Gothic Regency setting, scheduled for 8pm US Eastern time on Thursdays in April. Touchstones range from Jane Austen’s upper-middle class idylls of pastoral romance to classic pre-Victorian gothic romances and horror tales. No familiarity with the game’s touchstones or rules is necessary (rules will be explained before and throughout the game). I will send out a group email about a week before the first session to confirm everyone’s intent to play and to provide set-up and invitation details. A fourth seat is being held for a guest from outside the Gauntlet community. You are a teenage monster staying at (or in the near vicinity of) a rural English Regency-era estate house who must not only navigate supernatural horrors and conspiracy, but also face equally threatening masquerade balls, garden parties, and countryside picnics.</p>
<p><em>Shadowbrook Hall: home to one of England’s oldest and most influential families. An idyllic haven offering respite from the hustle and bustle of London. A nostalgic refuge, where superstitious things like ghosts, vampires, and witchcraft could not possibly intrude.</em></p>
<p><em>That is, until you arrived.</em></p>
<p><em>In Monsterhearts 2: Where Black Roses Bloom, you have been sent to (or live at) Shadowbrook Hall, an estate house in early 1800’s rural England. You may have any number of reasons for being here: a new servant, member of the reigning family, an intruding outsider, or the child of a family friend sent to pass the season in polite company. Our drama will emerge from the discoveries and conflicts that take place within and around the manor. While the setting is upper-middle to upper-class, characters are welcome to come from any social sphere.</em></p>
<p><em>Atmosphere, drama, and inclusivity will take priority over historical accuracy.</em></p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkX4zAGGOOlTD4Iji7" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkX4zAGGOOlTD4Iji7</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkXNwuuOLGaupskTzn" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkXNwuuOLGaupskTzn</a></p>
<p>Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY-wuEpTFgamn2LAX" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY-wuEpTFgamn2LAX</a></p>
<p>Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY4Mtb2cSoAcFvKLX" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY4Mtb2cSoAcFvKLX</a></p>
<p>Session 5: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY9zk9cXtIeipZrCs" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MUkY9zk9cXtIeipZrCs</a></p>
<p><strong>System :</strong> Monsterhearts 2</p>
<p><strong>Duration :</strong> Five 3-hour sessions</p>
<p><strong>Breaks :</strong> Short breaks at the top of each hour-ish (5-10 minutes)</p>
<p><strong>Venue :</strong> Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Recording :</strong> With permission from all participants before and after the session</p>
<p><strong>Attendance :</strong> Attendance to all sessions is strongly preferred but not required.</p>
<p><strong>Safety :</strong> Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.</p>
<p>This game will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p>If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the calendar posting and send me a heads-up. All-access sign-up opens on March 8, 1:00pm US Eastern.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-where-black-roses-bloom/6625/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-where-black-roses-bloom/6625/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 01:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6625-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-where-black-roses-bloom/6625.rss">Monsterhearts 2: Where Black Roses Bloom</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
