<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687</link>
    <description>The [Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace](http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace) is a Canadian focussed RPG marketplace. We sell both direct to consumers and to Canadian Friendly Local Game Stores. We sell both Print&amp;PDF and PDF only.

We pride ourselves on having beneficial policies for both publishers and local retailers.

From publishers, the Marketplace takes only a 10% cut which occurs after transaction processing fees, and any other discounts. This means that more funds go directly to our publishers.

For retailers, we provide a PDF guarantee for any physical books sold in your store to your customers, and we also have a “ship-to-store” option for our direct customers. Ship to store gives the customer a discount on shipping and gives the store a small credit.

At the moment we allow our direct customers to designate any Canadian FLGS to receive a 5% affiliate bonus on any kind of sale on checkout.

In addition to the above, we also provide publishers with assistance in cross-border fulfillment, which is particularly useful for USA based publishers looking to send product to their Canadian backers.

[details=&quot;**More Info for Publishers**&quot;]

**Here are the basics of Selling on the Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace:**

* We sell Print &amp; PDF, and PDF Only.
* Any print sales are always bundled with a PDF. We have a PDF guarantee for all our customers.
* Retailers received a 40% discount off MSRP. This applies before any other fees.
* Print material is placed on consignment, and you are responsible for getting your books to us. (We do have a USA shipping address.)
* CDG Marketplace takes only a 10% cut of all sales. This occurs after any other discounts or fees, transaction processing fees are ~3% + 30 cents.
* Payments to our publishers are made quarterly.
* All products are listed for you by our team.
* Prices are set in Canadian funds ($CAD), but customers can checkout with other funds. Currency conversion is automatically calculated.

Sales Examples

* A sale of a $10 PDF, would net a publisher $8.46
* A sale of a $20 book to a customer would net the publisher $17.19
* A sale of a $20 book to a retailer would net the publisher $10.20

**Fulfillment Services:**

We provide fulfillment services on Print books. This helps publishers with cross-border kickstarter fulfillment and ongoing direct sales within Canada. Reach out for more details.

Interested? Please [contact us](http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=information/contact). Currently, we setup all your products for you!
[/details]

 

[details=&quot;**More Info for Local Game Stores**&quot;]

Here at Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace, we love Friendly Local Game Stores, and we want to see you thrive. We are focussed on Canadian retailers, and primarily carry games from Canadian game designers and publishers.

**Benefits of Joining the Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace as a Retailer:**

* Retailers get a 40% discount on all our books, with a $10 flat rate shipping (or better).
* Get in hard to get titles without the hassle of cross-border shipping fees.
* Anyone who buys a physical book from you can receive a complimentary PDF from us (or through Bits&amp;Mortar).
* Ship to store: We list you as a shipping option for our direct customers. Customers who order directly from us can choose to have the book(s) delivered directly to your store. When this happens you earn 10% on the sale as credit to get other books from us, and the customer receives discounted shipping.

Create an account and [contact us](http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=information/contact), add we&#39;ll add you to the FLGS user group, or simply [contact us](http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=information/contact) and we&#39;ll set up the account for you. We&#39;ll also include you in our growing list of retailers

At the moment we allow our direct customer to designate any Canadian FLGS to receive a 5% affiliate bonus on any kind of sale.

[/details]

We recently started recording “unboxing videos” that explore the various titles we carry.

https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5sx-HHDKgg1oseNYQByGBUDYKgThjd47

My next post in this thread will highlight some of the titles on the marketplace, and I will aim to add to it regularly.

Questions welcome! I know there are a lot of indie game designers here on The Gauntlet, and we&#39;d love to talk about getting your games up, and what we offer.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 22:48:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jkitz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jkitz">@jkitz</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We have a bundle of new publishers! Several joined us after meeting us at fall conventions.</p>
<p><strong>we evolve</strong> - met at Tabletop Scotland, this UK publisher currently has:<br>
• <em>WILD</em> (Wake Initiated Lucid Dreaming) a tarot based dream spelunking game<br>
• <em>Gaslight Club</em>, a zine-sized game using the Mutant Year Zero engine about slowly realizing that your 1920s gaslight setting is populated by androids.<br>
• <em>Action Potential</em> a dystopian body-jumping transhuman forged in the dark engine game. Pull of heists and commit crimes in a hostile and unforgiving universe.<br>
Aegean, is forthcoming.</p>
<h3><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/we-evolve-publisher" rel="nofollow noopener"> we evolve </a></h3>
<p><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/25e88e5b7513668a205e2e3eaffe321d1c937885.gif" alt="composedreamgames.com" data-base62-sha1="5plULfeVEAfGCBbRoF2bXHQjs2h" width="75" height="75"> <a href="http://composedreamgames.com" rel="nofollow noopener">composedreamgames.com</a></p>
<p><strong>Parable Games</strong> - met at Tabletop Scotland, this UK publisher currently a number of titles supporting their <em>SHIVER</em> horror cinema RPG. Including custom dice, GM screen (handy for showing the doom clock tick up), the core rulebook, and a 5 adventure supplement called <em>The Cursed Library</em> .</p>
<h3><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/publisher-parable-games" rel="nofollow noopener"> Parable Games </a></h3>
<p><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/25e88e5b7513668a205e2e3eaffe321d1c937885.gif" alt="composedreamgames.com" data-base62-sha1="5plULfeVEAfGCBbRoF2bXHQjs2h" width="75" height="75"> <a href="http://composedreamgames.com" rel="nofollow noopener">composedreamgames.com</a></p>
<p><strong>Nathan Town</strong> - a Manitoba based publisher<br>
• The 13th Fleet (PDF) - A sci-fi roleplaying game of dark humour and treachery! The 13th Fleet is a light-hearted and occasionally co-operative tabletop role playing experience.<br>
A fantastic forged in the dark engine game, where you play incompetent backstabbing captains fleeing, er advancing backwards, from the nearly victorious battle.</p>
<h3><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/nathan-town" rel="nofollow noopener"> Nathan Town </a></h3>
<p><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/25e88e5b7513668a205e2e3eaffe321d1c937885.gif" alt="composedreamgames.com" data-base62-sha1="5plULfeVEAfGCBbRoF2bXHQjs2h" width="75" height="75"> <a href="http://composedreamgames.com" rel="nofollow noopener">composedreamgames.com</a></p>
<p><strong>Outer Edge Comics</strong> , joined after Phantasm Con, a Richmond Hill, ON publisher<br>
• Soloventure: The Warlock’s Dungeon - a card based solo play procedural dungeon crawler. Jeff did the writing, design and art.</p>
<h3><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/outer-edge-comics" rel="nofollow noopener"> Outer Edge Comics </a></h3>
<p><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/25e88e5b7513668a205e2e3eaffe321d1c937885.gif" alt="composedreamgames.com" data-base62-sha1="5plULfeVEAfGCBbRoF2bXHQjs2h" width="75" height="75"> <a href="http://composedreamgames.com" rel="nofollow noopener">composedreamgames.com</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 22:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6687-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687.rss">Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jkitz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jkitz">@jkitz</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>New Canadian Publishers to the Marketplace in 2021:</strong><br>
Here’s a run down of new publishers and designers who joined the marketplace in 2021. With comments on some of their products.</p>
<p><strong>A Smouldering Lighthouse</strong><br>
Has released their first 2 games this year. Both are GMless story-games.<br>
<em>This Spells Trouble</em> is a game about isolationist wizards making a mess of things when they go into the world, with a card for each of the spirits they can summon.<br>
<em>Faewater</em> is a one-page dark fantasy game about underwater fairies and the mortals they prey on. Both are free with a tip the creator option.<br>
<a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/A-Smouldering-Lighthouse-Manufacturer" rel="nofollow noopener">A Smouldering Lighthouse</a></p>
<p><strong>Alicia Furness Publishing</strong><br>
Joined with 2 titles.<br>
<em>Camp Flying Moose</em> , a powered by the Apocalypse game about a summer camp for teenage girls which probably has some monsters too.<br>
While in <em>Identity</em> you are a clone trying desperately to escape the corporation that created you. <em>Identity</em> uses the Wretched engine – you use a jenga tower, and a deck of cards and 10 tokens, and it is geared for solo play (but rules for more players are included.)<br>
<a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Alicia-Furness" rel="nofollow noopener">Alicia Furness</a></p>
<p><strong>Chris Challice Books</strong><br>
Chris has two free <em>Choose Your Own Fate</em> books, and a <em>Troika</em> based game born out of nostalgic love for old-school console adventure games <em>Oroboros</em> .<br>
He’s also one of the designers of Pendelhaven’s <em>Vanagard</em> and their adventure <em>Seith and Sword</em> .<br>
<a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/random-alien-games" rel="nofollow noopener">https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/chris-challice</a></p>
<p><strong>Random Alien Games</strong><br>
Creator of <em>Free Spacer</em> , a sandbox starship RPG, using their own “salvo” game engine. And yes, you can generate completely random aliens with this game. As well as random solar systems, planets and more.<br>
<a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/random-alien-games" rel="nofollow noopener">Random Alien Games</a></p>
<p><strong>Pendelhaven</strong><br>
Creators of an array of Runic Game System games where you resolve actions by drawing rune stones from a bag. Including <em>Fate of the Norns: Ragnarok</em> , <em>Vanagard</em> , and the newly released Children of Eiru (we’ll be getting that soon!).<br>
All games are deeply mythologically based. Those looking to get there hands directly on the mythology are encourage to get their <em>Illuminated Edda</em> , and <em>Celtic Cyclopedia</em> , or even one of their <em>Creatures of Fairy-Tale and Myth</em> for mythlogically grounded takes on monsters.<br>
<a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/pendelhaven" rel="nofollow noopener">Pendelhaven</a></p>
<p><strong>Broken Things</strong><br>
Broken Things joined with their game <em>Inspire</em> , a GMless story-game where you play a spirit hoping to become a god. “The kind of spirit that may one day become a god. Those other people around the table with you? Maybe they’re going to end up being on the same pantheon as you. Someone needs to be at the top of this pecking order though. That’s what you’re going to find out as you shape the first generations of this community, each spirit trying to be the one who saves the day, and ultimately become the head of your pantheon.”<br>
<a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/broken-things-games" rel="nofollow noopener">Broken Things Games</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 18:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6687-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687.rss">Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jkitz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jkitz">@jkitz</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Figured I would share some details on some specific titles. I’m aiming to include a title or two from most of our publishers, but I’ve probably missed a few, and add some more in future posts.</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/arden-vul" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>The Halls of Arde n Vul</strong> </a>, the largest OSR mega-dungeon ever, from <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Expeditious-Retreat-Press" rel="nofollow noopener">Expeditious Retreat Press</a>.<br>
C$109 PDF 1120 pages + maps</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Pod-Caverns-of-the-Sinister-Shroom" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>The Pod-Caverns of the Sinister Shroom</strong> </a>, the first of over 43 OSR modules in <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Expeditious-Retreat-Press" rel="nofollow noopener">Expeditious Retreat’s </a>Advanced Adventures line. If you love OSR, this adventure had a huge influence on it. I’ve personally run it multiple times, and love it.<br>
C$6.00, PDF black and white interior, 16 pages</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Free-Spacer-Core" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>Free Spacer</strong> </a>, a sandbox starship RPG about the crew of a commissioned starship performing contracts, from <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/random-alien-games" rel="nofollow noopener">Random Alien Games</a>.<br>
C$25 full colour PDF 354 pages</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Palanquin" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>Palanquin</strong> </a>, a one-shot RPG where players play either the Princess or one of the unusual figures who came together to escort her to safety, from <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_62" rel="nofollow noopener">Genesis of Legend Publishing</a>.<br>
C$12 print, C$7 PDF, 34 pages.</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/headcrushers" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>HeadCrushers</strong> </a> is a simple RPG for when you just need to crush a head to show you mean business, from <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_66" rel="nofollow noopener">Sword’s Edge Publishing</a>.<br>
$C6.50 PDF 45 pages.</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/the-quiet-year" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>The Quite Year</strong> </a> (revised burlap bag edition), a GMless map game about struggles of a post-apocalyptic community, from <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_68" rel="nofollow noopener">Buried Without Ceremony</a>.<br>
C$65 includes a bag, 40 page booklet, oversized card deck, six small dice, and 20 Contempt Tokens (shaped like weathered skulls) or C$10 for a PDF version</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_74" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>Choose Your Own FATE</strong> </a> adventure books for some entertaining solo adventures from <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_74" rel="nofollow noopener">Chris Challice</a>.<br>
Pay what you want PDF.</p>
<p><a href="http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/monsterhearts2-hc" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>Monsterhearts 2e</strong> </a>, a game of teenage monsters in love, using the Powered by the Apocalypse engine. From <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_68" rel="nofollow noopener">Buried Without Ceremony</a>.<br>
C$50 hardcover, C$34 softcover, C$13 PDF, black and white interior, 174 pages</p>
<p><a href="http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/After-The-War" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>After the War</strong> </a>, ten years after a galactic war, you are a survivor rebuilding on a frontier planet. Built on a modified Spark engine, it provides some narrative control to all players, and focusses on challenging and changing beliefs. The Spark engine is also in <a href="http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Sig-manual-of-the-primes" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>Sig: The City Between</strong> </a>, an homage to Planescape. From <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_62" rel="nofollow noopener">Genesis of Legend Publishing</a>.<br>
C$50 hardcover, C$20 PDF, black and white interior, 355 pages</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/The-Veil" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>The Veil</strong> </a>, a cyberpunk game powered by the apocalypse engine. The Veil itself is an part of the setting. It is the internet, and the virtual reality that overlays the “real” world. From Samjoko Publishing.<br>
C$45 softcover, C$19 PDF, full colour, 392 pages.</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/nefertiti-overdrive" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>Nefertiti Overdrive</strong> </a> mashes together ancient Egypt and over the top kung-fu action and you get Nefertiti Overdrive. The system here takes some cues from Marvel Heroic Roleplaying and lets you roll higher dice for describing cool action. From <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/Swords-Edge-Publishing" rel="nofollow noopener">Sword’s Edge Publishing</a>.<br>
C$30 softcover, C$16 PDF, print interior bw, pdf interior limited colour, 151 pages</p>
<p><a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/fox-magic" rel="nofollow noopener"> <strong>Fox Magic</strong> </a>, if you are intrigued by Japanese Folklore? Check out <em>Fox Magic</em> , from <a href="https://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=product/category&amp;path=60_65" rel="nofollow noopener">Fool’s Moon Entertainment</a>, where you get to play a kitsune of Japanese Legend.<br>
C$17.50, black and white interior, 93 pages</p>
<p>Happy to answer questions on any of these titles.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 02:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6687-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687.rss">Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jkitz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jkitz">@jkitz</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The <a href="http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace" rel="nofollow noopener">Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace</a> is a Canadian focussed RPG marketplace. We sell both direct to consumers and to Canadian Friendly Local Game Stores. We sell both Print&amp;PDF and PDF only.</p>
<p>We pride ourselves on having beneficial policies for both publishers and local retailers.</p>
<p>From publishers, the Marketplace takes only a 10% cut which occurs after transaction processing fees, and any other discounts. This means that more funds go directly to our publishers.</p>
<p>For retailers, we provide a PDF guarantee for any physical books sold in your store to your customers, and we also have a “ship-to-store” option for our direct customers. Ship to store gives the customer a discount on shipping and gives the store a small credit.</p>
<p>At the moment we allow our direct customers to designate any Canadian FLGS to receive a 5% affiliate bonus on any kind of sale on checkout.</p>
<p>In addition to the above, we also provide publishers with assistance in cross-border fulfillment, which is particularly useful for USA based publishers looking to send product to their Canadian backers.</p>
<details>
<summary>
**More Info for Publishers**</summary>
<p><strong>Here are the basics of Selling on the Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>We sell Print &amp; PDF, and PDF Only.</li>
<li>Any print sales are always bundled with a PDF. We have a PDF guarantee for all our customers.</li>
<li>Retailers received a 40% discount off MSRP. This applies before any other fees.</li>
<li>Print material is placed on consignment, and you are responsible for getting your books to us. (We do have a USA shipping address.)</li>
<li>CDG Marketplace takes only a 10% cut of all sales. This occurs after any other discounts or fees, transaction processing fees are ~3% + 30 cents.</li>
<li>Payments to our publishers are made quarterly.</li>
<li>All products are listed for you by our team.</li>
<li>Prices are set in Canadian funds ($CAD), but customers can checkout with other funds. Currency conversion is automatically calculated.</li>
</ul>
<p>Sales Examples</p>
<ul>
<li>A sale of a $10 PDF, would net a publisher $8.46</li>
<li>A sale of a $20 book to a customer would net the publisher $17.19</li>
<li>A sale of a $20 book to a retailer would net the publisher $10.20</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fulfillment Services:</strong></p>
<p>We provide fulfillment services on Print books. This helps publishers with cross-border kickstarter fulfillment and ongoing direct sales within Canada. Reach out for more details.</p>
<p>Interested? Please <a href="http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=information/contact" rel="nofollow noopener">contact us</a>. Currently, we setup all your products for you!</p>
</details>
<details>
<summary>
**More Info for Local Game Stores**</summary>
<p>Here at Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace, we love Friendly Local Game Stores, and we want to see you thrive. We are focussed on Canadian retailers, and primarily carry games from Canadian game designers and publishers.</p>
<p><strong>Benefits of Joining the Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace as a Retailer:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Retailers get a 40% discount on all our books, with a $10 flat rate shipping (or better).</li>
<li>Get in hard to get titles without the hassle of cross-border shipping fees.</li>
<li>Anyone who buys a physical book from you can receive a complimentary PDF from us (or through Bits&amp;Mortar).</li>
<li>Ship to store: We list you as a shipping option for our direct customers. Customers who order directly from us can choose to have the book(s) delivered directly to your store. When this happens you earn 10% on the sale as credit to get other books from us, and the customer receives discounted shipping.</li>
</ul>
<p>Create an account and <a href="http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=information/contact" rel="nofollow noopener">contact us</a>, add we’ll add you to the FLGS user group, or simply <a href="http://composedreamgames.com/marketplace/index.php?route=information/contact" rel="nofollow noopener">contact us</a> and we’ll set up the account for you. We’ll also include you in our growing list of retailers</p>
<p>At the moment we allow our direct customer to designate any Canadian FLGS to receive a 5% affiliate bonus on any kind of sale.</p>
</details>
<p>We recently started recording “unboxing videos” that explore the various titles we carry.</p>
<p>            <iframe width="480" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL5sx-HHDKgg1oseNYQByGBUDYKgThjd47&amp;wmode=transparent&amp;rel=0&amp;autohide=1&amp;showinfo=1&amp;enablejsapi=1" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" seamless="seamless" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-forms allow-popups allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox allow-presentation"></iframe>
</p>
<p>My next post in this thread will highlight some of the titles on the marketplace, and I will aim to add to it regularly.</p>
<p>Questions welcome! I know there are a lot of indie game designers here on The Gauntlet, and we’d love to talk about getting your games up, and what we offer.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 03:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6687-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/compose-dream-games-rpg-marketplace-canada-and-beyond/6687.rss">Compose Dream Games RPG Marketplace - Canada and Beyond</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
