<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Overdrawn draft: a method for rapid concepting</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825</link>
    <description>## Rationale


Sometimes you are caught with the need for a novel investigation without the lead-time to deeply read and internalise a new module.  Without specially designed tools, it can become easy to default to cliché and stereotype.


This tool rapidly forms the crux of a nuanced investigation without the &quot;mad-lib&quot; tendencies of other random generation systems.


## Method 


You will require a random oracle device (be they Tarot cards or story dice) and a grasp of the following acronym:


- **S**ite - the location where this takes place 


- **P**ersons - the humans involved 


- **E**ntity - the supernatural or extranormal incitement of the mystery 


- **A**ction - what happens when the previous two interact 


- **R**esult - what happens as a consequence of this 


- **S**uperstition - either some additional thematic depth, or a long forgotten resonance of the mystery (optional, but especially useful for vast and ancient mysteries).


Rather than rolling a dice or drawing a card for each heading, instead you **roll or draw nine symbols total, and draft from this selection**.  You cannot use the same symbol twice or reselect your symbols.  It&#39;s a case of looking over the symbols and deciding *which of these is the site*, and so on.  The process of drafting is key for thematic resonance.


Taken together, this can easily be boiled down into a **hook** and a **horrid truth**, and an investigation structure of your choice be applied on top (be that a linear thread, a node based investigation, or a reskinned Five Room Dungeon).


## Worked example 


Nine cards of the major arcana are drawn: the Sun, Strength, the Fool, the Moon, the Lovers, Temperance, the Chariot, the High Priestess, and Death.


- **S** - the High Priestess - a nunnery 


- **P** - the Fool - pilgrims 


- **E** - Death - ghosts 


- **A** - Temperance - a mellowing or lessening of the pilgrims&#39; souls 


- **R** - the Chariot - the pilgrims are taken to another realm, having been weakened 


- **S** - the Moon - a reflected inversion of their piety remains 


**Hook**: An acquaintance went on pilgrimage two weeks back.  She has yet to return.  This is merely one case amongst many this month.


**Horrid Truth**: Ghosts at the pilgrimage site have woken (why? perhaps a broken / stolen relic) and have been assaulting the pious through grievous dreams and visions.  The pilgrims&#39; spirits are stolen away and their bodies charged with revenant energies in a hellish inversion of their devout former lives.


## Other applications 


The draw 50% too many and draft procedure can easily be applied to other systematic ways of describing gameable elements - GRAPES for regional description (geography, religion, achievements, politics, economy, social structures), the 5RD (guardian, puzzle, drain, climax, twist), &amp;c.  The possibilities are considerable.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 09:41:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Overdrawn draft: a method for rapid concepting</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seanFsmith]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seanfsmith">@seanFsmith</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ooh, hadn’t come across Everway cards before — thanks for letting me know about them!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 09:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1825-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825.rss">Overdrawn draft: a method for rapid concepting</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Overdrawn draft: a method for rapid concepting</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes, I immediately thought of 5RD (Five room dungeons) as a great use for this. Everway cards if you can find them could work too.</p>
<p>It would be cool to create an app that people could submit their original content and others could use for this purpose.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 23:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1825-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825.rss">Overdrawn draft: a method for rapid concepting</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Overdrawn draft: a method for rapid concepting</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seanFsmith]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seanfsmith">@seanFsmith</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h2>Rationale</h2>
<p>Sometimes you are caught with the need for a novel investigation without the lead-time to deeply read and internalise a new module.  Without specially designed tools, it can become easy to default to cliché and stereotype.</p>
<p>This tool rapidly forms the crux of a nuanced investigation without the “mad-lib” tendencies of other random generation systems.</p>
<h2>Method</h2>
<p>You will require a random oracle device (be they Tarot cards or story dice) and a grasp of the following acronym:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>S</strong>ite - the location where this takes place</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>P</strong>ersons - the humans involved</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>E</strong>ntity - the supernatural or extranormal incitement of the mystery</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>A</strong>ction - what happens when the previous two interact</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>R</strong>esult - what happens as a consequence of this</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>S</strong>uperstition - either some additional thematic depth, or a long forgotten resonance of the mystery (optional, but especially useful for vast and ancient mysteries).</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Rather than rolling a dice or drawing a card for each heading, instead you <strong>roll or draw nine symbols total, and draft from this selection</strong>.  You cannot use the same symbol twice or reselect your symbols.  It’s a case of looking over the symbols and deciding <em>which of these is the site</em>, and so on.  The process of drafting is key for thematic resonance.</p>
<p>Taken together, this can easily be boiled down into a <strong>hook</strong> and a <strong>horrid truth</strong>, and an investigation structure of your choice be applied on top (be that a linear thread, a node based investigation, or a reskinned Five Room Dungeon).</p>
<h2>Worked example</h2>
<p>Nine cards of the major arcana are drawn: the Sun, Strength, the Fool, the Moon, the Lovers, Temperance, the Chariot, the High Priestess, and Death.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>S</strong> - the High Priestess - a nunnery</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>P</strong> - the Fool - pilgrims</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>E</strong> - Death - ghosts</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>A</strong> - Temperance - a mellowing or lessening of the pilgrims’ souls</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>R</strong> - the Chariot - the pilgrims are taken to another realm, having been weakened</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>S</strong> - the Moon - a reflected inversion of their piety remains</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hook</strong>: An acquaintance went on pilgrimage two weeks back.  She has yet to return.  This is merely one case amongst many this month.</p>
<p><strong>Horrid Truth</strong>: Ghosts at the pilgrimage site have woken (why? perhaps a broken / stolen relic) and have been assaulting the pious through grievous dreams and visions.  The pilgrims’ spirits are stolen away and their bodies charged with revenant energies in a hellish inversion of their devout former lives.</p>
<h2>Other applications</h2>
<p>The draw 50% too many and draft procedure can easily be applied to other systematic ways of describing gameable elements - GRAPES for regional description (geography, religion, achievements, politics, economy, social structures), the 5RD (guardian, puzzle, drain, climax, twist), &amp;c.  The possibilities are considerable.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 11:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1825-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/overdrawn-draft-a-method-for-rapid-concepting/1825.rss">Overdrawn draft: a method for rapid concepting</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
