<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bluebeard&#39;s Bride (one shot late October)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bluebeards-bride-one-shot-late-october/7429</link>
    <description>***One place in this game is saved for David S.***

In one version of the story, a young bride is wed to an ugly but powerful man with a blue beard. He invites her to explore the house, but one room is forbidden. Eventually, the young bride falls prey to her curiosity and opens it, discovering a gruesome display of prior brides’ corpses…

But that is only one version of the story. Maybe things will turn out better for you.

*Bluebeard’s Bride*  is a pbta game of &quot;feminine horror&quot; in the vein of Crimson Peak, American Horror Story and The Company Of Wolves. It deals explicitly with themes of gendered violence, abuse, poverty and lack of agency. We&#39;ll be using lines and veils, the X card and the open door as safety tools, and the game will run under the Gauntlet Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html.

No rules knowledge is required, and all rules will be taught during play.

The session will run over Streamyard, with short breaks on the hour. I&#39;ll ask if players are comfortable recording and posting the session, and will only do so with their consent. I&#39;ll send an email about a week before the game to share play materials, confirm attendance, etc.

Open access time for sign-ups is 1.30pm 29th September, AEST.

Session link: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MkVASSMIPfse84hc7o2</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 03:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bluebeards-bride-one-shot-late-october/7429.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bluebeard&#39;s Bride (one shot late October)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sandy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sandy">@Sandy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em><strong>One place in this game is saved for David S.</strong></em></p>
<p>In one version of the story, a young bride is wed to an ugly but powerful man with a blue beard. He invites her to explore the house, but one room is forbidden. Eventually, the young bride falls prey to her curiosity and opens it, discovering a gruesome display of prior brides’ corpses…</p>
<p>But that is only one version of the story. Maybe things will turn out better for you.</p>
<p><em>Bluebeard’s Bride</em>  is a pbta game of “feminine horror” in the vein of Crimson Peak, American Horror Story and The Company Of Wolves. It deals explicitly with themes of gendered violence, abuse, poverty and lack of agency. We’ll be using lines and veils, the X card and the open door as safety tools, and the game will run under the Gauntlet Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a>.</p>
<p>No rules knowledge is required, and all rules will be taught during play.</p>
<p>The session will run over Streamyard, with short breaks on the hour. I’ll ask if players are comfortable recording and posting the session, and will only do so with their consent. I’ll send an email about a week before the game to share play materials, confirm attendance, etc.</p>
<p>Open access time for sign-ups is 1.30pm 29th September, AEST.</p>
<p>Session link: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MkVASSMIPfse84hc7o2" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MkVASSMIPfse84hc7o2</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bluebeards-bride-one-shot-late-october/7429/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bluebeards-bride-one-shot-late-october/7429/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 03:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7429-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bluebeards-bride-one-shot-late-october/7429.rss">Bluebeard&#39;s Bride (one shot late October)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
