<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461</link>
    <description>While CATS (https://200wordrpg.github.io/2016/supplement/2016/04/12/CATS.html) will give people a good idea of what a given game should be like, it isn&#39;t very specific on what players will need to do to get there. Especially in light of discussions around GMless rpgs, but not exclusively, I think it would be nice to have a CATS-like framework for making sure people know what they signed up for, what a given game or gaming group will ask of them. There might be some overlap between this and explaining/facilitating/teaching the actual game? 

With help from the Gauntlet Slack, I came up with some rough ideas for categories and for what would be important to tell people upfront:

**Play**
- your character
- side characters
- how much of a connection must be made? 1st person? What would my character do?

**Invention**
- setting/history
- descriptions/events/locations
- scenes/situations
- characters/relationships/background
- react to a prompt
- flesh out a random element
- answer to questions
- judgement/task/scene resolution 
- interpretations 
- plans/tactics/strategies

**Math**
- move tokens
- dice mechanics
- stats

**Notes**
- making
- mapping

**Learning**
- setting
- genre
- rules/special abilities/moves/maneuvers

**Support**
- helping
- making space, especially in games without turn structure
- check in/use safety tools

There should probably be a way to highlight points that have proven to be especially difficult for people in play.

An Example:
Fiasco. In this rpg you play your character and might be asked to play side characters in other people&#39;s scenes. There is a setup phase to create your character and connect them to others, building a situation. In play, when it&#39;s your turn, you may choose to frame or to resolve a scene. On someone else&#39;s turn you might be asked to help frame a scene collaboratively. This will usually give everyone enough description to act in the framed situation as their characters would, so framing a scene will likely be the most difficult thing you&#39;ll have to do in Fiasco, especially since there aren&#39;t any prompts or random tables to use as concrete jumping off points. There is some light math (subtraction of dice results). You don&#39;t need to make notes since everything important will already be on index cards after the setup and because Fiasco is a oneshot game. The game mechanics are very simple, barely exceeding what has been said here. There will be a facilitator. As said, you might be asked to support other players by framing scenes and playing side characters.  

**Does supplementing CATS this way make sense to people? Is that something you already do and how? What do you think of the framework presented above?**</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 03:58:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t know if this is obvious: <em>length of play</em><br>
(i.e. how many sessions, length of a session)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/7</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 03:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1461-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss">Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gerrit]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gerrit">@Gerrit</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would add the following thoughts:</p>
<p>Does the RPG require reading (relevant for small kids and people who don’t speak / read the language of the game)?</p>
<p>I would extend the <strong>Play</strong> part by this:</p>
<p><strong>What is demanded in terms of driving the / a story?</strong><br>
<em>I’m thinking of what The Quiet Year is saying: our role is twofold: from the community’s point of view and to stir up drama.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>best for the characters / part of the world we control</li>
<li>antagonistic GM vs GM as moderator, fan of the characters etc.</li>
<li>Player versus Player</li>
<li>Play to lose / for drama (or whatever the better term is)</li>
<li>authority over own character / part of the world (“you will always be in full control of your character”)</li>
</ul>
<p>Actually, now looking at this, this seems to be a better suited format than what is in PbtA referred to as Agenda and Principles (both for players and GMs).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/6</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 15:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1461-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss">Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In <a href="https://sites.google.com/view/storyplaying" rel="nofollow noopener">Directions Storyplaying</a>, as you know I use the following <em>Story Margins</em> in the beginning to agree upon some common parameters:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ambience (bright - dark)</li>
<li>Realism (artificial - lifelike)</li>
<li>Dialogue (silly - serious)</li>
<li>Lethality (harmless - deadly)</li>
</ul>
<p>Especially the expected <em>Lethality</em> of a game setting is something very rarely discussed yet quite significant for the resulting roleplaying experience.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 05:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1461-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss">Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>/tangent please mostly ignore as it doesn’t really pertain to the thread</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="3" data-topic="1461">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/mathias/40/304_2.png" class="avatar"> Mathias:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>be bold so that the other players have something to react with</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is great advice. This often feels like the “sometimes take the spotlight” advice, but feels more concrete, and with reasoning why taking the spotlight for a moment can be helpful to other players. Just remember to give it up so other players can actually do the reacting! <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>/end tangent</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 14:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1461-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss">Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Mathias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mathias">@Mathias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Another example that comes to mind, as I am watching an Actual Play of it right now: In <em>Polaris</em> you absolutely have to lean into making definitive statements of what is happening. You can’t be timid about what your protagonist is doing because there is no one with authority around to confirm you. The game seems to (I haven’t played it but I’m dying to!) require you to be bold so that the other players have something to react with conflict phrases to!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 14:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1461-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss">Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Mathias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mathias">@Mathias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I like this a lot and I’ve occasionally included this. This came out of experiences where players clearly felt uncomfortable what a game was asking them to do… and often a discomfort because it was just a thing not in their wheelhouse; like scene framing, for instance.</p>
<p>Regarding the categories, I think they are good for reflection. For me they all tend to end up to revert back to “what play will demand”.<br>
So when thinking about what else beyond CATS you should be mention to set the right expectations, I like this list (but I wouldn’t extend the acronym by each of those categories).<br>
When I have done this, it was usually to indicate that a game specifically demands something of its players for it to work.</p>
<p>I can add some examples (CATS context shortened).</p>
<p>Here for <em>Songs for the Dusk</em> (version from December):</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Concept</strong>: Songs for the Dusk is […] about a crew of brave and compassionate adventurers exploring the ruins of a broken world and building a new world from the ruins of an old one. There are mysteries[…]</p>
<p><strong>Aim</strong>: We play to find out if the crew can truly build something good and kind among the teeming threats of warring factions, tyrant monarchs, […]</p>
<p><strong>Tone</strong>: This is an optimistic, hopeful game about […]</p>
<p><strong>Subject Matter</strong>: In Songs for the Dusk, magical realism, post-utopia, afrofuturism, […]</p>
<p><strong>Play</strong>: Songs for the Dusk is still in development, and it is Forged in the Dark.</p>
<p>While the text covers all the major points, is very fleshed out and Forged in the Dark games tend to be very robust in their base mechanics, we might run into situations where we need to find our own solutions and/or later revise rules/rulings, or adapt to a newer version.</p>
<p>We will work together to make sense of this in the fiction.</p>
<p>And the game is a Forged in the Dark, so it build on what Blades in the Dark and Scum &amp; Villainy have done. While it is very different in tone, it is very similar in the way it is played. Most importantly, everything flows from the fiction and back into it.</p>
<p>This means being pro-active, being curious and wanting to find out and discover in-play what your character is about is what the game works best with. It rewards switching from “behind your character’s eyes”-play to a more “writers’ room” approach and back, again, frequently.</p>
<p>This also means players get to ask questions, make up NPCs and frame their own scenes and be surprised by their own PCs.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Or for <em>Vagabonds of Yoon-Suin</em>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Concept</strong>: You are a group of adventurers following a substantial rumor about a some cultists that have hold themselves up in a place in the abandoned Old Town, west of the Yellow City.<br>
They are supposed to have come into possession of an Ancient Artifact that you (for whatever reason) covet.</p>
<p><strong>Aim</strong>: We play to find out if these adventurers can retrieve the artifact, how they will handle the cultists and if they can make their way out of Old Town with the prize and/or their lives.</p>
<p>We are also trying out Vagabonds of Dyfed and how it could be used in a typical sandbox setting, in this case with Yoon-Suin: The Purple Land.</p>
<p><strong>Tone</strong>: Typical hapless but savvy and capable adventurers exploring, conniving and fighting their way through dangers. Lots of random tables that will inform and inspire moment to moment play.</p>
<p>Yoon-Suin is a setting that is heavily south-eastern Asian inspired that leaves a lot of the details vague and to be determined by the group instead of presenting elements as straight real life analogies. It’s like how D&amp;D is inspired by western myths.</p>
<p><strong>Subject Matter</strong>: Cults and possessed people. Potentially unethical motivations in the PCs. Strange and unusual (for western fantasy) monsters. Fantasy fighting and the violence associated with it. Grave robbing. Greed. Death. Also potentially: opium and tea.</p>
<p><strong>Play</strong>: Vagabonds of Dyfed is designed to facilitate a fiction-first approach to typical dungeon delving/OSR-type of content. The latter means it’s about adventures that aim to be fun by focusing on player ingenuity and an unpredictability of events. To achieve that it asks for somewhat impartial judgement and openness to unforeseen outcomes (random tables galore!).</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Hearts of Wulin</em> example (I knew I had some players that were inexperienced with PbtA and came from 5e):</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Concept</strong>: In Hearts of Wulin players take the role of skilled martial artists in a world of rival clans, conspiracies, and obligations. Stories will be driven by the characters’ duties,romantic desires, and entanglements with other characters.Everyone has ties to factions, loves they can’t quite express, and secrets which will shake them to their core.</p>
<p><strong>Aim</strong>: We play to explore this melodrama and action. So, we aim at reactions and responses that are heightened; where nothing is ever simple and always something at stake.<br>
And while there may be factions, intrigue and shady dealings as backdrop, the game is about playing to find out about the web of relationships and the conflicts therein.</p>
<p><strong>Tone</strong>: By default character do wondrous things and fighting can be a conversation while otherwise drives, desires and emotions are often only spoken obliquely of.<br>
People believe things: if it it written down it must be true, a disguise is perfect until it isn’t. Embrace sincerity.</p>
<p><strong>Subject Matter</strong>: This is a fictional version of China, with the historical and cultural accuracy of a soap opera. We will be respectful of the cultures involved within the context of this heightened and fantastical space. There is a lot of fantasy martial arts and violence in-<br>
volved and fighting is a major part of character expression.</p>
<p><strong>Play</strong>: Hearts of Wulin is Powered by the Apocalypse and heavily mechanically inspired by Monsterhearts and Masks.</p>
<p>What this means for how it plays is that (almost) everything mechanically is supposed to flow from the fiction and back into it. So, players get to describe and roleplay their ideas out and it’s the MC’s job to call when mechanical “moves” have been triggered; we then follow their procedure and work the outcome back into the fiction. That doesn’t mean players are not welcome to be explicit about the mechanics they are trying to hit but that we will make sure how that is represented by something happening in the fiction.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These were the actual CATSP I gave out.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 14:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1461-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss">Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Julian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/julian">@Julian</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>While CATS (<a href="https://200wordrpg.github.io/2016/supplement/2016/04/12/CATS.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://200wordrpg.github.io/2016/supplement/2016/04/12/CATS.html</a>) will give people a good idea of what a given game should be like, it isn’t very specific on what players will need to do to get there. Especially in light of discussions around GMless rpgs, but not exclusively, I think it would be nice to have a CATS-like framework for making sure people know what they signed up for, what a given game or gaming group will ask of them. There might be some overlap between this and explaining/facilitating/teaching the actual game?</p>
<p>With help from the Gauntlet Slack, I came up with some rough ideas for categories and for what would be important to tell people upfront:</p>
<p><strong>Play</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>your character</li>
<li>side characters</li>
<li>how much of a connection must be made? 1st person? What would my character do?</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Invention</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>setting/history</li>
<li>descriptions/events/locations</li>
<li>scenes/situations</li>
<li>characters/relationships/background</li>
<li>react to a prompt</li>
<li>flesh out a random element</li>
<li>answer to questions</li>
<li>judgement/task/scene resolution</li>
<li>interpretations</li>
<li>plans/tactics/strategies</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Math</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>move tokens</li>
<li>dice mechanics</li>
<li>stats</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Notes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>making</li>
<li>mapping</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Learning</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>setting</li>
<li>genre</li>
<li>rules/special abilities/moves/maneuvers</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Support</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>helping</li>
<li>making space, especially in games without turn structure</li>
<li>check in/use safety tools</li>
</ul>
<p>There should probably be a way to highlight points that have proven to be especially difficult for people in play.</p>
<p>An Example:<br>
Fiasco. In this rpg you play your character and might be asked to play side characters in other people’s scenes. There is a setup phase to create your character and connect them to others, building a situation. In play, when it’s your turn, you may choose to frame or to resolve a scene. On someone else’s turn you might be asked to help frame a scene collaboratively. This will usually give everyone enough description to act in the framed situation as their characters would, so framing a scene will likely be the most difficult thing you’ll have to do in Fiasco, especially since there aren’t any prompts or random tables to use as concrete jumping off points. There is some light math (subtraction of dice results). You don’t need to make notes since everything important will already be on index cards after the setup and because Fiasco is a oneshot game. The game mechanics are very simple, barely exceeding what has been said here. There will be a facilitator. As said, you might be asked to support other players by framing scenes and playing side characters.</p>
<p><strong>Does supplementing CATS this way make sense to people? Is that something you already do and how? What do you think of the framework presented above?</strong></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 13:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1461-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461.rss">Supplementing CATS: What does a given rpg ask of its players?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
