<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Against the Vampire Conspiracy - Bucharest (1/3)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589</link>
    <description>&#39;Cam&#39; Duchamp, the former DGSE Hacker called for help when her partner went missing at the end of a previous Op. Answering the call is Jimmy Rook, deniable criminal asset for MI6, Sophia Manzanares, ex-Secret Service Driver, and Yelena Nikitichna Pushkina, who used to kill people for the SVR (and perhaps the Conspiracy).
After re-inserting the young woman Cam had rescued during that Op into the Conspiracy the team track her boss (and likely abductor) to an elegant villa on the outskirts of Bucharest. There&#39;s a creepy scientist, an armoured limo, and dangerous driving. Then, Yelena notices something odd about the limo driver ...

https://youtu.be/MIeQoEMF4m4</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 16:20:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Against the Vampire Conspiracy - Bucharest (1/3)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Against the Vampire Conspiracy - Bucharest (2/3)</strong><br>
We pick up with Yelena the former SVR Assassin confronting a supernatural Servitor in the front of an armoured limo, while Jimmy the former MI6 ‘deniable’ fails to intervene as expected. Meanwhile, Sophia, the team’s Driver, is incapacitated  which means that Cam, the French Hacker, has to get her hands dirty - which is when former Edinburgh Detective, Inspector Susan McLoed, arrives to help out. There’s gunshots, an explosive car chase, and an interrogation, before the next Operation begins to take shape … the opportunity to find out more about the ‘Van Helsing lineage’, by infiltrating a Club that’s the front for the Conspiracy in Bucharest …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="o2JiDUk6VWk" data-youtube-title="Against the Vampire Conspiracy (2/3)" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 16:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7589-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589.rss">Against the Vampire Conspiracy - Bucharest (1/3)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Against the Vampire Conspiracy - Bucharest (1/3)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>‘Cam’ Duchamp, the former DGSE Hacker called for help when her partner went missing at the end of a previous Op. Answering the call is Jimmy Rook, deniable criminal asset for MI6, Sophia Manzanares, ex-Secret Service Driver, and Yelena Nikitichna Pushkina, who used to kill people for the SVR (and perhaps the Conspiracy).<br>
After re-inserting the young woman Cam had rescued during that Op into the Conspiracy the team track her boss (and likely abductor) to an elegant villa on the outskirts of Bucharest. There’s a creepy scientist, an armoured limo, and dangerous driving. Then, Yelena notices something odd about the limo driver …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="MIeQoEMF4m4" data-youtube-title="Against the Vampire Conspiracy (1/3)" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 09:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7589-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/against-the-vampire-conspiracy-bucharest-1-3/7589.rss">Against the Vampire Conspiracy - Bucharest (1/3)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
