<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Lady Blackbird (one-shot)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot/2620</link>
    <description>I will be running a one-shot of John Harper&#39;s Lady Blackbird in August. Lady Blackbird is on the run from an arranged marriage to Count Carlowe. She hired a smuggler skyship, The Owl, to take her from her palace on the Imperial world of Ilysium to the far reaches of the Remnants, so she could be with her once secret lover, the pirate king Uriah Flint. Now she finds herself captured on the Hand of Sorrow. Can Captain Cyrus Vance and his crew escape? Will Lady Blackbird find her true love? What is a Snargle? Join me to find out, maybe.
August 24th https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjqtsZaP4ZNOjkzMZqA</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 19:03:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot/2620.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Lady Blackbird (one-shot)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JMCampbell]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmcampbell">@JMCampbell</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I will be running a one-shot of John Harper’s Lady Blackbird in August. Lady Blackbird is on the run from an arranged marriage to Count Carlowe. She hired a smuggler skyship, The Owl, to take her from her palace on the Imperial world of Ilysium to the far reaches of the Remnants, so she could be with her once secret lover, the pirate king Uriah Flint. Now she finds herself captured on the Hand of Sorrow. Can Captain Cyrus Vance and his crew escape? Will Lady Blackbird find her true love? What is a Snargle? Join me to find out, maybe.<br>
August 24th <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjqtsZaP4ZNOjkzMZqA" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjqtsZaP4ZNOjkzMZqA</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot/2620/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot/2620/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 19:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2620-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot/2620.rss">Lady Blackbird (one-shot)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
