<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Don&#39;t pay the Ferryman! Fantasy Espionage PBTA</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424</link>
    <description>Updated product on drivethrurpg - 

Don&#39;t pay the Ferryman! pbta rpg! clarified and updated with more Ectoplasm!

Espionage. Magic. Pogo sticks. Come for the Astral Space, stay for the Grue!

https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/235459/Dont-pay-the-Ferryman

any questions, feedback, comments - you are welcome to hit me up here or twitter @blakeryanbatman</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 02:14:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t pay the Ferryman! Fantasy Espionage PBTA</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The two main cultures of the setting are non-western european inspired.</p>
<p><strong>League of Free States</strong> : Aka The West.<br>
Peoples - Lots of Agamar (Lizard folk), Cyclops, Orks and Ranik (Frog folk). Some Dryad, Grakar (Pangolin folk), Kitsune (Fox folk), Lugat (Bat folk), Nekomata (Cat folk), Satyr, Tengu (Raven folk).</p>
<p>Cultural Notes :</p>
<ul>
<li>Archaeopteryx are considered sacred, cannot be harmed.</li>
<li>Buildings : Farms – Many corn fields and vineyards. Homes and Temples-Stepped pyramids. Theatres – open air, amphitheatres with weekly plays. Many pools and gardens throughout towns. Public bath-houses and marketplaces.</li>
<li>Caste System : Hierarchy of society is Sphinxes, Priests, Warriors/Sorcerers and then Workers.</li>
<li>Dead are mummified, goods buried with them in slopped pyramids. Organs stored in Canopic jars.</li>
<li>Every seven years the Priests of each nation decide on a racial enemy for the next 7 years.</li>
<li>Free market economy.</li>
<li>Lots of bronze tools still in regular use. Iron and steel weapons.</li>
<li>Most wear amulets, symbol of clan/god/animals etc.</li>
<li>Pass on stories and teaching by reciting tales and group songs. Written lore is on home and temple walls-cartouches.</li>
<li>People believe in good and honest life leads to reincarnation.</li>
<li>Public schools for 7-11 year olds. Learning Language, Religion and World lore.</li>
<li>Scarab beetles and Ibis are considered sacred. To see them near your home is a good omen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Xenek Empire</strong> : Aka Elven Empire.<br>
Peoples – Lots of Elves, Humans, Kitsune (Fox folk) and Nekomata (Cat folk). Some Agamar (Lizard folk), Dryad, Dwarves (Badger folk), Gnomes (Raccoon folk), Ranik (Frog folk), Satyr, Tengu (Raven folk).</p>
<p>Cultural Notes :</p>
<ul>
<li>Birthdays, Marriages and alliances are marked with giving of jade ornaments and jewellery.</li>
<li>Buildings : Farms – Many rice farms. Nobles have 3-7 level pagoda houses. Every house has a meditation room or Zen garden. Most homes have ceramic roof tiles.</li>
<li>Clothes - Conical hat, sandals, lose pants and shirt. Kimono for formal occasions.</li>
<li>Common food – Rice cakes, Ramen (Noodle Soup) and Sushi rolls (vinegar rice with meat), All meals eaten with chopsticks.</li>
<li>Dead are sent to the sky to become stars with funeral pyres, never burial.</li>
<li>Monks in Monasteries-Multiple shrines within. Summoning of Demons and Undead is illegal.</li>
<li>Most common hobbies are calligraphy, gardening and martial arts.</li>
<li>People of this culture have strong family ties have often all members of several families are allies for generations.</li>
<li>Shapeshifters and Humanoids are called Bakemono.</li>
<li>Warriors - Samurai practice bushido - What to do in war time and peace time. Loyalty to ruler, Courage, Endurance, Integrity, Duty to the truth and Honour.</li>
<li>Well patrolled roads, Agriculture-drainage and crop growing.</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 02:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2424-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424.rss">Don&#39;t pay the Ferryman! Fantasy Espionage PBTA</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t pay the Ferryman! Fantasy Espionage PBTA</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Updated product on drivethrurpg -</p>
<p>Don’t pay the Ferryman! pbta rpg! clarified and updated with more Ectoplasm!</p>
<p>Espionage. Magic. Pogo sticks. Come for the Astral Space, stay for the Grue!</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/235459/Dont-pay-the-Ferryman/../../../themes/dtrpg/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/235459/Dont-pay-the-Ferryman" target="_blank">drivethrurpg.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:326/500;"><img src="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/images/10875/235459.jpg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/235459/Dont-pay-the-Ferryman" target="_blank">Don't pay the Ferryman - Blake Ryan | DriveThruRPG.com</a></h3>

<p>Don't pay the Ferryman is a Fantasy Espionage roleplaying game based on the Powered by the Apocalypse engine, set in the</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>any questions, feedback, comments - you are welcome to hit me up here or twitter <span class="mention">@blakeryanbatman</span></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 22:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2424-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dont-pay-the-ferryman-fantasy-espionage-pbta/2424.rss">Don&#39;t pay the Ferryman! Fantasy Espionage PBTA</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
