<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Apocalypse Keys: Eurovision (three sessions in May)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-eurovision-three-sessions-in-may/6769</link>
    <description>*&quot;Your new mission might seem a bit unusual - you&#39;re going to the Eurovision Song Contest in Amsterdam. Stop rolling your eyes, and no, you&#39;re not going as contestants, what are you thinking, DIVISION isn&#39;t in the EBU. There have been ... incidents. Nothing too dramatic, a performer danced until his feet broke, somebody shattered all the glass on the stage, there were tears of blood and a ghostly voice singing out tightly kept secrets - but I think you deserve a less stressful mission after the events in Iceland, right? There are no volcanoes in the Netherlands, as far as I know. Please keep this thing as quiet as possible, it&#39;s very much in the public eye, so try to be subtle. And enjoy the show, if you find the time, it&#39;s going to be a blast this year!&quot;*

This is a game of Apocalypse keys over course of three games during April. Note that Apocalypse Keys is a game currently in playtest - it should run smoothly enough, but feedback is welcome and will be forwarded to Evil Hat. The game is about people who carry a powerful seed of Darkness within them, but are struggling against this Darkness - it&#39;s a game about heroic monsters fighting the Apocalypse (think Hellboy, or Doom Legion as media examples) and making connections with each other and the world around them.

Being able to attend all sessions is ideal but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.

No experience is needed; everything will be taught in the game.

**Venue** : Zoom

**Contact** : Players will receive an e-mail to check in about a week before the start of the game.

We will discuss Content, Aim, Tone, and Safety Tools in the first sessions. We will use Lines &amp; Veils, the X-Card, and the Open Door policy, and I will prepare a character keeper as a shared document.

The  **Gauntlet Code of Conduct**  will be in effect for this gam **e**  (https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html)!

Session 1 [date=2021-05-06 time=20:30:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;]: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8RCe2-dwUz0T-LyYJ
Session 2 [date=2021-05-13 time=20:30:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;]: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8ROa4Jbqdxf4YZhJj
Session 3 [date=2021-05-27 time=20:30:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;]: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8RXWvQJKvlqVTE2b2</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 18:05:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-eurovision-three-sessions-in-may/6769.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Apocalypse Keys: Eurovision (three sessions in May)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>“Your new mission might seem a bit unusual - you’re going to the Eurovision Song Contest in Amsterdam. Stop rolling your eyes, and no, you’re not going as contestants, what are you thinking, DIVISION isn’t in the EBU. There have been … incidents. Nothing too dramatic, a performer danced until his feet broke, somebody shattered all the glass on the stage, there were tears of blood and a ghostly voice singing out tightly kept secrets - but I think you deserve a less stressful mission after the events in Iceland, right? There are no volcanoes in the Netherlands, as far as I know. Please keep this thing as quiet as possible, it’s very much in the public eye, so try to be subtle. And enjoy the show, if you find the time, it’s going to be a blast this year!”</em></p>
<p>This is a game of Apocalypse keys over course of three games during April. Note that Apocalypse Keys is a game currently in playtest - it should run smoothly enough, but feedback is welcome and will be forwarded to Evil Hat. The game is about people who carry a powerful seed of Darkness within them, but are struggling against this Darkness - it’s a game about heroic monsters fighting the Apocalypse (think Hellboy, or Doom Legion as media examples) and making connections with each other and the world around them.</p>
<p>Being able to attend all sessions is ideal but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.</p>
<p>No experience is needed; everything will be taught in the game.</p>
<p><strong>Venue</strong> : Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong> : Players will receive an e-mail to check in about a week before the start of the game.</p>
<p>We will discuss Content, Aim, Tone, and Safety Tools in the first sessions. We will use Lines &amp; Veils, the X-Card, and the Open Door policy, and I will prepare a character keeper as a shared document.</p>
<p>The  <strong>Gauntlet Code of Conduct</strong>  will be in effect for this gam <strong>e</strong>  (<a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a>)!</p>
<p>Session 1 <span data-date="2021-05-06" data-time="20:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-05-06T18:30:00Z UTC">2021-05-06T18:30:00Z</span>: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8RCe2-dwUz0T-LyYJ">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8RCe2-dwUz0T-LyYJ</a><br>
Session 2 <span data-date="2021-05-13" data-time="20:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-05-13T18:30:00Z UTC">2021-05-13T18:30:00Z</span>: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8ROa4Jbqdxf4YZhJj">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8ROa4Jbqdxf4YZhJj</a><br>
Session 3 <span data-date="2021-05-27" data-time="20:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-05-27T18:30:00Z UTC">2021-05-27T18:30:00Z</span>: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8RXWvQJKvlqVTE2b2">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MX8RXWvQJKvlqVTE2b2</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-eurovision-three-sessions-in-may/6769/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-eurovision-three-sessions-in-may/6769/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 18:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6769-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-eurovision-three-sessions-in-may/6769.rss">Apocalypse Keys: Eurovision (three sessions in May)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
