<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gauntlet Calendar Sign Ups and Check Ins</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-calendar-sign-ups-and-check-ins/4348</link>
    <description>We’ve posted before about best practices for signing up on the Gauntlet Calendar. [You can see that here](https://bit.ly/2FWKNes). Generally folks have been really good about that. However I’ve had GMs reach out to me recently. One of our strengths has been reliability for sessions. We’re hoping to add new players with Gauntlet Gameways and I want them to have the best experience.

If you’ve had attendance issues, it’s legit to use a Check In system. GMs should be sending set up emails a week+ before session one: reminding players of times, sharing the character keeper, going over CATS. You can ask players to respond to your set up email to confirm they can make it. Put this in the first line of your email so this request is clearly highlighted. If a player hasn’t responded within 24-48 hours, send them a personal follow up. If they don’t respond to that within 24-48 hours, you should feel free to reach out to players on your waitlist.

It’s important to give players plenty of time to respond, given everyone’s hectic schedules. At the same time, if you have waitlisted players, you want to offer them the opportunity to fill an empty seat.

If you’re playing and can’t make it, it’s vital you drop from the session and give the GM a heads up. I know circumstances prevent this sometimes, but I worry about people when they don’t show up and don’t drop. For example we had a Gauntlet Facilitator Club participant sign up and be super eager about it, but then when the session rolled around they dropped out of contact. I’m still worried and hope nothing bad happened to them.

After the *Trophy* Kickstarter gets running I want to get the GM calendar alerts restored. I also hope to have more RVSP slots added to the Patreon. I hope this doesn’t come off as too forceful, but I want GMs to have some options in these situations. GMs: if you have players who have attendance issues repeatedly, please reach out to me. I can contact them to see if everything’s OK on their end.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 02:24:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-calendar-sign-ups-and-check-ins/4348.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Gauntlet Calendar Sign Ups and Check Ins</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We’ve posted before about best practices for signing up on the Gauntlet Calendar. <a href="https://bit.ly/2FWKNes">You can see that here</a>. Generally folks have been really good about that. However I’ve had GMs reach out to me recently. One of our strengths has been reliability for sessions. We’re hoping to add new players with Gauntlet Gameways and I want them to have the best experience.</p>
<p>If you’ve had attendance issues, it’s legit to use a Check In system. GMs should be sending set up emails a week+ before session one: reminding players of times, sharing the character keeper, going over CATS. You can ask players to respond to your set up email to confirm they can make it. Put this in the first line of your email so this request is clearly highlighted. If a player hasn’t responded within 24-48 hours, send them a personal follow up. If they don’t respond to that within 24-48 hours, you should feel free to reach out to players on your waitlist.</p>
<p>It’s important to give players plenty of time to respond, given everyone’s hectic schedules. At the same time, if you have waitlisted players, you want to offer them the opportunity to fill an empty seat.</p>
<p>If you’re playing and can’t make it, it’s vital you drop from the session and give the GM a heads up. I know circumstances prevent this sometimes, but I worry about people when they don’t show up and don’t drop. For example we had a Gauntlet Facilitator Club participant sign up and be super eager about it, but then when the session rolled around they dropped out of contact. I’m still worried and hope nothing bad happened to them.</p>
<p>After the <em>Trophy</em> Kickstarter gets running I want to get the GM calendar alerts restored. I also hope to have more RVSP slots added to the Patreon. I hope this doesn’t come off as too forceful, but I want GMs to have some options in these situations. GMs: if you have players who have attendance issues repeatedly, please reach out to me. I can contact them to see if everything’s OK on their end.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-calendar-sign-ups-and-check-ins/4348/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-calendar-sign-ups-and-check-ins/4348/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 02:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4348-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-calendar-sign-ups-and-check-ins/4348.rss">Gauntlet Calendar Sign Ups and Check Ins</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
