<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Macchiato Monsters: You Got A Job On A Garbage Barge (one shot)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/macchiato-monsters-you-got-a-job-on-a-garbage-barge-one-shot/7915</link>
    <description>One spot in this game is saved for a player new to the Gauntlet.

March 14 (the date of this session for me, although your time zone may vary) is Labour Day in Melbourne, a public holiday celebrating the victory of the local workers movements who were the first in the world to win an eight hour day. What better way to commemorate this vital union victory than with a horrible job for some desperate adventurers?

You Got A Job On A Garbage Barge is a zine/setting/adventure module by Amanda Lee Franck about an impossible garbage barge slogging endlessly up and down a vast river, accepting all kinds of untoward things in exchange for gas to keep the engines running. It’s less classic fantasy and more new-weird grossness. Things grow in the trash. Chemicals are leaching out of rusted barrels, growing legs, and heading out to seek their fortune. Beetles tell you their life stories, raccoons steal your pens. But it’s a good way... well, it&#39;s  *a*  way to make a little money, or get out of town in a hurry, and so here you are. Your first job: stop the gas lake from exploding. Good luck!

Macchiato Monsters is an OSR game by Eric Nieudan, which is an unfamiliar style for me (that I&#39;m excited to try out!) and I’m not real sure how it will go, so maybe only sign up if you’re okay with that some potential rough edges. No rules knowledge required, obviously, and you don’t need to know what ‘OSR’ means, either (although you should probably know that characters are fragile, combat best avoided, and player skill highly valued).

The game is likely to include violence and maybe some body horror. We&#39;ll use safety tools including lines and veils, the x card and the open door, and the session will run under the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct.

The session is listed for four hours to make sure we have enough time, but I&#39;ll aim to finish closer to three. We&#39;ll take short breaks on the hour. I don&#39;t intend to record this session.

I&#39;ll email players a week before the game to confirm attendance and share play materials.

Open access time for sign ups is 11:00am 7 March AEDT.

Sign-up link: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MxMIJBMSOs9FfkPyf_d</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 23:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/macchiato-monsters-you-got-a-job-on-a-garbage-barge-one-shot/7915.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Macchiato Monsters: You Got A Job On A Garbage Barge (one shot)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sandy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sandy">@Sandy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One spot in this game is saved for a player new to the Gauntlet.</p>
<p>March 14 (the date of this session for me, although your time zone may vary) is Labour Day in Melbourne, a public holiday celebrating the victory of the local workers movements who were the first in the world to win an eight hour day. What better way to commemorate this vital union victory than with a horrible job for some desperate adventurers?</p>
<p>You Got A Job On A Garbage Barge is a zine/setting/adventure module by Amanda Lee Franck about an impossible garbage barge slogging endlessly up and down a vast river, accepting all kinds of untoward things in exchange for gas to keep the engines running. It’s less classic fantasy and more new-weird grossness. Things grow in the trash. Chemicals are leaching out of rusted barrels, growing legs, and heading out to seek their fortune. Beetles tell you their life stories, raccoons steal your pens. But it’s a good way… well, it’s  <em>a</em>  way to make a little money, or get out of town in a hurry, and so here you are. Your first job: stop the gas lake from exploding. Good luck!</p>
<p>Macchiato Monsters is an OSR game by Eric Nieudan, which is an unfamiliar style for me (that I’m excited to try out!) and I’m not real sure how it will go, so maybe only sign up if you’re okay with that some potential rough edges. No rules knowledge required, obviously, and you don’t need to know what ‘OSR’ means, either (although you should probably know that characters are fragile, combat best avoided, and player skill highly valued).</p>
<p>The game is likely to include violence and maybe some body horror. We’ll use safety tools including lines and veils, the x card and the open door, and the session will run under the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct.</p>
<p>The session is listed for four hours to make sure we have enough time, but I’ll aim to finish closer to three. We’ll take short breaks on the hour. I don’t intend to record this session.</p>
<p>I’ll email players a week before the game to confirm attendance and share play materials.</p>
<p>Open access time for sign ups is 11:00am 7 March AEDT.</p>
<p>Sign-up link: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MxMIJBMSOs9FfkPyf_d" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MxMIJBMSOs9FfkPyf_d</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/macchiato-monsters-you-got-a-job-on-a-garbage-barge-one-shot/7915/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/macchiato-monsters-you-got-a-job-on-a-garbage-barge-one-shot/7915/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 23:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7915-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/macchiato-monsters-you-got-a-job-on-a-garbage-barge-one-shot/7915.rss">Macchiato Monsters: You Got A Job On A Garbage Barge (one shot)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
