<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683</link>
    <description>*Treasure-hunters seeking riches in the heart of the Kalduhr will frequently make a stop at Fort Duhrin, which is a half-day&#39;s journey from the terrible forest. Fort Duhrin is a bustling crossroads community ruled by a Governor and a contingent of elite warriors known as the kingsguard. What else do we know about Fort Duhrin?* 

@jesseross and I are putting together a standalone book for the Trophy RPG (the game and its many expansions are currently featured in each new issue of Codex). One of the things we&#39;re going to do with this book is include numerous tables that help flesh out the world Trophy takes place in. Keeping with the spirit of Trophy as a community project, we&#39;re going to be crowdsourcing many of the elements that go into these tables. 

Today we&#39;re starting with Fort Duhrin, which is mentioned in several places throughout the various Trophy publications. We&#39;re looking for 3 types of contributions to help flesh out Fort Duhrin:
**1. Personalities you might encounter in Fort Duhrin.**
**2. Ways in which the fort has been changed by its proximity to the Kalduhr forest.**
**3. Rumors heard about Fort Duhrin.**

You can submit as many entries as you wish, in any or all categories, by posting a reply here. By submitting here, you agree to let us use your contribution in the Trophy standalone book and PDF (you will be credited as a contributor). Submissions should be fairly brief (no more than a sentence or two). Here are some examples:

&quot;Jacol Pyree is the best fence in the entire kingdom. When something... unsavory is dislodged from the Kalduhr, he&#39;ll not only find a buyer for it, but will get it safely past the kingsguard—and all for an entirely reasonable 50% cut of the proceeds.&quot; 

&quot;A cottage industry of heroic, mournful songs about the Kalduhr—and the treasure-hunters who seek to conquer it—has sprung-up in Fort Duhrin. For a few silver, you can make sure your own bravery is immortalized with a verse.&quot; 

&quot;Rumors abound that the Governor himself is a former treasure-hunter, and that he built Fort Duhrin not in service to the king, but at the behest of something that lies in the heart of the malignant woods.&quot; 

![Darwaja_(The_Gate)|666x500](upload://g0IVNZQmrlPXMuCYVRS3zEt3UVA.jpeg)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:43:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Leonardo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/leonardo">@Leonardo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Roots regularly emerge in basements’ walls and they appear to come from the forest itself. If they are not taken care of quickly, they will take over a building’s foundations, making it crumble. It’s like the forest is trying to break down and reclaim Fort Duhrin, the place whose hubris defies the forest itself. Some townsfolk regularly cuts the roots off to avoid the collapse of the Fort. Unfortunately, those in this group seem to be under some sort of curse, as they age twice as fast as anyone else.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/37</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ostrichmonkey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ostrichmonkey">@ostrichmonkey</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>They say the stones that make up parts of the outer wall of the Fort, those closest to the forest, were stolen from some toppled ancient tomb, dragged callously from their home. The faintest of carvings, wards and sigils smoothed by time and rough hands, lend some credence to this story. That the stones are said to weep and keen in response to some silent call from deep within the forest, lends even more.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/36</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@steinea]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/steinea">@steinea</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>The Whipping Tree</strong>. There is a gnarled old tree rooted in the southeastern corner of Fort Duhrin that, when lashed, offers from between the great gouges in its bark a marvelous sap, restorative of many ailments. Some say, however, that it is when the tree weeps of its own accord that the sap is most potent and pure. But what restless treasure hunter can wait for the proof of such a tale?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/35</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@GroupSoliloquy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/groupsoliloquy">@GroupSoliloquy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Durhin Children’s Opera is run by headmistress Jonel. She uses the show to keep children busy, and out of the seedier parts of the fort during the summer months. Although the scripts are always of a whimsical nature, many attendees say the events on-stage echo their own expeditions into the forest.</p>
<p>Some say the stones of Fort Durhin were pulled from a quarry hundreds of miles away by the Governor’s orders. Others say the fort was found, not built, and has been occupied by every doomed empire known. Everyone agrees, the stones are not from here.</p>
<p>Beek: A lonely waif, a tawny shoe-shiner, a bedraggled, dung-smelling man, the sole shoe-shiner in the whole fort. If you need to know someone’s business, or where they’ve been recently, he knows. All Beek asks is for small promises in return. Just small, never inconvenient, <em>promises</em>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/34</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 16:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CiciOrcody]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ciciorcody">@CiciOrcody</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <ol>
<li>Nestled in the building farthest away from the heart of Kalduhr is the Mourning Club, a group of assorted townsfolk who take inventory of everyone who steps foot in the Fort. They memorialize the dead every Sunday, because who else would?</li>
<li>Every so often, treasure hunters are plagued by visions. Sometimes the sun is a little bit greener; other times a figure is seen walking the air. Whatever they are, they only last a second, and are easily passed off as tricks of the mind.</li>
<li>Rumor has it that the Kingsguard are barely holding onto their humanity. Kaldur has slowly siphoned away their souls, and one day they will be nothing left but monstrous husks. A more outlandish rumor states that the Governor has already suffered this fate.</li>
</ol>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/33</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 03:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CL_Bennett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cl_bennett">@CL_Bennett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>People say that treasure-hunters new to Fort Duhrin often complain of restless sleep and fever dreams of visitations from a great shadowy stag.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/32</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 02:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_Kershaw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_kershaw">@Joshua_Kershaw</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Initiates of the kingsguard, before they can earn their shield, must complete one final trial of strength and will. They must venture into the terrible forest, risking body and mind to retrieve a a token of fealty for the governor. Something of sufficient interest to please, or at least, momentarily ease the governor’s infamous bourgeoisie malaise. The horrors of that cursed place are reflected in the eyes of all kingsguard. It is the secret of their legendary courage. The kingsguard fear not death, for they have beheld fates infinitely more terrifying.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/31</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 15:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>They say on the south wall every seventh stone is notched so clean no smith’s blade could’ve done it. They say too that there’s a new stone notched each year when the new rains come. No one’s seen what’s did it, but the notches keep making their way around the wall.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 20:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>By the main entrance to Fort Duhrin, just a bit to the west, lives Hawthorne Wavery. Rumor has it that this crooked old man seems to know whenever someone falls victim to Kalduhr forest and builds a nice little kurgan next to his hut for the unfortunate fellow. Whether it’s true is hard to tell but each kurgan happens to coincide with him having a trinket or two to sell. A curious man this Hawthorne Wavery.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/29</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 16:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>At the back of a dead-end alley in the corner of Fort Duhrin closest to to Kalduhr, ancient roots emerge from beneath the crumbled city wall. The roots look sickly, but never die. When the full moon’s light shines upon them, you can see the faces of adventurers lost to the woods etched in the grain.</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>Ashlyn the clockmaker’s shop is a cacophony of ticking, jingling, and chiming. None of the clocks show the same time. They say that every time a clock strikes, the forest has taken another soul.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Visitors to Fort Duhrin often ponder why so little construction within its outer wall is made of wood: Imported brick and stone are expensive, and there are so many trees just across the river. But locals whisper of just what can befall those who sleep within a structure built of planks hewn from trees harvested from Kalduhr.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/27</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 14:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/signalstation">@signalstation</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Among the underpaid Kingsguard in Duhrin one may encounter lesser members of noble houses, especially from House Cliff’s Breaking, a House that prefers to enlist their bastard offspring in lieu of banishment, keeping them out of sight, in danger, and among those unsympathetic to their tales of highborn grievance.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/26</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 20:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rafaelbeltrame]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rafaelbeltrame">@rafaelbeltrame</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In the bowels of fort duhrin there’s a silent prisioner, kept for his divination capacities. It is said that he can show the future in the guts of a loved living creature.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 17:43:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_Kershaw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_kershaw">@Joshua_Kershaw</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>The Bad Penny:</strong> Well known among merchants and regulars of the Terraced Bazaar, a single copper coin of the smallest possible denomination carries a simple malediction bestowing the owner conspicuously poor luck. The curse worsens in severity and violence the longer one owns The Bad Penny.</p>
<p>Why not simply bury it in the ground or toss it down a well? Many a song is sung of those unfortunates ignorant of this particular precept of the curse; the misfortune is yours until the coin is taken <em>willingly</em> by another.</p>
<p>Nondescript in look, save for a few casual scuffs and scratches distinct to locals, it has become a cruel game among the denizens of the bazaar to secretly pass The Bad Penny during financial transactions or, better yet, to an unwitting adventurer.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/24</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 20:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasoncordova]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasoncordova">@jasoncordova</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For folks who had fun with Fort Duhrin, you may want to try your hand at The Rose District of Ambaret!</p>
<aside class="quote quote-modified" data-post="1" data-topic="2747">
  <div class="title">
    <div class="quote-controls"></div>
    <img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jasoncordova/40/2263_2.png" class="avatar">
    <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</a> <a class="badge-wrapper  bullet" href="/c/gauntlet-community"><span class="badge-category-bg" style="background-color: #92278F;"></span><span style="" data-drop-close="true" class="badge-category clear-badge" title="For general discussion of the Gauntlet community as a whole. (Not for miscellaneous/general discussions nor finding players.)  It is a place to discuss Gauntlet created content (eg. blog, Codex, and podcasts), give shout outs to wonderful members of the community, and the like.">Gauntlet Community</span></a>
  </div>
  <blockquote>
    Nestled in the great capital city of Ambaret is the jewel of civilization, the fabulous Rose District. Many a treasure-hunter desires nothing more than to be able to afford a lavish retirement there. But what makes the Rose District so special? What pleasures and delights await those who manage to survive their careers in the dark places of the world? 
<a class="mention" href="/u/jesseross">@jesseross</a> and I are putting together a standalone book for the Trophy RPG (the game and its many expansions are currently featured in each new i…
  </blockquote>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 17:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dsummerfield]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dsummerfield">@dsummerfield</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Rain is a slight woman far older than she seems. Normally found leaning over a customer in Squid Spit, the tattoo shop she is the proprietor of. Her prices are fair and she boasts her inks come from rare herbs - and other things - of the forest. The colors used in the tattoos are striking and the black is blacker than any other black pigment. Several of the Kingsguard have been patrons, but many folks do not care for her presence. Some adventurers that have returned to Fort Duhrin from the forest, both living and corpse, seem to have had the vivid colors of the tattoos she gave them “bleached.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 14:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Be careful on the South Road, the one that runs past the forest. Because, sometimes, when the forest is hungry, the road turns <em>in</em> to the forest…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/21</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 16:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@David_Schirduan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/david_schirduan">@David_Schirduan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>All stone in the fort slowly transforms to wood, requiring constant maintenance. And the wood has started growing again…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/20</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 16:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MattHaines]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/matthaines">@MattHaines</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Terkin Appledove is a quiet, unassuming man who strolls the streets, yards and courts of Fort Duhrin. In his hand he carries a short measuring stick and should he discover a hole he will test it’s depths. If the hole exceeds the stick he will make polite enquiries to unearth those responsible. And they will meet with a force sufficient to mend their ways. No one fucks with the Ditch Diggers Union!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/19</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 08:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>While this fad among young nobles is quite noticeable, what is less noticeable is the class of servants who accompany them: Quiet, friendly people with skin the colour of treebark and eyes the colour of needles, small but sturdy, uncomplaining and oddly alike. They carry the nobles provisions, set up camps and help them climb trees if they find that necessary. Not all come back, but most do, and in a week’s time, go out again. Yet they don’t speak, except amongst themselves, and they never tell stories.</p>
<p>It is said that Kalduhn has its own language. Scholars debate what it is, Ancient Kalduhran perhaps, or the tongue of the people who came before. Or maybe just the whisper of the air among leaves. There are no books written in this language. Only the forest itself.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/18</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 22:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A bizarre trend has been noted in recent expeditions leaving Duhrin. Young nobles have begun venturing into the forest on “quests”, laden with the most fashionable adventuring gear, elaborate ritual paraphernalia and a complete lack of experience. Each one boasts of how far they will go and what treasures they will bring back - but the few who return only shake their heads and refuse to speak on what they’ve seen.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/17</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 21:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MattHaines]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/matthaines">@MattHaines</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Old Auntie Gwen Doubleditch sells more jars of her Ditch-Berry Jam to visiting ladies than you had hot meals. But don’t you touch that jam! I seen what those berries prosper from and you best look otherwise for your sweet treats.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MattHaines]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/matthaines">@MattHaines</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>`Look out there, tell me, pay attention. What’s different? How many turnpikes did we walk? How many farmers markets and barn dances did we work to get here? Just look! New boots. Everyone here has new boots. So… where are all the cobblers?’</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/15</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MattHaines]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/matthaines">@MattHaines</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The best Portrait artists in the realm come from Fort Duhrin. The best pigments come from the forest. Want your mug on a locket for your sweetie? A canvas? Bring me back bark shavings from the South side of a river elm and a pot of clay dug from the heart of a storm struck beech and I’ll paint you fit for a King. Or perhaps a Queen?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/14</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 11:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Fort Duhrin</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DavidMorrison]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/davidmorrison">@DavidMorrison</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Augustine Silk is a wispy young man who serves as a valet. Gifted with the Sight, he used to make money on the side telling fortunes. The uncanny accuracy of his prophecies, though, means he has now turned his trade to pointedly <em>not</em> telling people their fortunes, for a fee.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 07:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2683-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683.rss">Trophy: Fort Duhrin</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
