<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Paws a game of touch, trust and feeling</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806</link>
    <description>Hello !
I have just finished the french translation of [Paws](https://dereel.itch.io/paws), a game where you play real animals talking as in the Fables. Not only am I super proud of the great accessibility and elegant central mechanic (a simple prisoner dilemma, really). But with some help here and there I can even say it looks good as a product. If you have downloaded the game earlier this week, you will see it is transfigured.

I am really excited that the game has been read by around two dozens persons already. That&#39;s not much but this is more than I hoped for, and an encouragement to work on the good looks of the other games that are coming out of my workshop. I am acquiring loads of resources (fonts, art) and making friends in the process.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 10:26:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Paws a game of touch, trust and feeling</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The shame I feel for double posting is overwhelmed by the pride I feel for what I have to announce. Not only is my goal for <a href="https://dereel.itch.io/">Paws / Patte douce</a> ten times achieved with a hundred of viewers and counting at a steady pace. But a customer (some people <strong>buy</strong> the game ! <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/upside_down_face.png?v=9" title=":upside_down_face:" class="emoji" alt=":upside_down_face:">) who is also an artist produced a beautifully crafted actual play podcast set in a precious casket of a blog post, an awesome and touching gift for me.</p>
<p><img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/blush.png?v=9" title=":blush:" class="emoji only-emoji" alt=":blush:"></p>
<p>I am overwhelmed by emotions and also definitely using the podcast for the promotion of the game ! I must make a disclaimer in all honesty : the table you can hear on the podcast is clearly well versed in ambient role playing games. They took the game’s proposition and ran with it gracefully.</p>
<p>You can follow this and other actual plays in french by Aregallia on his blog Subjoncticiel here : <a href="https://subjoncticiel.blogspot.com/">https://subjoncticiel.blogspot.com/</a></p>
<p>And if you’re an english reader curious about what’s going on in the ambient RPG french scene here’s a Gargle translation of the blog : <a href="https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;sl=auto&amp;tl=en&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fsubjoncticiel.blogspot.com%2F">https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;sl=auto&amp;tl=en&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fsubjoncticiel.blogspot.com%2F</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 09:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6806-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806.rss">Paws a game of touch, trust and feeling</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Paws a game of touch, trust and feeling</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello !<br>
I have just finished the french translation of <a href="https://dereel.itch.io/paws">Paws</a>, a game where you play real animals talking as in the Fables. Not only am I super proud of the great accessibility and elegant central mechanic (a simple prisoner dilemma, really). But with some help here and there I can even say it looks good as a product. If you have downloaded the game earlier this week, you will see it is transfigured.</p>
<p>I am really excited that the game has been read by around two dozens persons already. That’s not much but this is more than I hoped for, and an encouragement to work on the good looks of the other games that are coming out of my workshop. I am acquiring loads of resources (fonts, art) and making friends in the process.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 23:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6806-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/paws-a-game-of-touch-trust-and-feeling/6806.rss">Paws a game of touch, trust and feeling</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
