<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>OSR-mindset 5e oneshot dungeon — equal parts shark and whimsy</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633</link>
    <description>#### An ancient sink is guarded by glowing sharks.  They say the penultimate thief of time was buried there.

- **A gift**? Lassiclere, a high elf midwife (who helped birth a PC) is in town. She would love a rubbing from the headstone.

- **Pilgrimage**? The thieves&#39; union never mandates these missions, but good luck follows all that pray at the tomb.

- **Gentrification**? The sink houses a gam of sahuagin.  Drive them out and we can make better use of the space.

This short module is set in a wetlands environment near a city — perfect for your *Ghosts of Saltmarsh* campaign.  It plays out in a tight single session or a leisurely pair, and should take a group of level 3 PCs to level 4.

---

**Time Sink** is my first title for the DM&#39;s Guild - I&#39;ve otherwise written extensively of horror investigation and OSR absurdity.  **Time Sink** takes innovations from both spheres and will be a blast to play at your table, and again and again at conventions:

- the traps in the final location are randomly placed, lending it a roguelike air and great replayability

- there are procedures and guidelines to encourage player engagement and narrative focus

- there&#39;s a whimsical fishwoman trapmaker who&#39;ll feed the PCs secrets *and her roe*

https://www.dmsguild.com/m/product/291187

Happy to give comp copies away for listeners of **Fear of a Black Dragon**!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:36:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>OSR-mindset 5e oneshot dungeon — equal parts shark and whimsy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seanFsmith]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seanfsmith">@seanFsmith</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h4>An ancient sink is guarded by glowing sharks.  They say the penultimate thief of time was buried there.</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>A gift</strong>? Lassiclere, a high elf midwife (who helped birth a PC) is in town. She would love a rubbing from the headstone.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pilgrimage</strong>? The thieves’ union never mandates these missions, but good luck follows all that pray at the tomb.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Gentrification</strong>? The sink houses a gam of sahuagin.  Drive them out and we can make better use of the space.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This short module is set in a wetlands environment near a city — perfect for your <em>Ghosts of Saltmarsh</em> campaign.  It plays out in a tight single session or a leisurely pair, and should take a group of level 3 PCs to level 4.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Time Sink</strong> is my first title for the DM’s Guild - I’ve otherwise written extensively of horror investigation and OSR absurdity.  <strong>Time Sink</strong> takes innovations from both spheres and will be a blast to play at your table, and again and again at conventions:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>the traps in the final location are randomly placed, lending it a roguelike air and great replayability</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>there are procedures and guidelines to encourage player engagement and narrative focus</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>there’s a whimsical fishwoman trapmaker who’ll feed the PCs secrets <em>and her roe</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.dmsguild.com/m/product/291187" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.dmsguild.com/m/product/291187</a></p>
<p>Happy to give comp copies away for listeners of <strong>Fear of a Black Dragon</strong>!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3633-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633.rss">OSR-mindset 5e oneshot dungeon — equal parts shark and whimsy</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
