<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Slug Blaster Turbo 2-Shot</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/slug-blaster-turbo-2-shot/8178</link>
    <description>July 13 and 20 8AM EDT

Open access time for signups is 6/30 1PM EDT

This is a two-shot of Slugblaster Turbo. You will be playing a crew of teenage hoverboarders trying to make a name for yourselves in the world of slugblasting. Will you be a gutsy rich kid with a pair of signature jet shoes? A chill loser with a lovable robot sidekick and strict parents? A meta-dimensional princess with a negafriction katana? Mix and match elements to craft your character.

Attendance at both sessions is strongly encouraged; if possible please sign up for both halves.

Touchstones: Saturday morning cartoons, Infinity train, Big Hero 6, Sk8 the Infinity, The Goofy Movie, Tony Hawk Pro Skater

Duration: 2 sessions, 3 hours each, with short breaks on the hour.

Number of Players: 3 players. One spot is reserved for a player outside of the Gauntlet Community.

Content Warning: PG-13, Teens getting injured, teen angst and emotional turbulence, possible teen romance if desired.

Saftey Tools: Lines &amp; Veils, The X-Card, and an Open Door policy. All of which will be explained before the session. It will be run under the [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html))

The Pitch: In the small town of Hillview, teenage hoverboarders sneak into other dimensions to explore, film tricks, go viral, and get away from the problems at home. It’s dangerous. It’s stupid. It’s got parent groups in a panic. And it’s the coolest thing ever. This is Slugblaster Turbo. Just because you&#39;ve only been doing this two or three weeks, everyone thinks you&#39;re posers! Make a video, win a contest, or do something else to prove them wrong and get the scene&#39;s attention.

Rules: Slugblaster Turbo is a rules-light ttrpg designed specifically for one-shots and online play. It uses a stripped-down version of the [Forged in the Dark](https://bladesinthedark.com/node/33) engine, modified to power looking cool, doing tricks, and fast-paced laser-fantasy action in general. No familiarity with Slugblaster or Forged in the Dark rules is needed to play. All rules will be taught during the session.

Venue: Zoom. The session will not be recorded.

Contact: Players will receive an email about a week before the first session to confirm the commitment and receive links to play materials.

If you sign-up and your availability changes, remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N5fCGNgS2vXiNvhDwmP

Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N5fCa0wzhR1UK7wfg8i</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 17:39:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/slug-blaster-turbo-2-shot/8178.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Slug Blaster Turbo 2-Shot</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_Dungca]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_dungca">@Paul_Dungca</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>July 13 and 20 8AM EDT</p>
<p>Open access time for signups is 6/30 1PM EDT</p>
<p>This is a two-shot of Slugblaster Turbo. You will be playing a crew of teenage hoverboarders trying to make a name for yourselves in the world of slugblasting. Will you be a gutsy rich kid with a pair of signature jet shoes? A chill loser with a lovable robot sidekick and strict parents? A meta-dimensional princess with a negafriction katana? Mix and match elements to craft your character.</p>
<p>Attendance at both sessions is strongly encouraged; if possible please sign up for both halves.</p>
<p>Touchstones: Saturday morning cartoons, Infinity train, Big Hero 6, Sk8 the Infinity, The Goofy Movie, Tony Hawk Pro Skater</p>
<p>Duration: 2 sessions, 3 hours each, with short breaks on the hour.</p>
<p>Number of Players: 3 players. One spot is reserved for a player outside of the Gauntlet Community.</p>
<p>Content Warning: PG-13, Teens getting injured, teen angst and emotional turbulence, possible teen romance if desired.</p>
<p>Saftey Tools: Lines &amp; Veils, The X-Card, and an Open Door policy. All of which will be explained before the session. It will be run under the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a>)</p>
<p>The Pitch: In the small town of Hillview, teenage hoverboarders sneak into other dimensions to explore, film tricks, go viral, and get away from the problems at home. It’s dangerous. It’s stupid. It’s got parent groups in a panic. And it’s the coolest thing ever. This is Slugblaster Turbo. Just because you’ve only been doing this two or three weeks, everyone thinks you’re posers! Make a video, win a contest, or do something else to prove them wrong and get the scene’s attention.</p>
<p>Rules: Slugblaster Turbo is a rules-light ttrpg designed specifically for one-shots and online play. It uses a stripped-down version of the <a href="https://bladesinthedark.com/node/33" rel="nofollow noopener">Forged in the Dark</a> engine, modified to power looking cool, doing tricks, and fast-paced laser-fantasy action in general. No familiarity with Slugblaster or Forged in the Dark rules is needed to play. All rules will be taught during the session.</p>
<p>Venue: Zoom. The session will not be recorded.</p>
<p>Contact: Players will receive an email about a week before the first session to confirm the commitment and receive links to play materials.</p>
<p>If you sign-up and your availability changes, remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N5fCGNgS2vXiNvhDwmP" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N5fCGNgS2vXiNvhDwmP</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N5fCa0wzhR1UK7wfg8i" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N5fCa0wzhR1UK7wfg8i</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/slug-blaster-turbo-2-shot/8178/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/slug-blaster-turbo-2-shot/8178/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 16:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8178-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/slug-blaster-turbo-2-shot/8178.rss">Slug Blaster Turbo 2-Shot</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
