<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gauntlet Community Open Gaming: REGISTRATION OPENS TODAY</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-community-open-gaming-registration-opens-today/8365</link>
    <description>Registration OPENS Tuesday Sept 6th at 1200 US Eastern. 
GCOG&#39;s our FREE online ttrpg convention-- anyone&#39;s welcome to come and try it out. It runs September 22nd through 25h. It&#39;s focused on showing off indie &amp; story games, introducing new players to online play, demo&#39;ing best practices for games and safety.

Register here: https://gauntlet-con.firebaseapp.com/events
Find out more about that here: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/gauntlet-community-open-gaming.html

***Important: If you see someone posting anywhere (Twitter, forums, a Discord, etc) that they&#39;re having trouble registering-- please tell me. 99% of the time it is because they just signed up on the GCOG Calendar. Because of the way it is set up I have manually click their name to approve them to register.*** 

***I loathe this set up, but it is what it is.***

***I usually try to swoop through and check for new names throughout the day, but sometimes I don&#39;t get through fast enough and someone is left hanging. If you see this happen, please message me here or email gauntletcommunity@gmail.com.***</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 13:47:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Announcements</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-community-open-gaming-registration-opens-today/8365.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Gauntlet Community Open Gaming: REGISTRATION OPENS TODAY</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Registration OPENS Tuesday Sept 6th at 1200 US Eastern.<br>
GCOG’s our FREE online ttrpg convention-- anyone’s welcome to come and try it out. It runs September 22nd through 25h. It’s focused on showing off indie &amp; story games, introducing new players to online play, demo’ing best practices for games and safety.</p>
<p>Register here: <a href="https://gauntlet-con.firebaseapp.com/events">https://gauntlet-con.firebaseapp.com/events</a><br>
Find out more about that here: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/gauntlet-community-open-gaming.html">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/gauntlet-community-open-gaming.html</a></p>
<p><em><strong>Important: If you see someone posting anywhere (Twitter, forums, a Discord, etc) that they’re having trouble registering-- please tell me. 99% of the time it is because they just signed up on the GCOG Calendar. Because of the way it is set up I have manually click their name to approve them to register.</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>I loathe this set up, but it is what it is.</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>I usually try to swoop through and check for new names throughout the day, but sometimes I don’t get through fast enough and someone is left hanging. If you see this happen, please message me here or email <a href="mailto:gauntletcommunity@gmail.com">gauntletcommunity@gmail.com</a>.</strong></em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-community-open-gaming-registration-opens-today/8365/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-community-open-gaming-registration-opens-today/8365/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 02:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8365-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-community-open-gaming-registration-opens-today/8365.rss">Gauntlet Community Open Gaming: REGISTRATION OPENS TODAY</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
