<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback for The Elementalist, a Dungeon World class</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569</link>
    <description>Hey there! I&#39;ve been working on a custom class for Dungeon World, and I&#39;ve got it to a point where I&#39;m quite happy with it, at least in theory. Here&#39;s the short blurb I wrote for it:

[quote]
You used to be like the rest of the commoners, going about your majorly inconsequential life every day until one day you would die. But that is no longer the case. One day, someway, somehow, your potential became known and too great to be ignored. Whether in a destructive display of the forces at work within, or a quieter slip away from those you might hurt, you had to leave that life behind. Perhaps you were born for greatness, with destiny etched in lights above your little head. Or maybe it&#39;s a curse from a warlock, generations past and thought broken. No matter the reason, the result is the same: you live with a raging battle of the forces of nature taking place in your very soul. Will you tame the elements within, and bend them to your will? Or will you let the battle engulf you, with the elements themselves spraying forth from your very being? Well, I suppose you&#39;ll find out soon enough.
[/quote]
I&#39;m but one person, so my own playtesting is going to be slow and not the best in terms of varied information. I&#39;d really appreciate it if you would take some time out of your days and look over the playbook, and leave your thoughts and suggestions in the replies, over DM, or through the simple form I made. Thank you again for your time!

https://drive.google.com/file/d/10w8zX2HOlAfUIgOTg64X-5eg6DG8uxzC/view?usp=sharing
https://forms.gle/4PTc5Qt7dwcJ4Xns5</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 19:31:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Feedback for The Elementalist, a Dungeon World class</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@STEPHINFECTION]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stephinfection">@STEPHINFECTION</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello! I’ve updated the class, and felt it pertinent to update this post as well.<br>
The changes made are as follows;</p>
<ul>
<li>Changed the <em>Wind</em> option for the Elemental Soul move to <em>Water</em>, updated passive ability, and look to reflect the change.</li>
<li>Changed the passive look text of the <em>Storm</em> option for the Elemental Soul move.</li>
</ul>
<p>You should see these changes reflected in the document linked above, if not please let me know!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 19:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7569-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569.rss">Feedback for The Elementalist, a Dungeon World class</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Feedback for The Elementalist, a Dungeon World class</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@STEPHINFECTION]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stephinfection">@STEPHINFECTION</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hey there! I’ve been working on a custom class for Dungeon World, and I’ve got it to a point where I’m quite happy with it, at least in theory. Here’s the short blurb I wrote for it:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group">
<blockquote>
<p>You used to be like the rest of the commoners, going about your majorly inconsequential life every day until one day you would die. But that is no longer the case. One day, someway, somehow, your potential became known and too great to be ignored. Whether in a destructive display of the forces at work within, or a quieter slip away from those you might hurt, you had to leave that life behind. Perhaps you were born for greatness, with destiny etched in lights above your little head. Or maybe it’s a curse from a warlock, generations past and thought broken. No matter the reason, the result is the same: you live with a raging battle of the forces of nature taking place in your very soul. Will you tame the elements within, and bend them to your will? Or will you let the battle engulf you, with the elements themselves spraying forth from your very being? Well, I suppose you’ll find out soon enough.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’m but one person, so my own playtesting is going to be slow and not the best in terms of varied information. I’d really appreciate it if you would take some time out of your days and look over the playbook, and leave your thoughts and suggestions in the replies, over DM, or through the simple form I made. Thank you again for your time!</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/10w8zX2HOlAfUIgOTg64X-5eg6DG8uxzC/view?usp=sharing" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://drive.google.com/file/d/10w8zX2HOlAfUIgOTg64X-5eg6DG8uxzC/view?usp=sharing</a><br>
<aside class="onebox googledocs">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwR0x4N_x1ITqxzSsDqkSC6f8Or6JlhqprqYPL5qJ1rNggeA/viewform?usp=send_form" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">docs.google.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwR0x4N_x1ITqxzSsDqkSC6f8Or6JlhqprqYPL5qJ1rNggeA/viewform?usp=send_form" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><span class="googledocs-onebox-logo g-forms-logo"></span></a>

<h3><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfwR0x4N_x1ITqxzSsDqkSC6f8Or6JlhqprqYPL5qJ1rNggeA/viewform?usp=send_form" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">The Elementalist Feedback</a></h3>

<p>Thank you so much for trying out the playbook, please let me know what you liked and/or disliked about the class, and if you have any suggestions for how to improve it! &lt;3</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 02:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7569-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-the-elementalist-a-dungeon-world-class/7569.rss">Feedback for The Elementalist, a Dungeon World class</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
