<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Murder Hobo: Brave Adventurers Wanted!</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/murder-hobo-brave-adventurers-wanted/5036</link>
    <description>*Welcome to Gauntlet City, home of the famed Dark Dungeon! Well, it&#39;s more of a town really. Enjoy the sights, the Thieves&#39; Guild just put in a bowling alley. Look, we&#39;re villager NPCs, none of us are higher than level 4, don&#39;t expect too much. Anyway, you look like tough adventures, I&#39;m sure you&#39;ll kill the dreaded black dragon in a trice—no, that&#39;s not another word for &quot;a dungeon&quot;, a &quot;trice&quot; is, umm, a really short period of time.*

*A tavern? Why, of course we&#39;ve got a tavern! One-Eyed Cole hangs out there, he&#39;s our local law enforcement. And Gerda, the bar maid, is wink wink popular with out-of-towners. Yes, I said &quot;wink wink&quot; out loud, we&#39;re not noted for subtlety in these parts, if you want subtlety go to Obviously Fake Name City a few towns over.*

**Murder Hobo** is a freeform storytelling RPG about what adventurers do in between adventures. Fighting monsters is scary, but hanging out in the Black Dragon Tavern telling tall tales? That&#39;s easy and fun and involves copious amounts of alcohol.

No knowledge of the rules in necessary. No preparation, either. Some knowledge of fantasy RPG stereotypes is helpful, but honestly you can pretty much wing it. Just show up and play.

We will be using the X-Card, the Open Table policy, and Lines and Veils as safety tools. Tone will be light-hearted and silly, probably somewhere from PG to PG-13.

Session will be run with Zoom and will be recorded if all players consent. This is a one-shot with a flexible running time, I will call the last scene around the three-hour mark.

Sunday, May 3, 2:30pm EST: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M5NYRCzkxWoLPtTrMpw

[date=2020-05-03 time=14:30:00 timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;]: [https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M5NYRCzkxWoLPtTrMpw](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M5NYRCzkxWoLPtTrMpw)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:15:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/murder-hobo-brave-adventurers-wanted/5036.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Murder Hobo: Brave Adventurers Wanted!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@stevendj]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stevendj">@stevendj</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Welcome to Gauntlet City, home of the famed Dark Dungeon! Well, it’s more of a town really. Enjoy the sights, the Thieves’ Guild just put in a bowling alley. Look, we’re villager NPCs, none of us are higher than level 4, don’t expect too much. Anyway, you look like tough adventures, I’m sure you’ll kill the dreaded black dragon in a trice—no, that’s not another word for “a dungeon”, a “trice” is, umm, a really short period of time.</em></p>
<p><em>A tavern? Why, of course we’ve got a tavern! One-Eyed Cole hangs out there, he’s our local law enforcement. And Gerda, the bar maid, is wink wink popular with out-of-towners. Yes, I said “wink wink” out loud, we’re not noted for subtlety in these parts, if you want subtlety go to Obviously Fake Name City a few towns over.</em></p>
<p><strong>Murder Hobo</strong> is a freeform storytelling RPG about what adventurers do in between adventures. Fighting monsters is scary, but hanging out in the Black Dragon Tavern telling tall tales? That’s easy and fun and involves copious amounts of alcohol.</p>
<p>No knowledge of the rules in necessary. No preparation, either. Some knowledge of fantasy RPG stereotypes is helpful, but honestly you can pretty much wing it. Just show up and play.</p>
<p>We will be using the X-Card, the Open Table policy, and Lines and Veils as safety tools. Tone will be light-hearted and silly, probably somewhere from PG to PG-13.</p>
<p>Session will be run with Zoom and will be recorded if all players consent. This is a one-shot with a flexible running time, I will call the last scene around the three-hour mark.</p>
<p>Sunday, May 3, 2:30pm EST: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M5NYRCzkxWoLPtTrMpw" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M5NYRCzkxWoLPtTrMpw</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/murder-hobo-brave-adventurers-wanted/5036/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/murder-hobo-brave-adventurers-wanted/5036/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 17:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5036-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/murder-hobo-brave-adventurers-wanted/5036.rss">Murder Hobo: Brave Adventurers Wanted!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
