<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mothership: Dying Hard in Hardlight Station (Thursdays in October)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mothership-dying-hard-in-hardlight-station-thursdays-in-october/8357</link>
    <description>*It&#39;s Christmas Eve on* Hardlight Station *, a corporate-funded space station on the fringes of explored space. As is tradition, the crew of the station and employees of the businesses aboard are having the biggest party of the year. This year&#39;s corporate sponsor is Healthtek AG, which runs the station&#39;s hospital along with a medical research facility that develops new drugs. The party is going full swing when disaster strikes... Can you make it out alive?*

This is a four-part series run of the adventure *Dying Hard on Hardlight Staion* , written by D. Kenny. The sessions run Thursday nights in October. You must sign up for each session separately. Attendance at all four sessions is strongly preferred, though not strictly necessary.

***Dying Hard on Hardlight Station*** is an action-horror adventure for *Mothership* , inspired by 1980s action films *.*

* **Concept:** Characters are personnel aboard a space station that houses a medical research facility when something terrible happens. It&#39;s basically *Die Hard* meets *Aliens* in space.
* **Aim:** To tell a compelling action-horror story of survival (or not!) against enemies both alien and far-too-human.
* **Tone:** 1980s action-horror: Mostly serious but with enough sardonic humor to keep things interesting.
* **Subject Matter:** Body-horror, blood, violence, corporate malfeasance.

**System:** *Mothership* is a neo-OSR sci-fi/horror RPG. No experience is necessary: All rules will be taught at the table. You do not need a copy of the game to play. We will be using the revised &quot;1e&quot; version of the rules.

**Technology:** We will be using the facilitator&#39;s Zoom for video chat, a shared Google Sheet as a character keeper, and the online dice roller &quot;Roll Dice With Friends&quot;.

**Recording:** With the consent of the players, we will record this session. The facilitator will make the recording available to players for review, and with their consent, will post the video (or audio only if preferred) for public viewing.

**Safety Tools:** The X-Card, Lines &amp; Veils, and Open Door are all in-play. We will review these tools at the start of the session. The game abides by the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

[Session One](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB34Zlk672Yq-xD8q5u) Thursday 10/6/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)
[Session Two](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB34kb9ErDpGIGhqgrn) Thursday 10/13/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)
[Session Three](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB34tG67cd1UETL9znw) Thursday 10/20/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)
[Session Four](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB357E6VHLTp8XRen34) Thursday 10/27/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 16:12:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mothership-dying-hard-in-hardlight-station-thursdays-in-october/8357.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Mothership: Dying Hard in Hardlight Station (Thursdays in October)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>It’s Christmas Eve on</em> Hardlight Station <em>, a corporate-funded space station on the fringes of explored space. As is tradition, the crew of the station and employees of the businesses aboard are having the biggest party of the year. This year’s corporate sponsor is Healthtek AG, which runs the station’s hospital along with a medical research facility that develops new drugs. The party is going full swing when disaster strikes… Can you make it out alive?</em></p>
<p>This is a four-part series run of the adventure <em>Dying Hard on Hardlight Staion</em> , written by D. Kenny. The sessions run Thursday nights in October. You must sign up for each session separately. Attendance at all four sessions is strongly preferred, though not strictly necessary.</p>
<p><em><strong>Dying Hard on Hardlight Station</strong></em> is an action-horror adventure for <em>Mothership</em> , inspired by 1980s action films <em>.</em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Concept:</strong> Characters are personnel aboard a space station that houses a medical research facility when something terrible happens. It’s basically <em>Die Hard</em> meets <em>Aliens</em> in space.</li>
<li>
<strong>Aim:</strong> To tell a compelling action-horror story of survival (or not!) against enemies both alien and far-too-human.</li>
<li>
<strong>Tone:</strong> 1980s action-horror: Mostly serious but with enough sardonic humor to keep things interesting.</li>
<li>
<strong>Subject Matter:</strong> Body-horror, blood, violence, corporate malfeasance.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>System:</strong> <em>Mothership</em> is a neo-OSR sci-fi/horror RPG. No experience is necessary: All rules will be taught at the table. You do not need a copy of the game to play. We will be using the revised “1e” version of the rules.</p>
<p><strong>Technology:</strong> We will be using the facilitator’s Zoom for video chat, a shared Google Sheet as a character keeper, and the online dice roller “Roll Dice With Friends”.</p>
<p><strong>Recording:</strong> With the consent of the players, we will record this session. The facilitator will make the recording available to players for review, and with their consent, will post the video (or audio only if preferred) for public viewing.</p>
<p><strong>Safety Tools:</strong> The X-Card, Lines &amp; Veils, and Open Door are all in-play. We will review these tools at the start of the session. The game abides by the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB34Zlk672Yq-xD8q5u" rel="nofollow noopener">Session One</a> Thursday 10/6/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB34kb9ErDpGIGhqgrn" rel="nofollow noopener">Session Two</a> Thursday 10/13/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB34tG67cd1UETL9znw" rel="nofollow noopener">Session Three</a> Thursday 10/20/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NB357E6VHLTp8XRen34" rel="nofollow noopener">Session Four</a> Thursday 10/27/2022, 8:00 PM EDT (UTC -4)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mothership-dying-hard-in-hardlight-station-thursdays-in-october/8357/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mothership-dying-hard-in-hardlight-station-thursdays-in-october/8357/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 16:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8357-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mothership-dying-hard-in-hardlight-station-thursdays-in-october/8357.rss">Mothership: Dying Hard in Hardlight Station (Thursdays in October)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
