<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Checkpoint Midnight: The Clockmaker&#39;s Noose</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-the-clockmakers-noose/7111</link>
    <description>Your past is checkered, and Vienna is a dangerous place. All you&#39;ve got are your wits, your skills, perhaps some magic, and the Clockmaker&#39;s noose around your neck. Who will you trust?

This a four session playtest of Checkpoint Midnight, Cloven Pine Games&#39; PbtA game of spies torn between the great powers in Cold War Vienna to be run on Thursday nights at 8 PM US eastern time. You will play as supernatural beings, and freelance spies. You will start out doing a job for a black marketeer, The Clockmaker, who has some leverage over you, but from there we will play to find out what happens.

**Note: This is a play test. In particular, this series is a stress test on how well the game&#39;s mechanics handle oppositional play between characters, though not between players. We will collaborate to tell a story of PCs with competing goals, who cannot and do not always trust each other. It is possible that this may not work well, in which case we will adjust in play, but please only sign up if you are interested in playing a character in opposition to other PCs.**

Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. All Access time is 6/21/2021 at noon US eastern time.

I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Rules will be taught. Sessions will run up to three and a half hours. The game will be run over Streamyard. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils, script change and the X-Card for safety tools

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVRmJyY63top09yHeN

Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVS5redMiESC8h-PcG

Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVSd7rrVKPhcZ37Wsp

Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVTGq0N5kYZ_L6UuTh</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 18:55:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-the-clockmakers-noose/7111.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Checkpoint Midnight: The Clockmaker&#39;s Noose</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jesseabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jesseabe">@Jesseabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Your past is checkered, and Vienna is a dangerous place. All you’ve got are your wits, your skills, perhaps some magic, and the Clockmaker’s noose around your neck. Who will you trust?</p>
<p>This a four session playtest of Checkpoint Midnight, Cloven Pine Games’ PbtA game of spies torn between the great powers in Cold War Vienna to be run on Thursday nights at 8 PM US eastern time. You will play as supernatural beings, and freelance spies. You will start out doing a job for a black marketeer, The Clockmaker, who has some leverage over you, but from there we will play to find out what happens.</p>
<p><strong>Note: This is a play test. In particular, this series is a stress test on how well the game’s mechanics handle oppositional play between characters, though not between players. We will collaborate to tell a story of PCs with competing goals, who cannot and do not always trust each other. It is possible that this may not work well, in which case we will adjust in play, but please only sign up if you are interested in playing a character in opposition to other PCs.</strong></p>
<p>Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. All Access time is 6/21/2021 at noon US eastern time.</p>
<p>I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Rules will be taught. Sessions will run up to three and a half hours. The game will be run over Streamyard. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils, script change and the X-Card for safety tools</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVRmJyY63top09yHeN">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVRmJyY63top09yHeN</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVS5redMiESC8h-PcG">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVS5redMiESC8h-PcG</a></p>
<p>Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVSd7rrVKPhcZ37Wsp">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVSd7rrVKPhcZ37Wsp</a></p>
<p>Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVTGq0N5kYZ_L6UuTh">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McVTGq0N5kYZ_L6UuTh</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-the-clockmakers-noose/7111/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-the-clockmakers-noose/7111/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 18:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7111-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-the-clockmakers-noose/7111.rss">Checkpoint Midnight: The Clockmaker&#39;s Noose</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
