<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Crowdfunding Collection #175, including every tabletop rpg project started between 07/18 and 07/25</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-175-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-07-18-and-07-25/7215</link>
    <description>I present to you the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://teylen.blog/2021/07/25/crowdfunding-collection-176/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Crowdfunding Collection #175, including every tabletop rpg project started between 07/18 and 07/25&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.

This time there are many, cool games being funded. If I could, I would have backed each single one!

To start with something unusual for the English version. Donnerhaus currently aims to finance &lt;b&gt;Freude schöner Götterfunken…&lt;/b&gt; a campaign set in 1917 including a full rpg system. The game is delivered in a box with the rule books, maps, dice, pregenerated characters and more. I recommend having a look, if your German is sufficient, or you are interested in German rpgs.

Back to the English projects, let’s start with Monte Cooks newest game &lt;b&gt;The Devil Made Us Do It&lt;/b&gt;. The game puts you into the role of agents who are originally from the far future, yet ended up in roundabout nowadays. They have to succeed at heists, to keep the world intact. For this task they got the option to alter situation by just retelling the story. Making a door being there, which previously wasn’t, having a guard being nicely distacted or causing a blackout. Yet, if they go to big with the reality bending Paradox will hit, or,… well… bad stuff happens. The game is designed to be zero-prep, to be run right out of the box, and I feel enticed to back it. Then there’s the project &lt;b&gt;Pixies, Wyrms, Demonicity&lt;/b&gt;, which offers three Tri-Stat system (as seen in BESM). Everyone of the three games comes with a core booklet (32 pages), 6 pregens, 6 short scenarios and 4 custom dice. Pixies has you play as the titular pixies, who made their home on human homes. Wyrms has you playing creatures who fight and consume each other. Well and Demonicity sees you as secret oparatives who fight against the *dramatic voice* infernal darkness *coughs*. I like the concept, and the pitches for Pixies and Demonicity. Check it out. Then there’s the micro game &lt;b&gt;Banality&lt;/b&gt;. Which fits in a three times folded flyer. The first scenario of the quite narrative game, puts one in a post-utopian society, where the machines got uppity and one gotta flee them. I imaginge it to be like the the episode Automated Customer Service of Love, Death x Robots. Depending on the success of the project, 4 games might be added, offering new scenarios and more stories. I think it’s cool and the asking price is more than fair.
I did actually back the noir rpg &lt;b&gt;Bloodshadows: Chronicles of Guf.&lt;/b&gt; The game offers an alternate universe, in which some creatures that go bump in the night are known to roam the city of Guf. The flair is kinda 40’ish and one can play a mobster vampire! I already got the box of the previous edition, Battlefield Press being reliable and happily backed this one. With the system being completly overhauled with a Savage Worlds ruleset being a plus in my book. Take a look, and back it. Please, I want it to actually come to fruition. &lt;b&gt;Fedora Noir&lt;/b&gt; offers a more classical noire game for four players. While one will play the detectives, and do detective stuff, one will be playing the (in)famous hat, offering the inner monolog. A session should take about 2 hours and the game is card based.
Of course there are more interesting projects. You’ll find material to enhance your fantasy ttrpg session with the magazines &lt;b&gt;The Oracle Issue 13 – Floating Islands&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Delver: Resources for the Random-Rolling Referee&lt;/b&gt; – the first one with a focus on D&amp;D 5E rules and the latter more leaning towards OSR. If you like playing D&amp;D 5E, and you are looking for more stuff for druids and about the fey, you could have a look at &lt;b&gt;Druids: Secrets of the Primal Circle&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Professor Gilroy’s Guide to Fey&lt;/b&gt;. Though there is more D&amp;D 5E sourcebook material like &lt;b&gt;Wickerpunk RPG&lt;/b&gt;, next to many more projects. Fans of Mörk Borg might like to take a look at &lt;b&gt;In the footsteps of the Mad Wizard&lt;/b&gt; – a miniature game and rpg supplement.
You’ll find those, and other interesting projects, here:

&lt;b&gt;German Crowdfundings&lt;/b&gt;

1 Roleplaying Game

&lt;b&gt;English Crowdfundings&lt;/b&gt;

3 Roleplaying Games
2 Noir Roleplaying Games
2 Settings
2 Magazines
1 Mörk Borg Sourcebook
7 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebooks
4 Adventures
1 Dice Project
1 Accessoire
1 Deck of Cards
1 Enamel Pin
2 Mats
2 Various RPG Projects

&lt;b&gt;Spanish Crowdfundings&lt;/b&gt;

1 Roleplaying Game

Article: &lt;a href=&quot;https://teylen.blog/2021/07/25/crowdfunding-collection-176/&quot;&gt;https://teylen.blog/2021/07/25/crowdfunding-collection-176/&lt;/a&gt;</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 15:56:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-175-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-07-18-and-07-25/7215.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Crowdfunding Collection #175, including every tabletop rpg project started between 07/18 and 07/25</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the new <a href="https://teylen.blog/2021/07/25/crowdfunding-collection-176/" rel="nofollow noopener"><b>Crowdfunding Collection #175, including every tabletop rpg project started between 07/18 and 07/25</b></a>.</p>
<p>This time there are many, cool games being funded. If I could, I would have backed each single one!</p>
<p>To start with something unusual for the English version. Donnerhaus currently aims to finance <b>Freude schöner Götterfunken…</b> a campaign set in 1917 including a full rpg system. The game is delivered in a box with the rule books, maps, dice, pregenerated characters and more. I recommend having a look, if your German is sufficient, or you are interested in German rpgs.</p>
<p>Back to the English projects, let’s start with Monte Cooks newest game <b>The Devil Made Us Do It</b>. The game puts you into the role of agents who are originally from the far future, yet ended up in roundabout nowadays. They have to succeed at heists, to keep the world intact. For this task they got the option to alter situation by just retelling the story. Making a door being there, which previously wasn’t, having a guard being nicely distacted or causing a blackout. Yet, if they go to big with the reality bending Paradox will hit, or,… well… bad stuff happens. The game is designed to be zero-prep, to be run right out of the box, and I feel enticed to back it. Then there’s the project <b>Pixies, Wyrms, Demonicity</b>, which offers three Tri-Stat system (as seen in BESM). Everyone of the three games comes with a core booklet (32 pages), 6 pregens, 6 short scenarios and 4 custom dice. Pixies has you play as the titular pixies, who made their home on human homes. Wyrms has you playing creatures who fight and consume each other. Well and Demonicity sees you as secret oparatives who fight against the <em>dramatic voice</em> infernal darkness <em>coughs</em>. I like the concept, and the pitches for Pixies and Demonicity. Check it out. Then there’s the micro game <b>Banality</b>. Which fits in a three times folded flyer. The first scenario of the quite narrative game, puts one in a post-utopian society, where the machines got uppity and one gotta flee them. I imaginge it to be like the the episode Automated Customer Service of Love, Death x Robots. Depending on the success of the project, 4 games might be added, offering new scenarios and more stories. I think it’s cool and the asking price is more than fair.<br>
I did actually back the noir rpg <b>Bloodshadows: Chronicles of Guf.</b> The game offers an alternate universe, in which some creatures that go bump in the night are known to roam the city of Guf. The flair is kinda 40’ish and one can play a mobster vampire! I already got the box of the previous edition, Battlefield Press being reliable and happily backed this one. With the system being completly overhauled with a Savage Worlds ruleset being a plus in my book. Take a look, and back it. Please, I want it to actually come to fruition. <b>Fedora Noir</b> offers a more classical noire game for four players. While one will play the detectives, and do detective stuff, one will be playing the (in)famous hat, offering the inner monolog. A session should take about 2 hours and the game is card based.<br>
Of course there are more interesting projects. You’ll find material to enhance your fantasy ttrpg session with the magazines <b>The Oracle Issue 13 – Floating Islands</b> and <b>Delver: Resources for the Random-Rolling Referee</b> – the first one with a focus on D&amp;D 5E rules and the latter more leaning towards OSR. If you like playing D&amp;D 5E, and you are looking for more stuff for druids and about the fey, you could have a look at <b>Druids: Secrets of the Primal Circle</b> and <b>Professor Gilroy’s Guide to Fey</b>. Though there is more D&amp;D 5E sourcebook material like <b>Wickerpunk RPG</b>, next to many more projects. Fans of Mörk Borg might like to take a look at <b>In the footsteps of the Mad Wizard</b> – a miniature game and rpg supplement.<br>
You’ll find those, and other interesting projects, here:</p>
<p><b>German Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Roleplaying Game</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>3 Roleplaying Games<br>
2 Noir Roleplaying Games<br>
2 Settings<br>
2 Magazines<br>
1 Mörk Borg Sourcebook<br>
7 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebooks<br>
4 Adventures<br>
1 Dice Project<br>
1 Accessoire<br>
1 Deck of Cards<br>
1 Enamel Pin<br>
2 Mats<br>
2 Various RPG Projects</p>
<p><b>Spanish Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Roleplaying Game</p>
<p>Article: <a href="https://teylen.blog/2021/07/25/crowdfunding-collection-176/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2021/07/25/crowdfunding-collection-176/</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-175-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-07-18-and-07-25/7215/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-175-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-07-18-and-07-25/7215/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 15:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7215-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-175-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-07-18-and-07-25/7215.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #175, including every tabletop rpg project started between 07/18 and 07/25</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
