<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299</link>
    <description>Just a general thread about trad/mainstream/blockbuster tabletop rpgs.

I&#39;m not talking about the nostalgic charm of old TSR D&amp;D modules or the aesthetic appeal of WFRP 1st edition, I mean the current editions of these games - D&amp;D 5E, Pathfinder, Call of Cthulhu 7th edition, Fantasy Flight Star Wars games, Warhammer Fantasy Roleplay 4th edition etc.

Do you play them and if so why?
I don&#39;t intend for that question to sound sneering or snobbish, I&#39;m curious about what it is about these systems and settings that people like. I assume that relative ease of availability and a larger pool of players are strong selling points.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 14:03:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>New to this forum and wanted to add my answer to the original question.</p>
<p>First, I agree with folks that have said it’s often <em>harder</em> to find players for these RPGs rather than being easier (with D&amp;D 5e being one of the few exceptions). To me the distinction isn’t <em>traditional</em> versus <em>indie</em>, but instead <em>big</em> versus <em>small</em> systems/rules. This is probably a function of the fact that we’re all getting older and in general it’s harder to get people to commit to trying (and learning) big new systems. It’s also true that most new games (especially PbtA) make it really easy to get started (playbooks, random character creation, single page rules summaries, etc.); games that <strong>don’t</strong> have these are a harder sell.</p>
<p>As far as playing modern versions of traditional games: I’ve wanted to try the newest incarnation of Traveller but haven’t found folks interested in it (and don’t really expect to). I can play (or run) D&amp;D 5e when asked but I mostly learned it to be able to game with old friends. I haven’t been able to get excited about any of the others you listed (or other big modern games like Mutant: Year Zero, Numenara, Eclipse Phase, etc.).</p>
<p>As far as modern big games which might not be “traditional” (e.g. Burning Wheel, Ryuutama) or slightly older big games (e.g. Ars Magica 5e), I also struggle to find folks interested enough to learn the rules and commit to playing a story arc. In some of the groups I game with this is because we just enjoy smaller games with shared authorship more. In other groups, I think folks <em>would</em> enjoy a bigger game with more up-front planning and a slower burn on the story/system, but are hesitant to commit to a new system.</p>
<p>However, it’s hard for me to be sure that my interest in some of these big systems doesn’t come from a (perverse) interest in byzantine rules or from nostalgia. I have a belief that there are stories that would benefit from some of these systems (and players who might enjoy them more than the alternatives) but currently I don’t have a lot of evidence.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/73">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/73</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 14:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-73</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@gmjrollins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gmjrollins">@gmjrollins</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I know! I’m doing what I can to make that happen</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/72">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/72</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 01:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-72</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I found it, with authentic 1979 coffe stain!  Hommlet in all its glory …<img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/1f4be83b489283f8431abc249d2e5defcec27bbd.jpeg" alt="IMG_20190623_125135small" data-base62-sha1="4sRqMgRDsVPy9OLrIHyWXmDiFC5" width="300" height="400"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/71">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/71</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 19:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-71</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I went for the first time last year and came to the same conclusion so offered 3 x PbtA sessions this year.  I’ll probably do the same next year.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/70">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/70</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 17:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-70</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Charlie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/charlie">@Charlie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ha, no. I had a living dungeon of stained glass monsters. It was a fun setting with some great ideas, but the system was far less narrative than I thought, especially with a nervous and increasingly drunk GM telling me where he felt the narrative parts were. He was nice, he just didn’t need to draw back the curtain so much. It probably didn’t help that an experienced 13th Age GM was a player making repeated (often wrong) rules challenges throughout the evening.</p>
<p>Personally my whole Expo experience just made me feel like I need to GM a few games next year.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/69">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/69</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 16:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-69</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You need to get into a Gauntlet DW game ‘now’ <a class="mention" href="/u/gmjrollins">@gmjrollins</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/68">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/68</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 13:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-68</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaerdaph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I6 Ravenloft and the sequel I10 Ravenloft II blew my mind away at the time. Suddenly, AD&amp;D had come out of the dungeon and a world of new possibilities opened up.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/67">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/67</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 14:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-67</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I played 13th Age for the first time at UKGE … Perhaps we were at the same table (graveyard after graveyard full of increasingly dangerous undead? Didn’t really finish by 11.30pm?).<br>
It felt too much like a.n.other d20 to me … though the fairly random activation of a stunt during combat spiced it up a bit.  Still felt like roll-playing, though.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/66">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/66</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 14:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-66</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="52" data-topic="2299">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/a/439d5e/40.png" class="avatar"> Avi_the_Jackal:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>What are the big classic published campaigns for various classic RPGs?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>For D&amp;D, my go-to is Ravenloft.</p>
<p>For the uninitiated, this is a Gothic horror setting that revolves around the centuries-old vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, who rules the cursed land of Barovia from his haunted Castle Ravenloft.</p>
<p>In my opinion, the original is still the one to beat: The 1983 AD&amp;D module <span class="bbcode-i">I6: Ravenloft</span> by Tracy &amp; Laura Hickman. This was the first published D&amp;D module that gave character class levels to a monster: In addition to being a vampire, Strahd is also a 9th-level magic-user. The module was also a highly-detailed castle with six floors and two basement levels, and it just dripped the mood and atmosphere of Gothic horror.</p>
<p>[Note: Being a product of its time, the module does have some problematic content, particularly a racist  stereotype presentation of a Roma-inspired people, which were called by their most-common racial slur. In later editions, these people were renamed “Vistani,” but the stereotype presentation remains to this day.]</p>
<p>Ravenloft is such a long-standing and popular classic that TSR released a sequel, <span class="bbcode-i">Ravenloft II: The House on Gryphon Hill</span> in 1986. TSR later published a box set campaign setting for AD&amp;D 2e in 1990 called <span class="bbcode-i">Ravenloft: Demiplane of Dread</span>, and followed that with a bunch of adventures and setting material for AD&amp;D 2e.</p>
<p>After WotC acquired TSR in 1997, they licensed the Ravenloft IP to White Wolf. In 2000, WW produced a series of Ravenloft material for D&amp;D 3.0 through their “Sword &amp; Sorcery Studios” line.  WotC later took back the license, and put out a D&amp;D 3.5 hardback called <span class="bbcode-i">Expedition to Castle Ravenloft</span> in 2006. And let’s not forget the latest release: the excellent official 5e adventure hardcover <span class="bbcode-i">Curse of Strahd</span> (2016).</p>
<p>Both <span class="bbcode-i">Expedition to Castle Ravenloft</span> and <span class="bbcode-i">Curse of Strahd</span> include updated versions of the original Castle Ravenloft from the 1983 original. Of the two, CoS hewed much closer to the original vision.</p>
<p>About four years ago, I ran an on-the-fly conversion of the original 1983 TSR module <em>I6: Ravenloft</em> in Pathfinder. I just used the module straight, substituting Pathfinder monsters, traps, and other statistics for the AD&amp;D 1e stats, and moving the setting to Paizo’s “Inner Sea” campaign world, and modifying as little else as I could. My players and I all had a blast with it!</p>
<p>I have been strongly considering running this again with my new F2F gaming group, using <span class="bbcode-i">World of Dungeons</span> as the system…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/65">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/65</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 13:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-65</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Charlie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/charlie">@Charlie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I admit I fairly naively went from trad RPGs to indies and the G+ communities for games like Fiasco, Dungeon World and of course Dungeon World, assuming that everyone outside of D&amp;D and Pathfinder was doing the same. When I got round to revisiting <a href="http://RPG.net" rel="nofollow noopener">RPG.net</a> when I remembered it existed, I realised that all of the old stuff was still going on and I’d let a lot of it pass me by.</p>
<p>D&amp;D is of course still a thing, and hosting one-shot nights at my FLGS I always need at least one table as the thirst for D&amp;D doesn’t stop. Luckily I’ve had at least one indie table as well to sate my needs for running different games.</p>
<p>The evolution from the trad spheres, with games like Dungeon World (from D&amp;D), Lovecraftesque &amp; Cthulhu Dark (From CoC) are great and for me have replaced the originals. I’ve hit the point with WoD where if I wanted to run a story I’d used nWoD for, I’d probably use MotW, Urban Shadows or something along those lines.</p>
<p>I’ve only dabbled in the modern trad games, specifically in this year’s UK Games Expo and Free RPG Day.<br>
I played Era: Survival, Coriolis and 13th Age at Expo. 13th Age was crunchier than I thought it would be given people’s descriptions of it, but I liked the mutations to the old d20 style. Coriolis and Era: Survival reminded me that you’ve got one ‘game’ and then when combat starts, it’s kind of a whole different ‘game’. I’d been enjoying Coriolis and thought I’d figured out the system when it broke into combat and everything just became another combat system.<br>
There was a similar incident with revisiting oWoD for the first time since 2004, by playing Changeling: The Dreaming. The GM was one of the indie GMs from my fortnightly one-shots and we kind of discussed and agreed not to bother with combat. When there were fights they were short and didn’t really need initiative or a sub-system compared to continuing with the core game system. It sped up the game and let us focus on the social drama.</p>
<p>I’d be interested in seeing which trad games ignore the difference between combat/non-combat systems.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/64">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/64</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 11:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-64</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks a lot.<br>
I was a bit late to the party. In the late 80ies, early 90ies there were dungeons the thing you started with and learned walking so to say, but the real adventure was in complete continents with encyclopedias of stuff to learn. So I could only imagine how this “wow” moment was <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/63">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/63</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 11:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-63</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I can’t speak for the Temple of Elemental Evil - I’d come out of the other side of AD&amp;D by the time it came out in the 80’s, but the precursor ‘Village of Hommlet’ (1979-ish?) was ‘peak-AD&amp;D’ for me and my Univ group.  It blew my mind because it was … a village …!  not just a dungeon … but a village.<br>
It opened up new vistas for our play and got me to buy the City State of the Invincible Overlord (which had been around for a while I think but I’d always though ‘City? What could I do with a City … I have dungeons!’) and start using the AD&amp;D DM Guides random tables to populate hex map after hex map of LG kingdom after LE theocracy after CE failed state.<br>
So my feelings for Hommlet’ are entirely nostalgic - the details have been long sent into the recesses of memory whence little emerges apart from a warm glow.  It’s probably still in the basement, though - so I might refresh my memory. Happy, and simpler, days.  Thanks for prompting me to think about them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/62">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/62</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 10:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-62</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve heard by many people that it is a great module.<br>
Do you mind elaborate a bit?<br>
I haven’t played it yet.</p>
<p>What makes it special for you?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/61">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/61</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 10:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-61</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ohhhhh!  Hommlet … I’d forgotten about Hommlet … It was a VERY long time ago, though.  Oldies but Goldies.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/60">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/60</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 06:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-60</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@gmjrollins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gmjrollins">@gmjrollins</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m fairly new to ttrpg’s, and I’ve basically only played 5e. And I’m gonna go out on a limb and say that’s probably due to the availability/accessibility.</p>
<p>That being said, I’ve really loved the spotlight given to storytelling by other systems. I like the way that travel is run in Dungeon World (which I have yet to actually play - I’ve only heard it from listening to We Hunt the Keepers), and I’ve been toying with the idea of working that into our 5e game.</p>
<p>Getting back to the original question, I play 5e because that’s what currently gets me and my friends around the table; though,  I’m sure they’re up for any system.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/59">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/59</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 16:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-59</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m a pretty big fan of the Temple of Elemental Evil mega-campaign for D&amp;D that starts with the level 1 Village of Homlette.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/58">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/58</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 14:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-58</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Avi_the_Jackal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/avi_the_jackal">@Avi_the_Jackal</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yep, good suggestion.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/57">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/57</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 20:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-57</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AviatrixCat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/aviatrixcat">@AviatrixCat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Masks of Nyarlathotep for Call of Cthulhu for sure.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/56">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/56</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 19:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-56</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Hopeless_Wanderer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/hopeless_wanderer">@Hopeless_Wanderer</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes, I should have mentioned <em>River of Cradles</em> too. The final module is an important capstone for the whole Glorantha world vision.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/55">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/55</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 13:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-55</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For me, as for Hopeless Wanderer, the defining RQ campaign was the Pavis Campaign but supplemented by the River of Cradles set.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/54">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/54</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 09:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-54</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Hopeless_Wanderer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/hopeless_wanderer">@Hopeless_Wanderer</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>IMHO, the classic Runequest campaign is called, <em>Pavis, Gateway to Adventure</em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/53">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/53</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 06:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-53</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Avi_the_Jackal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/avi_the_jackal">@Avi_the_Jackal</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What are the big classic published campaigns for various classic RPGs?</p>
<p>I’m thinking like the Great Pendragon Campaign for Pendragon, the Enemy within for Warhammer Fantasy Roleplay, the Darkening of Mirkwood for The One Ring, etc.</p>
<p>I imagine there are a few for DnD but for me it’s the extended Queen of the Spiders series that runs from Against the Giants through the G, D and Q modules.</p>
<p>I’m particularly interested in identifying the classic campaigns for Runequest, Earthdawn or Mech Warrior if they exist.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/52</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 06:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I play a fair amount of FFG Star Wars with my face-to-face group. (I don’t run it myself, but two of the other part-time GM:s do.)</p>
<p>It’s a decent game, fairly streamlined mechanically, and character creation and advancement is fun. There are several drawbacks as well - there’s tons of species and equipment to keep track of, for my taste it’s a bit too (small-s) simulationist to get the proper Star Wars feeling - but the two big ones are that the latency is way too big (from declaring your actions to having resolved it fully there’s a lot of time spent assembling your dice pool, going back and forth with the GM about spending Destiny points, reading your dice, choosing how to spend your advantages etc) and that the abstract positioning doesn’t work very well with complex situations. Houseruling in some very basic rules for movement and range using miniatures actually made combats faster for us because you can see what’s going on and don’t need to ask what is where all the time. Also, space combat is a bit naff.</p>
<p>So, uh, that’s a lot of drawbacks. But it’s still fun enough to play, and as long as you don’t sweat the details too much it flows well. Honestly, the biggest hurdle for me is the dice rolling - it produces good results, but getting there is such a slog compared to PbtA style 2d6+stat or even a typical D&amp;D d20 plus mods vs DC.</p>
<p>I will say it does Jedi and other Force users very well, though. They get access to all the cool abilities, but they’re expensive enough that while the Jedi is mastering his ability to toss around things with their mind or manipulate the weak-willed, the smuggler will get an equal amount of pilot tricks and the alien with the massive gun will get even better at massive gunning. We’ve run several mixed parties without any issues.</p>
<p>So that’s my current big trad game. We used to play a lot of D&amp;D 4E and we’ve talked about getting that going again, but there are some issues with that game that I’ve spent several years trying to get to grips with.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/51</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 18:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I haven’t yet played <em>Cthulhu Dark,</em> and it’s very high on my “Want to try” list.</p>
<p>That very problem is why <em>Trail of Cthulhu</em> and the whole GUMSHOE system exists!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/50</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 16:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trad/mainstream rpgs</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Cthulhu Dark seems a very elegant basis for all those CoC books/pdfs that I never quite got to the table for the reasons you describe … and the frustrating ‘you need to find clue X to proceed’ situations.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299/49</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 12:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2299-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trad-mainstream-rpgs/2299.rss">Trad/mainstream rpgs</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
