<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cthulhu Dark: Hung by the Chimney With Care - Thursdays in December</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-dark-hung-by-the-chimney-with-care-thursdays-in-december/8498</link>
    <description>*It&#39;s December 1927. A telegram from an old ally sends the investigators to a college town in central New York State in search of a stolen mystical tome. But once they arrive, they discover that something dark, dangerous, and ravenous has descended upon the town... and all signs point to the missing book!*

This is a three-part series run of the short adventure &quot;Hung by the Chimney With Care,&quot; written by Mark Hart for the *Call of Cthulhu* RPG. This game will use RPG *Cthulhu Dark* by Graham Walmsley. These sessions run the first three Thursday nights in December at 8:00 PM EST (UTC-5). You must sign up for each session separately. Attendance at all three sessions is strongly preferred, though not strictly necessary.

**Hung by the Chimney With Care** is a Christmas-themed cosmic horror adventure set in the late 1920s.

* **Concept** : The characters travel to the town of Ithaca, New York to investigate a stolen Mythos text.
* **Aim** : To tell a compelling horror story about normal people facing off against unspeakable horror.
* **Tone** : Creeping horror with advancing dread. I&#39;m going for more of a &quot;slow-burn&quot; horror that may ratchet up quickly toward the end.
* **Subject Matter** : Kidnapping, human sacrifice, memetic horror, body horror

**System:** *Cthulhu Dark* is a rules-light investigative horror RPG. No experience is necessary: All rules will be taught at the table. You do not need to own a copy of the rules to play.

**Technology:** We will be using the facilitator&#39;s Zoom for video chat, a shared Google Sheet as a character keeper, and the online Trophy dice roller.

**Recording:** With the consent of the players, we will record this session. The facilitator will make the recording available to players for review, and with their consent, will post the video (or audio only if preferred) for public viewing.

**Safety Tools:** The X-Card, Lines &amp; Veils, and Open Door are all in-play. We will review these tools at the start of the session. The game abides by the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

[Session One](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NH2WPY_T9nYRVGVg1vD)
[Session Two](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NH2Wd6P25ysZiAGQf3W)
[Session Three](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NH2WrCE3ho3MiBxszoh)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 03:07:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-dark-hung-by-the-chimney-with-care-thursdays-in-december/8498.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Cthulhu Dark: Hung by the Chimney With Care - Thursdays in December</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>It’s December 1927. A telegram from an old ally sends the investigators to a college town in central New York State in search of a stolen mystical tome. But once they arrive, they discover that something dark, dangerous, and ravenous has descended upon the town… and all signs point to the missing book!</em></p>
<p>This is a three-part series run of the short adventure “Hung by the Chimney With Care,” written by Mark Hart for the <em>Call of Cthulhu</em> RPG. This game will use RPG <em>Cthulhu Dark</em> by Graham Walmsley. These sessions run the first three Thursday nights in December at 8:00 PM EST (UTC-5). You must sign up for each session separately. Attendance at all three sessions is strongly preferred, though not strictly necessary.</p>
<p><strong>Hung by the Chimney With Care</strong> is a Christmas-themed cosmic horror adventure set in the late 1920s.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Concept</strong> : The characters travel to the town of Ithaca, New York to investigate a stolen Mythos text.</li>
<li>
<strong>Aim</strong> : To tell a compelling horror story about normal people facing off against unspeakable horror.</li>
<li>
<strong>Tone</strong> : Creeping horror with advancing dread. I’m going for more of a “slow-burn” horror that may ratchet up quickly toward the end.</li>
<li>
<strong>Subject Matter</strong> : Kidnapping, human sacrifice, memetic horror, body horror</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>System:</strong> <em>Cthulhu Dark</em> is a rules-light investigative horror RPG. No experience is necessary: All rules will be taught at the table. You do not need to own a copy of the rules to play.</p>
<p><strong>Technology:</strong> We will be using the facilitator’s Zoom for video chat, a shared Google Sheet as a character keeper, and the online Trophy dice roller.</p>
<p><strong>Recording:</strong> With the consent of the players, we will record this session. The facilitator will make the recording available to players for review, and with their consent, will post the video (or audio only if preferred) for public viewing.</p>
<p><strong>Safety Tools:</strong> The X-Card, Lines &amp; Veils, and Open Door are all in-play. We will review these tools at the start of the session. The game abides by the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NH2WPY_T9nYRVGVg1vD" rel="nofollow noopener">Session One</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NH2Wd6P25ysZiAGQf3W" rel="nofollow noopener">Session Two</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NH2WrCE3ho3MiBxszoh" rel="nofollow noopener">Session Three</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-dark-hung-by-the-chimney-with-care-thursdays-in-december/8498/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-dark-hung-by-the-chimney-with-care-thursdays-in-december/8498/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 03:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8498-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-dark-hung-by-the-chimney-with-care-thursdays-in-december/8498.rss">Cthulhu Dark: Hung by the Chimney With Care - Thursdays in December</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
