<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dungeon World: The Vault of Kakistos (GFC Froghemoth one-shot)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dungeon-world-the-vault-of-kakistos-gfc-froghemoth-one-shot/8272</link>
    <description>**This event is part of the Gauntlet Facilitator Camp, and only people who are participating in GFC Froghemoth should sign up.**

*The Vault of Kakistos is the infamous home of treasures of incalculable value. That much everyone who hangs out in the shadier sort of tavern eventually hears. Unfortunately, that&#39;s about the only thing everyone agrees on about this long-lost hoard. But you&#39;ve sifted through the rumors, found the right ancient tomes and bribed the right people to get a lead. Now, after a grueling trek, you&#39;re standing before the sealed doors of what must be the notorious Vault. But does it contain your greatest longing — or your doom?*

**System:**  This is a one-shot game of Dungeon World, which aims to recreate the feel of Dungeons &amp; Dragons but using the narrative Powered by the Apocalypse engine. No prior experience with the game is necessary. All rules will be taught.

**Tone:**  Adventure with a touch of the grotesque.

**Technology:**  We will play using StreamYard for videoconferencing, a shared Character Keeper on Google Sheets, and an online dice roller.

**Safety Practices:**  We will be using a layered approach to safety, including Open Door, Lines &amp; Veils, and the X-Card. We will review safety practices at the start of the game. This game follows the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

Sign up [here](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8fXrIB_MvxslgBE55h).

Session date: [date=2022-08-11 time=19:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] → [date=2022-08-11 time=23:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;]</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 01:36:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dungeon-world-the-vault-of-kakistos-gfc-froghemoth-one-shot/8272.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Dungeon World: The Vault of Kakistos (GFC Froghemoth one-shot)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dhmontgomery]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dhmontgomery">@dhmontgomery</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>This event is part of the Gauntlet Facilitator Camp, and only people who are participating in GFC Froghemoth should sign up.</strong></p>
<p><em>The Vault of Kakistos is the infamous home of treasures of incalculable value. That much everyone who hangs out in the shadier sort of tavern eventually hears. Unfortunately, that’s about the only thing everyone agrees on about this long-lost hoard. But you’ve sifted through the rumors, found the right ancient tomes and bribed the right people to get a lead. Now, after a grueling trek, you’re standing before the sealed doors of what must be the notorious Vault. But does it contain your greatest longing — or your doom?</em></p>
<p><strong>System:</strong>  This is a one-shot game of Dungeon World, which aims to recreate the feel of Dungeons &amp; Dragons but using the narrative Powered by the Apocalypse engine. No prior experience with the game is necessary. All rules will be taught.</p>
<p><strong>Tone:</strong>  Adventure with a touch of the grotesque.</p>
<p><strong>Technology:</strong>  We will play using StreamYard for videoconferencing, a shared Character Keeper on Google Sheets, and an online dice roller.</p>
<p><strong>Safety Practices:</strong>  We will be using a layered approach to safety, including Open Door, Lines &amp; Veils, and the X-Card. We will review safety practices at the start of the game. This game follows the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p>Sign up <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8fXrIB_MvxslgBE55h" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>Session date: <span data-date="2022-08-11" data-time="19:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-08-12T00:00:00Z UTC">2022-08-12T00:00:00Z</span> → <span data-date="2022-08-11" data-time="23:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-08-12T04:00:00Z UTC">2022-08-12T04:00:00Z</span></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dungeon-world-the-vault-of-kakistos-gfc-froghemoth-one-shot/8272/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dungeon-world-the-vault-of-kakistos-gfc-froghemoth-one-shot/8272/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 01:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8272-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/dungeon-world-the-vault-of-kakistos-gfc-froghemoth-one-shot/8272.rss">Dungeon World: The Vault of Kakistos (GFC Froghemoth one-shot)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
