<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747</link>
    <description>*Nestled in the great capital city of Ambaret is the jewel of civilization, the fabulous Rose District. Many a treasure-hunter desires nothing more than to be able to afford a lavish retirement there. But what makes the Rose District so special? What pleasures and delights await those who manage to survive their careers in the dark places of the world?*

@jesseross and I are putting together a standalone book for the Trophy RPG (the game and its many expansions are currently featured in each new issue of Codex). One of the things we’re going to do with this book is include numerous tables that help flesh out the world Trophy takes place in. Keeping with the spirit of Trophy as a community project, we’re going to be crowdsourcing many of the elements that go into these tables. We have previously started a crowdsourcing thread for Fort Duhrin, which you can contribute to here:

https://discourse.funtimers.club/t/trophy-fort-duhrin/2683

For this installment, we’re exploring the Rose District of Ambaret, which is featured in one of the core game&#39;s Drives. We’re looking for 1 type of contribution here:

**People, places, and pleasures of the Rose District of Ambaret**

NOTE: Please avoid anything that feels like sexual predation or that is misogynistic in nature. We won&#39;t print such things.

You can submit as many entries as you wish. By submitting here, you agree to let us use your contribution in the Trophy standalone book and PDF (you will be credited as a contributor). Submissions should be fairly brief (no more than a sentence or two). Here are some examples:

&quot;The Rose District gets its name from the hedge maze garden at the heart of the neighborhood. On feast days, the maze is populated by performers and artisans—something new to see around every twist and turn.&quot; 

&quot;The wealthier denizens of the Rose District hold the softness of one&#39;s feet and the paleness of one&#39;s skin to be among the greatest of status symbols. As such, men and women being carried through the streets on covered litters is a common sight.&quot; 

&quot;Kali Ventrice is the foremost snail vendor in the Rose District. Her purple-hued gastropods—which she sources from the terrible, marshy Fen—are famous for both their delectable flavor and aphrodisiac-like qualities.&quot;
![61ad856a71e9facb6cdcc0d18c2d6160|690x350](upload://vo2b24dSWvka5qtI38nxj97WSGZ.jpeg)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 22:56:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@steinea]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/steinea">@steinea</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>St. Vernice the Enclosed</strong>. A holy woman living on the eastern end of Ambaret’s Rose District, St. Vernice the Enclosed is an anchoress who, it is said, was walled in to her small, stone cell long before any living memory (though, from her appearance, she cannot be older than thirty). She will, for a small offering, share a prophecy drawn from one of the many old tomes that line her rough-hewn shelves–only, the words she reads are in no language known to man. It is commonly believed that to hear this supernal speech is to hear the voice of long forgotten gods, and there are those who have devoted themselves to the decipherment of St. Vernice’s cryptic locutions, spending great fortunes in hopes of understanding.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/41</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 22:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CL_Bennett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cl_bennett">@CL_Bennett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would guess a mixture of laziness and apathy.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/40</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 02:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/signalstation">@signalstation</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That “presumably” is interesting. What prevents people from knowing where the bulls are going?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/39</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 02:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CL_Bennett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cl_bennett">@CL_Bennett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>During summer festivals, hundreds of rare albino bulls parade through the streets of the Rose District. Spectators will shower them with crimson rose petals as the bulls stride triumphantly to their destination—presumably to the slaughter house.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/38</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 22:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gabe">@Gabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We all know about Kali Ventrice and her excellent lavender snails. What most folks forget though, is that it takes a master chef to properly extract the snail’s flavor. From Kali’s place, head three doors down to Spiral. If you can get a table, order the preserved snail terrine with brown bread and prepare to be astounded.</p>
<p>The fancy residents of the Rose District would have you think that all the fighting pits are in the bottom’s. Heh. What they don’t want you to know is the rich folks love a good fight just as much as us commoners. Look for a black door with a carved lion’s head above it just west of the maze garden. Give 'em the password and go down to see the best fights this city can offer.</p>
<p>If you’re going to spend any real time in the Rose District you’ll need to get the right clothing. Before your first night, or your first visit to a noble, make sure to stop by Ilyana’s clothing shop. She’ll get you outfitted just right and for a reasonable price too.</p>
<p>The scent of the Rose District can be overpowering for new visitors on account of the enormous quantities of roses and other flowers that grow there. For a new visitor, I recommend picking up a fashionable mask to breathe through. It may mark you as a newcomer, but it’s a lot better than fainting in the street.</p>
<p>Have you spent so much time in the Rose District that you’re exhausted by the roses? Mort’s coffee shop and brewery is just what you need. There’s dark wood paneling, plenty to drink, and not a rose in sight. None of the food will even remind you of a flower. Come in for the daily lunch special.</p>
<p><em>Roses are red</em><br>
<em>They can also be yellow</em><br>
<em>Come visit The Headman</em><br>
<em>To get real mellow.</em></p>
<p>You need a guide? I’ve lived here all my life and I know every inch of this place. Name’s Elias Sparkfarmer. My hand? Oh, I lost that in the sewers when I was eleven. Want to hear the story?</p>
<p><em>Content warning: Suicide</em></p>
<p>Another dropped petal today. It’s an awful tradition, but every year around this time young people take their own lives by leaping from towers while dressed in all red. Some years it’s only a couple. Some years it’s more.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/37</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 17:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ghostPepperWonton]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ghostpepperwonton">@ghostPepperWonton</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Forty individuals, dressed entirely in a single white sheet that goes up to their noses attend a library, censoring the knowledge they believe to be forbidden for public consumption. They call themselves the Blind Eye. They are willing to pay handsomely for the retrieval of a book that they think if found, would undermine their order.</p>
<p>The trouble is that it’s held by an individual on the run. On the run from the order of the Blind Eye, claiming that they were exiled for wanting to reveal the contents of the book.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/36</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 04:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ghostPepperWonton]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ghostpepperwonton">@ghostPepperWonton</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In front of a major architectural building, there is an artist who has spent 15 years and more than a few commissions on an elaborate statue expressly for the purpose of up-staging the architect. The architect will pay anyone 10 gold if they can find a way to stop him from “making his impetuous monstrosity” in front of the architect’s magnum opus. The artist, however will offer you 15 for helping him with the piece de resistance: A fabled 1,000 carat ruby nested in the peak of the neighboring mountains.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/35</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 04:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@smythos]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/smythos">@smythos</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The coffee houses of the Rose District are home to the devotees of scholarly intellectual society. After debate and cofee, they meet in the vaulted cellars below the coffee houses, whispering and plotting in patchwork masks made from the stretched vellum of heretical treatises. With time, immersion in their secret ways leads to tears of ink and saliva of crimson and cerulean oozing from cracked tongues. The secretions are much valued by the learned.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/34</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 17:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Tucked into one of the many gardens of Ambaret is the statue of the laughing boy, his marble face twisted with mirth. Some who refuge there are keen or lucky enough to catch his face illuminated by a waxing quarter moon. It is only under the light of this moon that the boy’s facade falters and he weeps, a single tear of marble dropping into the fountain beneath him.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/33</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Amaranth, sweet parsley, lilyseed and Perilla is what the old baker says he puts in his cakes. He stays up all night baking, they say, and he’s always sold out by noon. Strange how nobody remembers the old man’s name, but a simple old sign above his shop’s door reads “Pyx” and so most simply call him that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/32</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 20:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There’s a rare Lilac Rose of Ambaret that’s hard to come by. But if you do, you’re in for a treat. With just a single thorn clinging to its stem it can produce wonderful images only for you to see. Pinch your index finger and let yourself wander in illusions of your choosing. You can go wherever you want and become whoever you wish to be. This journey is brief yet powerful. Just make sure you don’t confuse it with the Plum Rose, it’s lethal.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/31</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 18:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Getting mugged in the District of Ambaret is not uncommon. But there is always hope and it takes a form of grizzled Henry, a well known patron of the District. Watch out for him if you got robbed and make sure you have two petals of a white rose as he may be interested in exchanging them for your lost belongings.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/30</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 17:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Golden Mimes are renowned throughout Ambaret for their flawless performances and complete dedication to their craft. Such is their skill that only the trained eye can spot them among the other bronze statues in the gardens and gateways of the Rose District’s elite. Look upon them but be warned that no one has ever insulted a mime twice. They will watch and wait as long as they need until the moment comes to silence your mockery for good. It comes as no surprise that the Golden are also rumored to be the most costly and highly sought-after assassins in the land…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/29</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 17:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The lush gardens of the Rose District attract all manner of buzzing insects which pollinate the flowers - naturally, some plants consume these insects in turn. They say that if you write your secrets on tiny scrolls and feed them to a tooth fern, bladed tulip or Witch’s Claw, no one will be able to speak them aloud. Take care that the plants do not taste even a drop of your blood, however, or soon the entire garden will know your secrets and whisper them to passers-by.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/28</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 16:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oooh that’s so good!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 18:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/signalstation">@signalstation</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>“You can’t take it with you,” lesser minds have said of great fortunes. But in The Rose District, adventurers lacking family to bequeath their fortune to have been known to hire a Dualist, an actor who becomes their exact double, learning their tastes and tics, to carry on spending their fortune in their place, <em>as them</em>, once the grave renders them unable to do so themselves.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/26</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 20:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Roses grow with abundance in the district in the colours of red, white, lavender, yellow and pink. Old florists whisper if you take a petal from each rose colour and plant it in the moonlight, the next night a silver rose will grow. This silver rose can be used to grant eternal life, with a some risk of shattering the five most prominent moments of your life.</p>
<p>Mead is enjoyed at many taverns, but while blackberry and honey mead are frequently imbued, rose mead is costly and the after taste has been known to leave you with desire for nothing else. The exact recipe for rose mead is closely guarded, and it is known the price is not paid in coin.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/25</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 09:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rafaelbeltrame]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rafaelbeltrame">@rafaelbeltrame</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There’s a fine and sweet liquor called “petal kiss”, made from certain type of rose. It is made by the regurgitation of the already eaten flower by a red humming bird.<br>
It is very rare and expensive, and some vendors were accused of selling a adulterated version, with the regurgitation of…other beings.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/24</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 22:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_Kershaw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_kershaw">@Joshua_Kershaw</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Despite, or perhaps because of, the arid climate, it has become popular among the fashionistas of The Rose District of Ambaret to carry, as pets, dazzlingly colored salamanders.</p>
<p>Intrepid trappers comb the nearby forest for the various vivid species that dwell within. Those who make it back out can earn quite the fortune.</p>
<p>Amphibian aficionados, as a way to outdo one another, roam The Rose District toting elaborate contraptions designed to simulate the cool misty rains of their chromatic caudata’s natural habitat. By happenstance, of course, keeping the affluent cool and comfortable in the oppressive dry heat of Ambaret.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/23</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 18:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DavidMorrison]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/davidmorrison">@DavidMorrison</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Everet Steyn works for a cobbler in the Rose Disctrict, shoeing the wealthy and fashionable. His designs are works of art, and every piece is custom-made. They say he ventured into the Forest as a young man, though, and every now and then, he creates a work that can never see the light of day.</p>
<p>(Tagged on as I didn’t realise there was a limit to consecutive replies <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/sweat_smile.png?v=9" title=":sweat_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":sweat_smile:">)</p>
<p>A favoured pastime in the district is to smoke a little poppy - not too much, just enough to begin to float - and walk along the garlanded catwalks of the multi-tiered trellises the line the boulevards. Here one can find small, impromptu gatherings of folk sat among the flowers, watching the passersby below.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 14:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DavidMorrison]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/davidmorrison">@DavidMorrison</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In the park off Summerwine Street there is a pool, and in this pool it is said a woman is sometimes glimpsed. There are tales that she can grant wishes. But none dare to throw her their pocket change, for such may be seen as an insult. She demands more costly sacrifices.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 14:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DavidMorrison]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/davidmorrison">@DavidMorrison</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Much to the chagrin of the district guards, the House of Thorns is one of the capital’s most exclusive pleasure houses. It is staffed by elegant gentlemen who ply the patrons with the finest food and drink, surrounded by exquisite art and sublime music. And of course, as the name suggests, you can expect a prick or two.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 13:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OrbWitch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/orbwitch">@OrbWitch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The ghost of Penelope Dawn is believed to haunt the hedge maze. An illusionist of her time, her shows were something of legend, and now so is her spirit.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 02:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The many roses of Ambaret:</p>
<p>Scarlet Fever for a lover,<br>
Sky-the-Hunter for a knight.<br>
Snowcloud Shiver for the dying,<br>
Leafless Suncup for a child.</p>
<p>Pouting Moss for serf or druid,<br>
Poets choose the Dawn-that-Glows.<br>
Merchants love the Silver Shilling,<br>
but what is the truest rose?</p>
<p>It’s not Throne Thief, clad in amber,<br>
nor Tears Eternal, pale as fog.<br>
And not even Queen-Is-Bleeding.<br>
No. It is the rose-of-dog.</p>
<p>She’s the first, and she’s the strongest,<br>
On street or barrow, growing wild.<br>
On pauper’s grave or noble’s palace:<br>
Dog-rose is the Forest’s child.</p>
<ul>
<li>Children’s song in Ambaret.</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/18</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 17:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jan_Cantor]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jan_cantor">@Jan_Cantor</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Be careful, my dear, what you wish on Ambaret because it might reach to the ears of the Knights of the Black Rose and they will decide to grant it.</p>
<p>Later, when you are enjoying your wish, they will approach you and ask yo you to do them a small favor in return.</p>
<p>And they won’t stop never</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747/17</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 17:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2747-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-rose-district-of-ambaret/2747.rss">Trophy: The Rose District of Ambaret</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
