<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>GCOG: Hit the Nazi Retrieve the Ark</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-hit-the-nazi-retrieve-the-ark/7125</link>
    <description>In their efforts to protect Democracy,  Air Ace &#39;Bake&#39; Baker, Mesmerist Professor Bodenstein and Hustler &#39;Chance&#39; Le Chance are transporting an important artefact to the New Gauntlet City Museum. When they have to take a detour to avoid pursuing Nazi agents they find themselves driving through a busy fair and circus where they (literally) bump in to everyone&#39;s Friend and High School Teacher Marvin Roy and his mother.  There&#39;s bystanders to protect, circus strong men to mesmerise, and esoteric candelabra to keep track of ... then a surprise villain is revealed, Messerschmitts intervene, and a trader (pirate?) captain helps them reach an archaeological dig at the rumoured site of the garden of Eden ...

https://youtu.be/EIpNXHwfvzg</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:04:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-hit-the-nazi-retrieve-the-ark/7125.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>GCOG: Hit the Nazi Retrieve the Ark</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In their efforts to protect Democracy,  Air Ace ‘Bake’ Baker, Mesmerist Professor Bodenstein and Hustler ‘Chance’ Le Chance are transporting an important artefact to the New Gauntlet City Museum. When they have to take a detour to avoid pursuing Nazi agents they find themselves driving through a busy fair and circus where they (literally) bump in to everyone’s Friend and High School Teacher Marvin Roy and his mother.  There’s bystanders to protect, circus strong men to mesmerise, and esoteric candelabra to keep track of … then a surprise villain is revealed, Messerschmitts intervene, and a trader (pirate?) captain helps them reach an archaeological dig at the rumoured site of the garden of Eden …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="EIpNXHwfvzg" data-youtube-title="GCOG: Hit the Nazi - Retrieve the Ark" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-hit-the-nazi-retrieve-the-ark/7125/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-hit-the-nazi-retrieve-the-ark/7125/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7125-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-hit-the-nazi-retrieve-the-ark/7125.rss">GCOG: Hit the Nazi Retrieve the Ark</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
