<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>DIE: Reunited - August 28th 2pm BST, September 4th 2pm BST</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/die-reunited-august-28th-2pm-bst-september-4th-2pm-bst/7291</link>
    <description>This is a playtest of [DIE](http://diecomic.com/rpg) RPG by (er) me. DIE RPG is based on [the comic series DIE](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/www.diecomic.com), by Stephanie Hans and (er) me.

DIE has been in development for a few years, and I want to take the current core game - DIE CORE - out for a spin to try some things. [This will be the recently released 1.46 beta classes](https://kierongillen.itch.io/die-beta/devlog/283327/die-rpg-146) and the basic scenario of the game.

This is the first of two sessions. The first session is 3 hours, the second is 4. Attendance at both sessions is definitely advantageous, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.

**Concept** : To create a group of flawed, real world human beings (&quot;Persona&quot;), role-play them sitting down to play a fantasy role-playing game... and then have them transported to a fantasy world. Will they get home or not? What will they discover about themselves when they&#39;re there? What will they do (or not) to get what they always wanted?

We&#39;ll be playtesting a specific playset REUNITED which is based on the following concept:  *&quot;You all used to play fantasy RPGs together as teenagers at school. Now years down the line, you’re all back in town for a school re-union and have decided to get together to play a game for old time’s sake…&quot;*

**Aim:**  To quote from the manual:  *&quot;The aim of the game is to explore who these people really are.&quot;*  It&#39;s somewhat meta game about a group of people playing RPGs which uses the fantasy adventure to externalize their own lacks and issues.

**Tone:**  Will be somewhat negotiated at the table. To quote the manual:  *&quot;DIE can become an existential weird horror game, or can be a portal-fantasy romp - what do the players want?&quot;*  What do the players want is very much part of the game - why do we play Fantasy games anyway?

**Subject Matter:**  Will vary depending on the Persona&#39;s own nature, but takes the backbone of a fantasy adventure, twisted. Common themes are the loss of dreams, the compromises of adulthood, regrets. Player versus Player conflict is a possibility.

**Venue** : Sessions will be recorded via Streamyard and may be posted on Youtube if folks are cool with that.

**Contact** : Players will be contacted about a week before the game, where advance material will be mailed over. If no contact is heard from a player before 24 hours in the game it will be assumed they can&#39;t make it, and their place will be offered up.

The X-card will be in use, as will the[  **Gauntlet Code of Conduct** ](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html). We&#39;ll run with Open Door, and Lines &amp; Veils will be defined before the game.

[date=2021-08-28 time=14:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;] → [date=2021-08-28 time=17:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;] [Session 1](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mh9jeecYui3I-i4wLdc)
[date=2021-09-04 time=14:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;] → [date=2021-09-04 time=18:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;] [Session 2](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mh9jsUwPJS-y8nb_Ypr)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 17:06:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/die-reunited-august-28th-2pm-bst-september-4th-2pm-bst/7291.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>DIE: Reunited - August 28th 2pm BST, September 4th 2pm BST</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@kierongillen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/kierongillen">@kierongillen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is a playtest of <a href="http://diecomic.com/rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">DIE</a> RPG by (er) me. DIE RPG is based on <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/www.diecomic.com" rel="nofollow noopener">the comic series DIE</a>, by Stephanie Hans and (er) me.</p>
<p>DIE has been in development for a few years, and I want to take the current core game - DIE CORE - out for a spin to try some things. <a href="https://kierongillen.itch.io/die-beta/devlog/283327/die-rpg-146" rel="nofollow noopener">This will be the recently released 1.46 beta classes</a> and the basic scenario of the game.</p>
<p>This is the first of two sessions. The first session is 3 hours, the second is 4. Attendance at both sessions is definitely advantageous, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.</p>
<p><strong>Concept</strong> : To create a group of flawed, real world human beings (“Persona”), role-play them sitting down to play a fantasy role-playing game… and then have them transported to a fantasy world. Will they get home or not? What will they discover about themselves when they’re there? What will they do (or not) to get what they always wanted?</p>
<p>We’ll be playtesting a specific playset REUNITED which is based on the following concept:  <em>“You all used to play fantasy RPGs together as teenagers at school. Now years down the line, you’re all back in town for a school re-union and have decided to get together to play a game for old time’s sake…”</em></p>
<p><strong>Aim:</strong>  To quote from the manual:  <em>“The aim of the game is to explore who these people really are.”</em>  It’s somewhat meta game about a group of people playing RPGs which uses the fantasy adventure to externalize their own lacks and issues.</p>
<p><strong>Tone:</strong>  Will be somewhat negotiated at the table. To quote the manual:  <em>“DIE can become an existential weird horror game, or can be a portal-fantasy romp - what do the players want?”</em>  What do the players want is very much part of the game - why do we play Fantasy games anyway?</p>
<p><strong>Subject Matter:</strong>  Will vary depending on the Persona’s own nature, but takes the backbone of a fantasy adventure, twisted. Common themes are the loss of dreams, the compromises of adulthood, regrets. Player versus Player conflict is a possibility.</p>
<p><strong>Venue</strong> : Sessions will be recorded via Streamyard and may be posted on Youtube if folks are cool with that.</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong> : Players will be contacted about a week before the game, where advance material will be mailed over. If no contact is heard from a player before 24 hours in the game it will be assumed they can’t make it, and their place will be offered up.</p>
<p>The X-card will be in use, as will the<a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">  <strong>Gauntlet Code of Conduct</strong> </a>. We’ll run with Open Door, and Lines &amp; Veils will be defined before the game.</p>
<p><span data-date="2021-08-28" data-time="14:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2021-08-28T13:00:00Z UTC">2021-08-28T13:00:00Z</span> → <span data-date="2021-08-28" data-time="17:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2021-08-28T16:00:00Z UTC">2021-08-28T16:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mh9jeecYui3I-i4wLdc" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 1</a><br>
<span data-date="2021-09-04" data-time="14:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2021-09-04T13:00:00Z UTC">2021-09-04T13:00:00Z</span> → <span data-date="2021-09-04" data-time="18:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2021-09-04T17:00:00Z UTC">2021-09-04T17:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mh9jsUwPJS-y8nb_Ypr" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 2</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/die-reunited-august-28th-2pm-bst-september-4th-2pm-bst/7291/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/die-reunited-august-28th-2pm-bst-september-4th-2pm-bst/7291/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 17:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7291-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/die-reunited-august-28th-2pm-bst-september-4th-2pm-bst/7291.rss">DIE: Reunited - August 28th 2pm BST, September 4th 2pm BST</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
