<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Checkpoint Midnight: Uneasy Allies Quarterly Mini-Campaign (1-4 of 12)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-uneasy-allies-quarterly-mini-campaign-1-4-of-12/5752</link>
    <description>***Please note: This is a quarterly long-term playtest that will run for 12 sessions. Please wait 48 hours to sign up if you cannot commit in good faith to playing in this slot in November and December.***

1950 in Vienna. It&#39;s the dawn of the Cold War. The wounds of the Second World War are still fresh, and the city is divided. Control is shared by the victorious Allies, but the influence of the Nazis still lingers in the back alleys  *and*  the corridors of power.

In  *Checkpoint Midnight* , the players will take on the role of espionage agents engaged in the Great Game between the occupying powers: France, England, the USSR, and the USA.  *But they&#39;re not just any agents* . They&#39;ve all been touched by the strange, the uncanny, the  *supernatural* . They&#39;ll use their fantastic and terrifying abilities to navigate the treacherous political forces of their new home, and perhaps even prosper there.

This is a Gauntlet Quarterly offering! It&#39;s a mini-campaign that will run a dozen sessions, allowing us to test the advancement rules and develop a satisfying story arc for our characters! There will be 4 character total, 1 slot is reserved for the game&#39;s designer, Alexi Sargent.

Content warning: violence, betrayal, discussion of war including possibly war crimes. Roleplaying depicting criminal espionage activity including murder. We&#39;ll use Lines &amp; Veils, X-Card, and Open Door to make sure everyone can participate as safely as possible. This event adheres to the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

Tuesdays in October at 8:00 PM Eastern US time:
Oct 6: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Xf_npRXB3KMY4I6v
Oct 13: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3XvZvX6OtpA3EKFOo
Oct 20: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Y5IEVbRFJMrhiYOy
Oct 27: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Y5IEVbRFJMrhiYOy</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 02:39:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-uneasy-allies-quarterly-mini-campaign-1-4-of-12/5752.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Checkpoint Midnight: Uneasy Allies Quarterly Mini-Campaign (1-4 of 12)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em><strong>Please note: This is a quarterly long-term playtest that will run for 12 sessions. Please wait 48 hours to sign up if you cannot commit in good faith to playing in this slot in November and December.</strong></em></p>
<p>1950 in Vienna. It’s the dawn of the Cold War. The wounds of the Second World War are still fresh, and the city is divided. Control is shared by the victorious Allies, but the influence of the Nazis still lingers in the back alleys  <em>and</em>  the corridors of power.</p>
<p>In  <em>Checkpoint Midnight</em> , the players will take on the role of espionage agents engaged in the Great Game between the occupying powers: France, England, the USSR, and the USA.  <em>But they’re not just any agents</em> . They’ve all been touched by the strange, the uncanny, the  <em>supernatural</em> . They’ll use their fantastic and terrifying abilities to navigate the treacherous political forces of their new home, and perhaps even prosper there.</p>
<p>This is a Gauntlet Quarterly offering! It’s a mini-campaign that will run a dozen sessions, allowing us to test the advancement rules and develop a satisfying story arc for our characters! There will be 4 character total, 1 slot is reserved for the game’s designer, Alexi Sargent.</p>
<p>Content warning: violence, betrayal, discussion of war including possibly war crimes. Roleplaying depicting criminal espionage activity including murder. We’ll use Lines &amp; Veils, X-Card, and Open Door to make sure everyone can participate as safely as possible. This event adheres to the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p>Tuesdays in October at 8:00 PM Eastern US time:<br>
Oct 6: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Xf_npRXB3KMY4I6v" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Xf_npRXB3KMY4I6v</a><br>
Oct 13: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3XvZvX6OtpA3EKFOo" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3XvZvX6OtpA3EKFOo</a><br>
Oct 20: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Y5IEVbRFJMrhiYOy" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Y5IEVbRFJMrhiYOy</a><br>
Oct 27: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Y5IEVbRFJMrhiYOy" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MF3Y5IEVbRFJMrhiYOy</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-uneasy-allies-quarterly-mini-campaign-1-4-of-12/5752/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-uneasy-allies-quarterly-mini-campaign-1-4-of-12/5752/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 02:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5752-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/checkpoint-midnight-uneasy-allies-quarterly-mini-campaign-1-4-of-12/5752.rss">Checkpoint Midnight: Uneasy Allies Quarterly Mini-Campaign (1-4 of 12)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
