<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Until We Sink: The Last Days of Paradise (Monday, March 16, 8pm EST)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/until-we-sink-the-last-days-of-paradise-monday-march-16-8pm-est/4344</link>
    <description>Until We Sink is a GMless RPG set on a remote tropical island. The only people left on the island are one or two natives, and between two and four hotel guests. The climate is warm and pleasant, but a little humid. People keep talking of a coming storm. And the island is slowly but surely sinking into the ocean.

The game is played out over the course of five to seven evenings (rounds of play; this is a one-shot), with the characters sitting on the hotel verandah each evening, discussing the events of the day. There will be strange and mysterious events occurring throughout the course of the game, some of them introduced by Event Cards that are drawn each evening, and some arising in the course of conversation. It is up to the players to discover explanations for these unlikely incidents. There are no dice, no conflict resolution mechanics: it&#39;s entirely up to the players to cooperatively craft a satisfying story.

Safety tools will include Lines and Veils, the X-Card, Script Change, and the open door policy.

The game requires four or five players. If fewer than three players sign up, the game will be cancelled. (I expect to be participating solely as a facilitator, but will fill in as a player if needed.) I have scheduled the game for 3.5 hours, since I&#39;ve only run it once before and am not confident in my time estimate, but I think it will probably be a bit shorter than that, most likely 2-3 hours.

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Lyize0Bebu35O9njvl0</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 15:39:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/until-we-sink-the-last-days-of-paradise-monday-march-16-8pm-est/4344.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Until We Sink: The Last Days of Paradise (Monday, March 16, 8pm EST)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@stevendj]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stevendj">@stevendj</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Until We Sink is a GMless RPG set on a remote tropical island. The only people left on the island are one or two natives, and between two and four hotel guests. The climate is warm and pleasant, but a little humid. People keep talking of a coming storm. And the island is slowly but surely sinking into the ocean.</p>
<p>The game is played out over the course of five to seven evenings (rounds of play; this is a one-shot), with the characters sitting on the hotel verandah each evening, discussing the events of the day. There will be strange and mysterious events occurring throughout the course of the game, some of them introduced by Event Cards that are drawn each evening, and some arising in the course of conversation. It is up to the players to discover explanations for these unlikely incidents. There are no dice, no conflict resolution mechanics: it’s entirely up to the players to cooperatively craft a satisfying story.</p>
<p>Safety tools will include Lines and Veils, the X-Card, Script Change, and the open door policy.</p>
<p>The game requires four or five players. If fewer than three players sign up, the game will be cancelled. (I expect to be participating solely as a facilitator, but will fill in as a player if needed.) I have scheduled the game for 3.5 hours, since I’ve only run it once before and am not confident in my time estimate, but I think it will probably be a bit shorter than that, most likely 2-3 hours.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Lyize0Bebu35O9njvl0" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Lyize0Bebu35O9njvl0</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/until-we-sink-the-last-days-of-paradise-monday-march-16-8pm-est/4344/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/until-we-sink-the-last-days-of-paradise-monday-march-16-8pm-est/4344/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 15:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4344-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/until-we-sink-the-last-days-of-paradise-monday-march-16-8pm-est/4344.rss">Until We Sink: The Last Days of Paradise (Monday, March 16, 8pm EST)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
