<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>SWS: Traverser - Welcome To The Rest Of Your Life</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-traverser-welcome-to-the-rest-of-your-life/6151</link>
    <description>Here&#39;s a last-minute addition to the celebration of Rich&#39;s three year anniversary for SWS!

**NUMBER OF SESSIONS:**  1

**DURATION:**  3 hours

**NUMBER OF PLAYERS:**  2

**CONTENT WARNING:**  The tone of Traverser can be intensely emotional and involves characters who may have varying degrees of PTSD because it is, at least in part, an exploration of who people become when a war is done with them. There are likely to be moments of joy, wonder, and lightheartedness, and there may be moments of love and romance. This game may feature interpersonal conflict which may rise to the level of physical violence. Graphic violence will not occur on-screen in this game. There may be themes of romance/sexual tension between player-controlled characters, and/or player and GM-controlled characters, but anything more explicit than a passionate kiss or embrace will be veiled.

-------------------------------------------

In the wake of horrifying acts that killed entire planets, entire  *systems* , reality tore itself apart. Stress did it. Scarcity did it. Access to money, information, and human social intercourse dictated by oppressive forces did it. Our collective human stress just boiled up and rent reality to shreds.

And that’s how the galaxy ended.

Except it didn’t. It never does.

It reformed itself, put itself back together, only different. Maybe better. People live in smaller villages, and reality … well, everyone can see the seams in it now.

You are Force-sensitive, a woman in your 20s, and you felt all of this happen - every tear, every cry in the night, every single death, including on the planetary scale. And you helped where you could, but you couldn’t stop it.

But once the Empire, the First Order, and Palpatine were gone, much of the fighting was over. Many of the surviving soldiers on the losing side quietly destroyed as much evidence of their involvement as they could find, ran as far as they could travel, and tried to blend in wherever they ended up. 

And you? You can still use your abilities. You can still manipulate reality, but do you really want to? Is Force sensitivity a blessing or a curse for you? And after all this, you’re far from the home you once had, but do you even care about that anymore?

And what will you do now that you’re free?

-------------------------------------------

**SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:**  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet&#39;s Community Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html

**RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:**  11/29/2020, 14:00 Central Time

**SET UP INFO:**  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players will receive an email confirmation with links to relevant documents once the session is full.

**BREAKS:**  2 five minute breaks

**RECORDED:**  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.

**PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:**  No experience required, rules will be taught.

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLW-MXBKB3ZuPe6UG5</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:25:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-traverser-welcome-to-the-rest-of-your-life/6151.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>SWS: Traverser - Welcome To The Rest Of Your Life</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Here’s a last-minute addition to the celebration of Rich’s three year anniversary for SWS!</p>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF SESSIONS:</strong>  1</p>
<p><strong>DURATION:</strong>  3 hours</p>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF PLAYERS:</strong>  2</p>
<p><strong>CONTENT WARNING:</strong>  The tone of Traverser can be intensely emotional and involves characters who may have varying degrees of PTSD because it is, at least in part, an exploration of who people become when a war is done with them. There are likely to be moments of joy, wonder, and lightheartedness, and there may be moments of love and romance. This game may feature interpersonal conflict which may rise to the level of physical violence. Graphic violence will not occur on-screen in this game. There may be themes of romance/sexual tension between player-controlled characters, and/or player and GM-controlled characters, but anything more explicit than a passionate kiss or embrace will be veiled.</p>
<hr>
<p>In the wake of horrifying acts that killed entire planets, entire  <em>systems</em> , reality tore itself apart. Stress did it. Scarcity did it. Access to money, information, and human social intercourse dictated by oppressive forces did it. Our collective human stress just boiled up and rent reality to shreds.</p>
<p>And that’s how the galaxy ended.</p>
<p>Except it didn’t. It never does.</p>
<p>It reformed itself, put itself back together, only different. Maybe better. People live in smaller villages, and reality … well, everyone can see the seams in it now.</p>
<p>You are Force-sensitive, a woman in your 20s, and you felt all of this happen - every tear, every cry in the night, every single death, including on the planetary scale. And you helped where you could, but you couldn’t stop it.</p>
<p>But once the Empire, the First Order, and Palpatine were gone, much of the fighting was over. Many of the surviving soldiers on the losing side quietly destroyed as much evidence of their involvement as they could find, ran as far as they could travel, and tried to blend in wherever they ended up.</p>
<p>And you? You can still use your abilities. You can still manipulate reality, but do you really want to? Is Force sensitivity a blessing or a curse for you? And after all this, you’re far from the home you once had, but do you even care about that anymore?</p>
<p>And what will you do now that you’re free?</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:</strong>  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet’s Community Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a></p>
<p><strong>RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:</strong>  11/29/2020, 14:00 Central Time</p>
<p><strong>SET UP INFO:</strong>  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players will receive an email confirmation with links to relevant documents once the session is full.</p>
<p><strong>BREAKS:</strong>  2 five minute breaks</p>
<p><strong>RECORDED:</strong>  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.</p>
<p><strong>PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:</strong>  No experience required, rules will be taught.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLW-MXBKB3ZuPe6UG5" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLW-MXBKB3ZuPe6UG5</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-traverser-welcome-to-the-rest-of-your-life/6151/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-traverser-welcome-to-the-rest-of-your-life/6151/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:25:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6151-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sws-traverser-welcome-to-the-rest-of-your-life/6151.rss">SWS: Traverser - Welcome To The Rest Of Your Life</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
