<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Bump in the Dark: Welcome to Last Pine</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-welcome-to-last-pine/8208</link>
    <description>This is a 4 session, month-long series of  **Bump in the Dark**, a tabletop roleplaying game about a group of people who, for better or worse, have dedicated their lives to hunting and dealing with monsters. There are gruesome attacks, tense investigations, nasty cryptids, nefarious factions, powerful demons, action-packed showdowns, and regular folk caught in the middle. The game takes place in 1994, in the region of the fictional Ontonagon Peninsula known as &quot;Iron Country,&quot; a belt of mining towns barely clinging to life. It&#39;s a place ravaged by both the indifferent forces of industry and the supernatural forces of the void. You will play a hunter, and you&#39;ve promised to keep regular people safe from the horrors in the darkness. It is scheduled for Sunday mornings in September at 11 aM US Central Time, starting September 4th.

*Bump in the Dark*  uses a simplified version of the Forged in the Dark engine and the Redacted Materials investigation system seen in  *External Containment Bureau*  and adapted from  *Brindlewood Bay* . The game uses a simple d6 dice pool for action resolution, creating complications and consequences that drive the story forward. You spend luck to add dice to your pool or resist dangerous consequences and gather clues to aid in your investigation, leading to the inevitable showdown with the monster. Then it&#39;s downtime, geared toward pushing your hunters together and tearing them apart. No prior experience is required; rules will be taught at the table.

**Content**: The game focuses on investigation and combat with horror elements. It defaults to a gritty tone with difficult content such as violence, sacrifice, redemption, found family, othering, class conflict, and paranormal, demonic, psychological, and body horror. Think Buffy or Supernatural with an R rating. Romance can be included if desired.

**Attendance**: Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. RSVP Open Access Time is Wednesday, July 13 at 12 PM Central Time.

**Venue and Safety Tools**: We will use Streamyard for our sessions. Players can expect an email about a week before the first session with necessary links and resources. Please check your spam folders if you don&#39;t receive anything. Sessions will run up to three hours with a ten-minute break at the one-hour mark and a five-minute break at the two-hour mark. Sessions will be recorded but posted publicly only with everyone&#39;s enthusiastic consent. The [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) and [Open Door Policy](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/tools-of-the-table.html) will be in effect and safety tools will include [Lines and Veils](https://rpg.stackexchange.com/questions/30906/%20what-do-the-terms-lines-and-veils-mean), the [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg), and elements of [Script Change](https://briebeau.com/thoughty/script-change/). After the session, players will be invited to participate in an optional debrief using [Stars and Wishes](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/stars-and-wishes).

[date=2022-09-04 time=11:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] → [date=2022-09-04 time=14:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 1](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k7agOEFbHyK5FaQ04)
[date=2022-09-11 time=11:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] → [date=2022-09-11 time=14:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 2](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k7rHxb76uat336rFW)
[date=2022-09-18 time=11:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] → [date=2022-09-18 time=14:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 3](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k7ypuCoW3ONAdytp3)
[date=2022-09-25 time=11:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] → [date=2022-09-25 time=14:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/Chicago&quot;] [Session 4](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k87g5UsBdO875DNrv)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 02:09:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-welcome-to-last-pine/8208.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Bump in the Dark: Welcome to Last Pine</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is a 4 session, month-long series of  <strong>Bump in the Dark</strong>, a tabletop roleplaying game about a group of people who, for better or worse, have dedicated their lives to hunting and dealing with monsters. There are gruesome attacks, tense investigations, nasty cryptids, nefarious factions, powerful demons, action-packed showdowns, and regular folk caught in the middle. The game takes place in 1994, in the region of the fictional Ontonagon Peninsula known as “Iron Country,” a belt of mining towns barely clinging to life. It’s a place ravaged by both the indifferent forces of industry and the supernatural forces of the void. You will play a hunter, and you’ve promised to keep regular people safe from the horrors in the darkness. It is scheduled for Sunday mornings in September at 11 aM US Central Time, starting September 4th.</p>
<p><em>Bump in the Dark</em>  uses a simplified version of the Forged in the Dark engine and the Redacted Materials investigation system seen in  <em>External Containment Bureau</em>  and adapted from  <em>Brindlewood Bay</em> . The game uses a simple d6 dice pool for action resolution, creating complications and consequences that drive the story forward. You spend luck to add dice to your pool or resist dangerous consequences and gather clues to aid in your investigation, leading to the inevitable showdown with the monster. Then it’s downtime, geared toward pushing your hunters together and tearing them apart. No prior experience is required; rules will be taught at the table.</p>
<p><strong>Content</strong>: The game focuses on investigation and combat with horror elements. It defaults to a gritty tone with difficult content such as violence, sacrifice, redemption, found family, othering, class conflict, and paranormal, demonic, psychological, and body horror. Think Buffy or Supernatural with an R rating. Romance can be included if desired.</p>
<p><strong>Attendance</strong>: Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. RSVP Open Access Time is Wednesday, July 13 at 12 PM Central Time.</p>
<p><strong>Venue and Safety Tools</strong>: We will use Streamyard for our sessions. Players can expect an email about a week before the first session with necessary links and resources. Please check your spam folders if you don’t receive anything. Sessions will run up to three hours with a ten-minute break at the one-hour mark and a five-minute break at the two-hour mark. Sessions will be recorded but posted publicly only with everyone’s enthusiastic consent. The <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> and <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/tools-of-the-table.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Open Door Policy</a> will be in effect and safety tools will include <a href="https://rpg.stackexchange.com/questions/30906/%20what-do-the-terms-lines-and-veils-mean" rel="nofollow noopener">Lines and Veils</a>, the <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">X-Card</a>, and elements of <a href="https://briebeau.com/thoughty/script-change/" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change</a>. After the session, players will be invited to participate in an optional debrief using <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/stars-and-wishes" rel="nofollow noopener">Stars and Wishes</a>.</p>
<p><span data-date="2022-09-04" data-time="11:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-04T16:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-04T16:00:00Z</span> → <span data-date="2022-09-04" data-time="14:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-04T19:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-04T19:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k7agOEFbHyK5FaQ04" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 1</a><br>
<span data-date="2022-09-11" data-time="11:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-11T16:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-11T16:00:00Z</span> → <span data-date="2022-09-11" data-time="14:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-11T19:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-11T19:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k7rHxb76uat336rFW" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 2</a><br>
<span data-date="2022-09-18" data-time="11:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-18T16:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-18T16:00:00Z</span> → <span data-date="2022-09-18" data-time="14:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-18T19:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-18T19:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k7ypuCoW3ONAdytp3" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 3</a><br>
<span data-date="2022-09-25" data-time="11:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-25T16:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-25T16:00:00Z</span> → <span data-date="2022-09-25" data-time="14:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Chicago" data-email-preview="2022-09-25T19:00:00Z UTC">2022-09-25T19:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6k87g5UsBdO875DNrv" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 4</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-welcome-to-last-pine/8208/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-welcome-to-last-pine/8208/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 02:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8208-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/bump-in-the-dark-welcome-to-last-pine/8208.rss">Bump in the Dark: Welcome to Last Pine</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
