<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Brindlewood Bay: Who Killed Mr. Boddy? (A CLUE-Themed One-Shot)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/brindlewood-bay-who-killed-mr-boddy-a-clue-themed-one-shot/7604</link>
    <description>RSVP link: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mom-XhhghpFcUUk98Li

*The wizened antiquarian Mr. Boddy hosts a New Year&#39;s Eve soiree every year at his fabulous Tudor mansion outside Brindlewood Bay. This year, he has also promised to reveal his newest acquisition: a primeval, eldritch artifact he claims to have excavated from the wreckage of the infamous Deep Reaver, a ship lost at sea for over one hundred years. But someone at the soiree has other plans for how to ring in the New Year. Two questions arise. First, who killed Mr. Boddy? Was it Colonel Mustard with the revolver? Or perhaps Miss Scarlet with the candlestick? And second, just who was it that took Boddy&#39;s ancient artifact containing questionable connections to a malign cosmic void intent on dooming humanity to one million years of darkness?*

Who Killed Mr. Boddy? is a one-shot convention-length scenario for Brindlewood Bay in which the famous Murder Mavens (the PCs) are inserted into the classic board game, Clue (or Cluedo in the UK). Over the course of a New Year&#39;s party gone wrong, the mavens will work to solve the mystery of who killed Mr. Boddy and stole his artifact of the Void. Of course, just uncovering the murderer&#39;s identity is not enough--you&#39;ll have to stop them from summoning an eternity of certain doom, too! So hurry up! The stroke of midnight is fast approaching!

This is a playtest scenario designed similarly to previously published &quot;Sweeps Week&quot; mysteries and the scenario, &quot;Bed, Breakfast, and Beyond.&quot; To accommodate the scenario&#39;s short run-time, players will have a shared pool of New Year&#39;s-themed crown moves to bolster their rolls, rather than drawing from the standard crowns used in long-term play. Some maven moves may also be modified, added, or excluded.

While this is a playtest, I will certainly make sure everyone has a great time, and if all goes well may present a modified version of this one-shot at a GCOG in the future.

**System :** Brindlewood Bay

**Duration :** One 4-hour session

**Breaks :** Breaks at the top of each hour-ish (~5 minutes)

**Venue :** Zoom

**Recording :** With permission from all participants before and after the session

**Attendance :** One-shot

**Safety :** Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.

This game will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

All Access RSVP availability will open 11/20/2021 at 2am US Central Time.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 07:48:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/brindlewood-bay-who-killed-mr-boddy-a-clue-themed-one-shot/7604.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Brindlewood Bay: Who Killed Mr. Boddy? (A CLUE-Themed One-Shot)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@David_S]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/david_s">@David_S</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>RSVP link: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mom-XhhghpFcUUk98Li" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mom-XhhghpFcUUk98Li</a></p>
<p><em>The wizened antiquarian Mr. Boddy hosts a New Year’s Eve soiree every year at his fabulous Tudor mansion outside Brindlewood Bay. This year, he has also promised to reveal his newest acquisition: a primeval, eldritch artifact he claims to have excavated from the wreckage of the infamous Deep Reaver, a ship lost at sea for over one hundred years. But someone at the soiree has other plans for how to ring in the New Year. Two questions arise. First, who killed Mr. Boddy? Was it Colonel Mustard with the revolver? Or perhaps Miss Scarlet with the candlestick? And second, just who was it that took Boddy’s ancient artifact containing questionable connections to a malign cosmic void intent on dooming humanity to one million years of darkness?</em></p>
<p>Who Killed Mr. Boddy? is a one-shot convention-length scenario for Brindlewood Bay in which the famous Murder Mavens (the PCs) are inserted into the classic board game, Clue (or Cluedo in the UK). Over the course of a New Year’s party gone wrong, the mavens will work to solve the mystery of who killed Mr. Boddy and stole his artifact of the Void. Of course, just uncovering the murderer’s identity is not enough–you’ll have to stop them from summoning an eternity of certain doom, too! So hurry up! The stroke of midnight is fast approaching!</p>
<p>This is a playtest scenario designed similarly to previously published “Sweeps Week” mysteries and the scenario, “Bed, Breakfast, and Beyond.” To accommodate the scenario’s short run-time, players will have a shared pool of New Year’s-themed crown moves to bolster their rolls, rather than drawing from the standard crowns used in long-term play. Some maven moves may also be modified, added, or excluded.</p>
<p>While this is a playtest, I will certainly make sure everyone has a great time, and if all goes well may present a modified version of this one-shot at a GCOG in the future.</p>
<p><strong>System :</strong> Brindlewood Bay</p>
<p><strong>Duration :</strong> One 4-hour session</p>
<p><strong>Breaks :</strong> Breaks at the top of each hour-ish (~5 minutes)</p>
<p><strong>Venue :</strong> Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Recording :</strong> With permission from all participants before and after the session</p>
<p><strong>Attendance :</strong> One-shot</p>
<p><strong>Safety :</strong> Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.</p>
<p>This game will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p>All Access RSVP availability will open 11/20/2021 at 2am US Central Time.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/brindlewood-bay-who-killed-mr-boddy-a-clue-themed-one-shot/7604/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/brindlewood-bay-who-killed-mr-boddy-a-clue-themed-one-shot/7604/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 07:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7604-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/brindlewood-bay-who-killed-mr-boddy-a-clue-themed-one-shot/7604.rss">Brindlewood Bay: Who Killed Mr. Boddy? (A CLUE-Themed One-Shot)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
