<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Primetime Fiasco?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/primetime-fiasco/4832</link>
    <description>Been stuck in &quot;restricted movement&quot; in my area (I live in Kuala Lumpur) for a week already. Going to try something online with some friends soon. I have run one game of Fiasco in the past for a different group, and think it translates well into a Zoom meeting. 
But, that being said, I was thinking of Primetime Adventures becuase it gives us something to &quot;play with&quot;, as in the cards, but maybe Fiasco would be better. Most of the people would be first time rpg players, but they are part of a regular game night group (playing Eurogames, Codenames, etc) so the tangible aspect might be important.

As a side project, my brain goes into some kind of mashup of the two. Has anyone ever tried something similar or know of that?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 04:09:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/primetime-fiasco/4832.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Primetime Fiasco?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dannythewall]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dannythewall">@dannythewall</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Been stuck in “restricted movement” in my area (I live in Kuala Lumpur) for a week already. Going to try something online with some friends soon. I have run one game of Fiasco in the past for a different group, and think it translates well into a Zoom meeting.<br>
But, that being said, I was thinking of Primetime Adventures becuase it gives us something to “play with”, as in the cards, but maybe Fiasco would be better. Most of the people would be first time rpg players, but they are part of a regular game night group (playing Eurogames, Codenames, etc) so the tangible aspect might be important.</p>
<p>As a side project, my brain goes into some kind of mashup of the two. Has anyone ever tried something similar or know of that?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/primetime-fiasco/4832/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/primetime-fiasco/4832/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 03:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4832-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/primetime-fiasco/4832.rss">Primetime Fiasco?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
