<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Eotenweard - The Elmet Witch</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-elmet-witch/5055</link>
    <description>A session of **Eotenweard**, my PbtA game of Dark Age monster-hunting, run as part of this months **Gauntlet Community Open Gaming (GCOG)** weekend ... a Celtic Christian King needs an unkillable witch, killed ...
One of the players got it right when they said ... &quot;I&#39;m sitting here processing how it ended and realised that the most inhuman character (literally a sometimes incorporeal spirit) ended up growing the most as a person, the most human character ended up losing their humanity, the on-the-surface &quot;lighter&quot; cleric slayed the maybe-but-maybe-not a monster in a religious fervour and the on-the-surface &quot;darker&quot; cleric wept for the monster she was sworn to slay. That symmetry in our character arcs is just so satisfying!&quot;
It was a great session!

https://youtu.be/Bz2vAwJayQ8</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-elmet-witch/5055.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Eotenweard - The Elmet Witch</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A session of <strong>Eotenweard</strong>, my PbtA game of Dark Age monster-hunting, run as part of this months <strong>Gauntlet Community Open Gaming (GCOG)</strong> weekend … a Celtic Christian King needs an unkillable witch, killed …<br>
One of the players got it right when they said … “I’m sitting here processing how it ended and realised that the most inhuman character (literally a sometimes incorporeal spirit) ended up growing the most as a person, the most human character ended up losing their humanity, the on-the-surface “lighter” cleric slayed the maybe-but-maybe-not a monster in a religious fervour and the on-the-surface “darker” cleric wept for the monster she was sworn to slay. That symmetry in our character arcs is just so satisfying!”<br>
It was a great session!</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="Bz2vAwJayQ8" data-youtube-title="GCOG Eotenweard - The Elmet Witch" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-elmet-witch/5055/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-elmet-witch/5055/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5055-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/eotenweard-the-elmet-witch/5055.rss">Eotenweard - The Elmet Witch</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
