<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>[GFC Jack O’Bear] Alice is Missing (One-shot)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gfc-jack-o-bear-alice-is-missing-one-shot/8323</link>
    <description>*****This single-session game of Alice is Missing is part of Gauntlet Facilitator Camp Jack O&#39;Bear. All three seats are reserved for camp participants (but more &quot;Alice&quot; will be coming to the Gauntlet!).*****

## Alice is Missing

An immersive RPG played entirely via text message.

*Alice is Missing*  is a silent role-playing game about the disappearance of Alice Briarwood, a high school junior in the small town of Silent Falls.

​

The game is played live and without verbal communication. Players inhabit their character for the entirety of the 90-minute play session, and instead of speaking, send text messages back and forth to the other characters in a group chat, as well as individually.

* **System:**  Custom System for &quot;Alice&quot; (no experience with the system is necessary, rules will be taught. Please see below for more information). This system is GM-light, but we use tools to keep the flow going.
* **Content warnings:** Possible themes could include violence, gender violence, kidnapping, and teen death.
* **Duration:** 2 hrs (with an additional 30 minutes for feedback)
* **Breaks:** As this game is played via Text Chats only (on Discord), breaks will be at your discretion.
* **Venue:**  Lowell has kindly offered to set up a Zoom (and provide a link the night before via email).
* **Recording:**  Depending on participant wishes.
* **Safety Tools:**  Lines &amp; Veils, X-Card and Script Change. This game will follow [the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) and the Open Door Policy is in place, meaning anyone should feel free to leave the game or cancel as needed.
* **Play aids:**  While the game is being carried out on Discord we will use the cues and timers set up in Roll-20. You can check out the basic [AIM Game Guide here](https://www.huntersentertainment.com/_files/ugd/3e98ae_5754cba2f63c474aa68b3d6c59152f63.pdf).
* **Communication:**  A confirmation email will be sent 48 hrs prior.

We will begin on Zoom with a 30-minute prep. time (including talking about the Safety Tools and discussing the technical side of the game). We&#39;ll move to Discord for the 90-minute play period and then back to Zoom for our closing discussion and debrief.

## Player To Do:

1. Discord - [create an account for yourself](https://www.discord.app/register) (if you&#39;d like to add Travis as a Friend on Discord -  **not required for this game**  - his &quot;tag&quot; is Zoic#1489),
2. Watch for the invite to the special Discord Alice is Missing server set up just for this game (will come by email)
3. Roll20 - [create your account](https://app.roll20.net/create-account). Link will be sent game-night. 

[The Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in play and safety tools ([Script Change](http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m) and [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg)) will be in use.

[date=2022-08-30 time=20:00:00  format=&quot;LLLL&quot; timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;]  [Session 1](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N9h4w9grHfN3geCiAhO)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:20:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gfc-jack-o-bear-alice-is-missing-one-shot/8323.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>[GFC Jack O’Bear] Alice is Missing (One-shot)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Travis]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/travis">@Travis</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em><strong><strong>This single-session game of Alice is Missing is part of Gauntlet Facilitator Camp Jack O’Bear. All three seats are reserved for camp participants (but more “Alice” will be coming to the Gauntlet!).</strong></strong></em></p>
<h2>Alice is Missing</h2>
<p>An immersive RPG played entirely via text message.</p>
<p><em>Alice is Missing</em>  is a silent role-playing game about the disappearance of Alice Briarwood, a high school junior in the small town of Silent Falls.</p>
<p>​</p>
<p>The game is played live and without verbal communication. Players inhabit their character for the entirety of the 90-minute play session, and instead of speaking, send text messages back and forth to the other characters in a group chat, as well as individually.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>System:</strong>  Custom System for “Alice” (no experience with the system is necessary, rules will be taught. Please see below for more information). This system is GM-light, but we use tools to keep the flow going.</li>
<li>
<strong>Content warnings:</strong> Possible themes could include violence, gender violence, kidnapping, and teen death.</li>
<li>
<strong>Duration:</strong> 2 hrs (with an additional 30 minutes for feedback)</li>
<li>
<strong>Breaks:</strong> As this game is played via Text Chats only (on Discord), breaks will be at your discretion.</li>
<li>
<strong>Venue:</strong>  Lowell has kindly offered to set up a Zoom (and provide a link the night before via email).</li>
<li>
<strong>Recording:</strong>  Depending on participant wishes.</li>
<li>
<strong>Safety Tools:</strong>  Lines &amp; Veils, X-Card and Script Change. This game will follow <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a> and the Open Door Policy is in place, meaning anyone should feel free to leave the game or cancel as needed.</li>
<li>
<strong>Play aids:</strong>  While the game is being carried out on Discord we will use the cues and timers set up in Roll-20. You can check out the basic <a href="https://www.huntersentertainment.com/_files/ugd/3e98ae_5754cba2f63c474aa68b3d6c59152f63.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">AIM Game Guide here</a>.</li>
<li>
<strong>Communication:</strong>  A confirmation email will be sent 48 hrs prior.</li>
</ul>
<p>We will begin on Zoom with a 30-minute prep. time (including talking about the Safety Tools and discussing the technical side of the game). We’ll move to Discord for the 90-minute play period and then back to Zoom for our closing discussion and debrief.</p>
<h2>Player To Do:</h2>
<ol>
<li>Discord - <a href="https://www.discord.app/register" rel="nofollow noopener">create an account for yourself</a> (if you’d like to add Travis as a Friend on Discord -  <strong>not required for this game</strong>  - his “tag” is Zoic#1489),</li>
<li>Watch for the invite to the special Discord Alice is Missing server set up just for this game (will come by email)</li>
<li>Roll20 - <a href="https://app.roll20.net/create-account" rel="nofollow noopener">create your account</a>. Link will be sent game-night.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">The Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a> will be in play and safety tools (<a href="http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change</a> and <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">X-Card</a>) will be in use.</p>
<p><span data-date="2022-08-30" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="America/New_York" data-email-preview="2022-08-31T00:00:00Z UTC">Wednesday, August 31, 2022 12:00 AM</span>  <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N9h4w9grHfN3geCiAhO" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 1</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gfc-jack-o-bear-alice-is-missing-one-shot/8323/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gfc-jack-o-bear-alice-is-missing-one-shot/8323/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8323-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gfc-jack-o-bear-alice-is-missing-one-shot/8323.rss">[GFC Jack O’Bear] Alice is Missing (One-shot)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
