<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Thirsty Sword Lesbians - Sorority Slayers</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/thirsty-sword-lesbians-sorority-slayers/6206</link>
    <description>Thirsty Sword Lesbians - Sorority Slayers!

Saturdays at 1 pm CST in February!

For the first 72 HOURS please don&#39;t RSVP unless you identify on the LGBTQ+/GRSM spectrum

Ad in the Campus Creature Feature &#39;Zine: Are you one of the special gals out there that see the true depths of depravity in the dark corners of the world? The kind of sinister shame-mining that&#39;d make you smile more and act like a “lady” when they don&#39;t even get to know you! We need you and your gall, gals! Do you have tenacity? Are you ovaries iron? Do you want a kick ass sword to fight some monsters? THEN STOP BY OMEGA GAMMA SIGMA AND BECOME A SISTER OF THE SWORD! Pay by the monster brought in, dental and vision benefits, extra credit and skip days provided.

Welcome to a game of Thirsty Sword Lesbians set in a world of urban fantasy. You are the magical sword women standing in the way of the evil monsters who cling to outmoded ways of thought and who try to stomp down what they don&#39;t understand. You think your conservative uncle doesn&#39;t get pronouns? Try a 500 year old vampire! You will be embodying one of the TSL Playbooks in a modern style game with a Dr. Strange/Buffy the Vampire Slayer/Teen Wolf veneer over the supernatural layers.

You are the sisters of the Sorority OGS, known colloquially around campus as &quot;OG Sorority&quot; for the fact they don&#39;t screw around and have access to quite a lot of swords. In this world of monsters they are the Slayer Sorority, willing to put themselves on the line for love, life, and liberation. You all are newly pledged sisters to the House, your clique joining you together in the fight against darkness. Draw your swords, sisters, and prepare for battle! And maybe a midterm...

Touchstones include: Jennifer&#39;s Body, Buffy the Vampire Slayer, MTV/CW urban fantasy shows, the Netflix She-Ra run, and iZombie. The tone is horror with comedic tones; dark but with a nightlight.

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO016VATXH6D4i67VBd
Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01IMMmbQBt_1neeEs
Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01Y6XOEdB6VBaMEOe
Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01lJCQX2zwzXOuePJ</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:35:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/thirsty-sword-lesbians-sorority-slayers/6206.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Thirsty Sword Lesbians - Sorority Slayers</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Ferret]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ferret">@Ferret</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thirsty Sword Lesbians - Sorority Slayers!</p>
<p>Saturdays at 1 pm CST in February!</p>
<p>For the first 72 HOURS please don’t RSVP unless you identify on the LGBTQ+/GRSM spectrum</p>
<p>Ad in the Campus Creature Feature 'Zine: Are you one of the special gals out there that see the true depths of depravity in the dark corners of the world? The kind of sinister shame-mining that’d make you smile more and act like a “lady” when they don’t even get to know you! We need you and your gall, gals! Do you have tenacity? Are you ovaries iron? Do you want a kick ass sword to fight some monsters? THEN STOP BY OMEGA GAMMA SIGMA AND BECOME A SISTER OF THE SWORD! Pay by the monster brought in, dental and vision benefits, extra credit and skip days provided.</p>
<p>Welcome to a game of Thirsty Sword Lesbians set in a world of urban fantasy. You are the magical sword women standing in the way of the evil monsters who cling to outmoded ways of thought and who try to stomp down what they don’t understand. You think your conservative uncle doesn’t get pronouns? Try a 500 year old vampire! You will be embodying one of the TSL Playbooks in a modern style game with a Dr. Strange/Buffy the Vampire Slayer/Teen Wolf veneer over the supernatural layers.</p>
<p>You are the sisters of the Sorority OGS, known colloquially around campus as “OG Sorority” for the fact they don’t screw around and have access to quite a lot of swords. In this world of monsters they are the Slayer Sorority, willing to put themselves on the line for love, life, and liberation. You all are newly pledged sisters to the House, your clique joining you together in the fight against darkness. Draw your swords, sisters, and prepare for battle! And maybe a midterm…</p>
<p>Touchstones include: Jennifer’s Body, Buffy the Vampire Slayer, MTV/CW urban fantasy shows, the Netflix She-Ra run, and iZombie. The tone is horror with comedic tones; dark but with a nightlight.</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO016VATXH6D4i67VBd" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO016VATXH6D4i67VBd</a><br>
Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01IMMmbQBt_1neeEs" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01IMMmbQBt_1neeEs</a><br>
Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01Y6XOEdB6VBaMEOe" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01Y6XOEdB6VBaMEOe</a><br>
Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01lJCQX2zwzXOuePJ" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MO01lJCQX2zwzXOuePJ</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/thirsty-sword-lesbians-sorority-slayers/6206/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/thirsty-sword-lesbians-sorority-slayers/6206/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 06:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6206-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/thirsty-sword-lesbians-sorority-slayers/6206.rss">Thirsty Sword Lesbians - Sorority Slayers</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
