<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Black Armada hath a Patreon</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374</link>
    <description>Hi everyone

I&#39;m excited to announce that today we (Josh and Becky) are starting a [Patreon](https://www.patreon.com/blackarmada). We hope to use it to put more time into creating smaller RPGs, writing supplements for our games, and blogging about gaming.

We&#39;re super-excited about getting our teeth into some focused, evocative little games. You can get a taste of what we&#39;ve got planned by checking out the Patreon page, and by downloading our free sample game, [Soap Bubble](https://www.patreon.com/posts/27548830). Soap Bubble follows the lives of the characters in a soap opera that you create, and the actors who play them. It&#39;s great fun!

You can also take a look at the Black Armada blog, where we&#39;ve already got loads of great gaming content. The latest article was posted today, about [how I prep investigation games](https://blackarmada.com/how-i-run-investigation-games-part-1-prep/). More coming soon!

You&#39;ll also get access to a patrons-only discord channel where you can chat to us about our games and gaming in general. I hope to see you on there!

Please do [support us on Patreon](https://www.patreon.com/blackarmada), and we&#39;d really appreciate it if you shared the link on social media as we really want to get the word out about this. Thanks for all your support :)

Cheers

Josh and Becky</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 19:32:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Black Armada hath a Patreon</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rabalias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If you’ve been pondering getting on the Black Armada patreon, you might be interested to know our latest game, <em>What the Water gave me</em> by <a class="mention" href="/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a>, has just been released to our backers.</p>
<p><em>WTWGM</em> tells tales of tragedy and death across the centuries, around a sinister and cursed millpool. You play characters in the 17th century and modern times, and your experiences around the millpool echo and feed back into each other. It’s delightfully bleak!</p>
<p>If you like the sound of that, check out the patreon link above.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 19:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2374-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374.rss">Black Armada hath a Patreon</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Black Armada hath a Patreon</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rabalias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi everyone</p>
<p>I’m excited to announce that today we (Josh and Becky) are starting a <a href="https://www.patreon.com/blackarmada" rel="nofollow noopener">Patreon</a>. We hope to use it to put more time into creating smaller RPGs, writing supplements for our games, and blogging about gaming.</p>
<p>We’re super-excited about getting our teeth into some focused, evocative little games. You can get a taste of what we’ve got planned by checking out the Patreon page, and by downloading our free sample game, <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/27548830" rel="nofollow noopener">Soap Bubble</a>. Soap Bubble follows the lives of the characters in a soap opera that you create, and the actors who play them. It’s great fun!</p>
<p>You can also take a look at the Black Armada blog, where we’ve already got loads of great gaming content. The latest article was posted today, about <a href="https://blackarmada.com/how-i-run-investigation-games-part-1-prep/" rel="nofollow noopener">how I prep investigation games</a>. More coming soon!</p>
<p>You’ll also get access to a patrons-only discord channel where you can chat to us about our games and gaming in general. I hope to see you on there!</p>
<p>Please do <a href="https://www.patreon.com/blackarmada" rel="nofollow noopener">support us on Patreon</a>, and we’d really appreciate it if you shared the link on social media as we really want to get the word out about this. Thanks for all your support <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Cheers</p>
<p>Josh and Becky</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 15:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2374-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/black-armada-hath-a-patreon/2374.rss">Black Armada hath a Patreon</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
