<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622</link>
    <description>Hi everyone, I think I&#39;m at the edge of something, but I&#39;m still having problems to put things together, perhaps you can throw me a line here. I&#39;m back to my old game design and I wanted to try something else. It&#39;s the old distribute GM chores among players, except that I&#39;m really keen on making it so nobody feels them like chores.

Like, I spent a few years investigating and testing stuff for quick cooperative worldbuilding, until I got a 20-min minigame where players draw a map together, get a few questions and random tables to get them going. I also went the Fate Accelerated way about letting players come up with their skills, powers and items during the game, so at the start of the game they only need a concept for their character and establish bonds between their characters and the world they just made up. Everything ties back into worldbuilding and adventure creation thightly so far, but now I&#39;m searching for two things:

1-get players to help in creating interesting challenges (Could those be tied to their character bonds? Also, I was watching [the gameplay of Vast](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=scZo1EKqDG8), a tabletop game where one player gets to play the dungeon, another plays the orcs and another plays the dragon. It&#39;s competitive but it got me thinking, what if I could get players into the proper mindset and have a simple move they could pull out to flesh out some good challenges here and then?. I already tested something similar, a deck of cards anyone could take whenever it wasn&#39;t their turn that let them add details to the scene, like sounds, descriptions of minor objects, take control of an NPC or even a monster, where the GM provided a goal for such character to the player and it was up to her to explain how they confronted the task. Still needs work, but maybe I&#39;m missing simpler options?

2-get players to second-guess parts of plot development so the GM can take those suggestions up to 11 and into the next level. This is nothing new, like mountain-witching the players has been there for ages and I&#39;ve totally been using it, and there&#39;s just listening to players ideas when they are excited and sprout something like &quot;hey, wouldn&#39;t be fun if...?&quot;. Yet I&#39;m sure other designers have already come up with more tools to help players accomplish this. My goal here would be to have some sort of procedure where players can eventually come up with the solution to a mystery the GM hasn&#39;t invented yet, based on the accumulation of details and facts they have feed the setting with since the beggining of the session. It needs some way to filter pieces that don&#39;t fit into a plausible solution, branding them as red-herrings to keep results coherent. Have you heard of some game mechanic that already does this?

Thanks everyone for your time, whatever you can throw me here would be really appreciated.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:15:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Great post! A few additional things I’ve discovered with playtesting:<br>
-On Why? I can add that brainstorming the setting together get’s everyone in the same page quicker and gets everybody’s expectations on the same level. No more lengthy introductions to the setting or expectations betrayed by the focus taken by the GM.<br>
-Asking players for facts (like your “One Truth” happens to be a bit aggressive on them. As in <em>may cause a blank page syndrome</em> because nobody still knows how wild or even gonzo things can go, or what’s the atmosphere others are looking for. Of course, eventually everyone adapts, but the first player giving input ends up focusing on being bold instead of just saying what they would like to see. The GM is usually that first player, so she usually won’t have problems being bold. However by using the Palette and letting everyone just say a single word on what they want to see or not in the game, they get more relaxed as nothing is set on stone yet.</p>
<p>All the rest is great advice, especially build upon whatever has been said before. I do a lot of follow-up questions too to keep building upon things, specially after players create their PCs. By nature everyone will create characters that could inhabit that world but at the same time those characters will imply the existence of more material, like cultures, history, etc. I still need to add the follow-up questions as part of the process though, I totally forgot to mention them!</p>
<p>There’s a limit to how much material you really need and will see use in the game in short term, that’s why my worldbuilding process is that brief and limited to a single kingdom/region/area or even just one town. So, while it’s cool to have lots of stuff to choose from, leaving too much outside betrays the expectations of some players. That’s the reason I chose to keep player input somewhat limited, at least until more material is needed.</p>
<p>And I totally agree there’s nothing better than being surprised by your own players wild ideas.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/39</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yochaigal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yochaigal">@yochaigal</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is wonderful. I’ve also just discovered your actual setting palette tool, very cool. I wrote a <a href="https://newschoolrevolution.com/2020/02/19/build-your-world" rel="nofollow noopener">post</a> on collab worldbuilding earlier this year, this is making me feel inspired all over again!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/38</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 14:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="https://resourcefullrpg.wordpress.com/2020/04/05/setting-brainstorming-sheet-version-2-0/" rel="nofollow noopener">Worldbuilding tool updated!</a></p>
<p>This improved version includes technology and population into the Palette, as it’s actually this moment in the brainstorming where players mention such things. It gets rid of the third front because players usually become a front themselves, so another one rarely sees enough use, becomes decorative or just makes short campaigns confusing. Anyway, the tool is there if you really want to make more fronts. The fronts stats were an additional step that in practice proved to be unnecessary, even if rolling dice to generate them randomly was kinda fun. I think it’s best if this tool keeps track of things useful to the GM, so a big part of that got replaced with space for PCs, NPCs, and all sorts of bonds. I found that these bonds really do get things in motion, better than an Event Generator, so that one went away too. As long as you keep building upon the player’s input and link their characters to everything you can and between themselves, players will give you motivations and kickers they will really be invested into.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/37</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 20:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, I should update the worldbuilding tool too, but I’ve got some work to finish first. It may take a while <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/36</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Are you going to copy / paste this to your blog some time ?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/35</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 06:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Fun fact: I’ve done this too! <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=9" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"><br>
I used <span class="hashtag">#1</span> and <span class="hashtag">#2</span> to start a D&amp;D campaign. After we brainstormed the setting and a rough map I told the players: “you come together at the Inn, as usual. Drinks come and go and each of you hears a different rumour around that picks your interest. What is it?”. Each one said something simple that was related to their character, each one a nice simple thing I could have spun into a good adventure, but the last one just asked the barman for adventure and got me suggesting they could go into an ancient battleground to try and find magical weapons. Except that later in the campaign I took all their suggestions and built on what could have happened in all these places that they didn’t go. On one of them a small demonic posession became a demon stronghold that blocked the capital and was about to open a portal to bring reinforcements from hell.</p>
<p>Also at some point I asked a player what do his character do. Jokingly he said “Ok, I kick a Tarrasque”. I didn’t laugh and reply “all right, you do. It’s a really small one that goes flying, falls against a tree and then runs away”. Everyone laughed. A couple of sessions later they discovered an imprisioned group of tieflings summoned the devourer of planes to get their revenge, except that they failed the invocation due to anti-magical measures present on their eternal prision. When they were released along with the dragon’s orb of power (the item that kept them imprisioned and got cut in half by one of the PCs cursed sword) I tell the player: “At that point, distracted by the battle, you see a small shadow jump at half of the orb of power… yes, it’s the Tarrasque you kicked weeks ago, now growing to full size and looking at you reaaally pissed”</p>
<p>I made an end-session mechanic where players could try to improve their Bonds with other characters. I gave Bonds a durability score like if they were items, so, In the middle of the session, whenever they rolled a fumble they could chose to fail foward and take damage to their bonds. At the end of the session they could play scenes to try and fix these by roleplaying, so we got some downtime scenes where either their character got warming bonding moments or drama further ensued.</p>
<p>The instant character-relevant secrets might be easier to introduce as a blank Bond that can be either created by the player or suggested by the GM when it makes sense. Like, whenever players choose to fail foward they could put instead points into this “dark secret” bond and once it reaches a value (4 or 6, nothing too high so it acts sooner) their secret is discovered. Either at the start of the game or just when it’s discovered, the player can talk it with the GM and decide what it is.</p>
<p>I’ve also been working on another procedure to create/discover mysteries at the same time. I’ll try to sketch what I have so far:</p>
<p>First step can be prepped by the GM or done with the player’s help, it doesn’t change things too much either way as long as players keep what they wrote in secret. The GM/the group fills 10 cards with simple generic clues: “a corpse”, “somebody dissapears”, “something important is missing”, “tracks of blood”, “a tomb”, etc. All cards are mixed into a single pile. The GM draws and shows everyone the first card to set a starting point for the mistery and then takes 4 cards.</p>
<p>On each scene a card from the pile is revealed, though players have to explain what makes this clue particular, interesting or relevant and write it down on the card. If they can’t link it yet to the case, the GM can reveal one of their own cards as another clue, or save it for later if she can’t make the connection. If the GM uses all her cards, it’s game over and the GM narrates a bad ending: the mystery isn’t completely resolved, the problem continues, the culprit escapes, etc. If the players manage to connect 5 cards with the case and explain it, the mystery is solved and a positive outcome is narrated.</p>
<p>If players need to use any of the GM clues to solve the mystery, the GM can introduce a negative twist or consequence for each one used.</p>
<p>This is totally untested but if you can see any potential pitfalls please let me know. Perhaps the clues can be predefined with a random table like Fiasco’s sets? Still needs a lot of work.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 02:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The things I have fooled around with in the past are:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Have the players suggest clues and theories, and then have a procedure for secretly determining which are true and/or which are valid clues. Basically, the players suggest “rumours” (“we heard there is treasure in the sunken ship”/“we heard the mayor is actually a werewolf”), and the GM secretly rolls for what’s actually true - it’s true, it’s false, it’s true but misleading somehow, or it’s far more true than the rumour suggests. This can be fun, but I haven’t run with this quite enough to feel I’ve explored these techniques.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The players are given prompts to create material, and then I, as the GM, have tools for drawing connections between those things. Here’s a really obvious example:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Player one says that they have a mentor who holds some important secrets.</li>
<li>Player two says that they are searching for their ex-lover.</li>
<li>The GM rolls some dice and determines that the mentor and the ex-lover must be linked somehow. Perhaps you decide that they are one and the same person.</li>
</ul>
<p>Instant character-relevant secrets/drama. If you do this a lot, you start to get the implications of further mysteries “behind the scenes” which you then have to detail and reveal. (For me, that’s part of the fun of this playstyle, but I get the impression that you want to be able to get all the details upfront, more like the first example.)</p>
<p>Generally speaking, though, I’ve yet to see anything which generates <em>great</em> mysteries “on the spot”. Usually, something carefully crafted by one person in their off time tends to be of much better and more satisfying quality. It all depends what you value most in your game!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/33</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 23:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s as if there were two systems, like those campaigns you worldbulid with a worlbuilding game, then play with an adventure game. It has to be stated clearly but it sure works.</p>
<p>An idea I had for a hunters / hunted VtM scenario was to alternate play of one set of characters with another set of characters. The hunted would leave tracks for the hunters to follow. In your case, this would go : GM sets clues, newbies find clues, players propose theories for them, flashbacks on the ancients validate them, leaving more clues. You need one rule to limit what the ancients can assert. I’d prefer if there was a mechanism for newbies to “find” (in fact, produce) clues independent of the GM.  I would also enjoy a system where a player would be rewarded for having their character believe false theories. Affording “playing to lose” would free up mental space to focus on the workings of mystery-discovery.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 12:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree. Though I’ve got a particular point of view about having the players coming up with details of the mystery and acting to solve the mystery. They are definitely at odds if you try to use both at the same time, but can’t they work together if used in separate moments of the game?</p>
<p>Like, when you see a movie or any fictional material with a mystery and you figure out it before its revealed… but better. Let’s say that as a GM you use cards or another randomizer to give the players a starting point and use some questions to help them create further detail for each clue. Then with the third clue, in the middle of the game you decide “Ah, this would be the mystery then”, announce to the players that you know the solution and then the players try to solve it. No further input can be added in the form of clues by the players, now they have to connect the dots and find out evidence that the GM can now easily decide if it exists or not. Thus you probaly only need the framework for the first half of the session, maybe a bit more. Does it make sense?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/31</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 03:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Very interesting!</p>
<p>I see two things, from an initial read:</p>
<p>First, in the mystery that failed, you are trying to combine two things - the players coming up with/inventing the details of the mystery, and the players acting to solve/discover the mystery. Those two things are quite at odds, as I hope you can see.</p>
<p>So, what you need is some kind of clever framework.</p>
<p>In the second, successful example, you’ve got a clever framework: the setup and the cards (which are designed to be incompatible) are creating clear goals for the players, and enough constraints that them simply playing those characters is enough to flesh out the mystery. No one is at cross-purposes; the point of play at any given moment is crystal clear.</p>
<p>So, the immediate and obvious lesson we might draw from this is that a) when you have a mystery in place, and you want to answer it without answering it yourself, b) you build a framework (a scenario, basically, or even a mini-game) that the players can play through to flesh out the details of the mystery. In this case, the fictional frame (providing constraints) and the secret cards which set them at odds with each other are what is doing the heavy lifting. I don’t know how generalizable this is, but it seems to me that this is what happened and how it worked in your example. Do you agree or disagree?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/30</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 03:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Not exactly a failure but…<br>
We had a great cyberpunk campaign with my players. Once that finished we started a new one set a 1000 years after an apocaliptic event that destroyed the setting from the previous. The PCs in the new campaign are discovering that their old PCs were involved. None are directly related to their old PCs but each of the old ones has left their mark in the new world.<br>
That got solved in the branstorm for the worldbuilding session we did.<br>
However there’s the unsolved mystery of what was the event that destroyed everything and how exactly were their old PCs involved. I’ve got some ideas but for me it calls for a heavy effort in writing details about how each character died trying to save the world, and coming up with a way to explain it to the players through the ruins, remains and old recordings. On top of that all this information needs to be discovered by the players in the right order so the mystery isn’t spoiled.</p>
<p>All this means for me that I’ve got to do the heavy lifting as a GM and can’t rely too much on the players. And that at least for the mystery part I’ve got to build a theme-park railroad, a practice I’m not so fond of today. I’ll have to do it anyway and already have guidelines on how, but I wish I had better procedures to get help from the players to create that stuff when the time comes and not before… <em>because I’d like to be surprised too</em>.</p>
<p>One of the things that convinced me it was possible to involve the players in solving mysteries by creating them was when some years ago, with a different group of players on another campaign, we played a session with a hacked version of Microscope to brainstorm a flashback explaining a similar mystery. It worked wonderfully.</p>
<p>That time we were all aware of the constraints of the setting: that the people from the distant past had very advanced technology, that they had to fight something far superior to their possibilities and were defeated, but somehow left something for their descendants, something to hope on. I told all players they would roleplay each a King of the old civilization and that they could create five of any technologycal device they could think of.</p>
<p>Next, interdimensional aliens attack and they roleplay separately how they barely fend off the first wave of the invasion using those devices. They get an ultimatum from the aliens, so they set a holo meeting. Then we randomly get one card each where a constraint is added for each of the Kings: every one has an agenda or a condition they need to fullfill to give their aid and form a united front, so now the scene is about negotiating those conditions. As it turns out, its these cards that make them incompatible and end up explaining what did each one and why humanity lost. Like, I played a king that would do anything to get a truce. Another one wanted to ensure their people would be safe. There was one would help but only if they gpt anything from it, and so on. In the end, each got to describe what did they do before the final colapse and how each king died. So at the end of that session I narrated how the regular PCs saw this as a holovideo recorded by the last surviving inmortal king, who had been the villain of the whole campaign and only was trying to either stop humanity from becoming a threat again for the aliens and calling their attention but at the same time testing them and pushing them to evolve so they could defeat the aliens one day.</p>
<p>Anyway, I got amazed by this as a GM and definitely wouldn’t be able to come up with something so good on my own. It didn’t felt like we were writing anything, we just roleplayed through the whole thing and the constraints did the rest of the work. Zero blank page syndrome, zero creative pressure. I wasn’t too sure at the start but now I’m glad we went this way.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/29</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 01:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You’re right. It also depends on player expectations. If the game is clear about the whole case being improvised and the fun not being about “guessing right as a player” but about gaming the system so “your character guesses things right” then there can be a viable path to get a different fun.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 21:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It also depends on the genre of mystery : hardboiled gets away with holed plots, while supernatural / madness can cover up fantastic plot holes. If you want a Conan Doyle perfect plot, you’ve got to start by the end, which requires specific tools.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 08:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think the key might be for you to tell us about a specific kind of failure in this sense - tell us about an actual session that didn’t go as well as you’d hoped - and then we can start thinking about how you wish it had gone, instead. And then we can brainstorm solutions and tools.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/26</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 03:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Well, right now I don’t feel prepared to impro a mystery/crime confidently with the tools I’ve got at hand. A simple random table isn’t enough to get a good starting kick for my tastes, nor for adding clues that make sense <em>always</em>. Leaving that to the players puts too much pressure on them, specially without a proper procedure to limit their input enough so they don’t feel the pressure nor the need to wrap things up with the next big reveal. I’m ok if the players propose a solution to the mystery/crime based on all/some of the clues they already have and then roleplay/roll to find evidence that confirms their theory. Everything else not used becomes red herrings and is discarded as coincidence or the felons covering up their tracks.</p>
<p>Seems that part of the answer takes me back to my Resourcefull Deck project, so I’m back working on this right now. I’ll put a link to a new thread on that later.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 20:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Now we’re getting into fruitful territory. Great answers!</p>
<p>And I agree that Okult will be a good thing to look at.</p>
<p>It seems that you have a specific way of playing already in mind (or already at the table), and you’re just looking for ways to streamline or improve it. For that, perhaps an example of a “problem” (or something you want to improve) for an actual game might serve as illustration. Where do you wish things would flow differently?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/24</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 20:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve been designing a deck of cards close to the universal RPG Tools, but have been switching the approach from one way to another. The previous version looks like all Chronicle cards decks smashed into one, with each card holding several words, icons or images, one for each random table distributed through the deck. The list of things it provides is similar to the whole chronicle decks combined and perhaps a bit more. On the last version though I’m trying to simplify things a bit more and take a Tarot-like approach, minus having to memorize a list of intrepretations for each image. I’m drawing images that directly depict archetypes of characters and events, while also working on more organic ways to show additional information on those cards, so things don’t get chaotic. Drawing everything is what it makes the progress so slow, since I have little time to put on that project now.</p>
<p>Anyway, the idea behind such tools is to use it to spark ideas and add elements instead of having it come up with everything. Having a person look at the information and interpretate it is what makes the result a living, breathing thing instead of a bunch of random stuff that may or may not make sense together, or might get hard to fit into the fiction. So the less precise the random table, the better.</p>
<p>I’m giving a thought on the Okult take on questions, as well as how the mystery is discovered in The Murder of Mr. Crow, somethig about mixing those two seems to be the right thing to do.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 01:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I can’t take credit for Capes, it’s by Tony Lower-Basch. I only meant that I was inspired by the concept of having conflicts carry over until their resolution, which was different from the declare-roll-resolve sequence I was used to. (Dogs in the Vineyard also stretched out resolution but I discovered it after.)</p>
<p>To me, the mystery plot can be done with universal RPG Tools, but it doesn’t really shine treated this way. Sure, you can have a Revelation or Connect-the-dots move, but that’s not the same thing. I read about Okult and think Whilhelm has got the thing you want : it’s all about asking the good questions.</p>
<p>I believe asymetric information in a conversation is a huge thing that needs specific tools and rules. Tools that are cumbersome in a collaborative environment, and (social) table rules going at cross-purpose.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/22</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 10:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi DeReel! heh, I saw what you did there, the Resourceful Deck is still under revision, I think it’s fifth version now <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"> I gotta finish that thing sometime, as it currently works as a nice complement for this game.</p>
<p>Hmm, you’re partially right. I do want to keep my role as facilitator/ordinay GM but share it with players whenever their imagination sparks better ideas than mine. However, yes, I do need to write down a limited form of the procedures I use for players to add their input.</p>
<p>I adressed number 1 by ditching the agenda of principles (I agree, It’s too vage) and focusing on techniques, ritual phrases and procedures, a sort of GM moves triggered when either the GM has no idea what lies ahead or when players directly mention interesting ideas or make a question that infers they have an objective expectation of what lies ahead. (I probably should formalize this move, as I believe now that I have internalized it so much I actually didn’t include it in the written manual). About 2 and 3, see my answer above to Paul-T.</p>
<p>Congrats on Capes, great design there! I’d totally steal the Goals mechanic but besides being illegal <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"> it breaks on my design which is honed for princess play (I still hate Eero for coining that term and long for the old days when it was called Power Fantasy <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=9" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"> ), low impact Tactical Simulation and some loose fictional resources management.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/21</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 02:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks! actually writing things down helps me get things clearer.</p>
<p>And yes, it’s working fine so far, except when the player agenda includes a mystery. While I can do that on prep, I mean, create the material and make a trail of crumbs to get the players to discover something while the criminal runs circles around the PCs always one step ahead… or come up with a misterious event that leads the PCs into finding out something amazing… both ways require a creative effort that I can rarely have enough time to make, or stress me up since it requires an amount of illusionism I’m no longer comfortable with (I used to be good at theme park railroading but got burned up and later felt terrible for taking away player’s agency)</p>
<p>So that got me thinking about how good players are at coming up with amazing and interesting twists and conclusions then they are presented with partial data, and how easy is to take those ideas and narrate them up to eleven back to the players. The result has always been amazing both for me and the players, as I get surprised by the story as much as them and their expectations are not only meet but exceeded. Now I’m searching for a way to turn that into a proper mechanic.</p>
<p>I believe the mechanic has to include a way to create a kick, a starting event. Then it has to help players create interesting partial data (clues) that their PCs can explore into branching scenes. There must be a limit for such scenes (I’d go for 5, as the 5 room dungeon. This number is actually great to have in mind to keep one-shots or single sessions from overextending or getting boring). Finally it has to consider that some of the partial information presented to/generated by the players can be red herrings or coincidences, so the full data doesn’t need to be used to create the final solution to the mystery.</p>
<p>Most if not all of these things have been done before either by crude random tables or more refined procedures. I’ve been reading some interesting options I could add in this thread so far, that make me feel it’s possible. Now I need to codify all this into a somewhat simple move the GM can use to guide the players to create a mystery, come up with a solution and narrate it back to the players turned up to eleven.</p>
<p>So far I tried the random tables at the start to create things, but it’s still a slow procedure for me and an interruption in the game flow, as the GM has to stop talking with the players, roll dice, consult some tables, take notes and laugh maniacally to finally get back at them, 10 or so mins later with something half-cooked that can blow up the moment the players decide to take a different path.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/20</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 01:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello, WarriorMonk. I like that kind of design, Resourceful and all.<br>
I guess you want to write down the procedures so that other players could take the Facilitator role you play. After all, they already are competent worldbuilders.<br>
I’d say your problem is<br>
1° facilitation requires attention to multiple factors so that a linear procedure misses the point and an agenda of principles runs the risk of being too vague. Decision making requires sophisticated technology and you’re not ready to take the GM-ful leap, given that …<br>
2° you want an aesthetic unity and a narrative closure (“to avoid a branching that could derail the story”) GM leadership can give.<br>
Also 3° For murder mystery a GM serves you asymetric information on a silver plate.</p>
<p>I follow a parallel path but have decided from the start that the <strong>cost</strong> of having only one GM is too high. Using Capes’ Goals mechanic, I let players come up with all kind of challenges in little time, only some of them being validated, then fought for, sometimes left on the side and reserved for later. Providing “ready made” challenges and outcomes, I expect my players will hone their narrative and dramatic skills. (and it works, except for those who like Princess Playing, Tea Party, Tactical simulation and Playing Shop, the game pulling strongly toward crisis and resolution and being too dirtyhippey to care for fictional resources management)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 21:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s a really good description! And very helpful.</p>
<p>However, it also sounds like it’s working well already. What’s missing or not working as well as you would like? How would your ideal version of the game or play style be different? Where is it less than satisfying?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/18</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 16:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>All right, I’ll try to narrow things down. It’s clear to me where I’m right now with the design as it is.</p>
<p>Right now the game works like a platform to help players create a setting and create characters bound to that setting. I run it as an ordinary GMed game but I have several procedures and a few techniques/ ritual phrases that allow me as a GM to get the players come up with stuff on the go, with no creative pressure. My impro skills are already honed to say yes to their input or ask them for a roll and then proceed to build upon it. I’m listening to them as we play, I identify the player’s agenda as we come up with stuff and get to add a bit of my own.</p>
<p>I can keep things going pretty fast so players keep focused and it turns things into a hectic fun brainstorm; yet I have identified the amount of material needed to start and keep things going, so I ask the players just the bare minimum instead of stopping everyone in their tracks when they throw too much stuff at me (this happens sometimes anyway, but then players know they are going too far and are ok if I say no. We barter a bit, I may still add extra input if I find a good place for it.</p>
<p>I’m not focusing on a genre or anything too narrow in the theme, since the player’s agenda may vary a lot with the worldbuilding procedures I’m using. I do add custom mechanics when we play a long campaing and players decide to focus on something, like a cyberpunk setting or replicating Horizon Zero Dawn main mechanics in a similar setting. But I won’t use those custom mechanics for this particular version of the game (and I think I can replace most with a few generic mechanics that can have different esthetics according to the game)</p>
<p>For example I’m using some old school durability mechanic (blackhack or whitehack, can’t remember right now from where I stole this one) where items start with a durability of 4 and each time it gets damagedm, it’s charges get used or ammo is depleted, player rolls 1d6. Over 4, she still has enough charges or item is undamaged. If the player rolls under, the durability goeas down by one and GM describes the damage or the PC has to waste their turn recharging, etc. If it hits 0, the object is destroyed or no longer can be used until the PC finds charges/ammo. The same mechanic can be applied to bonds, so now it covers a wide array or genres, and can be skipped for some items if the game’s agenda is more about power fantasy/princess play.</p>
<p>You can say that right now the game has a GM because it makes players feel less pressured on creating content, or creating quality content. The GM takes their input and builds upon it, connects the dots and gives it back at them so they can do the same. Things scalate and again the GM is here to keep some degree of control, to avoid a branching that could derrail the story. The GM does have ordinary functions in the design, but should be able to skip some of them here and there, be lazy and come unprepared to the game. On another level, the GM presence gives the players enough confidence to start giving their input, as it is comforting enough to stop fearing blank page syndrome.</p>
<p>About <span class="hashtag">#2</span> &amp; 3 yes, that’s been the way I’ve been working until now. I’ve been reading, playing, hacking and stealing from many indie RPGs for years, and I’m still hungry for more, I just wanted some new recommendations. I was hoping someone else had invented somewhere a procedure or some mechanic to help a group come up with a feasible mystery/whodunnit without having anyone prep stuff before the game. I’ve seen some good ideas on the links posted here.</p>
<p>It’s a bit late, so let me know if there’s anything else that I can clarify to get better feedback, I’ll try to answer it on the next days. Thanks a lot for your and everyone’s time, help and interest!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 03:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I hear what you’re saying, <a class="mention" href="/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> (and I’m also a familiar person from SG!).</p>
<p>I think we’ve all spent time thinking about such things, but the issue here is, as <a class="mention" href="/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> says, a lack of clarity in terms of your goals. You need more constraints in place and a more clear idea of what you want before you can create an implementation. It sounds like you’re grasping for something, but you’re not exactly sure what it is.</p>
<p>Here are three things you can try:</p>
<ol>
<li>Give a long, hard thought to what shape you want the game to take. What are the roles of the players? What is their relationship to their characters? What tools is the GM (you?) happy to use, and which do you wish they didn’t need to use at all? Etc.</li>
</ol>
<p>I’m not entirely sure, from your writeup so far, why the game even has a GM, for example.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<p>Or, from the opposite end: just try a variety of things. Don’t worry about the end goal, but grab for one vision, technique, or tool at a time and throw it into the mix. Some will stick and some will not. (This may demand an understanding and easygoing group.) Play a variety of games, too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Start typing up or otherwise recording moments in play that are <em>just right</em>, feel good, or bring you joy. Write an example, whether from your actual game or from your imagination, and then throw it at us to see if it might inspire an implementation. That’s much easier than a vague prompt to making your game “different” and “more distributed”, which is very hard to pin down.</p>
</li>
</ol>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 22:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sorta did something similar in a game and I’m planning . The players had a deck of moves they could draw whenever their characters weren’t on the scene. I was amazed how quickly the players got into the mindset of using these cards to GM stuff into other player’s scenes and the amount of awesome material we got to keep things going. In time this feeds my own inspiration so I can throw curve balls back at them. Whole interesting narrative twists begun from scenes the players made up using these tools. I still need to improve these cards to get a wider arrange of scenes and make limitations on each card use more clear.</p>
<p>The way we used it the card got discarded once the player had given their input on the scene and it was left for me as a GM to finish connecting the dots from that scene to the next. I’m still ok with this, as I’m not aiming for total GMfull game, just one with a very lazy GM.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622/15</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4622-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-need-help-getting-closer-to-a-distributed-gm-game-system/4622.rss">I Need help getting closer to a distributed GM game system</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
