<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sale and Pledge Drive for All My Games</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sale-and-pledge-drive-for-all-my-games/7513</link>
    <description>Hey folks!

[I&#39;ve got a sale going on all my role-playing games on itch](https://itch.io/s/57278/35-damn-years-sale), as well as a pledge drive to get some attention on my Patreon and Ko-fi.

* All my games and supplements are 35%-off
* You can get everything in one bundle for $35
* You can also get all my self-published work, as well as future prototypes and releases, for as little as $1 a month by [subscribing on Patreon](https://www.patreon.com/notwriting) or becoming a [member on Ko-fi](https://ko-fi.com/notwriting)

If you&#39;re wondering where to start, some of my more popular titles are:

* [World Maker](https://notwriting.itch.io/world-maker): a solo game/tool for GM&#39;s to build a fictional world by addressing the traits and histories of characters
* [Neon Black](https://notwriting.itch.io/neon-black): Cyberpunk forged in the dark game about communities helping each other and stealing from the rich
* [A Torch in the Dark](https://notwriting.itch.io/a-torch-in-the-dark): Solo dungeon crawling game, forged in the dark, about robbing the tombs of undead nobles.

I&#39;m a full-time freelance writer/designer so reliable income is pretty important, and I&#39;m giving a helluva deal in exchange. 

And if you&#39;re not in a spot where you can buy games or subscribe, but want to check my games out, they each have plenty of community copies thanks to the support I&#39;ve already received.

If you have any questions, please let me know!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 21:03:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sale-and-pledge-drive-for-all-my-games/7513.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Sale and Pledge Drive for All My Games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sohkrates]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sohkrates">@Sohkrates</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hey folks!</p>
<p><a href="https://itch.io/s/57278/35-damn-years-sale" rel="nofollow noopener">I’ve got a sale going on all my role-playing games on itch</a>, as well as a pledge drive to get some attention on my Patreon and Ko-fi.</p>
<ul>
<li>All my games and supplements are 35%-off</li>
<li>You can get everything in one bundle for $35</li>
<li>You can also get all my self-published work, as well as future prototypes and releases, for as little as $1 a month by <a href="https://www.patreon.com/notwriting" rel="nofollow noopener">subscribing on Patreon</a> or becoming a <a href="https://ko-fi.com/notwriting" rel="nofollow noopener">member on Ko-fi</a>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you’re wondering where to start, some of my more popular titles are:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="https://notwriting.itch.io/world-maker" rel="nofollow noopener">World Maker</a>: a solo game/tool for GM’s to build a fictional world by addressing the traits and histories of characters</li>
<li>
<a href="https://notwriting.itch.io/neon-black" rel="nofollow noopener">Neon Black</a>: Cyberpunk forged in the dark game about communities helping each other and stealing from the rich</li>
<li>
<a href="https://notwriting.itch.io/a-torch-in-the-dark" rel="nofollow noopener">A Torch in the Dark</a>: Solo dungeon crawling game, forged in the dark, about robbing the tombs of undead nobles.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m a full-time freelance writer/designer so reliable income is pretty important, and I’m giving a helluva deal in exchange.</p>
<p>And if you’re not in a spot where you can buy games or subscribe, but want to check my games out, they each have plenty of community copies thanks to the support I’ve already received.</p>
<p>If you have any questions, please let me know!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sale-and-pledge-drive-for-all-my-games/7513/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sale-and-pledge-drive-for-all-my-games/7513/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 19:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7513-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/sale-and-pledge-drive-for-all-my-games/7513.rss">Sale and Pledge Drive for All My Games</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
