<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691</link>
    <description>I always have a long-term campaign running, but on nights when we don&#39;t have a full complement I open up our weekly game night to all comers and run RPG one-shots (or pull out some board games when I need a break). I&#39;m looking for recommendations to expand my repertoire—specifically, RPGs with quick set up and tight rules. I&#39;m trying to build a set of 7-10 games of varied genres that I can always have on hand, ready to go at a moment&#39;s notice.

Our most-played one-shot is ***Fiasco***, which I have run many, many times. I love it, but I also enjoy mixing things up mechanically. I&#39;ve also run ***Psi-Run*** a fair amount.

Other one-shots we&#39;ve tried that hit the trifecta of a low-prep+tight rules+satisfaction within a 2-4 hour time frame:

* ***Soth***
* ***Lovecraftesque***
* ***The King Machine***
* ***Carolina Death Crawl***
* ***Bootleggers***
* ***Fall of Magic***
* ***Durance***
* ***Dread***

One-shots we&#39;ve tried that hit one or two of those marks, but not all three:

* ***Battle Between the Worlds***
* ***Spirit of &#39;77***
* ***In a Wicked Age***
* ***The Quiet Year***
* ***Cheat Your Own Adventure***
* ***Ghost Lines***
* ***Microscope***
* ***Into the Odd***
* ***Tales from the Loop***
* ***Night Witches***
* ***The Warren***
* ***Funnel World***
* ***Freebooters on the Frontier***

Please share what&#39;s in your portmanteau!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 15:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Although I have not played these, I have seen from a very good source on rpggeek, the following suggestions:</p>
<p><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpg/27926/juggernaut" rel="nofollow noopener">Juggernaut</a><br>
<a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpg/649/dirty-secrets" rel="nofollow noopener">Dirty Secrets</a><br>
<a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpg/26211/unheroes" rel="nofollow noopener">Unheroes</a></p>
<p>Here are some games that technically could be played for more than one session, but in my experience are perfect for one-shots and no more…</p>
<p><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpg/669/dust-devils" rel="nofollow noopener">Dust Devils</a><br>
<a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpg/2042/danger-patrol" rel="nofollow noopener">Danger Patrol</a>/<a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpg/19555/pocket-danger-patrol" rel="nofollow noopener">Pocket Danger Patrol</a><br>
<a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpg/11213/hollowpoint" rel="nofollow noopener">Hollowpoint</a></p>
<p>I also don’t think anyone mentioned Trophy or Trophy Gold.  Trophy Gold looks awesome!</p>
<p>In addition, for a one shot I forgotTiny D6 games (Tiny Frontiers, Tiny Dungeon, Tiny: Mecha and Monsters) are great if you want a simple one shot dungeon crawl  / pick up and deliver / kill the kaiju game.  The huge number of mini-settings with hooks and villians works great for a one-shot. It fails in the character development and feels areas though.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/37</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 15:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Two games I haven’t heard mentioned yet:</p>
<ul>
<li>Dogs in the Vineyard</li>
</ul>
<p>Better as a long term game, but still makes for great one shots! (I’m developing a “kit” for particularly easy play, which eventually I’ll have thrown together.)</p>
<ul>
<li>A Taste for Murder</li>
</ul>
<p>A nice, light-hearted GMless detective mystery, a la Agathie Christie. Very British.</p>
<ul>
<li>Muse</li>
</ul>
<p>A GMless storytelling game, easy to learn and play and always satisfying.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/36</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 05:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Marcio_Moreira]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/marcio_moreira">@Marcio_Moreira</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks, that’s very kind. Looking forward to playing a lot of those</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/35</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 20:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Charles_Moore]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/charles_moore">@Charles_Moore</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Here’s a slightly different take on the question…</p>
<p>I keep a dop kit full of pokerchips, dice, pens, pencils, playing cards, notecards, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/eBoot-Plastic-Display-Holder-Rotatable/dp/B01NADFJSB" rel="nofollow noopener">card holders</a>, and a microfiber cloth.  If I can find one I like (and will fit), I may add something a tarot deck to help with inspiration.</p>
<p>I also, keep a number of clipboards and binders around with notes, printed playbooks, NPC’s, and etc.  I keep one per game system (it wasn’t planned that way, it just worked out).</p>
<p>And an old Kindle Fire chock full of PDFs.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/34</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 18:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="31" data-topic="3691">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/marcio_moreira/40/538_2.png" class="avatar"> Marcio_Moreira:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I tried searching for Dragons and bananas but didn’t really find much. Do you have a link?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Ops, translated the name from the Swedish one, and forgot that the game is called something else in English. I updated the <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/24" data-bbcode="true">original post</a> with links to all games.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/33</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 18:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So some of my favorites are listed above already, but I’ll add one that’s missing and add some more detail about why they are in <strong>MY</strong> kit.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>For the Queen: I absolutely love this game. It’s a game where we learn about the individuals traveling party on a quest as the game progresses. The game IS the character creation as we learn about each other by answering very pointed questions (presented by the cards/game rules). Another reason I love it is that the entire instructions for the game are on 20ish cards you can pass around the table (the instructions tell you to do this) and start play. The act of passing around the cards is also a warm up to get use to reading a card and talking. The actual mechanics are real simple, and pretty loose. You can model good behavior (like asking questions for further detail) or pause to answer anything that is unclear. It definitely helps to have a facilitator who has played before to help model good behavior, but is also not necessary. It’s very re playable even though the same questions can come up, what has already been answered, who answers, and how they answer vary the game dramatically. The fact I can just pull out the deck of cards or spin up a new Roll20 instance makes it a less than 5 minute prep for both online or in person gaming.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Dialect is a game about a language and how it dies. Yes it’s a language building game, but it’s also a game where you learn about this dying community through the lens of several of it’s members. I think the game is well structured and does a good job of guiding you through play. It is a bit melancholic as it is known going in, the language (and community) will die out. That doesn’t mean all the characters will die, they might be assimilated into a larger population or something else. There can also be individually heroic stories/arcs, but the undertone will have notes of loss. The only prep is deciding what backdrop to use (which usually takes about 5 minutes) and setting up the actual table (about another 5 minutes).  So a 10 minute prep game (both for in person or online, again a Roll20 module) makes it one of my go to games for no-prep one shots.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Reunion is a Descended from the Queen game, I’ve been working on with Jenn Martin and Andy Munich. It’s about a group of people who used to be real close, but have been a way for a while and are coming back together. It’s not released yet, so it doesn’t really help anyone here at the moment. But it shares many of the benefits of For the Queen, plus I get to see my own game being played (which can help to improve it).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fall of Magic is a game where you travel with a group on a quest and learn about them through vignettes on the journey. The quest is that magic is dying and with it the last magus, you journey to Umbra, where magic was born. Maybe to restore it? Maybe to watch end? While it matters somewhat what the end is, it’s more about the Journey than the destination. The physical map and pieces are absolutely gorgeous (the online version is very pretty too, but lacks some of the heft and satisfying physicality of the physical version). I am way more likely to play this as a substitute game online than in person, not because the play is better, but because UNLESS I am playing at my house, I am just unlikely to have my copy of the game with me. Sometimes at cons or other places there will be a copy around to use, and then I’ll use it. But I’ve discovered, for myself, that while the physicality is beautiful and wonderful, it also makes it a lot harder to just toss it in my bag of gaming stuff and carry with me.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Dead Friend by <a class="mention" href="/u/oh_theogony">@oh_theogony</a> is a wonderful 2 player game where one person plays someone trying to summon the ghost of someone they care about, the other person plays said ghost. The structure of the rules guides you fairly well through the whole process. The rituals of play also help give the game a great atmosphere. I’ve only played once, but now keep a couple copies printed out in my game bag just in case.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>It may be obvious but all of the games on my list are facilitated rather than GMed. All but Fall of Magic (which to me is more of a three shot game to get to the end), are explicitly designed for one session of play. They don’t have character creation, or rather the mechanics have you learn about the characters over the course of the game, rather than per-defining a bunch of stuff before hand.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/32</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 16:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Marcio_Moreira]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/marcio_moreira">@Marcio_Moreira</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hey, great recommendations!<br>
I tried searching for Dragons and bananas but didn’t really find much. Do you have a link?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/31</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 14:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Marcio_Moreira]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/marcio_moreira">@Marcio_Moreira</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Grant Howitt’s one page RPGs are delightful.<br>
Honey Heist is great, but I also played a session of <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/goat-crashers-23997994" rel="nofollow noopener">Goat Crashers</a> using the Tearable RPG system and I think it was the most fun I’ve ever had with a game</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 14:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_Kershaw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_kershaw">@Joshua_Kershaw</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Lasers and Feelings and Psi-Run are great.<br>
Havoc Brigade is a blast for in person games. You play Orcs (and a bunch of goblins in a trench coat) trying to infiltrate a castle…farcical hilarity ensues.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/29</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 20:27:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasonlutes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasonlutes">@jasonlutes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Re: <em>The King Machine</em>, there’s an “opening crawl” you can read to get players quickly up to speed with the setting; the rules are relatively short; character creation is quick; and a number of tables are provided to generate aspects of the world. Whoever runs the game will need to read the rules ahead of time to fully grok them, though⁠—you can’t just take out the book and go.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/28</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 17:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Tuirgin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/tuirgin">@Tuirgin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-post="1" data-topic="3691">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jasonlutes/40/728_2.png" class="avatar"> jasonlutes:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Other one-shots we’ve tried that hit the trifecta of a low-prep+tight rules+satisfaction within a 2-4 hour time frame:</p>
<p><code>&lt;snip&gt;</code></p>
<ul>
<li><em><strong>The King Machine</strong></em></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’m curious if you have any particular thoughts/comments about your experience running this as a one-shot.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/27</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 16:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I ran a short-lived <em>Monster of the Week</em> campaign awhile ago, so I have around four scenarios for that game I’ve already written up and can play without prep:</p>
<ul>
<li>Opportunistic grave robbing at a quarry awakens a terrible curse (and ghouls)</li>
<li>Wizard plus followers starts making waves in a generally-creepy small town</li>
<li>Vampiric turf war taking place primarily through rival waste disposal companies</li>
<li>Secretive government site runs afoul of local Wendigo spirit and werewolf servants</li>
</ul>
<p>For the other three (Troika, DCC, Knave) I have a large collection of old D&amp;D/AD&amp;D modules as well as zines and modern modules, including many of the DCC modules. (I also have some old maps and notes for scenarios I’ve created but since I have an over-supply of zines and modules I’m usually excited to try out one of those.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/26</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 15:48:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasonlutes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasonlutes">@jasonlutes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/rickard">@Rickard</a>, thank you for taking the time to write a summary of each game, helps me a lot.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/25</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 15:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I play mostly at conventions.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.memento-mori.com/rpg/inspectres" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">InSpectres</a>: Takes me around 45 minutes to play, including pitch and character generation, where I introduce rules as we go. We usually play this twice, where I can introduce even more rules.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.erebaltor.se/rickard/tip/" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">This is Pulp</a>: Takes about 70 minutes to play, including pitch, character generation and world generation.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.story-games.com/forums/discussion/20439/dungeons-bananas-its-finally-here" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">Dungeons and Bananas</a>: Takes about an 60-90 minutes to play, including pitch, character generation and world generation.</p>
<p>All these are based around banana challenges, where the game master creates challenges where the players describe their way out of the situation. “How do you overcome the locked door, using a banana”.</p>
<p><a href="https://kagematsu.wordpress.com/kagematsu-rules/" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">Kagematsu</a>: Convince the lone ronin to defend your village. Takes about 3-4 hours to play.</p>
<p><a href="https://semielgames.wordpress.com/2012/07/25/the-coyotes-of-chicago-playtest-document/" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">The Coyotes of Chicago</a>: Playtest document, where we have three game masters and one player, and each game master have their own agenda and elements to introduce. Takes about 3-4 hours to play.</p>
<p>I rarely play Kagematsu because I refuse to play it unless a female is playing the samurai according to the rules. I mostly play Coyotes, if the participants wants to play something longer, and I want to show them something unusual.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.urverkspel.com/vara-spel/oevriga-projekt" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">The Murder of Mr. Crow</a>: Takes about an hour to play. A storytelling game that takes place in a Sherlock Holmes inspired environment where the detective is just about to tell everyone involved who’s the murderer.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.urverkspel.com/vara-spel/oevriga-projekt" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">Imagine</a> A non-conflict storytelling game that takes about an hour to play, including pitch and rules explanation. A game that makes people emerged in the story, and you’re only allowed to speak one sentence and then have to wait until someone else have spoken. Based around the East-asian narrative structure kishotenketsu.</p>
<p>Why play longer games when you can play several ones (or the same one) during the same time? <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/24</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 15:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasonlutes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasonlutes">@jasonlutes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="20" data-topic="3691" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jmstar/40/566_2.png" class="avatar"> Jmstar:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I always have a deck of <em><strong>Archipelago</strong></em> cards on hand and am thus prepared for a good time with zero notice.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>My own deck has yet to be deployed, I think the time has come.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/23</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasonlutes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasonlutes">@jasonlutes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="17" data-topic="3691">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/christopher_gmelch/40/448_2.png" class="avatar"> Christopher_Gmelch:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>The one-shot I played most is <strong>SPI*RUN</strong></p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>A typo that makes me want to get hacking. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<p>But is it about international espionage during the Cold War, or the management of Simulations Publications, Inc. from 1969 to 1983?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/22</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seanFsmith]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seanfsmith">@seanFsmith</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What are the prepared scenarios? Are they the same for the most part or do you have a specific for each system?</p>
<p>Most of my off-the-cuff scenarios these days are boiled down to a clear <strong>hook</strong> and a <strong>horrid truth</strong> (but then again, much of my material is horrid investigative fare)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/21</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I always have a deck of <em><strong>Archipelago</strong></em> cards on hand and am thus prepared for a good time with zero notice.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/20</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 14:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AbacusMensch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/abacusmensch">@AbacusMensch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I echo the recommendation for Lady Blackbird. Not only is it ideal for a one shot, it is the best game bar none for introducing players new to the hobby to roleplaying.</p>
<p>Keys mean players are mechanically rewarded for roleplaying in ways specific to each character.</p>
<p>I’ve run Lady Blackbird at Games on Demand at Gen Con and for my parents so they understand my hobby. Each character sheet has the rules at the bottom. Everything is self-contained.</p>
<p>It’s a marvel of doing a lot with a little.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/19</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 13:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@empowermint]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/empowermint">@empowermint</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is a great thread! I help run a night which is exclusively one-offs, so lists like this are super useful to me.</p>
<p>In addition to the games others have already mentioned here, many of which I love, here some satisfying low-prep one-shots from my arsenal:</p>
<ul>
<li>Archipelago by Matthis Holter</li>
<li>A Penny for My Thoughts by Paul Tevis</li>
<li>Best Friends by Gregor Hutton</li>
<li>InSpectres by Jared Sorensen</li>
<li>Kingdom by Ben Robbins</li>
<li>Svart av Kval Vit av Lust by Simon Pettersson</li>
<li>Trollbabe by Ron Edwards</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/18</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 13:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christopher_Gmelch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christopher_gmelch">@Christopher_Gmelch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The one-shot I played most is <strong>SPI*RUN</strong>. I really love it’s pick up and play character. Besides reading the rules there isn’t much to do.<br>
Others I played and enjoyed are:<br>
<strong>Lady Blackbird</strong><br>
<strong>Final Girl</strong><br>
<strong>Game of Love</strong><br>
<strong>10 Candles</strong><br>
<strong>Cheat your own adventure</strong><br>
<strong>For the Queen</strong></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/17</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 11:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Manifest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/manifest">@Manifest</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My one shot picks depend on whether it’s a pick up random game or if it’s something prepared where I have time to print my pregens.</p>
<p>Pick up games:<br>
<strong>Zombie World</strong> -having a lot of fun with this despite a slight hip cup with the resolution mechanic.<br>
<strong>Cartel</strong> -just simply love this game but I’m biased since I can pull a lot of background knowledge.<br>
<strong>One Shot World</strong> - my favorite Dungeon World hack. I can’t sing enough praises about this pretty cool game.</p>
<p>If it’s something prepared ahead of time so I can print my pregens and adventure:<br>
<strong>Dresden Files Accelerated</strong>- love the book series so I’m very biased.<br>
<strong>The Secrets of Cats</strong> - everyone plays as cats in our society who protect humans (known as burdens) from the supernatural. Always a lot of fun.<br>
<strong>Monster of the Week</strong> - great game despite some mechanics that I’ve grown tired off.<br>
<strong>Legend of the Elements</strong> - same as MotW.<br>
<strong>Firefly RPG</strong> - always a lot of fun with the right group. Lot of fun to play iconic characters.<br>
<strong>Marvel Heroic Roleplaying</strong> - probably the best superhero rpg I’ve played so far. Lot of fun to play iconic characters.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Logan_Howard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/logan_howard">@Logan_Howard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Very cool! I’m trying to build a couple short starters that kick off with nothing and have the players building their zero-level characters on the fly. I’m borrowing from some well-known DW, Funnel World, and WoD mechanics. I thought I might need to have the players prep a few things but your comment gave me the idea of having a stack of playbooks in the center of the table that they’ll pick from after the game is introduced. I want the whole experience to feel like playing the game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/15</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 20:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasonlutes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasonlutes">@jasonlutes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hey <a class="mention" href="/u/logan_howard">@Logan_Howard</a> – happy to hear you’ve enjoyed <em>Funnel World</em>! I have run it many times as a one-shot, and it works just fine, everyone always has a good time, but for a fall-out-of-bed one-shot I<br>
would want it to be even lower prep than it already is. Like, for instance, if each player just drew card with their occupation and starting gear on it, another card with their personality, maybe another card that prompts them to provide a setting detail; then maybe everyone participates in a three-card draw that defines the funnel itself. That’s the level of quick-prep I’m talking about.</p>
<p>(Hmm…)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/14</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 19:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Logan_Howard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/logan_howard">@Logan_Howard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m curious about Funnel World. You have it listed as one of the ones that didn’t hit all three marks. Why? I’m working on a zine that will pay homage to your game and run with some principles from it. I’d like to hear your thoughts on where you feel it doesn’t work in that situation because you may have some insights that would effect my design.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/13</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 18:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3691-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691.rss">What&#39;s in your one-shot kit?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
