<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monster Care Squad (New Players: January)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monster-care-squad-new-players-january/7562</link>
    <description># **New Players Welcome**

# **For the first 48 hours please only sign up if you haven’t yet played a regular Calendar game with me**

**So if you&#39;ve only played GCOG sessions with me, feel free to sign up.**
This is for four January US morning sessions of *Monster Care Squad*, “A Ghibli-inspired tabletop adventure of healing Monsters and solving local problems in the gentle world of Ald-Amura.” These PbtA-inspired rules will be taught. Attendance at all sessions is encouraged, but not mandatory. In session one we will set tone and safety, make characters and get to helping monsters.

One seat is being reserved.

*The pitch: Monster Care Squad is a tabletop roleplaying game set in the tranquil world of Ald-Amura. The peaceful state of the world is threatened when a mysterious poison known as The False Gold finds its way into the veins of the world&#39;s Monsters, causing terrible, maddening Wounds, which drive these incredible beings into uncontrollable rages. The once unbreakable bond of harmony and respect between Humans and Monsters is on the brink of collapse, and it&#39;s up to you and your allies to set things right.*

*You play as Monster Care Specialists, elite vets equipped with the knowledge to heal any wound, given enough time and preparation. In the game, you travel this amazing Miyazaki-esque world, going from town to town in hopes of finding Monsters infected with The False Gold, diagnosing their illnesses, crafting cures, and healing their minds and bodies of the strange, magical Wounds which drive them to destruction. To do this, you&#39;ll solve local problems, investigate the land and its mysteries, and apply the skills, abilities, and knowledge you&#39;ll build up throughout play.*

We will use Zoom for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the links and to confirm attendance. CHECK YOUR SPAM FILTER. Sessions will run up to three hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The Gauntlet Code of Conduct will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils and the X-Card for safety tools.

If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.

S1 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6B_2POGhnwjJvkE5
S2 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6iyQZSR5Uh9n9lBO
S3 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6ylEXy3o5C_wx8dg
S4 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb7CWtYEfiFtjQLlSZ
![monster care 1|500x500](upload://6KsQ34M5PM8vLiFqZaeiPoUQAAi.jpeg)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 18:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monster-care-squad-new-players-january/7562.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Monster Care Squad (New Players: January)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h1><strong>New Players Welcome</strong></h1>
<h1><strong>For the first 48 hours please only sign up if you haven’t yet played a regular Calendar game with me</strong></h1>
<p><strong>So if you’ve only played GCOG sessions with me, feel free to sign up.</strong><br>
This is for four January US morning sessions of <em>Monster Care Squad</em>, “A Ghibli-inspired tabletop adventure of healing Monsters and solving local problems in the gentle world of Ald-Amura.” These PbtA-inspired rules will be taught. Attendance at all sessions is encouraged, but not mandatory. In session one we will set tone and safety, make characters and get to helping monsters.</p>
<p>One seat is being reserved.</p>
<p><em>The pitch: Monster Care Squad is a tabletop roleplaying game set in the tranquil world of Ald-Amura. The peaceful state of the world is threatened when a mysterious poison known as The False Gold finds its way into the veins of the world’s Monsters, causing terrible, maddening Wounds, which drive these incredible beings into uncontrollable rages. The once unbreakable bond of harmony and respect between Humans and Monsters is on the brink of collapse, and it’s up to you and your allies to set things right.</em></p>
<p><em>You play as Monster Care Specialists, elite vets equipped with the knowledge to heal any wound, given enough time and preparation. In the game, you travel this amazing Miyazaki-esque world, going from town to town in hopes of finding Monsters infected with The False Gold, diagnosing their illnesses, crafting cures, and healing their minds and bodies of the strange, magical Wounds which drive them to destruction. To do this, you’ll solve local problems, investigate the land and its mysteries, and apply the skills, abilities, and knowledge you’ll build up throughout play.</em></p>
<p>We will use Zoom for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the links and to confirm attendance. CHECK YOUR SPAM FILTER. Sessions will run up to three hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The Gauntlet Code of Conduct will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils and the X-Card for safety tools.</p>
<p>If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.</p>
<p>S1 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6B_2POGhnwjJvkE5">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6B_2POGhnwjJvkE5</a><br>
S2 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6iyQZSR5Uh9n9lBO">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6iyQZSR5Uh9n9lBO</a><br>
S3 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6ylEXy3o5C_wx8dg">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb6ylEXy3o5C_wx8dg</a><br>
S4 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb7CWtYEfiFtjQLlSZ">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Mnb7CWtYEfiFtjQLlSZ</a><br>
<div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2f4daa77adfe90261a8741e338ad539835a0e1fa.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/6KsQ34M5PM8vLiFqZaeiPoUQAAi.jpeg?dl=1" title="monster care 1"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/2/2f4daa77adfe90261a8741e338ad539835a0e1fa_2_500x500.jpeg" alt="monster care 1" data-base62-sha1="6KsQ34M5PM8vLiFqZaeiPoUQAAi" width="500" height="500" srcset="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/2/2f4daa77adfe90261a8741e338ad539835a0e1fa_2_500x500.jpeg, //gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/2/2f4daa77adfe90261a8741e338ad539835a0e1fa_2_750x750.jpeg 1.5x, //gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/2/2f4daa77adfe90261a8741e338ad539835a0e1fa_2_1000x1000.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/2/2f4daa77adfe90261a8741e338ad539835a0e1fa_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">monster care 1</span><span class="informations">1205×1205 1.64 MB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monster-care-squad-new-players-january/7562/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monster-care-squad-new-players-january/7562/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 18:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7562-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monster-care-squad-new-players-january/7562.rss">Monster Care Squad (New Players: January)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
