<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323</link>
    <description>There&#39;s a category of move I encounter in Powered by the Apocalypse games. I think of them as &quot;dramatic entrance&quot; moves. Here&#39;s one example from Masks:

**There when it matters:** When you defend someone, on a hit you can hold 1 instead of choosing one from the list. Spend your hold when they are in danger later to arrive on the scene ready to help.

I&#39;m interested in how these moves play at other people&#39;s tables. In my experience, these moves have been underwhelming. It always seems that, if it&#39;s cool for a character to be in a scene, the GM will say yes to it, no move required. This makes it feel like a waste of a move.

How have other people used these moves? Any interesting or exciting experiences? Has anyone hacked the moves to make them more impactful?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 19:45:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That would be my immediate reaction as well, but why, really? If the player uses the move to escape imprisonment, they’re telling you that they don’t like that their character is imprisoned and would prefer a more active role in the game.</p>
<p>So I think I’d let them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/27</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 19:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If I were running a HoW game I would probably lean against letting the move help someone get out of imprisonment or capture - unless in so doing they were going to have real impact on the other scene.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/26</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 22:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve seen the Move “Have Sword, Will Travel” pop up in two Hearts of Wulin games - and both times, they worked pretty well, getting the character in question somewhere they shouldn’t have been, really. But then, HoW character tend not to hang around each other constantly.</p>
<p>Also, we had the situation that a character with this move was imprisoned by our enemies, and it was pretty clear that this Move might be used to escape without much explanation.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/25</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 22:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I struggled with this with <em>Night Witches</em>. I wanted players to be able to aid one another during missions, but I didn’t want to categorize how that would happen. My solution was the Vedomaya move, which allows every plane to watch over another plane, which they historically did. When you are Vedomaya, you can take on a consequence of failure or partial success for your wing-mate. In play this leaves all the causality and fictional positioning to the players. How exactly do you take the Harm pointed at them? How exactly do you get your plane damaged instead of theirs? Why are you Marked instead of them? It foregrounds self-sacrifice and camaraderie, it adds a satisfying tactical nuance (who you Vedomaya for matters), and it encourages player creativity at night, which can become a series of tense die rolls without any roleplaying if you aren’t careful.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/24</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Pseudo310]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/pseudo310">@Pseudo310</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oh yeah, for me the moves have never really been invalidated because, for the Apocalypse World ones anyway, I see them as honest-to-goodness powers. In one game the Hocus was being held at gunpoint by a hardholder in the middle of a scrap between their followers, and the Faceless was just behind him all of a sudden. It’s not, “It’s appropriate for you to be there.” It’s, “There is no way on heaven and earth that you could possibly be here right now and yet there you are barreling into the middle of it with a big axe and a bad attitude.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 23:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rabalias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If someone has a move like that in my game then I’ll pay closer attention to the issue than I would otherwise. I’ll make sure other people aren’t getting the benefit for free.</p>
<p>Also, in any game I’ll pay attention to gross differences in location. You’re on the island and they’re on the mainland, so no you can’t join the scene. Unless you have bonefeel.</p>
<p>It’s one of those things that’s frequently not needed at all - but when it is, it makes a big difference.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/22</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 22:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeremy_Strandberg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think part of Why the “entrance” moves work for both the Savvyhead and the Faceless is the built-in weirdness of the moves and the playbooks they belong to.</p>
<p>Like, <em>of course</em> the Savvyhead just shows up… that guy is always underfoot. And <em>of course</em> the Faceless shows up when things get bloody. That’s where she does.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/21</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 20:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Pseudo310]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/pseudo310">@Pseudo310</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>When I put together the Faceless playbook for AW I made the Scent of Blood move to give it the Jason Voorhees teleportation flavor, and rolled it into the sex move to give it the creepy protectiveness I imagined the character having. It’s still one of my favorite moves.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/20</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 19:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jon">@Jon</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="1" data-topic="323">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v3/letter/a/d26b3c/40.png" class="avatar"> Alexi_Sarge:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It always seems that, if it’s cool for a character to be in a scene, the GM will say yes to it, no move required. This makes it feel like a waste of a move.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>As someone playing The Bull in a Masks campaign who <em>took</em> that move, I feel ya.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/19</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Mathias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mathias">@Mathias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I actually like the original <em><strong>Bonefeel</strong></em>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Bonefeel: at the beginning of the session, roll+weird. On a 10+, hold 1+1. On a 7–9,<br>
hold 1. At any time, either you or the MC can spend your hold to have you already be<br>
there, with the proper tools and knowledge, with or without any clear explanation why.<br>
If your hold was 1+1, take +1forward now. On a miss, the MC holds 1, and can spend it to<br>
have you be there already, but somehow pinned, caught or trapped.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Because it also allows the MC to make use of the hold, it creates another level of tension of play between the two. I’ve also used it to great effect, taking this move as an Angel is amazing, for example.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/18</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Kevin_Petker]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/kevin_petker">@Kevin_Petker</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>And, technically, another Protagonist Character could use a move to counter that or put a penalty on the roll.</p>
<p>Or the players could discuss it at the table before resolution.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/17</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 23:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Kevin_Petker]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/kevin_petker">@Kevin_Petker</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The <strong>Ninja Princess</strong> in <em><strong>Princess World</strong></em> has this:</p>
<p><em><strong>Surprise!</strong></em><br>
When you want to suddenly appear where someone else is, you may <em>Roll with Threads</em>:</p>
<p><strong>On a hit:</strong> You’re there!<br>
<strong>On a 10+:</strong> You may choose to reveal yourself immediately or remain hidden.<br>
<strong>On a 7-9:</strong> Others know you’re there.</p>
<p><strong>On a miss:</strong> You wind up some place you don’t want to be.</p>
<p>“Roll with Threads” is kind of like Roll+Hx in Apocalypse World; the more strongly connected you are to the character in the scene, the easier it is for you to get to them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 23:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Stentor_Danielson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/stentor_danielson">@Stentor_Danielson</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What if the move was written like:</p>
<p>When you defend someone, on a hit you can <strong>have them</strong> hold 1 instead of choosing one from the list. <strong>They can</strong> spend <strong>their</strong> hold when they are in danger later to <strong>have you</strong> arrive on the scene ready to help.</p>
<p>That puts the control in the hands of the help-ee to call on the help-er, which removes the danger of barging in unannounced. “Call on someone for help” becomes an option that the help-ee has in their arsenal of ways to respond to situations. And the help-er then has this debt hanging over their head, this idea that they may get pulled away from their other tasks by their obligation to help a particular friend.</p>
<p>Now, that raises issues of the help-er’s consent to be pulled into helping. But depending on the game it could be coupled with a resistance move (a la Urban Shadows and debts), so that there’s a potential cost to not answering the call.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/15</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 15:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve seen this used to cool effect in several PbtA games, especially as a means of reconnecting a split group, as suggested. In my experience, you get two kinds of players who take it. Ones who completely forget about it and others who shape their actions around it. David L in our Reign of Crows Fate game used it to set up his big final scene.</p>
<p>But although its also infrequent, it’s also a potential friction point at the table. I try to make sure we check in with the player whose scene the new player’s popping into. Do they want the assist? Have they gotten what they want out of the moment? I’ve seen a couple of times here moves like this have sucked the air out of a scene or stolen a player’s forward momentum. I’ve seen this happen in WWW more than elsewhere, usually because someone gets excited about the energy of the moment and comes in without checking in a little.</p>
<p>And I mean that surprise and twist is part of the fun, but not when it takes away from someone else’s high point. And there’s a social pressure at the table to accept these kinds of shifts (I hesitate to say intrusions), which can make a player who wants to finish their moment say yes and then be unhappy later. It just means as GMs I think we have to be particular aware of the dynamics of those moments.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/14</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 14:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dissonance]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dissonance">@Dissonance</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m a huge fan of moves that give players permission to appear somewhere unexpectedly: in hiding, in disguise, or just with a healthy dose of serendipity. It establishes a lot about the character.</p>
<p>In PbtA one could argue that a conversation with the GM might result in the same permision, but I’d argue that players having explicit permission from the rules means that they’ll hit upon that note more often and I feel their extra agency in the situation makes the use of such abilities feel more impactful and satisfying.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 14:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@inarvan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/inarvan">@inarvan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I love this idea. WWW has the Run-In move, which lets you butt into almost any situation for dramatic purposes, which highlights the constant shifting stories in pro wrestling. It helps bring characters together for storyline purposes and it really sings when it’s used well.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/12</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 13:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This this this this. This.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 05:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yup, that Bull Move is a permission slip to the MC to a) regularly nail the Bull with the ‘Separate Them’ consequence, because this Move allows them to bust out of wherever they might be, which is fictionally pretty cool. I would almost certainly require them to say what they have to break through or down to arrive on the scene…</p>
<p>and b) regularly force the Bull to choose between hanging around with the group and running off to defend a loved one or friend who’s in danger, but not in the scene. It’s the player telling you to force them to make that choice regularly.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/10</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 05:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One of the powerful elements there is also the heavy amount of restriction placed on the scene. It’s not really a narrative mobility move, it’s more of a “snowglobe” move that lets you set a very specific type of scene. So it has some overlap, but I think it’s also actually pretty restricted; you can’t use it to just show up in a scene, for instance.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 17:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gerrit]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gerrit">@Gerrit</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That is an interesting observation. I would say it strongly depends on the game and on the fictional specifics of the Move. It seems from the discussion that the Masks Move is working less well for example than the Urban Shadows version since the idea of the party is so different.</p>
<p>I have to think about one of my favourite Moves from Monsterhearts (The Wyrm):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Plot to catch someone alone and spend 4 Strings on them: you’ll frame the next scene either of you appear in. Describe the place, but leave it unsaid how you came to be there. Until you make a Move, no one else can show up and the someone can’t leave.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Amazingly painful, isn’t it? This Move is strongest before it actually gets used. The gathering of Strings are a constant reminder. I wonder what other Entrance Moves can learn from that design to better fit into their game?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/8</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_G]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_g">@Joshua_G</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I used that move every chance I got the one time I played a Tainted and it was awesome. But yeah, I can see if being a lot less useful depending on the game - specifically how likely it is that the party will be split. The tainted one also lets you dodge danger really well, which this Masks version does not allow.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 03:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@flatvurm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/flatvurm">@flatvurm</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Also, it certainly depends on the wording of the move in question, but take <strong>There when it matters</strong>, for example, there’s no reason the other character in question has to be a PC! I think that opens up some cool possibilities for MCs to move the action or otherwise switch scenes in a pretty interesting way if the target is an NPC. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=6" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 02:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My other thought with, say, the Bull move, is that maybe I just need to set up more circumstances where people are separated from the group. If the person the Bull has the hold with is being held captive by a villain, for example, that would be a prime opportunity to bust right in using that move.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/5</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 01:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alexi_Sarge]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alexi_sarge">@Alexi_Sarge</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s an interesting point. Maybe these moves are less interesting in games/genres where we assume the PCs are together most of the time, and more interesting in games/genres where the PCs are likely to be separated and pursuing their own agendas.</p>
<p>Maybe this move category needs to have bigger fictional and mechanical fallout to be fun in more team-based stories. So here’s a hack of the Bull move:</p>
<p><em>Just in time</em>: When you defend someone, on a hit you can hold 1 instead of choosing one from the list. Spend your hold when they are in danger later to just be there, at the exact right moment, no matter how implausibly, and take the consequence for them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PbtA Entrance Moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve seen some cool uses of the Tainted from Urban Shadows, who has a move that lets them cash in a debt to whoosh into a scene unannounced, but I think that works because everyone has their own independent schemes and whatnot. In a Masks game I’m running, the Bull has a Team Move like this, but the team’s all generally around one another anyway.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 20:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-323-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pbta-entrance-moves/323.rss">PbtA Entrance Moves</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
