<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Passion de las Passiones: Passions of the Peak</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/passion-de-las-passiones-passions-of-the-peak/7460</link>
    <description>**This event description may contain spoilers for Twin Peaks**

A body has been discovered in your small, strange remote town. The death has revealed the fault lines that always existed and unearthed secrets that were best kept buried.

This is five sessions of Passion de las Passiones, drifted in order to to tell a story inspired by Twin Peaks, run on Thursday evenings in December 2021, at 8 PM US Eastern Time. All access time is 9:30 AM on 10/6.

We will be telling a story of surreal melodrama in a small town recently wracked by tragedy, and punctuated by the mysterious supernatural. The game will explore themes of trauma, love, loss, the horrors that people inflict on those closest to them and the beauty of the strange and grotesque. Genre will be more primetime soap than mystery. **NOTE: This is NOT an investigative game. Though players may choose to investigate the death, or any strange occurrences that take place in town they should not expect to discover satisfying answers to any mysteries they attempt to solve, only unsettling new questions.**

Content Warning: The touchstone for this series includes graphic violence, sexual violence, incest and other sensitive and difficult subjects. We will use safety tools that will help us navigate this material, and these specific elements and any others may be lined so that they do not appear in our game. However, trauma, both individual and collective, is core to the themes of the series, and will play a role.

We will use Streamyard for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Sessions will run up to three hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. [The Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in play and we will use Lines and Veils and the [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg), as well as Script Change.

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5KOS-UIkHb69yodF3

Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5Kd3670Eo4on7aWrI

Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5KszY8OTn90yLij2b

Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5L3j1IaGhUDAwwd89

Session 5: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5LL1c3FYgNsy3lM6Z</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 13:33:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/passion-de-las-passiones-passions-of-the-peak/7460.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Passion de las Passiones: Passions of the Peak</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jesseabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jesseabe">@Jesseabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>This event description may contain spoilers for Twin Peaks</strong></p>
<p>A body has been discovered in your small, strange remote town. The death has revealed the fault lines that always existed and unearthed secrets that were best kept buried.</p>
<p>This is five sessions of Passion de las Passiones, drifted in order to to tell a story inspired by Twin Peaks, run on Thursday evenings in December 2021, at 8 PM US Eastern Time. All access time is 9:30 AM on 10/6.</p>
<p>We will be telling a story of surreal melodrama in a small town recently wracked by tragedy, and punctuated by the mysterious supernatural. The game will explore themes of trauma, love, loss, the horrors that people inflict on those closest to them and the beauty of the strange and grotesque. Genre will be more primetime soap than mystery. <strong>NOTE: This is NOT an investigative game. Though players may choose to investigate the death, or any strange occurrences that take place in town they should not expect to discover satisfying answers to any mysteries they attempt to solve, only unsettling new questions.</strong></p>
<p>Content Warning: The touchstone for this series includes graphic violence, sexual violence, incest and other sensitive and difficult subjects. We will use safety tools that will help us navigate this material, and these specific elements and any others may be lined so that they do not appear in our game. However, trauma, both individual and collective, is core to the themes of the series, and will play a role.</p>
<p>We will use Streamyard for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Sessions will run up to three hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html">The Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> will be in play and we will use Lines and Veils and the <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg">X-Card</a>, as well as Script Change.</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5KOS-UIkHb69yodF3">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5KOS-UIkHb69yodF3</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5Kd3670Eo4on7aWrI">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5Kd3670Eo4on7aWrI</a></p>
<p>Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5KszY8OTn90yLij2b">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5KszY8OTn90yLij2b</a></p>
<p>Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5L3j1IaGhUDAwwd89">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5L3j1IaGhUDAwwd89</a></p>
<p>Session 5: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5LL1c3FYgNsy3lM6Z">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Ml5LL1c3FYgNsy3lM6Z</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/passion-de-las-passiones-passions-of-the-peak/7460/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/passion-de-las-passiones-passions-of-the-peak/7460/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 13:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7460-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/passion-de-las-passiones-passions-of-the-peak/7460.rss">Passion de las Passiones: Passions of the Peak</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
