<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347</link>
    <description>I&#39;d like a good fantasy role-playing game with a strong social element. 

That is, I want the game to build-in rules for handling all sorts of social situations mechanically with the kind of love and respect that is usually given to killing things. Simply adding a set of skills like &quot;persuade&quot; and &quot;intimidate&quot; is not sufficient. I find anything that treats persuasion as &quot;social combat&quot; to be psychopathic.

Here are some use cases I&#39;d like an RPG to address:

* Building rapport and trust as the primary means of non-psychopathic persuasion
* Swaying groups of people
* Making friends and enemies
* Winning long-term political challenges
* Building factions and larger organizations
* How power dynamics (rank, popularity, etc.) influence persuasion

So right out of the gate, D&amp;D is out. People are going to mention Burning Wheel but I don&#39;t think it does these things that well (and Duel of Wits is semi-psychopathic &quot;social combat&quot;). One Roll Engine maybe?

Any contenders out there? Is this still a ruleset waiting for me to write it?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 13:17:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>hey Adam –</p>
<p>Nice. Agreed, you’re going to need new moves to fit the specific theme and scope you’re looking for. Regarding scope; that’s what tier is for, basically. The Faction game is all about what you’re thinking about, namely:<br>
– It’s not wielded like a sword: If you don’t honor your commitments to other factions, they like you less. That is, if you treat an Ally like you don’t care about them, they will do the same.<br>
– As Tier increases, so does your sway. A Tier 0 faction has gangs of a couple of people with crappy equipment and nobody knows them, while a Tier 4 faction has large gangs and a lot of sway.</p>
<p>Hearts of Wulin is likely also your jam! There’s a lot of good design out there to steal from.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 13:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="22" data-topic="3347">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/thomas_junk/40/959_2.png" class="avatar"> Thomas_Junk:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Sounds you maybe want to “steal” from <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/hearts-of-wulin.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Hearts of Wulin</a></p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Okay, dude, this is awesome. The first page of the Moves document already addresses some of my “not psychopathic” social interaction concerns. Its heart is in the right place but it still treats NPCs as objects to be manipulated, but it’s a lot softer than a lot of mechanics.</p>
<p>(There seems to be this belief among game designers that you can just wield personal charisma as a sharp sword to make people do what you want, without consequence. Building rapport really doesn’t work that way.)</p>
<p>I do love the idea of essentially marking stress (“elements” in the text) when you won’t do what people are pressuring you to do, and then an Inner Conflict move that forces you to deal with the stress you’ve let build up.</p>
<p>I think there are some great ideas in Hearts of Wulin to mine for my inevitable game design quest.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/26</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 02:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> I’ll peek at that!</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/julian">@Julian</a> That’s a very cool mechanic. Worth stealing and reusing for when I inevitably write my own game to do what I want.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a>:</p>
<p>Yeah, that stuff is all cool, and I can see that it’s definitely more complicated than “one and done” systems for interpersonal interactions, but I don’t see how it handles any of the larger scale stuff I want to do.</p>
<p>I have a setting based on 1300 AD Hungary, which faced a ten-year interregnum during which time “Baron Palatines” (oligarchs) ruled giant swaths of the country and jockeyed to place their choice of dude on the throne. At least four different people made some claim to the throne, with the Pope backing one and a bunch of barons backing one other.</p>
<p>So I have to figure out how PCs can play kingmaker. Some of it may be by sword or by spell, but I think a lot of it can come down to influence peddling, and I want to model that fairly strongly. I could turn it into a series of a hundred NPC interactions but that’s probably not optimal.</p>
<p>I also have this idea of growing (PC) fame that I’d like to model somehow. Because of their deeds, PCs are literally impressing spirits into bonding with them, giving them power. If they can awe spirits, they’re probably gobsmacking villagers. I’d like to know how PCs can use their fame to sway crowds or organizations. The <em>Leader</em> move looks cool to make a cohort fight, but it doesn’t make them elect the 13-year-old girl as Queen of Junnia.</p>
<p>Make sense?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 02:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Or moves?</p>
<p>Blades is, of course specifically about scoundrels and would take some adapting to be what you want. Still, these moves are more than “roll dice, tick a clock”. The clock is to obstacles in Blades as hit points are to combat in D&amp;D – the baseline that is changed by abilities. Instead of Sleep and Bless spells, we gotta look to the moves.</p>
<p>Here’s a few moves that do that, taken from the Blades online SRD:</p>
<h3>Like looking into a mirror</h3>
<p>You can always tell when someone is lying to you.</p>
<h3>Leader</h3>
<p>When you Command a  <strong>cohort</strong>  in combat, they continue to fight when they would otherwise  <strong>break</strong>  (they’re not taken out when they suffer level 3 harm). They gain  <strong>+1 effect</strong>  and  <strong>1 armor</strong> .</p>
<h3>Mesmerism</h3>
<p>When you Sway someone, you may cause them to forget that it’s happened until they next interact with you.</p>
<h3>Subterfuge</h3>
<p>You may expend your  <strong>special armor</strong>  to resist a consequence from suspicion or persuasion, or to  <strong>push yourself</strong>  for subterfuge.</p>
<h3>Trust in me</h3>
<p>You get  <strong>+1d</strong>  vs. a target with whom you have an intimate relationship.</p>
<h3>Weaving the web</h3>
<p>You gain  <strong>+1d</strong>  to Consort when you gather information on a target for a score. You get  <strong>+1d</strong>  to the  <strong>engagement roll</strong>  for that operation.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 12:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Julian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/julian">@Julian</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I like the Encounter rules from The One Ring. They’re simple, don’t cover all of your bullet points and are kind of specific to the setting, but I feel they might still help with what you’re trying to do.</p>
<p>The two features that make them stand out to me are Introductions and Tolerance.</p>
<p>The former simply says that whoever wants to participate in a social situation has to introduce themself first. NPCs have a (usually secret, might be inferred though) preference of whether they wish to interact with a single spokesperson for the adventuring party or whether they’d like everyone to introduce themself.</p>
<p>Tolerance is either a number of rolls that the party may collectively fail until they’ve overstaid their welcome and the encounter ends. Or the number of rolls they are allowed to make/points they may raise (that’s a house rule variant I like). Calculating Tolerance counts in social standing, customs, the immediate situation and so on. There is another house rule variant, where the manner in which the encounter ends when the party runs out of Tolerance is cleverly tied to the lands they’re in. In Free Lands for example, there will be a polite close to conversations while in Shadow Lands you will be threatened with violence and essentially never talked to again.</p>
<p>[House rules by Ralph Mazza, Paul Beakley, Ara Winter. They’re probably still available from them.]</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 09:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sounds you maybe want to “steal” from <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/hearts-of-wulin.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Hearts of Wulin</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 07:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, I’ve played Blades a few times.</p>
<p>The Towerlands setting I am building needs a system that can handle fantasy adventure, interpersonal interaction, small factions, and even kingdom building. I am still looking for a system that does all that.</p>
<p>I’m not sure that “roll dice; tick a clock” has the mechanical complexity I want. Characters should be able to learn how to be good at different kinds of political techniques. There should be political and social “stunts” or “feats” or whatever.</p>
<p>When I talk about the complexity of D&amp;D combat (even, like, Basic D&amp;D, but more like 5e), I’m not just talking about whittling down hit points, and I think reducing D&amp;D combat to just hit-point accretion either does it a disservice or badly misunderstands its complexity. I assume that anyone in this thread who has played D&amp;D will understand what I mean after a bit of thought, but I’ll break it down for anyone who genuinely doesn’t understand.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 02:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Do you know Blades In The Dark yet, Adam?</p>
<p>As, if nothing else, your City of Brass fits it fairly well with a different crew sheet. I’ve been meaning to talk to you about it for a couple of months.</p>
<p>It doesn’t have moves in quite the same way as most pbta games, and has as much support for talking to people as it does for hitting people. Long-term politics can be clocks, which are player facing and not quite what you’re used to from pbta.</p>
<p>I think it hits a lot of the notes you’re looking for. But who knows.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 01:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JasonT]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasont">@JasonT</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Another suggestion: I really like what Chris McDowall is talking about for his upcoming follow-up to <em>Into the Odd,</em> <em>Electric Bastionland.</em> You can see it described in a few places already, but the one I found most helpful was <a href="https://twitter.com/bastionland/status/1159737219793465344" rel="nofollow noopener">this Twitter thread</a> (which I was just reminded of by another thread around these parts).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/19</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 01:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@noah_t]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/noah_t">@noah_t</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This might be a little slant to your core question, but I think <em>The Spire</em> has some interesting ideas around this. You play revolutionary dark elves resisting colonization by high elves in a mile-high city with a hole in reality at tits heart.</p>
<p>I don’t think the system avoids your critique about how “anything that treats persuasion as ‘social combat’” being psychopathic, but it does have mechanics that make your character feel like a member of a community, rather than a murder hobo.</p>
<p>To further your revolution, you form relationships with individuals and communities, and recruiting those relationships to help you puts stress on the relationship. Ask too much, and they might decide to stop helping you, or run into trouble with the authorities. This gives your social web a certain granularity and self-direction, and keeps it from feeling like your friend the gunsmith is just a weapons-vendor or an extra die.</p>
<p>Most interestingly, virtually <strong>every special ability</strong> in the game is tied to a particular community, religious sect, or secret society. The advancement system is technically accomplishments-driven. When you make a major change in the city of Spire, you get a major advance (potentially game-altering special powers).</p>
<p>However, because powers are also tied to particular communities and communal knowledges, your character either has to cultivate relationships with new groups, or take on greater roles (and therefore greater responsibilities) in the communities they’re already a member of to level up. I really love the ways this reinforces the game’s themes of revolution and coalition-building against oppression.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/18</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 20:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JasonT]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasont">@JasonT</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="15" data-topic="3347">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/adam/40/2644_2.png" class="avatar"> Adam:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I get what you’re saying but all of this complexity is fictional positioning and not directly supported by the mechanics the way, say, <em>D&amp;D</em> combat is.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I am not sure I follow. The way I see it, the mechanics are very much the point here: whether you do or do not get what you want is dependent on how you roll, which is mathematically influenced by how good your character is at persuading people. And there are a lot more rules for resolving social interaction than there are for resolving combat (at least in Burned Over, though that may not be the case in AW 2nd edition). The only difference I can see between how much these rules support social interaction and how much D&amp;D supports combat is that the Apocalypse World rules require everything to be tied to fictional position, while D&amp;D combat rules can be 100% abstracted to hit points and attack ranges without ever discussing what that means in fiction—but I thought that was precisely the model you didn’t want for social rules.</p>
<p>To be clear, I’m not trying to do a “gotcha!” here. I’m just not clear on what you’re looking for, but I’m really interested in the topic, and curious to find out more.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A Song of Ice and Fire (the Game of Thrones rpg)  might be what you are after.  You can take a sort of damage from verbal “combat” and verbal conflicts are treated the same mechanically as a physical duel but with different consequences</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 15:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve played <em>Apocalypse World</em> quite a bit, and a fair number of <em>PbtA</em> games including <em>Urban Shadows</em>. I get what you’re saying but all of this complexity is fictional positioning and not directly supported by the mechanics the way, say, <em>D&amp;D</em> combat is. At best, these games support one-on-one social interaction better than most games, but they don’t really manage group interactions or political games very well.</p>
<p>I do love the mechanical idea of Strings in <em>Monsterhearts</em> and how a social interaction might not make you do something, but it certainly makes things hurt if you don’t do it. It’s sort of the “with teeth” game design philosophy of <em>In a Wicked Age</em> and I’ve used a similar mechanism in some of my own game designs.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 14:27:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@darren]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/darren">@darren</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would look at Urban Shadows, amongst these other wonderful suggestions. The game as a whole may not be what you’re looking for, but I think the way its moves center relationships, community, and social interaction are (at least) a wonderful starting point.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 12:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JasonT]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasont">@JasonT</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If you haven’t already, look into Dramasystem games (like Hillfolk) for a pretty involved model for social exchange.</p>
<p>And while persuasion moves in Apocalypse World offshoots can seem pretty one-and-done, Apocalypse World itself has a lot of social complexity built into moves even beyond “seduce or manipulate.” Rather, you have multiple ways to get information about motives and needs of other characters, and either negotiate or coerce them to get what you want.  This is more obvious in the recent hackbook “Burned Over,” which lacks an explicit seduction move, and which modified the original “go aggro” move into “confront someone,” making it not necessarily about violence, in addition to the move that gets information by reading people. What’s interesting to me about these is that they very much aren’t psychopathic mind control moves; they constrain what a target can do, but don’t dictate it. On a strong roll, they can still refuse to intentionally give you what you want, but leaving themselves at your mercy (confront someone), leaving no room for doubt as they shut you down (charm or deceive), or giving answers to certain kinds of questions through nonverbal cues even if they refuse to speak (read someone). The 7-9 results tend to open things up to even more complexity, such as leading to bargaining, promises, or demands for proof of claims, any of which potentially leading into entire side ventures to meet their wants, needs, or expectations.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 12:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Jeremy,</p>
<p>This is all very clever and very exciting. I’ll have to dig in deeper and see if it’ll work for my Towerlands setting, and how much adaptation that would require.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/12</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 01:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeremy_Strandberg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi Adam,</p>
<p>Stonetop is still in production, but I’ve got my nose to the proverbial grindstone. You can find most of the relevant rules in the documents at the bottom of that blog post. Specifically, check out the <strong>Moves &amp; Gear</strong> and the <strong>Stonetop Steading Playbook</strong>.  We’re in closed playtest right now, but it’ll likely switch to open in the next month or so.  Let me know if you’ve got a group that’s interested in playing!</p>
<p>The game is definitely rooted in D&amp;D style play: you go on adventures, often exploring ruins and killing monsters and saving kidnapped villagers. The moves for violence outnumber the moves for social interaction.</p>
<p>But, as <a class="mention" href="/u/calris">@calris</a> says, the game’s premise (and the class playbooks) are rooted in a specific home town. They’re going on expeditions to kill monsters that threaten their home and neighbors, or acquire resources they can use to prop up the town, or to rescue someone’s lost nephew… that sort of thing. The PCs themselves often have big personalities and big goals, too, but the bulk of the game gets pushed and pulled by the needs of the community.</p>
<p>Rules-wise, the main social mechanic is Parley:<br>
<img src="/uploads/default/original/2X/d/d5e3860ae5744c92e3d9019fc438062d54b074c5.png" alt="image" data-base62-sha1="uw9aqRueZIHMzqs9H0TZnkairDn" width="410" height="303"></p>
<p>You’ll notice that it doesn’t give the PCs any ability to control minds or force agreement. It ends up being an information-gathering move a lot of the time, revealing how you <em>could</em> convince them to go along, and then it’s back on the player’s to decide whether they’ll do that.</p>
<p>The town itself has stats: Fortunes (morale and general well-being), Population (growing or shrinking), Prosperity (material wealth and trade, quality of gear PCs can get), and Defenses (militia’s skill and readiness).  There’s a subtle economy between all those stats, but it all serves to generate threats and opportunities and give the players projects to work towards.</p>
<p>There aren’t mechanics for tracking popularity or factions per se, but fictional positioning goes a long way here: as the Marshal, I can probably get everyone to go along with building a palisade, as long it’s not taking bodies away from spring planting or fall harvest.  But if the Seeker wants to get a workcrew to help him build his crazy magic weather-vane, he’ll need to do some convincing.</p>
<p>The game also borrows from <em>Apocalypse World</em> 2e and has you create problematic NPCs and factions and afflictions as “threats” with stakes questions and/or countdowns. Because these people are your neighbors, you can’t just ignore them*.  You can’t just kill them or beat them up, so you have to work with them or around them, and factions and popularity and politics can come into play there, too.</p>
<p>There’s a generalized <strong>Make a Plan</strong> move for designing long-term challenges, based largely on the Savvyhead’s workshop framework, so if you wanted to undertake a long-term project to, say, establish a town council and get yourself elected mayor, you could.</p>
<p>Mostly, though, the social interactions go back to that one Parley move:  it really does a lot of heavy lifting in the game.</p>
<p>Happy to answer any questions you’ve got, about this or the linked materials!</p>
<p>*(Or, I guess you can. But that’s how you end up with a nascent cult kidnapping refugees and sacrificing them for power out in the Great Wood.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/11</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Anything using Fate. the Fate Fractal means organisations can be stated up in such a way that PCs can interact mechanically with them.<br>
Meanwhile there’s a good range of social skills that can be used to attack, defend, create advantages and overcome just line ‘fight’.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/10</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 23:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> is the author - guessing he can point you in the right direction - though doing a search here might also get you a pointer to relevant docs…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/9</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 22:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/calris">@calris</a>, I found <a href="https://spoutinglore.blogspot.com/2018/07/stonetop.html" rel="nofollow noopener">this for Stonetop</a>. Is there a PDF I can buy somewhere?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/8</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 22:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Cass]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cass">@Cass</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The more I play it the more I am impressed by the mechanical balance.</p>
<p>I will say, my best experience is with my longer term game group. We’d all GM’d for each other before trying Flotsam, and I think that made it a smoother experience. Since you do think like a PC and a GM throughout the session.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/7</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 21:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/cass">@Cass</a>, that sounds really cool. Thanks for the link, too!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/6</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 21:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Cass]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cass">@Cass</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This answer may not work depending on what kind of mechanics interest you, but having played a few sessions of <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/268658/Flotsam-Adrift-Amongst-the-Stars" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>Flotsam: Adrift Amongst the Stars</em></a>, I feel like the game really focuses on social roleplay in an interesting, multilayered way. (This is a sci-fi game by default, but the playbooks are general enough I think they could easily be adapted for fantasy).</p>
<p>The game is a gmless/gmfull system where each player has an aspect of the setting they run, a primary character they play, and then everyone plays NPCs and contributes to worldbuilding as needed.</p>
<p>The setting elements are broken up into things like community, gangs, war, poverty, so the complications players introduce are inherently about a mix of societal forces and factions. One player remarked that in one session we’d already naturally defined a gang faction in more complex, creative ways than they get after multiple sessions of using <em>Blades in the Dark</em> factions.</p>
<p>You also play a primary character, and the mechanics lean into relationships and social motivations there too. For example, each character type has different flaws and problems (almost all of which tie into relationships or how society treats them). You often frame a scene by asking the group how that flaw is causing you a problem, then play out the scene from that conflict. So the central or opening tension is socially focused.</p>
<p>But the game also motivates you to think about relationships. If your primary character interacts with another primary character in set ways (e.g. ask a favor from the fixer playbook), you get a token which can power special abilities. As a player, I found myself actively looking for ways to pull in other characters because I wanted that token so I could use my cool psychic powers. At the end of each scene, if your relationship changed with another important character in a significant way, you earn a check/xp towards advancement.</p>
<p>Now, the game doesn’t use dice rolls or skill checks like some traditional games…but I think that’s part of why the social elements work. It’s about creating complications and trying to solve them through relationships…while often creating more complications in the process.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/5</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 21:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It has specific rules for interacting with people and groups that is more complicated than a single roll?</p>
<p>My frustration is that getting into physical combat is super exciting: you have a list of special powers, magic weapons and armor, special stats like hit points, and time literally changes into <em>rounds</em> and it gets all this attention.</p>
<p>Then when you get to social interaction, the rules are, like, “dude, just roleplay it” or, at best, “roll Diplomacy to make him do what you want.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 21:41:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m not sure if it’s exactly what you’re looking for, but you should take a look at <em>Stonetop</em> (loosely based on <em>Dungeon World</em>) for examples of a game/setting that focuses heavily on the social ties in a small community, along with building (or breaking) those bonds to accomplish large-scale political objectives.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 21:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3347-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fantasy-rpgs-with-good-social-systems/3347.rss">Fantasy RPGs with good social systems</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
