<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fourth World 1.5</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282</link>
    <description>The latest (and probably last) version of [Fourth World](https://divnull.com/blog/2019/seed-fourth-world-1-5/), my “drift” of *Dungeon World* to support the setting of *Earthdawn*, is now available. It is targeted at supporting longer-term campaign play.

For those that don’t know, *Earthdawn* is a high-fantasy game created by FASA in 1993. Like most games from this era, it has an extremely detailed body of setting information, and terrible mechanics. It was, however, a cut above a typical fantasy heartbreaker, particularly setting wise. The world is actually the distant past of the setting in *Shadowrun*, with some characters existing in both. (If you squint a bit, the setting also has some similarities to the *Fallout* series of video games.)

If you tinker with *Dungeon World*, but aren’t so interested in the *Earthdawn* setting, you might still want to take a look. Some design tech in there might be useful to you. If you have questions about the choices I made, here is the place to ask.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 18:22:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Fourth World 1.5</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@wordman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/wordman">@wordman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One day, I’ll read the 1500 page omnibus that I have on my bookshelf at work, and I’ll be motivated to build a <em>New Gods</em> game. Probably won’t be PbtA, though.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/7</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 18:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1282-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282.rss">Fourth World 1.5</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fourth World 1.5</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Apropos of nothing, but every time I see that header I get excited about a Jack Kirby <em>New Gods</em> hack someone did, and every time I am disappointed. I won’t stop looking, though.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 17:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1282-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282.rss">Fourth World 1.5</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fourth World 1.5</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Von_Bednar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I always LOVED the world of Earthdawn, and hated how cumbersome the system was (I remember, back in high school we met for a session and managed to only finish a single combat of 4 PCs and around 10 enemies). I mean, the system was fine (and even interesting) by the 90s standard, but I wanted something less crunchy. However, the setting is where the world has really shined. I feel like it struck a right balance between being derivative of Tolkien and doing its own thing.</p>
<p>Earthdawn is the only major fantasy game that has a good explanation of why there are so many “dungeons” in the world. I will take a Kaer over any other fantasy dungeon any time! It was the only “high fantasy” that ever made sense to me.</p>
<p>With all that - I am really glad you are making a PbtA version of it. I will dig into the rules in the near future. Just know, that even if I might not be playing it right now, I am very thankful for your hard work.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 15:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1282-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282.rss">Fourth World 1.5</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fourth World 1.5</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@wordman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/wordman">@wordman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Earthdawn</em> is now back in the hands of a resurrected FASA, who held a Kickstarter for the fourth edition not long ago. They introduce the setting <a href="https://fasagames.com/earthdawn-whatis/" rel="nofollow noopener">like this</a>. They categorize it as “hopeful, post-apocalyptic fantasy”, which sounds about right to me.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 13:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1282-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282.rss">Fourth World 1.5</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fourth World 1.5</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@wordman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/wordman">@wordman</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The latest (and probably last) version of <a href="https://divnull.com/blog/2019/seed-fourth-world-1-5/" rel="nofollow noopener">Fourth World</a>, my “drift” of <em>Dungeon World</em> to support the setting of <em>Earthdawn</em>, is now available. It is targeted at supporting longer-term campaign play.</p>
<p>For those that don’t know, <em>Earthdawn</em> is a high-fantasy game created by FASA in 1993. Like most games from this era, it has an extremely detailed body of setting information, and terrible mechanics. It was, however, a cut above a typical fantasy heartbreaker, particularly setting wise. The world is actually the distant past of the setting in <em>Shadowrun</em>, with some characters existing in both. (If you squint a bit, the setting also has some similarities to the <em>Fallout</em> series of video games.)</p>
<p>If you tinker with <em>Dungeon World</em>, but aren’t so interested in the <em>Earthdawn</em> setting, you might still want to take a look. Some design tech in there might be useful to you. If you have questions about the choices I made, here is the place to ask.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 13:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1282-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fourth-world-1-5/1282.rss">Fourth World 1.5</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
