<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702</link>
    <description>A lot of our games deal with emotionally fraught subject material, and the community has developed a variety of safety mechanics and best practices to make for safer spaces.

What we rarely discuss is the failures. Without that, it can be difficult to know what to look for as a facilitator, and what to design to avoid. This is not about wallowing in those failures, but in making them public so we can do better. Please only share ones where public discussion is acceptable for those involved.

For example: The first time I played The Tribunal, the bleed was bad and I had a panic attack. I missed a night&#39;s sleep, and it took me a while to process it. To stress: This wasn&#39;t the fault of the facilitator of the game. I learned a lot from it, mostly about privilege.

I&#39;ve avoided repeating the outcome both by increasing my own emotional awareness and by better knowing my triggers. I&#39;ve for-sure continued to LARP and have had some deep experiences there, and that&#39;s worked out for me pretty well.

What failures have you seen? What failures have you been a part of? What did you learn from those? How can we improve the culture to better mitigate these failures?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:23:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@czakita]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/czakita">@czakita</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, I think talking about it could do some good <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/50</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oh my. That’s rough, and I’m sorry.</p>
<p>There are so many failures here – do you have interest in pulling them out, discussing mitigation strategies, etc?</p>
<p>It sounds like you know what went wrong, but it might help others.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/49</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@czakita]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/czakita">@czakita</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My WORST gaming experience about which I started joking just a day later that this will be my go-to anecdote about safety on even the lightest larps was when my friends asked me to introduce them to LARPs on our annual near-Christmas meeting that I was hosting. I was delighted that I can show them the hobby and chosen a good, quite popular Polish larp/jeepform based on a movie called Perfect Strangers. The permise is that there is a meeting of old friends - there are two or three pairs in relationships and one single person. They decide to play a game - they will read all text messages aloud and pick up the calls on speaker. The audience of the game is responsible for writing texts and calling to the players.<br>
I tried to be careful. I told them that they shouldn’t role play in their actual relationships. I introduced safe words, I said that everybody is free to walk away from the game at any point. The game is played with real phones, so put some emphasis on the fact that real-life phone calls and texts don’t participate in the game, and they shouldn’t read them aloud.<br>
What I didn’t predict was the fact that one of the players will decide to engage people from outside the game (and of course this is the one person that actually knew something about LARPs and really wanted to play in one at last).<br>
So we have this guy who suddenly starts getting messages that he reads aloud, but I see that no one on the audience had sent them. They are consistent with his character’s plot though (it was concerning drugs), so I decide that hey, maybe I just didn’t see something. And then he picks up the phone and we all see that it isn’t an in-game call, cause no one on the audience is doing it. The player, nevertheless, picks up on speaker, and the person calling is terrified, they say that they can’t contact their friend that they did some drugs (the guys plot concerned drugs) and that they don’t know what to do.<br>
At this point we’re almost shouting at the player to take the person of the speaker, so he does, he goes to other room, talks for a while, comes back, assures us that everything’s alright now. We were obviously too shaken to continue playing, and he kept trolling us for five more minutes before he told us that it was a prank and he only wanted to make game more interesting.<br>
So, I think that, especially with new players, and ESPECIALLY with new players who think they know enough, establishing that there is a FINE line between the fiction and the reality and that rules are there because they are needed is a very basic safety tool that maybe we sometimes forget, because it is too obvious.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/48</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 10:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hi Erik; that sounds to me a little like the “door is always open” idea, which I think is so important for games which can be emotionally intense for <em>whatever</em> reason. I know that when I was at Metatopia we were a little way into one of my games, and one of the players said “I’m sorry, I don’t think I can do this game”, and that was fine. I reassured them that we were perfectly happy for them to do that, that it wouldn’t be a problem and wished them well. Little did I suspect that eight hours later I’d be in just the same situation myself, and I had to excuse myself from a game for various reasons, and they graciously assured me that it wasn’t a problem.</p>
<p>I suspect that may be the most useful of all the safety techniques I’ve actually seen used.</p>
<p>Best wishes,</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/47</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I feel like things are getting better. There are many drivers for this. Some institutional drivers:</p>
<p>Games on Demand, in its various incarnations, totally normalizes this, and converts people. You go in expecting weird stuff and that’s what you get. Some of that is content and some of that is social contract. You take the good bits home, or at least accept them when you encounter them. Spend two hours at any GoD and the routine use of safety tools will never be a foreign concept again.</p>
<p>New World Magischola has had a huge impact in the North American larp world by implementing and normalizing safety tools that actually work. It attracts people from across the larp cultures of play, usually well-heeled thought leaders, who return to their little silos and introduce the OK check-in and other tools organically. This actually happens and it is very exciting to me.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/46</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 01:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>When these things work out, it’s glorious.</p>
<p>But, getting back to the topic: Are we, as a larpy gamey culture, getting better at this?</p>
<p>That is, are we:</p>
<ul>
<li>Better at knowing that it can happen?</li>
<li>Better at resolving it when it does?</li>
<li>Learning how to mitigate the risks?</li>
</ul>
<p>I think we are. I’ve seen and witnessed changes in safety mechanics, and thing the use is becoming more and more normalized.</p>
<p>Am I mistaken?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/45</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 17:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>No thought went into individual relationships at all. I don’t even remember who you are talking about, but I’m really happy it worked out.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/44</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:50:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> Time for a behind the curtain question.</p>
<p>At Tipford, the person you assigned to be my daughter I see on a semi-regular basis, and we’ve larped together before and trust each other. That was really great, and we were both glad to get to explore that relationship.</p>
<p>Did you know we knew each other when you assigned?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/43</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Let’s leave it. Too much analysis would probably risk outing the other folks involved, which is not my goal. Just wanted to share how badly off the rails things can go even when everyone thinks they’ve properly nodded towards safety.</p>
<p>If something like this happened today I’d be much, much better equipped to handle it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/42</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 16:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Jim that’s awful and highlights a gigantic smorgasbord of failures, both on the organizer’s part and on yours. Would it be helpful to break those down or would you prefer to leave this one alone as a monument to awfulness?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/41</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 13:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>“The Door Is Always Open” is predicated on not stigmatizing the behavior, so part of the spiel is usually:</p>
<p>“You can check out at any time, for any reason. You can take a break, or leave forever as necessary. No one will question your choice and you won’t wreck the game, so take care of yourself. If you are leaving permanently it is a courtesy to let the facilitator know so we don’t worry about you.”</p>
<p>With this in mind running after someone and asking them what’s wrong focuses unwanted attention on their perfectly normal choice. It’s the exact opposite of what the technique espouses. it disincentivizes the technique for others.</p>
<p>Of course you should check in and make sure everyone is OK, but the moment someone walks out is not the time to do it unless there are obvious signs of distress. That’s a real judgement call but I tend to err on the side of leaving people alone. After the game, definitely check in.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/40</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 13:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My Worst Game Ever: a few years ago, many of my tabletop friends were leaving tabletop gaming for the new hotness of freeform LARPs, particularly the Nordic stuff.</p>
<p>I wanted to keep playing with them, so I decided to try joining in on on one of the high-bleed high school simulators. It was a poor fit and I probably should have known that going in.</p>
<p>The place where it really broke down was in being a game where players were supposed to use the face/arm touching technique for simulating sexual activity. There was extensive safety discussion, practice to get us comfortable, and the ironclad assurance that we were free to opt out of anything we didn’t want to do. All very conscientious.</p>
<p>And then I’m handed the in-game plot for my character, a torrid secret affair including lots of sex with an older girl… who was played by a woman in her early 20s. I was in my mid-40s.</p>
<p>I completely melted down and had no idea what to do. RPing sex in secret with her was just a deeply uncomfortable proposition, but bailing entirely  on the game removed a major aspect of HER character, and isn’t she an adult who can say no if she’s uncomfortable, and Jesus Christ how many times has some creep laid THAT line down?</p>
<p>It was a nightmare, I wondered for years (to this day) if it was trolling me on purpose. I basically stopped being friends with the host and a bunch of people involved, not because they’re bad, but because I was, and remain, so ashamed at totally fucking up that night. Actually getting beaten up would have been less upsetting to me. I haven’t really LARPed since and the thought of participating in a game without the safety tool of the table itself can bring on panic.</p>
<p>There’s two obvious-to-me morals, I guess? One is to trust your instincts about what you’ll enjoy and not. The other is a corollary to <a class="mention" href="/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a>’s note about outside factors: no amount of pre-game prep would fix needing to stand in a bathroom and pretend to fuck some girl young enough to be my actual daughter. The table is the first, best safety tool, and consideration of the outside-of-play social factors going into what you’re asking players to simulate (and with whom) can prevent situations that force folks to reckon with them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/39</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 07:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks! Being someone who thanks people for doing it in a way that helps you feel safer helps propagate best practices!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/38</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 07:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Question, <a class="mention" href="/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a>: if I’m reading this right — you are saying that rushing to check that someone is OK after they walked out of a LARP is not a good approach.  Is that always the case? If someone doesn’t follow up with them, are you potentially exposing the person who left to a worse experience of whatever happened because they may not get support they need and be vulnerable in a public place? How do you know when to follow up with them and when not to?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/37</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 03:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@GroupSoliloquy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/groupsoliloquy">@GroupSoliloquy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> I think you used the zeroth safety rule at that convention: Walking away from the table. It’s not always discussed, but an essential component to safety in games. Sometimes the only thing you can do for your safety is to walk away. It’s important that we not stigmatize that behavior in any way, ask questions, or interrogate someones desire to walk away.</p>
<p>On your X-card question:<br>
I think it’s important to explain that it’s purpose is not to explore potentially dangerous content, but to provide relief from content not anticipated to be dangerous. That’s why it’s so often tied with lines and veils. <a class="mention" href="/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> does the most stellar safety discussion before every game. He reminds people of the open door and inclusivity policy, does CATS, works through lines and veils (importantly allows players to submit them anonymously), and ends with X-card for all the things that the previous tools don’t cover. That conversation is abbreviated, but recurs with <em>every</em> session and if a new player joins everything is re-stated and re-calibrated.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/36</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sorry for the double-post, but reading some of the other comments brought up some more thoughts.</p>
<p>I feel like sometimes the use of X-Cards can be seen as / used as an excuse to “push” on more edgy content, ie “I can do this and if someone is uncomfortable they can just X-card it.” I’d be interested in getting people’s thoughts on how to counteract this, without playing down the good the X-card can do.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/35</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I had a rough time playing a story-game at a convention recently, even though we were using X-cards, Veils, the whole nine yards. I excused myself from the game maybe 2/3rds of the way through cuz of the emotions and feelings the game was bringing up. It was one of those “everyone dies at the end” type games, and not in the “fun” way like Fiasco. It was my first time playing a game like that, and it was probably a mistake on my part to try it out in a convention setting with strangers. The lesson I took away from it is that Safety tools aren’t 100% effective, especially if you’re not really sure what it is you’re getting yourself into / it’s your first time playing an “intense” game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/34</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Cass]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cass">@Cass</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="28" data-topic="702">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/william_nichols/40/530_2.png" class="avatar"> William_Nichols:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Not knowing ourselves: We encounter novel situations or material and, well, play to find out. Sometimes this hits us in ways we don’t expect. I absolutely do not have a good solution for this and, well, I’ve learned a lot about myself from some of the worst experiences</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>My worst experiences probably fall into this category. Specifically, I play a lot of games with something like the Belief mechanic from Burning Wheel. When I need to create my own belief from scratch, especially if I need something quickly so I don’t hold up character creation, I’ve noticed a tendency to default to things too close to my own experience which leads to bleed happening a lot easier.</p>
<p>I’ve since learned to try and play characters with very different beliefs from my own experiences, but it made me wish more games had example beliefs to pick from so it would be easier to quickly choose something deliberately very different.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/33</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BrieBeau]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/briebeau">@BrieBeau</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oh, and in this model, everyone is responsible for this - not just facilitators or people with trauma!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/32</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BrieBeau]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/briebeau">@BrieBeau</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would say one thing I’ve been working on in home games in support of my work on Script Change and my own table experience is creating a culture of care rather than a culture of play. It’s based on stuff I learned based in caring ethics, and something I hope to integrate into Script Change. I’ve addressed bits in the recent Leading with Class episodes.</p>
<p>The steps are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Changing from caring about to caring for, basically refocusing from “sure, I care about this person/these people” to “I will make an effort to give care to these people” - it takes more work but refocusing helps us do the following steps.</li>
<li>Asking questions - what do you want to see in game? What don’t you want to see? How can I help you enjoy the game? How can I mitigate harm? What is a soft line, what is a hard line? Etc.</li>
<li>Using the answers from the questions to customize safety tool use for the table (maybe you need Script Change and the X-card, etc.) and ensuring everyone has access to the tools outside of game.</li>
<li>Framing the game and environment as an environment where play is happening but care comes first - “it’s fun” does not override “it squicks/triggers/bores a player.” Check in regularly to ensure one person’s fun isn’t another person’s harm.</li>
<li>Normalizing checkins and asking players how they feel, how they can be supported, and how the experience can improve. (Pause is good for this.)</li>
<li>Being willing to stop doing what is happening, even the whole game, to care for someone.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s what I’ve got so far!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/31</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For sure <a class="mention" href="/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a>. We just had a bit of a shakeup, with a friend having an amicable split out and bringing in another friend.</p>
<p>You can bet for sure that before we had a game, I made sure we had a discussion about safety tools, and that we stressed You Are More Important Than The Game. We usually have the x-card, and made sure it was out in the open.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/30</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think it is important to note that the safety tools need to be calibrated to the game and experience. Not every tool is the right fit for every game/experience/situation. The affordances of tabletop make it a little easier to standardize, but even then, I strongly feel that you need to tune your tool-set appropriately.</p>
<p>For example, I don’t use an X-card with my home group, who have been playing together for almost 20 years. We have a good idea of our boundaries and limitations and we love and trust each other very much. But if we invite a guest I totally will put one on the table.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/29</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The mainstay of failures seem to fall into two related components:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Not knowing ourselves: We encounter novel situations or material and, well, play to find out. Sometimes this hits us in ways we don’t expect. I absolutely do not have a good solution for this and, well, I’ve learned a lot about myself from some of the worst experiences.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Lack of player empathy: Sometimes other players (sometimes, I think we all fall into this) value The Game over The Players. This is completely understandable: We are here to play a game. This is dangerous, and it is a good idea to both better understand why we do it, and how to notice when others are doing it.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>The second one I think we can do something about, as described by many others:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Normalize the use of safety tools. I know I do OK-check-in quite a bit more than I think necessary, both because it is only minimally invasive and because it normalizes the use.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If others do not treat these tools as important, use what privilege and social standing we have to ensure they are treated as important. This can include calling people on the bad behavior, but also providing the positive example.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>What have I missed?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sometimes you can see this in real time at conventions - somebody at an adjacent table being badly run just shuts down, their eyes go dead, and you just know they will never be back. I feel like this happens a lot. I often meet people who are returning to try again a decade or more after a bad experience and am always a little amazed - if I’d tried bird watching and had a horrible time because the other bird watchers made me feel awful, I would not look back.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> to keep the thread focused on failures: People treating the X-card like a joke and not calling them on it instantly.</p>
<p>Rushing after someone who walked out of a larp to make sure “everything is OK”.</p>
<p>Doggedly sticking with an “important” plot point even though it was obviously making someone else unhappy. Hey, they could use the safety tools, right?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/27</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 13:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It sucks you had that experience. From what you wrote it seems like a social contract issue - your friend was trying to set something up they thought you would enjoy, and they were mistaken but got no feedback to course correct. This less-formal piece of system (friends sitting around a table) feels best addressed with less formal tools (friends checking in with one another). A mid-session check-in (“How is everybody feeling? Is there anything we absolutely want to see in the second half tonight? Anything not catching fire?”) has been successful for me - the timing is right to make it constructive rather than critical, and people are in the moment and engaged with a clarity that rapidly fades post-session.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702/26</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 13:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-702-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/frank-discussion-on-failures-in-gaming-safety/702.rss">Frank discussion on failures in gaming safety</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
