<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Vigor: Into Dust – Open Playtest</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vigor-into-dust-open-playtest/3801</link>
    <description>Howdy Friends! 
Looking for folks who want to join the open playtest of a game we have coming to KS in November: 

_Vigor: Into Dust_ – Character-Forward Collaborative Storytelling in a World on the Brink. 

If you jump over to [vigorrpg.com](https://www.vigorrpg.com/), you can click the link to join the playtest Discord and get a free beta pdf copy of the game. 

I&#39;m curious as to what jumps out at you about the game in general, but I&#39;m looking particularly for any feedback on the sections on Assets (items), and The Dust (magic). Those are on pages 40 and 22 of the pdf, respectively. 

Both are intentionally built to allow the players to create on the fly, but I wonder if they&#39;re too vague, or if there&#39;s enough to feel like you can build off of. It&#39;s hard to get that balance right with a game meant to leave a lot of worldbuilding to the players, you know? 

Anyway, I&#39;d love your thoughts if you&#39;re interested!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 17:29:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vigor-into-dust-open-playtest/3801.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Vigor: Into Dust – Open Playtest</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jake-householder]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jake-householder">@jake-householder</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Howdy Friends!<br>
Looking for folks who want to join the open playtest of a game we have coming to KS in November:</p>
<p><em>Vigor: Into Dust</em> – Character-Forward Collaborative Storytelling in a World on the Brink.</p>
<p>If you jump over to <a href="https://www.vigorrpg.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">vigorrpg.com</a>, you can click the link to join the playtest Discord and get a free beta pdf copy of the game.</p>
<p>I’m curious as to what jumps out at you about the game in general, but I’m looking particularly for any feedback on the sections on Assets (items), and The Dust (magic). Those are on pages 40 and 22 of the pdf, respectively.</p>
<p>Both are intentionally built to allow the players to create on the fly, but I wonder if they’re too vague, or if there’s enough to feel like you can build off of. It’s hard to get that balance right with a game meant to leave a lot of worldbuilding to the players, you know?</p>
<p>Anyway, I’d love your thoughts if you’re interested!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vigor-into-dust-open-playtest/3801/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vigor-into-dust-open-playtest/3801/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 17:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3801-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/vigor-into-dust-open-playtest/3801.rss">Vigor: Into Dust – Open Playtest</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
