<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Itchio Creator Day</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/itchio-creator-day/6958</link>
    <description>Today is [Itchio Creator Day](https://t.co/gpvfS9ccVk?amp=1)! 100% of what you pay for games on itchio will be going to creators. Itchio is supporting the community of game creators by waiving its usual cut.

There are some cool sales and bundles going on for the day. [This bundle](https://itch.io/s/49754/creator-day-bundle) includes a solo journaling game that uses both a Jenga tower and Scrabble letters! This &quot;deep cuts&quot; [bundle](https://itch.io/b/882/creator-day-ttrpg-deep-cuts-bundle) offers a score of games for $20.

I&#39;ve put up a game of my own for sale also: As of today, [the zine edition of Great Soul Train Robbery is available on itchio](https://cloven-pine-games.itch.io/the-great-soul-train-robberyzine-edition)! Pick up the PDF to play your very own game of Desperados stealing from a train bound for damnation.

Anyone else have a new or on-sale itchio game to promote today? Or have you found any exciting games while checking out what&#39;s on offer?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 16:22:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/itchio-creator-day/6958.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Itchio Creator Day</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alexi_Sarge]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alexi_sarge">@Alexi_Sarge</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Today is <a href="https://t.co/gpvfS9ccVk?amp=1" rel="nofollow noopener">Itchio Creator Day</a>! 100% of what you pay for games on itchio will be going to creators. Itchio is supporting the community of game creators by waiving its usual cut.</p>
<p>There are some cool sales and bundles going on for the day. <a href="https://itch.io/s/49754/creator-day-bundle" rel="nofollow noopener">This bundle</a> includes a solo journaling game that uses both a Jenga tower and Scrabble letters! This “deep cuts” <a href="https://itch.io/b/882/creator-day-ttrpg-deep-cuts-bundle" rel="nofollow noopener">bundle</a> offers a score of games for $20.</p>
<p>I’ve put up a game of my own for sale also: As of today, <a href="https://cloven-pine-games.itch.io/the-great-soul-train-robberyzine-edition" rel="nofollow noopener">the zine edition of Great Soul Train Robbery is available on itchio</a>! Pick up the PDF to play your very own game of Desperados stealing from a train bound for damnation.</p>
<p>Anyone else have a new or on-sale itchio game to promote today? Or have you found any exciting games while checking out what’s on offer?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/itchio-creator-day/6958/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/itchio-creator-day/6958/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 16:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6958-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/itchio-creator-day/6958.rss">Itchio Creator Day</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
