<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987</link>
    <description>![5N1TZUhQ2|450x253](upload://vU8ElCKAVnaEG9fAgaMCnpzZXGM.jpeg) 
With the *Fate of Cthulhu* KS in full swing, I&#39;ve revised and updated my Fate System Guide for New Players. The first half&#39;s up on the blog today.

**[Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one)**

As I mention in the post, I&#39;m one of the Fate-friendly gamers on the Gauntlet. That&#39;s been a running joke because of some of my friend&#39;s attitudes about the game, koff *Rich* koff. I like it warts and all, especially the flexibility it offers. So I wanted to offer an entry-point overview for those wondering what&#39;s up with the game. (And I recognize it opens me up to the &quot;I hate Fate because of X&quot; comments). 

But there&#39;s stuff there for non-Fate players. One of the beauties of the system is that the light-weight mechanics don&#39;t take up too much room in the text. You could easily pick up *Uprising*, *Fate of Cthulhu*, or the *Fate Horror Toolkit* and get great, usable material for other games. That&#39;s going to be particularly true for next week&#39;s post when I go through all the amazing Worlds of Adventure supplements.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 15:33:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve always played pretty loose with aspects on the table. I’ve played with some Fate vets who cover the table with them. I don’t do that. Creating an aspect has an intent: changing the situation or supporting someone. In the latter case it feels like an active result and I stress that-- in some cases its about reading that intent and scope of results to see if its more Overcome or Create Advantage. If its a support action, we try to give it shape.</p>
<p>Part of the reason that works for me is that I work in smaller scales. In some games I’ve seen GMs create big number obstacles constantly to tax the player’s resources. That’s not what I’m about. We’re playing a story game and we go to the system for resolution questions. Costs given to up things are a kind of hard move, spending resources should be a hard choice, etc. I keep things moving so we don’t bog down on things. It’s actually a critique that I got from Gerrit, and I think a reasonable one, that I de-emphasize the economy in play.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 15:33:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1987-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987.rss">Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So I have only played Fate once or twice, but for your wall burning example - in my limited experience Fate tends to require a fair amount of meta discussion - at least a comfort bouncing in and out since the whole idea of Aspects is pretty meta. That being the case I would assume that you wouldn’t do something creating a temporary Aspect unless you were planning to use it yourself or you had already coordinated with another player to do so. When I played it was very much a chain of doing things people built on until one person Did The Thing making use of all those supporting actions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 15:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1987-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987.rss">Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I haven’t played Fate, but I have some queries/reservations about it (based on my limited understanding)</p>
<p>During a fight, if someone creates an aspect eg sets the wall on fire.</p>
<ul>
<li>they have used their action/turn to do this.</li>
<li>if no one else uses this aspect, then that turn is wasted in terms of action economy.</li>
<li>making that aspect socially obligates others to use their turn/bennies in conjunction with the aspect?</li>
</ul>
<p>So i’m not sure how making/changing/removing aspects A-affects the flow of the timeline of events, and B-affects the flow of team cohesion. ?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 08:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1987-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987.rss">Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/df9bf99900f3a139dbdf0042f0266c5b5d26ff30.jpeg" alt="5N1TZUhQ2" data-base62-sha1="vU8ElCKAVnaEG9fAgaMCnpzZXGM" width="450" height="253"><br>
With the <em>Fate of Cthulhu</em> KS in full swing, I’ve revised and updated my Fate System Guide for New Players. The first half’s up on the blog today.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one" rel="nofollow noopener">Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</a></strong></p>
<p>As I mention in the post, I’m one of the Fate-friendly gamers on the Gauntlet. That’s been a running joke because of some of my friend’s attitudes about the game, koff <em>Rich</em> koff. I like it warts and all, especially the flexibility it offers. So I wanted to offer an entry-point overview for those wondering what’s up with the game. (And I recognize it opens me up to the “I hate Fate because of X” comments).</p>
<p>But there’s stuff there for non-Fate players. One of the beauties of the system is that the light-weight mechanics don’t take up too much room in the text. You could easily pick up <em>Uprising</em>, <em>Fate of Cthulhu</em>, or the <em>Fate Horror Toolkit</em> and get great, usable material for other games. That’s going to be particularly true for next week’s post when I go through all the amazing Worlds of Adventure supplements.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 14:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1987-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/age-of-ravens-fate-system-guide-for-new-players-part-one/1987.rss">Age of Ravens: Fate System Guide for New Players (Part One)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
