<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Lady Blackbird One-shot (May 2)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038</link>
    <description>**Open access time for signups will be 4/23 at 4PM EDT**

Lady Blackbird is a [free-to-play](http://www.onesevendesign.com/ladyblackbird/) swashbuckling action-adventure game. This will be a one-shot so I can dip my toe in as a first-time Gauntlet Facilitator, so there may be some rough edges.

**Duration**: 3.5 hours, with short breaks on the hour. I scheduled 3.5 hours in case we need it to reach a good stopping point but I’m aiming for 3 hours

**Content Warning**: Lady Blackbird is a generally lighthearted game but includes violence and possible romance between player characters, and while it won’t be a major part of the story it does allude to slavery.

**Saftey Tools**: Lines &amp; Veils, The X-Card, and an Open Door policy. All of which will be explained before the session. It will be run under the [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html))

**The Pitch**: Lady Blackbird is on the run from an arranged marriage to Count Carlowe. She hired a smuggler skyship, The Owl, to take her from her palace on the Imperial world of Ilysium to the far reaches of the Remnants, so she could be with her once secret lover: the pirate king Uriah Flint. HOWEVER, just before reaching the halfway point of Haven, The Owl was pursued and captured by the Imperial cruiser Hand of Sorrow, under charges of flying a false flag.

EVEN NOW, Lady Blackbird, her bodyguard, and the crew of The Owl are detained in the brig, while the Imperial commander runs the smuggler ship’s registry over the wireless. It’s only a matter of time before they discover the outstanding warrants and learn that The Owl is owned by none other than the infamous outcast, Cyrus Vance.

How will Lady Blackbird and the others escape the Hand of Sorrow? What dangers lie in their path? Will they be able to find the secret lair of the pirate king? if they do, will Uriah Flint accept Lady Blackbird as his bride? By the time they get there, will she want him to?

**Venue**: Zoom. The session will not be recorded.

If you sign-up and your availability changes, remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.

**Sign-up link**: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N0CmlWTIsVX-dKRLEQp</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 21:24:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Lady Blackbird One-shot (May 2)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Would love to join a game one day, especially this one, but too bad that you’re using Zoom.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 21:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8038-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038.rss">Lady Blackbird One-shot (May 2)</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Lady Blackbird One-shot (May 2)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_Dungca]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_dungca">@Paul_Dungca</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Open access time for signups will be 4/23 at 4PM EDT</strong></p>
<p>Lady Blackbird is a <a href="http://www.onesevendesign.com/ladyblackbird/" rel="nofollow noopener">free-to-play</a> swashbuckling action-adventure game. This will be a one-shot so I can dip my toe in as a first-time Gauntlet Facilitator, so there may be some rough edges.</p>
<p><strong>Duration</strong>: 3.5 hours, with short breaks on the hour. I scheduled 3.5 hours in case we need it to reach a good stopping point but I’m aiming for 3 hours</p>
<p><strong>Content Warning</strong>: Lady Blackbird is a generally lighthearted game but includes violence and possible romance between player characters, and while it won’t be a major part of the story it does allude to slavery.</p>
<p><strong>Saftey Tools</strong>: Lines &amp; Veils, The X-Card, and an Open Door policy. All of which will be explained before the session. It will be run under the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a>)</p>
<p><strong>The Pitch</strong>: Lady Blackbird is on the run from an arranged marriage to Count Carlowe. She hired a smuggler skyship, The Owl, to take her from her palace on the Imperial world of Ilysium to the far reaches of the Remnants, so she could be with her once secret lover: the pirate king Uriah Flint. HOWEVER, just before reaching the halfway point of Haven, The Owl was pursued and captured by the Imperial cruiser Hand of Sorrow, under charges of flying a false flag.</p>
<p>EVEN NOW, Lady Blackbird, her bodyguard, and the crew of The Owl are detained in the brig, while the Imperial commander runs the smuggler ship’s registry over the wireless. It’s only a matter of time before they discover the outstanding warrants and learn that The Owl is owned by none other than the infamous outcast, Cyrus Vance.</p>
<p>How will Lady Blackbird and the others escape the Hand of Sorrow? What dangers lie in their path? Will they be able to find the secret lair of the pirate king? if they do, will Uriah Flint accept Lady Blackbird as his bride? By the time they get there, will she want him to?</p>
<p><strong>Venue</strong>: Zoom. The session will not be recorded.</p>
<p>If you sign-up and your availability changes, remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.</p>
<p><strong>Sign-up link</strong>: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N0CmlWTIsVX-dKRLEQp" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N0CmlWTIsVX-dKRLEQp</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8038-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lady-blackbird-one-shot-may-2/8038.rss">Lady Blackbird One-shot (May 2)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
