<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fever Dreaming Marlinko with Whitehack</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fever-dreaming-marlinko-with-whitehack/1843</link>
    <description>CW: Overly literal interpretation of consuming the body of Christ

We had fun exploring Marlinko last night. The PCs (and all the rest of the occupants of the city) had been kept awake by serious nightmares so they hadn&#39;t recovered enough HP to leave the city and continue their adventures. Instead they explored the city. First they went shopping, stocking up on oddly reasonably price magic items from the stall of a travelling Ogre Mage.

While they shopped it started raining blood.

They then moved on to the Church of the Sun God and the Blood Jesus where they were told that the Sun God would soon be reborn and they were offered to eat from the body of the blood Jesus and handed a plate of raw meat. They were told that humans are made in the image of the Sun God and that the meat was donated by a devout follower. The PCs left in a hurry.

Then they went to visit the tomb of the Marlinkan gods who founded this city with the creation of their own tomb. They too were supposed to return when Marlinko was the biggest city in the world. Did I mention that The Yellow City has just been wiped out by a tsunami? The magic users in the party could sense the power of the undead in the eight Marlinkan tombs.

They left the tomb and found that it is still raining blood. They decided that it&#39;s probably time to leave the city.

Running D&amp;D on Easter Monday gets weird quick.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 12:26:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fever-dreaming-marlinko-with-whitehack/1843.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Fever Dreaming Marlinko with Whitehack</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BrianAshford]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brianashford">@BrianAshford</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>CW: Overly literal interpretation of consuming the body of Christ</p>
<p>We had fun exploring Marlinko last night. The PCs (and all the rest of the occupants of the city) had been kept awake by serious nightmares so they hadn’t recovered enough HP to leave the city and continue their adventures. Instead they explored the city. First they went shopping, stocking up on oddly reasonably price magic items from the stall of a travelling Ogre Mage.</p>
<p>While they shopped it started raining blood.</p>
<p>They then moved on to the Church of the Sun God and the Blood Jesus where they were told that the Sun God would soon be reborn and they were offered to eat from the body of the blood Jesus and handed a plate of raw meat. They were told that humans are made in the image of the Sun God and that the meat was donated by a devout follower. The PCs left in a hurry.</p>
<p>Then they went to visit the tomb of the Marlinkan gods who founded this city with the creation of their own tomb. They too were supposed to return when Marlinko was the biggest city in the world. Did I mention that The Yellow City has just been wiped out by a tsunami? The magic users in the party could sense the power of the undead in the eight Marlinkan tombs.</p>
<p>They left the tomb and found that it is still raining blood. They decided that it’s probably time to leave the city.</p>
<p>Running D&amp;D on Easter Monday gets weird quick.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fever-dreaming-marlinko-with-whitehack/1843/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fever-dreaming-marlinko-with-whitehack/1843/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 11:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1843-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fever-dreaming-marlinko-with-whitehack/1843.rss">Fever Dreaming Marlinko with Whitehack</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
