<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184</link>
    <description>I have a group and their tired of my indie RPG/OSR antics. So, I&#39;m going to try running 5E for them. But none of my OSR dungeons are going to work. Any suggestions on 5E adventures?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 14:47:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I very much plan on running Ghosts of Saltmarsh.  It is written as separate adventures that you can string into a longer campaign and easily fit some of your own stuff into it. It is  also a pretty evocative pirate setting which appeals to me.  In addition, the book gives a large bunch of ways to tie the stories together and the characters to the locations.  Finally, it was build off at least partly on 1e adventures so presumably there is some OSR style built into the adventures.</p>
<p>As far as an official book of adventures (not a pure campaign - of which the Curse of Strahd is generally considered the best railroady campaign), this is generally considered the strongest 5e entry.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/34</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 14:47:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for the link! I hadn’t seen that!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/33</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 14:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@EricVulgaris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ericvulgaris">@EricVulgaris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah I saw it. the first post of it came out literally on day 2 of my marathon lol. I utilized it as best I could, like the changes for how to include Jarlaxle more and nimblewrights.</p>
<p><a href="https://thealexandrian.net/wordpress/41217/roleplaying-games/dragon-heist-remix-part-1-the-villains" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener"> link</a> for others who haven’t seen it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Will_H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/will_h">@Will_H</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Have you seen The Alexandrian’s remix of Dragon Heist? It is so extensive as to be its own book (as it abandons the whole seasonal enemy/plot thing and just makes it about an actual heist with multiple factions vying) but it’s very good reading.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/31</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hmmm…</p>
<p>About 10 years ago, I started prepping the 3.5 mega-adventure <em>Expedition to Castle Ravenloft</em>.</p>
<p>My initial read-through was very positive. I’d successfully run the original 1983 AD&amp;D module <em>I6: Ravenloft</em> a few times over the years, (a 3.5 conversion of the original was central to the revision), and thought that the build-out from there looked like a lot of fun!</p>
<p>But then I started reading it closely to prep for running it, I realized there were a LOT of glaring problems with it. First of all, it seemed to be a hodgepodge of various incompatible horror tropes thrown together, rather than an extended rumination on Gothic horror that I wanted to run. I spent a good month re-tooling it, and eventually gave up. I ran Paizo’s “Rise of the Runelords” adventure path instead.</p>
<p>From what you say, it sounds like <em>Waterdeep: Dragon Heist</em> might have the same issues of too many writers not pulling off a coherent whole!</p>
<p>Oh… and if I’d known ahead of time that becomming owners of a tavern was an integral part of the adventure, I would have brought in a very different character.</p>
<p>That said… I am still having fun!</p>
<p>Oh… and on Ravenloft… I have a copy of the 5e <em>Curse of Strahd</em>, and I think it’s a much better expansion of the original than was the 3.5 <em>Expedition to Castle Ravenloft</em>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/30</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 18:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@EricVulgaris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ericvulgaris">@EricVulgaris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My own unwanted two cents about dragon heist.</p>
<p>I arathoned Waterdeep: Dragon Heist in two days leading up to pax unplugged last year. Did the whole thing in about 20ish hours of play with 9 players.</p>
<p>I’m a pretty good dm and can handle so many players and all that and thank the gods I am because you will be doing so much heavy lifting to make sense out of that adventure. I’ve been running pre-written adventures since the Savage tide in dungeon magazine. I’m no stranger here to the format.</p>
<p>It feels like this adventure was mismatched or mismanaged and the final product has a hydra like design goal. like if the scope was a little honed in it’d be better. Right now it feels like 5 cool ideas but the best parts of them were left on the cutting room floor. I would not recommend that adventure to anyone old or new. It’s an anemic adventure to say the least.</p>
<p>Beware: there is no heist as written for the PCs, the game feels more like the ready player one of forgotten realms, full of winks and references to cool things and people but of little substance. There’s a lot of “hey look at this cool thing or person. It’s cool right?! <em>wink</em>” but the players don’t have a lot of fictional flexibility in the game. <em>no touching. Only look at how cool this was, PCs!</em></p>
<p>If you’re like me and like priming players and setting expectations, be aware that nowhere in that adventure does it declare a critical part of that adventure being you must be cool with owning a tavern and dealing with the classic FR factions. Those are a must to get any mileage out of this one.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/29</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 15:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, it sounds like the early discussions they’ve had about any potential 6E really focus on taking online/streamed play into account. I’m not sure how much they’ll incorporate from the indie world, or even how much they’ll change the rules (seems like they’ve kind of hit a good sweet spot between accessibility and complexity), but I have no doubt that the biggest lessons WOTC are learning are about online play. I’d love to see more integration with something like DnD Beyond from the get-go. It’s a pretty great tool, but it’s obviously an afterthought in many ways. If they build the system from the ground-up with online play in mind, the tools will be hopefully great from the start as well.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/28</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 21:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dolan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dolan">@Dolan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I really think they will. That and have integration for online play from the get go due to the popularity of D&amp;D streams nowadays.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/27</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 20:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dissonance]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dissonance">@Dissonance</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s kind of what I expected the result would be. I know there are a few other nods to indie games hidden in the rules of 5e. I’m curious if a 6th edition will take that any further.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/26</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 19:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s a variant listed in the DMG that adds “success at a cost” and “degrees of failure.” I was going to copy/paste the text but it’s a lot and I don’t feel great about copying over several paragraphs of copyrighted material. I will however share a couple of the examples offered for success at a cost. First, “a character manages to get her sword past a hobgoblin’s defenses and turn a near miss into a hit, but the hobgoblin twists its shield and disarms her.” Another is “a character fails to intimidate a kobold prisoner, but the kobold reveals its secrets anyway while shrieking at the top of its lungs, alerting other nearby monsters.”</p>
<p>I’ve used these variant rules in play in my last D&amp;D campaign that I ran (note I said “last” and not “most recent”) and … it was fine? But honestly, at the end of the day, trying to run D&amp;D in that way did largely feel in tension with the rest of the game, and I came to the realization that I would just rather be running Dungeon World. And I haven’t shaken that feeling since; I’ll still play D&amp;D as a player and have a great time, but I don’t think I’ll ever run it again. It really felt like I was trying to make the game do something it wasn’t meant to do, and I realized that thing is something I need in a game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/25</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 19:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dissonance]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dissonance">@Dissonance</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s absolutely not supported by the rest of the rules but apparently there is some text hidden in DnD 5e that essentially says " … and also the GM might sometimes rule a failure as a complicated success."</p>
<p>I’d really like to hear from some GMs who run with that permission and see what happens.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/24</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 01:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dolan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dolan">@Dolan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I personally feel the biggest issue with D&amp;D it’s it’s Binarity. I’ve adopted a “fail forward” approach for my own table. If you are between 1-5 away from your DC, yeah you don’t fail but a complication is introduced.</p>
<p>I also use passive investigation / perception a lot, Since it just expedites the discovery of clues.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/23</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 23:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I wrote…</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I have deliberately not purchased or read  <em>Waterdeep: Dragon Heist</em> , so as not to spoiler myself.<br>
That said: I’ve been pretty happy with this game so far! It’s an urban adventure, with a fair amount of city politics. It uses an alliance and reputation system, where each PC can become allied with an organization and gain reputation aboung its members. As one’s reputation increases, it’s possible to lean on the organization for resources or information.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our last session didn’t go so well, and it showed the limitations of running investigation-style play in D&amp;D. There were a couple of clues we missed because everyone rolled low on their “Perception” checks, and nobody had proficiency in the “Investigate” skill. We ended up flailing around going down blind alleys… I was getting bored, and our GM was getting a bit frustrated with us. Eventually, an NPC came along and pointed us in the right direction… which made me feel like our PCs were idiots.</p>
<p>Since my other group is playing a GUMSHOE game, I kept wanting to use an Investigative skill to automatically find clues, or to spend a point to just have the GM tell us what the clue means and where to go next!</p>
<p>In both situations, the GM is just telling us what’s next, but… in in GUNSHOE, the PCs figure it out, while in D&amp;D, the GM had to send in an NPC to bail out the party. VERY differnt feel!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/22</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 18:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dolan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dolan">@Dolan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m currently starting a campaign of Waterdeep: Dragon Heist, and I recommend that if you’re looking for a city-crawl campaign with plenty of downtime. Second to that I’d recommend Curse of Strahd or Lost Mines of Phandelver since those are solid adventures with clear goals and motivations for your players.</p>
<p>Princes of the Apocalypse is a nice hexcrawl, but can suffer from a lack of focus at the start.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/21</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 14:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Will_H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/will_h">@Will_H</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>He does a bunch of other fun adventures, but Wild Sheep Chase is my favourite. I ran a mini-campaign stringing together his adventures which capped off with the lvl20 adventure set at the end of time itself, using the party all plucked from moments before their deaths. That was a lot of fun too!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/20</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 23:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@EricVulgaris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ericvulgaris">@EricVulgaris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I heard complaints and friction around Zephyros and the sky castle/info dump portions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/19</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 19:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/ericvulgaris">@EricVulgaris</a> what are the problems with the story you’ve heard of? (Do we have spoiler tags here? Doesn’t seem like it …)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/18</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 18:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@EricVulgaris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ericvulgaris">@EricVulgaris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Great call <a class="mention" href="/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a>. I didn’t know that’s the author behind the city encounters in waterdeep but i adore that little supplement too.</p>
<p>For others wondering, SKT isn’t perfect. It’s far from it. I’ve heard some of the issues with certain parts of the game’s story as written. But as far as a product goes, it’s extremely mineable for other games as well. With so many locations and NPCs you cold easily deconstruct this adventure and turn it into a west marches sandbox. That’s a very useful product!</p>
<p>What’s really interesting here is that so little of WotC product design has changed since the 90s or even earlier. If you’re willing to deep dive, there’s great lists of adventures in Dungeon magazine and stuff. Now with Ghosts of Saltmarsh coming out to pair with Tales from the Yawning Portal, great 3e modules are seeing life again-- stuff like The Styes.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/17</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 17:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve run a group part of the way through SKT (before the group fell apart due to scheduling) and we had a blast. It’s a well-written adventure and I like it a lot. I enjoyed the more sandbox-esque feel.</p>
<p>For one-shots or dipping your toes in, I really enjoy the work of <a href="https://www.dmsguild.com/browse.php?author=M.T.%20Black" rel="nofollow noopener">M.T. Black</a>. I think he’s one of the best 3rd party D&amp;D adventure writers working right now. I actually strung together a series of his adventures (the “Triboar trilogy”) as a start to SKT, and it worked really well.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/16</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jamesdbr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jamesdbr">@jamesdbr</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The first D&amp;D adventure I ever tried to run was Storm King’s Thunder explicitly because it was a sandbox connected by a metaplot and I was hoping the group would go for a sort of Dracula Dossier play experience, it’s definitely a fun adventure!  I’m currently <em>playing</em> Curse of Strahd which from my limited POV has a ton of fun stuff in it, despite my character being more (entirely) suited to social combat than combat-combat.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/15</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 14:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@EricVulgaris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ericvulgaris">@EricVulgaris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve personally never read nor played this one, but Storm Kings Thunder is often touted in my circles as the best D&amp;D 5e product. In the sense that it’s a series of sandboxes connected by a metaplot. These folks are all pretty experienced dungeon masters so I certainly trust their opinions, but I’m not sure it’d be the best product for a newer dungeon master.</p>
<p>For that person, Lost Mines is still the best. Period.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/14</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 20:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Charlie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/charlie">@Charlie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We played that at Dice Saloon recently. It was good fun and a definite recommend for a one-shot.</p>
<p>Personally I still want to run a Bioware as heck Dragon Heist, possibly using that Witch+Craft sourcebook currently on KS to make it more pastoral (or I guess the city-based version of ‘pastoral’).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/13</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 18:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I have deliberately not purchased or read <em>Waterdeep: Dragon Heist</em>, so as not to spoiler myself.</p>
<p>Also: Our GM is known to modify published adventures to fit the PCs and our play-style, so some of what we’ve encountered may not actually be in the book.</p>
<p>That said: I’ve been pretty happy with this game so far! It’s an urban adventure, with a fair amount of city politics. It uses an alliance and reputation system, where each PC can become allied with an organization and gain reputation aboung its members. As one’s reputation increases, it’s possible to lean on the organization for resources or information.</p>
<p>While I am truly enjoying this game, I have a few critiques…</p>
<p>First, we seem to bump elbows with a LOT of published high-level NPCs. This is a personal bias of mine, but are first-level schmoes <em>really</em> going to be recruited by NPCs for whom the publisher’s game materials have been named? (E.g., we were hired by Volo…of the D&amp;D book <em>Volo’s Guide to Everything</em> fame.)</p>
<p>Loot levels seem very low… to the point that the PCs feel empoverished.</p>
<p>On a related note: The game seems to encourage the PCs to be murder-hobos by making it hard to be successful adventurers while following the law. For example, we’ve taken on a few “Patron missions” for which we didn’t get paid, but caused us to use resources. And later, when we were conducting an off-the-record investigation into criminal activity agaist our business, we found quite a bit of valuable treasure that we felt compelled to hand over to the city guards as evidence… which meat that we effectively lost it. (The GM said that this action increased our reputation with the City Watch, meaning that we can now count them as allies… but reputation doesn’t pay the rent!)</p>
<p>The game seems to assume that the PCs are interested in running a business. While this is kind of fun, I guess, I already work a full-time job, and don’t really want to play a game about hiring staff, HR issues, making payroll, and paying taxes. I do that in real life already! Sometimes, you just want to punch monsters in the face!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/12</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 17:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ClaytonStine]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/claytonstine">@ClaytonStine</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m actually interested to hear more about your <em>Dragon Heist</em> game. I wrote a half-lucid review for it some time ago, and I wasn’t overly positive about its usability/accessibility in information architecture and layout.</p>
<p>Mind you, I still had a blast playing it. Ended up running new players through it and had a very crazy finale with Mr. Infinity Gaunlet and Eyeball Basketball.  But I had to do a lot of heavy lifting to get it there.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/11</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 05:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Haladir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/haladir">@Haladir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m a player in a D&amp;D 5e group that’s running through <em>Dragon Heist</em>.</p>
<p>It’s a lot of fun, and isn’t one of those “all combat all the time” adventures.</p>
<p>One of the big sub-plots is that the PCs become owners and operators of a tavern. That’s not something I’ve seen in a published D&amp;D adventure before!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184/10</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 19:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-184-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/best-module-adventure-for-d-d-5e/184.rss">Best Module/Adventure for D&amp;D 5E</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
