<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037</link>
    <description>Continuing the discussion from [What rpgs were you most pleasantly surprised by in the last few years?](https://discourse.funtimers.club/t/what-rpgs-were-you-most-pleasantly-surprised-by-in-the-last-few-years/3002/18):

I&#39;m just spinning this off into a new thread because it&#39;s become off topic from the premise of the original thread. 

@Deckard wrote: &quot;It has s not the skills per se, more that this is pretty much all the basic game offers from what I can tell. Plus, Fate is clearly built with railroading in mind. I much prefer to play to find out what happens and get surprised, even as the GM.&quot;

I have to disagree that Fate was built with &quot;railroading in mind&quot;. While it has many features of a traditional RPG, it does offer baked in shared world-building, shared narrative, and starting at the place of &quot;describe what you want to do and THEN consult the rules to do that thing&quot; (Golden Rule). The Fate Fractal (Bronze Rule) lets you build almost anything you need in the game (organizations, weapons, magic systems, superpowers, vehicles, etc.) with the same pieces you use to build a character (Aspects, Skills/Approaches, Stunts, Stress, Consequences) which makes play easier and is where the system gets exciting for me. And you are always free to ignore the rules if they get in the way of what makes narrative sense (Silver Rule).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 18:29:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Huh, that’s super weird.  I’ve never actually read Fate Core, but accelerated basically just says this for difficulties:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Low difficulties are best when you want to give the PCs a chance to show off and be awesome. Difficulties near their approach ratings are best when you want to provide tension but not overwhelm them. High difficulties are best when you want to emphasize how dire or unusual the circumstances are and make them pull out all the stops.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Along with a sidebar about how different approaches might have different difficulties and some rules of thumb like “If you can think of at least one reason why the task is tough, pick Fair (+2)”.</p>
<p>More proof that Fate Accelerated is the best Fate game, I guess. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=9" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/36</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 20:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jco]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jco">@jco</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I read the fate core rulebook and have started a somewhat rules light fate game.</p>
<p>The aspects and fate points seems interesting. Somewhat reminiscent of burning wheel, in a good way. Curious to see how it plays out, but I like systems that use mechanics to encourage the group to play into the drama they’ve decided matters to their character.</p>
<p>Something I hated from the book though was how they recommended setting the values for skill challenges. They actively recommended against trying to be objective, and more aim for how hard you want it to be…I hate this! Pragmatically I get it, but then like…why bother with the skill pyramid at all if the GM is encouraged to be like “hrm, this should be a player skill-2 type challenge…” I think being aware of how skillful they are in crafting encounters etc is obviously good, but always anchoring off of their skills in that way really rubbed me the wrong way.</p>
<p>These days I find myself with little patience for skill systems I guess. I think this is an area where PbtA shines in comparison.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/35</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Manifest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/manifest">@Manifest</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Like it’s been mentioned before, you go with the Approach that best makes narrative sense according to the fiction the players are presenting. However sometimes more than one Approach can be argued to be triggered by the fiction. For example say I’m trying to blind a foe by throwing dirt in their eyes. We can argue that the best approach is Sneaky but one can make a case for Quick, Clever, Forceful, Careful, or even Flashy.</p>
<p>This is why I tell players that some Approaches may have a lower difficulty than others because they make more narrative sense in the story. Maybe your foe is a supernaturally fast creature so Quick might be an Overcome of +6 while Sneaky would be a +4 difficulty, or your foe can read minds making the Sneaky approach impossible because they know what trick you’re trying to pull.</p>
<p>I always try to tell my players the difficulty of an Overcome or Create Advantage action ahead of time so they can make an informed decision. I tell them that sometimes your character knows that what they’re trying to do is almost impossible so step back maybe Create some Advantages and try again when things are stacked in their favor.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 04:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You get a +3, two +2s, two +1s and a 0, so yes. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/33</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 22:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Presumably people often have a best and a good approach at least, so that they will have a choice of a couple of approaches for most situations? I’ll have to take a look at the FAE system resource document and read up what that says.</p>
<p>Cheers</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/32</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 21:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>To add to what <a class="mention" href="/u/airk">@Airk</a> said, by choosing one aspect,  e.g. ,Forceful you are in effect NOT being Sneaky. That should allow the DM (Dramatic Manager) to reign in spamming because always being loud &amp; Forceful is going to cause so many problems.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/31</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 06:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In my experience, people definitely ANGLE towards their best approaches, and that’s sortof the point.  I don’t remember the rules saying anything about certain approaches being verboten for particular circumstances, but certainly a bunch of them do seem obvious – forceful pairs poorly with subterfuge actions and careful pairs poorly with time sensitive situations. Clever can be more tricky to rein in.  But really, at the end of the day, if people can frame an action in a way that’s within striking distance of an approach, I’d let them do it.</p>
<p>This is a fiction first system, so you don’t get to say “I’m doing this cleverly” you have to describe what you’re doing and then pivot back to picking the approach that makes sense.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 20:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Does Fate Accelerated ever run into the problem where a player just spams the same approach for everything because it is their best one? Or is there a bit of table discussion (or even rules discussion) about some approaches almost never being valid in certain circumstances (forcefully sneaking perhaps??)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/29</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 20:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ah, okay, so a little less like Masks then.  Pretty close, but not quite the same, obviously.</p>
<p>The difference – a rather crucial one to me – between this method and Apocalypse World is that in AW, each rating is tied to specific actions.  Barring playbook specific moves, you don’t get to Attack Someone with +Cool;  This is not the case in Fate Accelerated – Forceful hacking can totally be a thing.  As a result, it feels more like “people try to do things the ways they are good at” instead of AW’s “people try to do the things they are good at.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/28</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Toby]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/toby">@Toby</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="26" data-topic="3037">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/airk/40/2435_2.png" class="avatar"> Airk:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>my impression of The Veil (Disclaimer: I haven’t read it) is that since your stats are kinda your emotional state (Kinda like Masks?) they change with some frequency?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>My understanding is that your states are constant. They describe how well you deal with each emotional state. You choose which one to use when you roll, but that doesn’t change them. (Exception: it’s possible to use one emotional state so much that it spikes, and then you get a penalty.)</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="26" data-topic="3037">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/airk/40/2435_2.png" class="avatar"> Airk:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>FAE, being a little more action-move-like, is more interested in “This guy is the Careful guy. He likes to do things methodically, and gets flustered and does badly if forced to do something Quickly. But this is the Forceful woman; She knows how to push through opposition and doesn’t back down, but she tends to be loud and unsubtle, so she does badly in situations where being Sneaky is called for.” archetyping.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is <em>just</em> like Apocalypse World and some other PbtA games, then… Your ‘hard’ is not a measure of physical toughness or anything like that, but more a measure of what kind of role you play in the story, and how you tend to deal with situations.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/27</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 14:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s not dissimilar to how things work in The Veil, though FAE Approaches are pretty static, whereas my impression of The Veil (Disclaimer: I haven’t read it) is that since your stats are kinda your emotional state (Kinda like Masks?) they change with some frequency?</p>
<p>FAE, being a little more action-move-like, is more interested in “This guy is the Careful guy. He likes to do things methodically, and gets flustered and does badly if forced to do something Quickly.  But this is the Forceful woman;  She knows how to push through opposition and doesn’t back down, but she tends to be loud and unsubtle, so she does badly in situations where being Sneaky is called for.” archetyping.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/26</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 13:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Toby]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/toby">@Toby</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="23" data-topic="3037">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/airk/40/2435_2.png" class="avatar"> Airk:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Fate Accelerated dispenses with skills entirely. Instead, characters have a short list of Approaches that they use, that answer the question not of “what are you doing?” (“I’m hacking the system!” “I’m punching the bear!”) but instead “How are you doing it?” – “How are you hacking the system?” “Well, honestly, there isn’t time for a lot of futzing around; I’m just going to brute force this. I don’t care if I leave a trail or what.” (Forcefully) or “How are you punching the bear?” “I don’t want to get into a bear hug or anything nasty, so I’m darting in and out, float like a butterfly, sting like a bee!” (Quickly) etc.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I’m not familiar with Fate but this is super interesting. Isn’t it the same idea, or similar, to how states work in The Veil (“I’m doing this angrily!” “I’m doing this confidently!”)? And, now I come to think of it, it also lines up with what I think is a reasonable interpretation of stats in Apocalypse World.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/25</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/airk">@Airk</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> that totally helped me differentiate between the two.</p>
<p>Now to actually try to run something in FAE (it sounds like it would be more along the lines of what I like to play these days).</p>
<p>Thanks.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/24</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 04:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The default assumptions of Fate Core is that characters have various skills at certain levels. You’ll probably have different skills for different games, but they’re going to be pretty much the usual style of stuff – “Hacking” or “Piloting” or “Rhetoric” or “Shaolin Kung-fu”.  Whatever. Skills. You know 'em. You’ve played a bunch of games that use them.</p>
<p>Fate Accelerated dispenses with skills entirely.  Instead, characters have a short list of Approaches that they use, that answer the question not of “what are you doing?” (“I’m hacking the system!” “I’m punching the bear!”)  but instead “How are you doing it?” – “How are you hacking the system?” “Well, honestly, there isn’t time for a lot of futzing around;  I’m just going to brute force this. I don’t care if I leave a trail or what.” (Forcefully) or “How are you punching the bear?” “I don’t want to get into a bear hug or anything nasty, so I’m darting in and out, float like a butterfly, sting like a bee!” (Quickly) etc.</p>
<p>It turns a lot of traditional assumptions sideways and makes for a very interesting game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/23</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 23:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaerdaph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The big difference between Fate Core and Fate Accelerated is that Core uses a list of 18 default skills (what you do) and Accelerated uses a list of six approaches (how you do it). This also affects how stunts are written since Accelerated doesn’t use skills, but stunts essentially work the same. There are some minor differences involving stress tracks and consequences. You can easily pull things from Core into Accelerated though. And vice versa - lots of Fate Core players import the Mooks and Groups of Mooks rules from Fate Accelerated into their games.</p>
<p>I really like the Fate build in Fate Freeport which is essentially D&amp;D converted to Fate Core. Instead of the default list of 18 skills though, it uses six skills each named after one of the traditional six D&amp;D ability scores. It’s a nice middle ground between Core and Accelerated.</p>
<p>As for actual play, there really isn’t much difference at all between Core and Accelerated. Accelerated is a nice choice when the PCs are going to have very similar roles like a police procedural for example; instead of everyone having the same or similar skill lists, they can each approach a task in different ways: one cop will Carefully interrogate a suspect, another will do so Forcefully, a third might do so Cleverly.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 23:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="17" data-topic="3037">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/manifest/40/2589_2.png" class="avatar"> Manifest:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Also I wanted to point out that I’m biased and much prefer Fate Accelerated rather than Core.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/manifest">@Manifest</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a></p>
<p>I have heard this multiple times, and I’ve never really understood it. Note: I have only played Mindjammer Fate (which I think was FC), and only for 2 sessions. So my Fate experience is very minimal.</p>
<p>I own both books however, and have read FAE and skimmed Core. Besides Core being “bigger”, what is the in-play experience difference?</p>
<p>Thanks in advance…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 22:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaerdaph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I admit it can look that way at face value. There’s a little more to it than that though. As mentioned previously, the compel should be some sort of complication that the player <em>wants</em> to see come up in the fiction. The rules also encourage negotiation between the player and GM (and the whole table even) of what the compel does and how it will look. After discussion with the player and input from the table and deciding the compel doesn’t make sense, a compel can also be withdrawn by the GM and cost the player nothing in Fate points.</p>
<p>Ultimately, if it is getting in the way of enjoyment of the game, then it should be dropped, and the rules cover this.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 11:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is the piece that still rubs me the wrong way: you either do what the GM says and get a Fate point or you say no and lose a Fate point. (And if you have no Fate points you just have to do what they say, yes?)</p>
<p>The agency piece there just doesn’t feel right to me…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 01:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaerdaph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I prefer Fate Accelerated as well but I do bring some things in from Fate Core. I also really like Fate Freeport which is basically Fate D&amp;D. It sits at a nice sweet spot between FAE and Fate Core with its limited skill set of six skills named after the six basic D&amp;D abilities.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/18</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 23:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Manifest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/manifest">@Manifest</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a></p>
<p>Yes that is correct about the two pools of Fate points. I just wanted to clarify that NPCs don’t have unlimited Fate points.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="16" data-topic="3037">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jaerdaph/40/1747_2.png" class="avatar"> jaerdaph:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>two examples each for how you might invoke your aspect, how your aspect might be invoked against you, and how your aspect might be compelled.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is a good role of thumb for Session Zero, which are a must for Fate just like some PbtA games.</p>
<p>Also I wanted to point out that I’m biased and much prefer Fate Accelerated rather than Core.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 23:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jaerdaph]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jaerdaph">@jaerdaph</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Welcome, <a class="mention" href="/u/manifest">@Manifest</a>!</p>
<p>I agree: the compels suggested for any aspect should be in tune with what the player had in mind for compels when they created that aspect. The compel is what the player felt would be an interesting negative situation for their character that they would like to see come up in play.</p>
<p>And actually a Fate GM has two pools of Fate points: a limited pool for NPCs to use in a scene (one Fate point per PC), and an unlimited pool for compels. That pool is unlimited to ensure that GMs can always give the players a chance to earn a Fate point by accepting a compel thus keeping the Fate point economy flowing.</p>
<p>I’ve also found when creating an aspect for your character, it is helpful to try and come up with at least two examples each for how you might invoke your aspect, how your aspect might be invoked against you, and how your aspect might be compelled.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/16</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 18:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Manifest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/manifest">@Manifest</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I usually just lurk on these forums but this topic prompted me to make an account. I’m a big fan of fate and I’ve been playing fate since spirit of the century and I wanted to just say a couple of things that sprung to me as I was reading these posts.</p>
<ol>
<li>GMs do not have an endless supply of fate points. For their NPC’s they get a pool of fate points equal to one fate point per player at the beginning of a new scene, and this is a pool of Fate points that is shared by all the NPC’s.</li>
<li>I don’t see compels as bribery to get players to do something they don’t want to do. First if it is something they don’t want to do then they can reject the compel. Additionally if I’m compelling a player aspect then I’m compelling an aspect that they created together with the table and it is something that they want to happen in game. For example if I create a character with an aspect such as “Haunted by Murderous Brother” then obviously that means that as a player I want that aspect to come into play for my character otherwise I wouldn’t have created that. I feel like this is very much in the vein of most Pbta games. For example in Dungeon World if I picked the Ranger as a playbook then that telegraphs to my GM that I will like to see at some point me be able to track or do something survival based.</li>
<li>My last point that came to mind, though I’m sure I have many more, is that fate to me can be very tactical. I think it’s very much like 16 HP dragon example for Dungeon world, in that a lot of Fate has to do with fictional positioning especially because of aspects. Aspects are facts things that are always true and as a GM I try to make sure to tell my players that simply just attacking over and over again won’t really do much in fate. My fate veterans know that in order for you to take down a powerful enemy you have to create multiple advantages, that one player can then invoke all together and deal a powerful blow. This means that most of our combats deal with my players trying to change the environment or tactically approach the enemy from a different angle.</li>
</ol>
<p>Now I agree that fate is not for everybody and I’ve run it for several people who have simply decided that it just wasn’t for them and that’s fine but I just want to make sure that we give a game a fair shake and not judge it based on misconceptions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 16:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@marden.muller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/marden.muller">@marden.muller</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>But then again, on the prep-heavy(-ish) vs. prep-light side of things, there is FAE to consider. Since I’ve never played it, I wouldn’t know how it actually fares in comparison, regarding the facilitation of predominantly improvised game sessions. Any thoughts?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 03:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Right.  And the whole, I want to play out story X sounds very on the rails compared to the PbtA improvisational gaming I have become accustomed to playing and reading.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 03:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@marden.muller]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/marden.muller">@marden.muller</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="3" data-topic="3037">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/deckard/40/2412_2.png" class="avatar"> Deckard:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>FATE tries to bribe players to do something they feel their characters would not or to take risks they as players generally would not. PbtA makes this happen naturally by adding risks to the 7-9 roll.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Even though I’m totally on the Fate fan corner in this debate, I think you may be onto something concerning this bullet point in particular, <a class="mention" href="/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> . Now, I agree with the repliers who pointed out that much of what in the Fate points economy appears appendant rather than ingrained in the rules is probably a result of how they are handled by the players. At the same time, however, there is an undeniable simplicity in PbtA’s having setbacks built into the 7-9 range for 2d6 rolls. It’s game design done elegantly as hell. So I understand how Fate’s expedient (exchanging tokens back and forth across the table to signify invoking and compelling, procedures that, one could argue, demand a good deal of burdensome Aspect tracking) can seem like a designer’s afterthought in comparison.</p>
<p>Frequently, Fate points, invokes and compels can be misused and, at least in my own experience as player and GM, they tend to be handled poorly during the first couple of sessions, when everyone is still getting used to the engine. But --and this should not be overlooked-- so do the [6 or lower/7-9/10+] tiers in PbtA die rolls. The fact that, in my own experience as GM, people usually have to ask for clarification regarding the use of Fate points during play while die rolls in PbtA games tend to feel more fluid and intuitive <em>to the same</em> group of players might be of some significance to the matter at hand. But I think it rather points to differences in gaming styles than to differences in design quality. PbtA’s design is, from the get go, addressing the recurrent necessity of players to be able to put together a session on the fly. It is a one-shot friendly engine and that’s an important part of its near-omnipresence in the indie scene; Fate Core, on the other hand, is comprised of elements that seem to encourage a good deal of preparatory worldbuilding, long games, and (relatively speaking, of course) the conservation of a modicum of “crunch”. And, of course, a certain amount of table prop thingies.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037/12</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 23:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3037-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fate-core-fate-accelerated-what-it-is-and-what-it-isnt/3037.rss">Fate Core/Fate Accelerated: What it Is and What it Isn&#39;t</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
