<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291</link>
    <description> &gt; More games with safety, diversity, and empathy built into the game itself.
&gt; &gt;Does anyone have any examples of games that do this?

So depending on which portion of the original statement there are lots of different examples.

1. Safety
a. The start is including Safety tools and safety tool discussions into the core texts of books. This includes things like, The X-Card, Script Change, Lines and Veils, Subject Matter Discussions,CATS, Same Page Tool, Open Door Policy, Debriefs, and others. Just having them in the core text helps to normalize them and the discussion that safety is part of the game.
b. Having the tools themselves worked into the game. Microscope has a section built in where the players include or exclude certain content. For the Queen has the ability to pass a card onto the next player, or just remove it from the game entirely. 
2. Diversity 
a. Urban Shadows - The ethnicity line has a bunch of options, but &quot;White&quot; is last, skewing the &quot;default&quot; else where. The setting of modern urban cities is also great, because we can see 2nd, 3rd (and further generations) of people and how their cultural background affects their modern experience without it being a foreign land, those PoC are here right now in familiar places too. I&#39;m half Japanese, but I can&#39;t speak Japanese, I&#39;ve never been to Japan, I probably know less about anime and other Japanese pop culture than a lot of other folks... but I do know about growing up looking different than others, having some different rituals and traditions at home, eating different food, etc. I personally wouldn&#39;t feel comfortable being the &quot;expert&quot; on ancient Japan, but I do know about being an Japanese American in California.
b. Games that have settings that are not just fantasy Europe. Thousand Arrows is about &quot;samurai action and tragedy in the Japanese Warring States Period&quot;, Mendez has a [great article on sensitivity, respect and appropriation](https://jamesmendezhodes.com/blog/2018/10/31/thousand-arrows-and-sensitivity-part-1). It&#39;s definitely worth a read.

3. Empathy
a. For me, I see this often in games with options or moves about being vulnerable, opening up to other characters, having character scenes or downtime scenes, that may not &quot;move the plot&quot; along.
b. Lady Blackbird&#39;s refresh scenes. Any &quot;Comfort or Support&quot; moves, like from Hearts of Wulin or &quot;Reach Out&quot; from Night Witches. One Child&#39;s Heart is all about empathy. The #sadmechjam contest basically had empathy built into the premise. So while I haven&#39;t looked at or played anywhere near all the 177 games that came out of it, I bet quite a few had empathy designed into them.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 15:57:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@klintron]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/klintron">@klintron</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I made a one-page <em>World of Dungeons</em>/Turbo game that tries to put much of what is discussed here into practice: <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1RdMdFeJ6Ss4dyGg4jxR4aLVqYMr87OLItlDUMQUxzUM/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener"><em>Be the Media</em></a>. (Consider this an alpha release at best.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/64">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/64</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 15:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-64</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@J.D.McAlistaerie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/j.d.mcalistaerie">@J.D.McAlistaerie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Solid article. Thanks for passing it on. Pretty much answers my questions above. I’ve bookmarked it for future and frequent reference. Will be passing it along to a few writer friends of mine too – the advice seems equally applicable to creating literary charcters with realistic cultural nuance and respect.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/63">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/63</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 03:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-63</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ClaytonStine]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/claytonstine">@ClaytonStine</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for this response. I’ve played more and more characters unlike myself lately, but I’m worried about implications I’ll be blind to because of my privilege.</p>
<p>I’ve done more of the Hobbes approach. Playing characters like Chris Washington’s in <em>Get Out</em> requires a much more in-depth discussion with the table.  I’m preparing to host a game of Harlem Unbound for my company, so I’ve been devouring articles like this in preparation because I think it’s clear I’ll be having one.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/62">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/62</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 22:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-62</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MagpieMark]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/magpiemark">@MagpieMark</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="60" data-topic="291">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/claytonstine/40/828_2.png" class="avatar"> ClaytonStine:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m a white cis gendered man and I found this <a href="https://jamesmendezhodes.com/blog/2019/2/14/may-i-play-a-character-from-another-race" rel="nofollow noopener">article </a> interesting. Could someone with a more diverse background than myself weigh in with an assessment? It seems very thoughtful to me.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I think this article is great! Mendez is always really thoughtful about this stuff, and I think this is a great place to start thinking about playing people across racial/ethnic boundaries. But I also think that Avery’s advice on queer characters is good here too: sometimes their queerness is really important and sometimes it’s a side note to all the other stuff that’s going on with the character.</p>
<p>Think about a character like Hobbes from the Fast and the Furious series. Yeah, The Rock is a big, brown dude with lots of thoughts about being a minority. But that’s not what that character is about in the story (mostly). He is just an awesome brown dude who kicks butt and takes names and loves his daughter.</p>
<p>Contrast that with the main character of Get Out (Chris Washington). The story and the situation mean that his “blackness” is central to the story. It’s what the whole story is about and so that actor needs to be able to play that character (and let’s not forget that Daniel Kaluuya is actually British, so there’s another level of ‘playing someone not like yourself’ going on there too.)</p>
<p>When I play a character of a different race, I calibrate what I’m bringing to the table based on what I really know about that culture and the markers that I feel comfortable using. When I play white people (which is me not playing my race!), I feel pretty comfortable saying a lot about the white experience. That’s much less true about playing someone who is from a First Nations group that I’ve never really interacted with in person.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/61">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/61</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 21:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-61</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ClaytonStine]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/claytonstine">@ClaytonStine</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m a white cis gendered man and I found this <a href="https://jamesmendezhodes.com/blog/2019/2/14/may-i-play-a-character-from-another-race" rel="nofollow noopener">article</a> interesting. Could someone with a more diverse background than myself weigh in with an assessment? It seems very thoughtful to me.</p>
<p>There are prejudiced people out there, but from my experience in higher education and creative advertising, there are a lot of well-meaning players who want to avoid harming others. In focus groups for commercial and product testing, subjects often change their behavior based on who is in the room, and I don’t mean they hide their prejudices, I mean they grow more cautious for fear of being wrong with the nuances of what they don’t know.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/60">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/60</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 05:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-60</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>From a game of Noir World I played, I’d say who introduces their character first may set the tone/diversity of the game. I asked out loud, “The Fatale playbook can be a male-presenting?” and when the answer was yes, Sven Fatale was born, and his actively stated pansexuality combined with the Fatale playbook took the chains off – I don’t think there ended up being a straight character (and there were 8 players) in the game by the end. And I honestly think it was because I introduced Sven first, making it clear that anything goes. I don’t actually remember what Sven looked like (skin color, etc.) except he was of course smoking hot.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/59">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/59</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 03:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-59</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@J.D.McAlistaerie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/j.d.mcalistaerie">@J.D.McAlistaerie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is great discussion with several related threads. I appreciate everyone’s thoughtfulness. There is an issue that we haven’t touched upon, but that has been foreshadowed:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="55" data-topic="291">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/magpiemark/40/834_2.png" class="avatar"> MagpieMark:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>And sometimes we just tell a story about four white people and their engagement with communities they don’t understand. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=6" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is really the crux of playing across racial/ethnic (or any other) boundaries, isn’t it? What does it mean to play a character of another race/ethnicity/gender/sexual orientation/religion, etc from yourself when you don’t have the experience of being a person with that identity in the world?</p>
<p>I am genuinely interested in hearing people’s experiences with playing characters having identities other than themselves (especially racial/ethnic) and how they embodied that race/ethnicity in the fictional world. What experiences did you call upon? Were there other players of that race/ethnicity at the table? If so, did you unintentionally give offense by playing into stereotypes or otherwise? If so, how was it handled at at the table?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/58">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/58</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-58</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rabalias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Wandering a bit off the main thread of the discussion so far, I wanted to talk about some advice I got recently about a PBTA move of mine. The move is about blowing off steam to reduce (game mechanical) pressure, and a potential 7-9 consequence of it is that you fall into someone’s arms. I had been thinking about the issues around consent in relation to who would decide whether this consequence arose, and who would decide the specifics (i.e. whose arms? what does “fall into the arms of” mean exactly?)</p>
<p>What I hadn’t thought of is the 6 result. I was all “this is fine, the MC will just make a Move, job done”. Until someone pointed out that this set up could easily prompt the MC to bypass your consent and my carefully crafted 7-9 results and have you wake up in someone’s bunk. The 6 or less set up lets you do that, and only your principles stop you doing it. But in this case, a well-defined 6 or less result could be an important way to protect consent, and therefore safety.</p>
<p>I wanted to share that example because I think it shows how building safety into mechanics requires some serious thought about each individual game component and the issues it might generate. Blanket tools are all well and good (and I’m a fan of such tools, of course), but there’s no way to shortcut that kind of detailed thinking.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/57">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/57</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-57</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rabalias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rabalias">@rabalias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I wonder if there would be a benefit to starting out discussing the ethnic (and other) groups in your setting? Like, it is literally impossible for a game designer to produce a list of all possible groupings you might want to cover, because you don’t know the context the gaming group is operating in, or the context they want the fiction to be operating in (which are two different things, right?)</p>
<p>So, start off with “what are the groups”. Then “and which of these will you be playing?”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/56">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/56</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 20:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-56</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MagpieMark]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/magpiemark">@MagpieMark</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="54" data-topic="291">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/oh_theogony/40/511_2.png" class="avatar"> oh_theogony:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>This is super interesting, <a class="mention" href="/u/magpiemark">@MagpieMark</a>! Now I’m wondering if my presence at tables makes straight, cis players more (or less?) likely to play queer or trans characters!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Maybe! I mean… I also sometimes just straight call it out. Like if I get a table of white players and they all play white characters, I may say “That’s interesting that you all chose white characters” and see how they react. Sometimes I can get one of them to say “Oh, I was going to maybe say Latinx, but… let’s do it!”</p>
<p>And sometimes we just tell a story about four white people and their engagement with communities they don’t understand. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=6" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/55">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/55</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 19:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-55</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@oh_theogony]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/oh_theogony">@oh_theogony</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>Contrary to <a class="mention" href="/u/oh_theogony">@oh_theogony</a>’s experience, I’ve seen lots of white folks play across race, but that may be because my identity authorizes them to do so. (I think if you look at Masks as a community, we’ve had even more success establishing non-white as the baseline.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is super interesting, <a class="mention" href="/u/magpiemark">@MagpieMark</a>! Now I’m wondering if my presence at tables makes straight, cis players more (or less?) likely to play queer or trans characters!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/54">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/54</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 17:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-54</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@klintron]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/klintron">@klintron</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I also tend to play white characters. I think it’s less a matter of worrying that I’ll fall back on offensive stereotypes as it is me not being confident that I’d do anything but play the character as essentially white, if that makes sense. Games like <em>Nauhaul</em>, where I have no choice but to play someone from a particular community, break me of this habit pretty well.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/53">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/53</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 17:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-53</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MagpieMark]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/magpiemark">@MagpieMark</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m definitely listening to all the criticism here about how the racial lists are presented in <em>Urban Shadows</em>! Both Drew and I felt it was kinda wild at the time to include anything like what we included, but clearly it’s just the start of a conversation about what it looks like to include racial content in a game. I always look forward to seeing folks come up with new and different solutions to this stuff.</p>
<p>Like Yoshi noted, the main thing that we were trying to do was to get people out of the default of playing only white characters. We saw how much both <em>Apocalypse World</em> and <em>Monsterhearts</em> had shaped expectations around playing across gender, and we hoped that we’d be able to do the same thing with race. Contrary to <a class="mention" href="/u/oh_theogony">@oh_theogony</a>’s experience, I’ve seen lots of white folks play across race, but that may be because my identity authorizes them to do so. (I think if you look at Masks as a community, we’ve had even more success establishing non-white as the baseline.)</p>
<p>But we also didn’t want to confuse “Look” with “ACTUAL RACIAL IDENTITY” and the compromise we struck seems like sometimes people think we’re actually asking people to choose their race instead of how they look. So it’s an imperfect solution. (For example, I would pick White and Latinx for my look, but I’m not sure that’s clearly communicated on a playbook!) I think some heritage stuff is a good move, but I also think that you’re basically going to get white people saying “Here’s my white heritage” and moving on with their day.</p>
<p>But I also hear what <a class="mention" href="/u/pedro">@Pedro</a> is saying about how NA-centric the list ended up. I feel the same way about all the guns we included in the game! <em>Urban Shadows</em> is definitely written with a US/NA focus, and anyone who is playing in London or Bangalore or Sydney is going to have to do some work to get the playbooks to fit their locale, both in terms of talking about race and guns and politics and other stuff. There’s a tension here between making the game evocative and making the game open. But the “other” line is definitely not an afterthought; we spent a lot of time trying to figure out how to make a list that tried to include everyone, and I’ll definitely make a note to the effect of “These categories are NA-centric, like all the guns!” if we ever do a second edition/reprint.</p>
<p>This is something I continue to work on. In <em>Cartel</em>, I don’t have racial pick lists. It makes no sense to impose those ideas on a Mexican setting. Miguel Ángel Espinoza has some really, really interesting options going on in <em>Nahual</em>, but it involves lists that I’m still absorbing, definitely stuff outside of my cultural wheelhouse. I thought about including them in <em>Cartel</em>, but they don’t seem like a great fit. In the end, I think I’m just going with “You’re all Mexican” and focusing on other details that make those characters human.</p>
<p>I think all of this is basically me saying “I’m trying to figure this problem out, but I think the issues raised are good ones.” I know that sitting at a table with white people means they are mostly going to play white people, but I also know that if I don’t push the issue (with a pick list or with a setting that demands everyone be Mexican, etc) then I’m not doing my job.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/52</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 16:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeremy_Strandberg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="46" data-topic="291" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/oh_theogony/40/511_2.png" class="avatar"> oh_theogony:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>What do you all think of this? “Fill in the blank with your character’s cultural heritage. This could mean any combination of race, ethnicity, nationality, tribal affiliation, and/or regional ancestry.”</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>How about just:</p>
<ul>
<li>Your people: ________</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/51</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 01:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That could work. I like blanks. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/sunglasses.png?v=6" title=":sunglasses:" class="emoji" alt=":sunglasses:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/50</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 22:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/yoshi">@yoshi</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="48" data-topic="291">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v3/letter/p/ea666f/40.png" class="avatar"> Parrish:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I spent a silly amount of time in the past explaining that RPG’s are not physically dangerous</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is interesting to me. I, personally, have not had to explain that RPGs were not physically dangerous, but I can see how that might be frustrating.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="48" data-topic="291">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/letter_avatar_proxy/v3/letter/p/ea666f/40.png" class="avatar"> Parrish:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>words and wording are important.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Absolutely. I think that “Safety” is a perfectly appropriate word. But that might be because I think emotional and mental well being are important and deserve similar level or attention as physical well being.</p>
<p>This brings me to another thought, I know there is some discussion about safety tools being clumsy because they bring you “out of the fiction” and how it might be nice to have more integrated in fiction tools. BUT I also sort of think of this as a feature not a bug. If someone is about to do something physically dangerous, I want to be able to warn them and I want them to know in a way that they will NOT interpret as an in game thing. For me, this follows through to emotional and mental safety. I want to deliberately stop the fiction and make sure we get everyone safe before continuing. The fact that it is jarring is kind of the point.</p>
<p>That being said, I do like gentler ways to handle things too, and those can be in fiction methods, but if some stuff is going really poorly I <strong>WANT</strong> an out of fiction method that can stop us and get us back to a safe place. This could just be, “Hey guys, I need to stop us, I cannot continue with what’s going on, can we talk about what’s making me uncomfortable?”, but that sentence is not always the easiest to get out, and it can be much harder depending on the person and their past experiences.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/49</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 20:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Parrish]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/parrish">@Parrish</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The term “safety”.  I spent a silly amount of time in the past explaining that RPG’s are not physically dangerous.  I think “well being” better describes it and is a synonym of safety.   I imagine a casual or curious person seeing this <span class="hashtag">#1</span> item and thinking, “oh my it’s dangerous”.  I am going to apologize to anyone who thinks I am splitting hairs, I can see that point of view, but words and wording are important.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/48</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 19:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@astralfrontier]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/astralfrontier">@astralfrontier</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I feel like it depends on the goal of the game. For example, why is a given game asking about ethnicity? Can a game instead ask “how does society view your character” or something like that? Sometimes a goal might be “make a nonwhite player feel welcomed” and nonwhite listings achieve that, but I’d still keep the larger goal in mind.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/47</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@oh_theogony]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/oh_theogony">@oh_theogony</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What do you all think of this? “Fill in the blank with your character’s cultural heritage. This could mean any combination of race, ethnicity, nationality, tribal affiliation, and/or regional ancestry.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/46</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dr_mitch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dr_mitch">@dr_mitch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Safety: There’s a good spread of safety tools in the games in Pelgrane’s Seven Wonders anthology. The Fate Horror Toolkit has lots about safety.</p>
<p>Diversity: I appreciate the fact that Urban Shadows pushes ethnically varied cities, like the big cities I’m familiar with, and not just playing as white people. I’m not 100% sure of every part of the implementation, but it’s generally good, and the fact it pushes it is pretty great.</p>
<p>Developed settings presenting a range of cultures and ethnicities are another good route. There’s not in my opinion quite enough of this in “real world” settings, whether present, or historical, or historical fantasy. I <em>try</em> to do this with things I write, and don’t always succeed.</p>
<p>Fantasy settings which step outside fake Medieval Europe, and science fiction settings involving people who are explicitly not just future Americans also add to the diversity of gaming in general. There are lots of these, and the best don’t fetishise the cultures involved…I’m thinking here of Capharnaum and Bastion for fantasy, and Coriolis for science fiction, but there are many more and we should all talk about them more. We should also talk about games from outside the English speaking world when we can.</p>
<p>Empathy: Bite Me! is great for this. A big part of it is about exposing your emotions, and bonding with your pack.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/45</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@oh_theogony]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/oh_theogony">@oh_theogony</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, maybe “cultural heritage” and a fill-in-the-blank?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/44</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 17:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dissonance]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dissonance">@Dissonance</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Speaking of experience: my experience has been that white people tend to play white characters more often when there are actual PoC at the table, for whatever reason. I have to assume it’s a comfort issue for them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/43</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 17:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Perhaps ask them what their heritage is. That leaves it pretty open, including allowing cultural shifts in concepts of ethnicity.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/42</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 17:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m game, that sounds interesting and useful.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/41</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 17:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@oh_theogony]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/oh_theogony">@oh_theogony</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In my current design project, despite having a very racially diverse set of NPCs, I don’t have a race question on the character sheets at the moment, because it turns out to be a very weird question when dealing with <em>time travel.</em> There’s an entire population in the game (Visigoths) who have arrived from the year 410 into 1996 – are they…white? Not according to the contemporary construction of whiteness? Should I ask everyone what continent(s) their ancestors are from?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291/40</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 17:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-291-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/examples-of-safety-diversity-empathy-in-games/291.rss">Examples of Safety, Diversity, Empathy in games</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
