<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>RPGs of 2012 Week 4: #ttrpgs2012</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rpgs-of-2012-week-4-ttrpgs2012/8177</link>
    <description>***Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood 2nd Edition***
The original of this came out in 2004, an early indie storygame. This version expanded that original slightly (44 pages vs 36), adding clarifications, new rules, contributions from notable game designers, and striking art. It would be successful enough to get both a German and Italian translation.

Intended to emulate the feel of campfire stories, it is set in a vaguely defined Colonial America. Actually the A24 film *The Witch* feels like a great touchstone for this. In the game itself, there’s a lot of backstory, legend, and atmosphere creation before you ever get to the mechanics. You’re over halfway before you get a whiff of that.

There’s a GM, the Watcher, and players, the Walkers, who define their characters vaguely through concept and motive. Resolution is simple. Throughout the game you gain cold token for shock. When you want to find out what happens, you roll a d6 and try to get above the number of tokens you have. You’re out of play when you get your sixth token. It’s simple, but it gets out of the way of the atmosphere which is what it is really about.    
https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/131424/dont-walk-winter-wood-second-edition

***Dungeon Crawl Classics Role Playing Game***
It is wild to me that DCC is only 10 years old. It feels like such an evergreen product. Goodman had done well through the d20 boom with a line of sourcebooks and the DCC adventure series. Plus games like *DragonMech, Etherscope*, and *XCrawl*. They shifted seamlessly over to D&amp;D 4e. BUt in 2011 they released the beta and starter for their own old-school system, *Dungeon Crawl Classics*, with the final version coming out the next year. This also shifted the DCC line of adventures over to the house system. 

DCC has garnered a committed following, in part based the strength of the ongoing DCC series. They’ve also established a strong, distinct art style with the work of Doug Kovacs. His use of color, the pulpy images with buried references, and the way Goodman Games has put his work front and center have made this one of the most recognizable lines in gaming. 

The other big concept to come out of DCC is the Funnel. Each player generates a random set of four 0-level characters. Then this horde descends into a dungeon to be slaughtered. A player can select a surviving character to advance to 1st level and make a standard adventurer. It’s a great concept which pokes fun at the genre and OSR conventions at the same time.   
https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/125109/dungeon-crawl-classics-role-playing-game

***Dungeon World*** 
Yesterday I was shocked that it had only been 10 year since DCC’s release. Today I’m shocked about *Dungeon World*. DW’s the PbtA rpg with the largest volume of add-ons, new playbooks, fan sourcebooks, and third party releases. Seriously– check for the DW system on DTRPG. 

It was also a PbtA game that sparked a ton of discussion about PbtA-style play and play in general. It emulates, for better or worse, the classic D&amp;D experience, with levels, damage dice, etc., but it allows for fast play and rich collaboration. 

DW’s among the really important first gen second gen PbtA games (along with MotW, Masks, MH). And our community wouldn’t be what it is without it. The Discern Realities podcast drew in a lot of people to us years ago.  
https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/129201/dungeon-world-roleplaying-game

***Durance***
A striking and potentially painful rpg, *Durance* has you playing two characters in a sci-fi penal colony. But the two occupy radically different positions in the hierarchy, Authority vs. Convicts and Top of the Ladder (Colony Leader, Criminal Overlord) vs. Bottom of the Food Chain (Conditionally free convicts, political prisoners). It has a great and quick system for building the colony and some interesting dice mechanics. It all feels very modern and it&#39;s a game that would feel modern if it was released today (with some safety discussion added).

*Durance* was one of the earliest rpgs I played online. It was a pick-up game from some of us on RPGGeek. I remember it distinctly because when we got close to the end, my upper hierarchy characters forced a Sophie’s Choice on one of the PCs. One of those moments which makes me thankful we have safety tools around commonly now. 

I liked the game enough to write and run an X-Men hack, a kind of Days of Future Past situation set in a Mutant Containment facility. It worked OK, but not great. 
https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/2014/09/durance-meets-x-men-days-of-future.html
https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/2014/10/durance-meets-x-men-days-of-future.html
https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/131757/durance

***Eldritch Skies (Unisystem)***
A near-future humanity against the Elder Gods rpg, released after a successful early Kickstarter and the winner of a Judge Spotlight ENnie. 

Now I heard a story about this particular version, which uses Unisystem (AFMBE, Buffy). This came from someone who worked with Eden Studios, created of Unisystem. All of this is allegedly and second-hand. But what he said was that the designers of *Eldritch Skies* had mentioned doing a game with Unisystem to them, but hadn’t followed up. The first they heard about the game was after its release and getting some attention. And at that point the folks from Eden apparently told them no. 

Hence you can’t find the Unisystem version for sale anymore, though a Savage Worlds version came out a couple of years later. I don’t know how true this is. And I had a contract with Eden which they never paid me for, so I may have an axe to grind. But it’s a story anyhow. 
https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/126958/eldritch-skies</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 19:13:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rpgs-of-2012-week-4-ttrpgs2012/8177.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>RPGs of 2012 Week 4: #ttrpgs2012</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em><strong>Don’t Walk in Winter Wood 2nd Edition</strong></em><br>
The original of this came out in 2004, an early indie storygame. This version expanded that original slightly (44 pages vs 36), adding clarifications, new rules, contributions from notable game designers, and striking art. It would be successful enough to get both a German and Italian translation.</p>
<p>Intended to emulate the feel of campfire stories, it is set in a vaguely defined Colonial America. Actually the A24 film <em>The Witch</em> feels like a great touchstone for this. In the game itself, there’s a lot of backstory, legend, and atmosphere creation before you ever get to the mechanics. You’re over halfway before you get a whiff of that.</p>
<p>There’s a GM, the Watcher, and players, the Walkers, who define their characters vaguely through concept and motive. Resolution is simple. Throughout the game you gain cold token for shock. When you want to find out what happens, you roll a d6 and try to get above the number of tokens you have. You’re out of play when you get your sixth token. It’s simple, but it gets out of the way of the atmosphere which is what it is really about.<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cf.geekdo-static.com/icons/favicon2.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/131424/dont-walk-winter-wood-second-edition" target="_blank">RPGGeek</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:319/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/1/12170494cbacf04320ba1d9e7669d1225c01e480.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="319" height="500" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/1/12170494cbacf04320ba1d9e7669d1225c01e480_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/131424/dont-walk-winter-wood-second-edition" target="_blank">Don't Walk in Winter Wood (Second Edition)</a></h3>

<p>Publisher Blurb:
Are you ready for a walk in the woods? 
Don't Walk in Winter Wood is a storytelling game of folkloric fear. Players take on the roles of hapless villagers who must enter a legend-haunted forest and uncover its sinister secrets. The...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
<p><em><strong>Dungeon Crawl Classics Role Playing Game</strong></em><br>
It is wild to me that DCC is only 10 years old. It feels like such an evergreen product. Goodman had done well through the d20 boom with a line of sourcebooks and the DCC adventure series. Plus games like <em>DragonMech, Etherscope</em>, and <em>XCrawl</em>. They shifted seamlessly over to D&amp;D 4e. BUt in 2011 they released the beta and starter for their own old-school system, <em>Dungeon Crawl Classics</em>, with the final version coming out the next year. This also shifted the DCC line of adventures over to the house system.</p>
<p>DCC has garnered a committed following, in part based the strength of the ongoing DCC series. They’ve also established a strong, distinct art style with the work of Doug Kovacs. His use of color, the pulpy images with buried references, and the way Goodman Games has put his work front and center have made this one of the most recognizable lines in gaming.</p>
<p>The other big concept to come out of DCC is the Funnel. Each player generates a random set of four 0-level characters. Then this horde descends into a dungeon to be slaughtered. A player can select a surviving character to advance to 1st level and make a standard adventurer. It’s a great concept which pokes fun at the genre and OSR conventions at the same time.<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cf.geekdo-static.com/icons/favicon2.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/125109/dungeon-crawl-classics-role-playing-game" target="_blank">RPGGeek</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:386/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/7/70d15ed858f085c32ae5fde000165ba6fc9b853c.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="386" height="500" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/7/70d15ed858f085c32ae5fde000165ba6fc9b853c_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/125109/dungeon-crawl-classics-role-playing-game" target="_blank">Dungeon Crawl Classics Role Playing Game</a></h3>

<p>From the publisher's website:


        You're no hero. You're an adventurer: a reaver, a cutpurse, a heathen-slayer, a tight-lipped warlock guarding long-dead secrets. You seek gold and glory, winning it with sword and spell, caked in the blood and...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
<p><em><strong>Dungeon World</strong></em><br>
Yesterday I was shocked that it had only been 10 year since DCC’s release. Today I’m shocked about <em>Dungeon World</em>. DW’s the PbtA rpg with the largest volume of add-ons, new playbooks, fan sourcebooks, and third party releases. Seriously– check for the DW system on DTRPG.</p>
<p>It was also a PbtA game that sparked a ton of discussion about PbtA-style play and play in general. It emulates, for better or worse, the classic D&amp;D experience, with levels, damage dice, etc., but it allows for fast play and rich collaboration.</p>
<p>DW’s among the really important first gen second gen PbtA games (along with MotW, Masks, MH). And our community wouldn’t be what it is without it. The Discern Realities podcast drew in a lot of people to us years ago.<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cf.geekdo-static.com/icons/favicon2.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/129201/dungeon-world-roleplaying-game" target="_blank">RPGGeek</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:334/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/6/638f3dc924cac5e5d246144b7a1ca1c1a07ba38f.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="334" height="500" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/6/638f3dc924cac5e5d246144b7a1ca1c1a07ba38f_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/129201/dungeon-world-roleplaying-game" target="_blank">Dungeon World Roleplaying Game</a></h3>

<p>From the product website: 

        Dungeon World is a world of fantastic adventure. A world of magic, gods, demons, Good and Evil. Brave heroes venture into the most dangerous corners of the land in search of gold and glory. You are those heroes....</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
<p><em><strong>Durance</strong></em><br>
A striking and potentially painful rpg, <em>Durance</em> has you playing two characters in a sci-fi penal colony. But the two occupy radically different positions in the hierarchy, Authority vs. Convicts and Top of the Ladder (Colony Leader, Criminal Overlord) vs. Bottom of the Food Chain (Conditionally free convicts, political prisoners). It has a great and quick system for building the colony and some interesting dice mechanics. It all feels very modern and it’s a game that would feel modern if it was released today (with some safety discussion added).</p>
<p><em>Durance</em> was one of the earliest rpgs I played online. It was a pick-up game from some of us on RPGGeek. I remember it distinctly because when we got close to the end, my upper hierarchy characters forced a Sophie’s Choice on one of the PCs. One of those moments which makes me thankful we have safety tools around commonly now.</p>
<p>I liked the game enough to write and run an X-Men hack, a kind of Days of Future Past situation set in a Mutant Containment facility. It worked OK, but not great.<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/2014/09/durance-meets-x-men-days-of-future.html" target="_blank">ageofravens.blogspot.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:638/335;"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2c9e921a9fbc29619f46321e8270303348bcc16e.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="638" height="335"></div>

<h3><a href="https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/2014/09/durance-meets-x-men-days-of-future.html" target="_blank">Durance Meets X-Men: Days of Future Passed: An RPG Hack (Part One)</a></h3>

<p>CAMP X  Durance  is an rpg about space penal colonies. It is smart, generally diceless, and narrative-focused. I’m going use that to run ...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/2014/10/durance-meets-x-men-days-of-future.html" target="_blank">ageofravens.blogspot.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/362;"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/e/ef57ffa6e54458a251718943d9e04dd6aacd1712.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="690" height="362" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/e/ef57ffa6e54458a251718943d9e04dd6aacd1712_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://ageofravens.blogspot.com/2014/10/durance-meets-x-men-days-of-future.html" target="_blank">Durance Meets X-Men: Days of Future Passed: An RPG Hack (Part Two)</a></h3>

<p>PAST FUTURE OF DAYS  Here's the second part of the reskinning I'm doing to Durance  to make it fit with superpowered gulags. You can see ...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cf.geekdo-static.com/icons/favicon2.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/131757/durance" target="_blank">RPGGeek</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:333/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/6/64efd86b19bf2bd82e0fc8352682963891497616.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="333" height="500" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/6/64efd86b19bf2bd82e0fc8352682963891497616_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/131757/durance" target="_blank">Durance</a></h3>

<p>Publisher blurb:

On a remote planet orbiting a distant star...
...the worst criminal scum from a dozen star systems have been dumped, charged with building new lives under the watchful eye of Authority. Within a brutal hierarchy of savagery and...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
<p><em><strong>Eldritch Skies (Unisystem)</strong></em><br>
A near-future humanity against the Elder Gods rpg, released after a successful early Kickstarter and the winner of a Judge Spotlight ENnie.</p>
<p>Now I heard a story about this particular version, which uses Unisystem (AFMBE, Buffy). This came from someone who worked with Eden Studios, created of Unisystem. All of this is allegedly and second-hand. But what he said was that the designers of <em>Eldritch Skies</em> had mentioned doing a game with Unisystem to them, but hadn’t followed up. The first they heard about the game was after its release and getting some attention. And at that point the folks from Eden apparently told them no.</p>
<p>Hence you can’t find the Unisystem version for sale anymore, though a Savage Worlds version came out a couple of years later. I don’t know how true this is. And I had a contract with Eden which they never paid me for, so I may have an axe to grind. But it’s a story anyhow.<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cf.geekdo-static.com/icons/favicon2.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/126958/eldritch-skies" target="_blank">RPGGeek</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:389/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/7/7049d3017a142edccd8bc09cbb2926ef2d4438e2.jpeg" class="thumbnail" width="389" height="500" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/7/7049d3017a142edccd8bc09cbb2926ef2d4438e2_2_10x10.png"></div>

<h3><a href="https://rpggeek.com/rpgitem/126958/eldritch-skies" target="_blank">Eldritch Skies</a></h3>

<p>Publisher Blurb:

It is 2030. The Gilman-Hawking drive has given us access to the stars. But we are not alone.

They're out there: aliens, gods and monsters. They're also down here. The Miskatonic Antarctic Expedition found the elder ones' city in...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rpgs-of-2012-week-4-ttrpgs2012/8177/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rpgs-of-2012-week-4-ttrpgs2012/8177/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 15:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8177-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rpgs-of-2012-week-4-ttrpgs2012/8177.rss">RPGs of 2012 Week 4: #ttrpgs2012</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
