<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416</link>
    <description>In the design I have been noodling around in my head for a while, I like the idea of borrowing the Dramasystem approach of having scenes as the basic unit of play, so players ( or the GM ) will set up scenes and then we play them out.

The basic elements I have for the set up are:

* Where the scene takes place
* When the scene takes place
* Which characters are in the scene
* What the establishing character hopes to get out of it.

This is mostly codifying standard stuff, I think, but unlike Dramasystem this is a game with stats, moves, playbooks and dice ( I&#39;ve been thinking PbtA as I know that fairly well but I&#39;m not married to it ) and I feel like there might be *something fun* about having an &quot;establish scene&quot; type dice roll at the start of a scene ( why yes, we have been playing *Swords Without Master* how can you tell? ) 

The problem is I can&#39;t think of what would be the most interesting way to make it work - the obvious thing to me is that the roll gives a resource that you use in the scene. I have thought of these:

* The roll giving a number of tokens you can spend on full or partial successes through the scene, replacing dice rolls altogether or the total number of dice available to be rolled through the scene.
* The roll giving number of dice rolls you can make before you take penalties during the scene or conferring advantage/disadvantage a couple of times during the scene based on the initial result.
* The roll a number of dice rolls that, if hit during the scene, allows you to mark XP
* The roll affects the position of the scene  in a Blades style Controlled/Risky/Desperate kind of way. 
* The roll gives a number of dice rolls before the PC loses control of the scene ( perhaps something like the way Ironsworn uses Momentum as a resource )
* The roll defines which XP triggers are available to you ( this is along the SWM tone approach but offers a nudge to the player&#39;s direction, in a game where players have more personal or group driven XP triggers available. )

It needs to be fun and not too complicated, but I feel like it is also an opportunity to give the players the opportunity to feel clever by making good use of it, to help create a degree of tension in scenes and to keep scenes from dragging on. It seems to me that there is something there, but I&#39;m not sure what is the most interesting avenue to take things down and given that this is one of the places where players would most routinely interact with the games systems it also needs to be easy to pick up and play..

Are there any of these ideas that stand out to you, or is there something that you think would work better for this?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 22:22:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was thinking of before every scene because I want a scene to have a very clear boundary and transition, a marker between time-in and time-out that is unambiguous for the whole table. This thread has really helped me to clarify that what I’m really interested in, at the simplest level, is having something that shows us what the risks are during the scene. It could almost be as simple as “on a success you have an extra resource you can call on, on a failure the character you are petitioning/confronting/the environment has an extra resource it can call on” kind of balance. This could also offer fun guidance as GM - this seems like a relatively simple scene ( often if a scene has low stakes it might not be worth playing out ) but with the players failing their opening roll, we now know there is some looming threat that will come into play during the scene.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/36</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 22:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bengrayawhile]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bengrayawhile">@bengrayawhile</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Would you want this to be a roll before every scene?</p>
<p>If this was a roll reserved for more climactic scenes it could be something along the lines of how many unknown threats/elements/opportunities are available for the players to take advantage of. Perhaps this is a roll that accumulates through play?</p>
<p>Say for instance your characters are preparing for a heist. In previous scenes players may have been casing an area for later. If they failed in that roll you might make note to add dice to the “Establishing” roll later on.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/34</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 17:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is something I have been thinking about in terms of some types of scenes being almost like their own mini game, somewhere on the line between Firebrands games and the way duels happen in Burning Wheel. Fundamentally it’s something I like, but I need to get this core scene format down first and figure out the default configuration…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/33</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 22:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My game Leadtown does that in a very limited way.  Basically,  a character gets 2 moves to start.  One strong and one weak and they really give color and do exactly what you suggest.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/32</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 14:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Fascinating topic!</p>
<p>Would it help or hinder to have different moves for different types of scenes? Either based on the character’s goals (“When you try to make someone do what you want”) or the type of action in the scene (“When you’re in a car chase”).</p>
<p>My thinking is that this could help make the stakes more clear and perhaps genre specific, especially if you have PbtA-style picklists.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/31</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 10:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is a really interesting question, I think that it is character outcome that interests me more, so the goal is to favour that, but I hadn’t framed it in those terms so it helps me clarify what I’m aiming at.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/29</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 22:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think it’s important to be clear if you wish to have uncertainty (dice roll) from player perspective (i.e. narrative authority) or from player <em>character</em> perspective (i.e. character “success” or outcome).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/28</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 21:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think that is part of what I like about rolls, also that moment of suspension, of potential at the table when the dice are in motion. What happens if it goes wrong? To me that uncertainty is fun and definitely something I want to keep in the game, also it reflects the unpredictable flow of life, I think when characters are working more collaboratively than in opposition to one another it provides a source of drama and failure, taking a little weight off the GM in that regard.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/27</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 22:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>On tokens vs roll : tokens are unforgiving levers of all or nothing. The gamefeel is very much Mastermind. Rolls are easily disclaimed as random. They feel more in sync with the flow of action, with only a second or two of wonder.<br>
For preparedness, tokens. For the upper hand rolls.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/26</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 16:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>How do you find that stuff like this effects immersion?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These sorts of mechanics usually do pull players out of the immersion.  I am hoping to reduce this in my game Leadtown with a mechanic where the player with the largest bet for a hand declares what their character’s motivation in the scene. Then, players in the scene also get a little bonus in scenes when they use another character’s nickname in a scene.</p>
<p>I am hoping this structure and incentives transition the players unconsciously from the meta-game back into character immersion.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/25</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 04:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="CrudelyDrawnSwords" data-post="23" data-topic="5416">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/crudelydrawnswords/40/1576_2.png" class="avatar"> CrudelyDrawnSwords:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>while you have control of the situation you start with more flexibility, but as things run badly within the scene a possible failure cost would be losing control of the situation so the next scene begins worse.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Not entirely related but I love the idea of mechanics for advantage <em>debt</em>. IE you demand an advantage now that gives yourself or others a negative currency which will hurt you later.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/24</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:46:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is interesting too ( following up on both your and <a class="mention" href="/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a>’s observations ) I wonder whether there might be a larger structure at play about the position in the narrative, too, perhaps the roll I’m thinking of here is less useful than a degree of narrative control that perhaps varies based on the fictional positioning, behaving somewhere between the position in <em>Blades</em> and momentum in <em>Ironsworn</em>  - while you have control of the situation you start with more flexibility, but as things run badly within the scene a possible failure cost would be losing control of the situation so the next scene begins worse.</p>
<p>If anything the problem I’m having here is that there are a lot of super-interesting ideas flying round and it’s going to be very tricky to figure out what will work best. I’m stomping through the other components of the game in the hope of getting some kind of rickety but playable framework together to test it out.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/23</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 23:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="pizzazzeria" data-post="17" data-topic="5416" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/pizzazzeria/40/3845_2.png" class="avatar"> pizzazzeria:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>How do you find that stuff like this effects immersion?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Part of my thinking is that I feel that this could be more immersive - by having a clear delineation between the metagame setting up the scene and the in-character play once it begins, the scene itself feels like it should be able to be less encumbered by the structures of the game.</p>
<p>My roleplaying origins are very much in LARP where you have the concepts of time in and time out, but you also end up having the intermediate <em>time-ish</em> state where you’re sort of in character but someone is sorting out something mechanical so you can’t get on and do what you actually want to do right now, or it’s technically after time-out but everyone wants to keep playing their characters and you end up kind of balanced on the IC/OC fence. A lot of tabletop games feel to me as though they happen in time-ish, which is fine - that is often a good time -  but I am really interested by the idea that marking those boundaries could create a different atmosphere.</p>
<p>Definitely influenced by the way Dramasystem works as well - that does a great job of keeping the structures of the game out of scenes, but to put it in crude terms I tend to enjoy PvE rather than PvP types of game ( of course there is a lot of crossover anyway ) and so I’m interested in taking some of that dynamic and experimenting with moving it into a more traditional adventure-story type environment.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/22</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 23:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="pizzazzeria" data-post="17" data-topic="5416">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/pizzazzeria/40/3845_2.png" class="avatar"> pizzazzeria:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>How do you find that stuff like this effects immersion?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>It’s not the play style (or result) one is after when playing with these kind of mechanics. The “fun” should instead be about being immersed in the story (or group building).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/21</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 16:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Even if we keep scene mechanics character focused, that can still be another lever by which we roleplay. If we were to make “scene preparedness” a stat, it could fit neatly into the superhero genre for “mastermind” type characters, heroes or villains.</p>
<p>In regards to your second comment, I think dice and tokens both have benefits. A token system ensures that all players get an equal amount of scene influence, but a random check both adds variance and lets players exert different levels of influence.</p>
<p>For example, in a post-apocalyptic survival game, having scene influence fluctuate emphasizes the disempowerment and need to always consider retreat. You never know when things will be stacked against you.</p>
<p>Alternatively, in a heist game, having “scene control” be a stat means players that enjoy setting traps or creating infiltration routes can specialize while players that prefer responding to surprises get more points to raise other stats.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/20</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 13:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a>, personally I’d find it important that dice don’t determine the <em>amount</em> of narrative authority (here, token economy seems fairer) but rather the <em>flavor</em> of narrative authority.<br>
For example. cards or dice rolls could determine if you are allowed to introduce new character, location or other plot element.</p>
<p>Also, haave you looked at Archipelago III? The Fate cards might be interesting.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/19</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 10:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="pizzazzeria" data-post="17" data-topic="5416">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/pizzazzeria/40/3845_2.png" class="avatar"> pizzazzeria:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I find meta-things like engagement rolls and mechanics tied to scenes position players more as editors or screenwriters than as the characters themselves.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Well games like these with scene framing authority sure put players more in a “screenwriter” position. Some like playing like this, some players prefer staying focused on “their” character.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/18</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 10:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pizzazzeria]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/pizzazzeria">@pizzazzeria</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>How do you find that stuff like this effects immersion? I’ve played more DnD and PbtA than Blades in the Dark, but I find meta-things like engagement rolls and mechanics tied to scenes position players more as editors or screenwriters than as the characters themselves.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/17</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 08:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What I’m interested in is having some random element - having a roll at the start would probably take the place of having dice rolls during the scene so it gives you a certain amount of currency to spend during it rather than rolling moves. I quite like the need to improvise and the sense of risk that having a random element introduces.  In a way <a class="mention" href="/u/deckard">@Deckard</a>’s card approach is really good for this- you have your cards for the scene but you get to choose how and when to use them - it’s random but restricted and you still have a lot of agency on how you use it in play.</p>
<p>Using it like an engagement roll at the start of the scene also gives you an opportunity to decide how complicated things are as the scene begins and have that clearly on the table, fictional positioning is going to be most of the game and that is definitely more interesting to me when there are some unexpected or unpredictable elements to it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 22:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree with beepeegee.  Tokens to spend or collect to determine which character has an narrative advantage seems like a good way to handle this.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/15</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 04:38:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m still trying to understand what would be the benefit of dice rolls in establishing a scene. I’d probably stick to a token economy to keep things fair.<br>
I could imagine dice roll to for random tables related to scene framing.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 22:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That was a hell of a wall of text I posted!  I’m glad someone got through it!  <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"><br>
Sounds like you see the idea, if not the particulars of my game and examples.</p>
<p>The other nice thing about using card games that finish at the end of the deck is that it helps with pacing.  Faro is always 25 hands long.  If we are done with 13 hands and but we have already played for more than 90 min, I should pick up the pace.  This helps when running one-shots or games at conventions.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/13</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This sounds complicated (as someone who has never gambled!) but it’s also really clever and super in-keeping with the theme of an old-west game, I bet if that was a paradigm of play I understood it would fit together nicely. Having it run as a hand works really well too in terms of the size of the scene and the wider context of the game. This has definitely given me some thoughts on how an initial roll could set up a dice pool.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/12</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 23:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I have found that if A) characters’ Ambitions and the game themes are built tight enough AND<br>
B) The stakes of a scene and the PCs included in a scene are decided mechanically,<br>
then determining your 1st, 3rd, and 4th bullet points is easy.  Personally, I don’t have a gimmick for the start positioning of a scene.  I don’t think it is really needed.</p>
<p>In my Old West rpg Leadtown (which is currently in draft) uses a scene as a unit of play. Mechanically, the game runs with the archaic gambling game of Faro with some built in cheats. Faro is like Roulette but with an extra suit of Spades as the wheel and with most bets pushing to the next hand rather than losing.  Each hand represents the introduction and resolution to a scene.</p>
<p>The size of the bet controls the level of stakes.  The character’s Ambition and the card hand suggest the theme, and what the establishing character hopes to get (and from whom).  Then, the player chooses what their character wants in this scene using everything above plus the character’s archetype and background to fill in the details of the scene.</p>
<p>The way a scene starts is that any players with bets on the two cards in the hand (the winner and the loser) are included in the scene.  The theme of the scene is determined by the gamblers from the two suits in the hand (hearts = relationships / influence, diamonds = investments or gambling, clubs = violence, and spades = authority).  The stakes of the scene are represented by the size of the bet.  If the gambler has a large wager in the second half of the game, the scene will be a critical one.  (Bet maximums prevent the game from peaking in the first half).</p>
<p>The scene is set in an appropriate location considering the theme from a random list of locations in the town.  So, let’s say, the character being played is the gambler archetype.  The Ambition of this archetype is to defeat the reigning card champion in town in a gambling game and take the thing most important to the old champion.  Here are a couple examples of how a scene could go down in this system.</p>
<p>Just before the scene starts the player running The Gambler decides what they want to get from the scene in order to move towards accomplishing their Ambition or perhaps supporting another character in getting accomplishing theirs.</p>
<p>Now let’s say The Gambler is in a scene with a serious bet placed in the second half of the game and the suit chosen between the two cards is Diamonds, then The Gambler is allowed to resolve her Ambition in the scene and attempt to defeat the old champion in a card game at the saloon.</p>
<p>Now let’s say the timing of the hand is near the beginning of the game, the chosen suit is Hearts, and the bet is only $5 -10 (10 -20% of start $), The Gambler player should suggest something with much lower stakes, for examples:</p>
<p>*The player states she wants The Gambler to gain an ally in a future game against the current Champ, where she will hopefully get the advantage of free drinks or signalling when she finally plays the Champ.<br>
*The player states she wants to ask someone in town to introduce The Gambler to the current Champ and thus be able to set up a later scene to accomplish her PCs Ambition.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/11</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 20:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CrudelyDrawnSwords]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crudelydrawnswords">@CrudelyDrawnSwords</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is really helpful - I had come to the <em>Engagement Roll</em> as the general model too, and this is a good angle on it.</p>
<p>I like the idea of the mechanical push to help drive the story - the design I’m working on is purposely open to telling a lot of different kinds of story, but the type of character that is being played should drive that - so it could be like the engagment roll approach based on “how do you plan to achieve this goal” and/or “how important is the goal of this scene to you?” I can see this being a good way to establish the size of a clock required to achieve their goal, but I’m not a huge clock fan for reasons I have never quite understood, so I’m trying to think of something that appeals to me more.</p>
<p>As I think about it, this feels to me like the central mechanic for the game in play, so I really want to get it right. I guess the answer is probably to try and slam something together and playtest it to see what works or doesn’t…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416/10</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 23:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5416-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/mechanically-defining-a-scene-as-a-unit-of-play/5416.rss">Mechanically defining a scene as a unit of play</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
