<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pasión de las Pasiones - Cambiar Las Estaciones Quarterly</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-cambiar-las-estaciones-quarterly/6192</link>
    <description>**NUMBER OF SESSIONS:**  13 sessions total, being able to attend each session is strongly requested, you must RSVP to each session.
**DURATION:**  3 hours
**NUMBER OF PLAYERS:**  2, seats are reserved for Bethany Harvey and Maria Morabe
**CONTENT WARNING:**  This game  *may*  include violence and how it can affect a life. If players consent, there may be themes of romance/sexual tension between player-controlled characters, and/or player and GM-controlled characters, but anything more explicit than a passionate kiss or embrace will be veiled. It may include separation or divorce. It could, if  *all*  players in the session give  *enthusiastic*  consent, include characters coming out and how people in their life react to it (both positively and negatively), or how that happened in the past and helped make them who they are today. It will explore aging and what happens as we age, and may include characters becoming disabled. It will explore relationships and how we try to support, sustain, and maintain them, as well as what happens to relationships when we neglect them.
**-------------------------------------------**
Players will assume the role of residents in Ciudad Soñando in their late teens and early 20s.

Each month will jump forward in time a few years to tell a longer-term story about how these characters change and mature, from the fumbling steps toward adulthood in the late teens and early 20s to old age, exploring what happens at these stages of life, what we know and learn, and how we grow. If players are unable to attend a session and someone else joins, they will be introduced as someone who met the other players at the current stage of life, while the other character’s absence may be characterized as some form of estrangement, divorce, moving elsewhere for work, etc. If players need to miss a session, they’re encouraged to describe what their character is doing at that time of life that called them away.

Players should keep in mind that they may not resolve something in each month - it may be a relationship issue, a character struggling to come to terms with some integral aspect of who they are, and so on; it may pop up in a future session, it may be a regret of theirs. We’ll quickly revisit relationship questions at the beginning of each session to see if characters want to change them (or if player attendance requires a change).
**-------------------------------------------**
**SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:**  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet&#39;s Community Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html
**RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:**  12/13/2020, 19:00 Central Time
**SET UP INFO:**  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the series starts.
**BREAKS:**  2 five minute breaks
**RECORDED:**  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube (eventually; everyone knows I&#39;m slow with that stuff).
**PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:**  No experience required, rules will be taught
January
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrc7q8WjefMcvih-jC
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrc9cw4-FUUmS54afh
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcAjYcrQbDWHcSEEG
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcBlXPT4Cc8DsQfY8

February
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcCkE8exJPxLI4Qu2
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcDnlYuDQ1Az4lpB8
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcEmuu-BsJJ7RyHXD
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcG7MQ5BNhe8nQASZ</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 16:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-cambiar-las-estaciones-quarterly/6192.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Pasión de las Pasiones - Cambiar Las Estaciones Quarterly</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>NUMBER OF SESSIONS:</strong>  13 sessions total, being able to attend each session is strongly requested, you must RSVP to each session.<br>
<strong>DURATION:</strong>  3 hours<br>
<strong>NUMBER OF PLAYERS:</strong>  2, seats are reserved for Bethany Harvey and Maria Morabe<br>
<strong>CONTENT WARNING:</strong>  This game  <em>may</em>  include violence and how it can affect a life. If players consent, there may be themes of romance/sexual tension between player-controlled characters, and/or player and GM-controlled characters, but anything more explicit than a passionate kiss or embrace will be veiled. It may include separation or divorce. It could, if  <em>all</em>  players in the session give  <em>enthusiastic</em>  consent, include characters coming out and how people in their life react to it (both positively and negatively), or how that happened in the past and helped make them who they are today. It will explore aging and what happens as we age, and may include characters becoming disabled. It will explore relationships and how we try to support, sustain, and maintain them, as well as what happens to relationships when we neglect them.<br>
<strong>-------------------------------------------</strong><br>
Players will assume the role of residents in Ciudad Soñando in their late teens and early 20s.</p>
<p>Each month will jump forward in time a few years to tell a longer-term story about how these characters change and mature, from the fumbling steps toward adulthood in the late teens and early 20s to old age, exploring what happens at these stages of life, what we know and learn, and how we grow. If players are unable to attend a session and someone else joins, they will be introduced as someone who met the other players at the current stage of life, while the other character’s absence may be characterized as some form of estrangement, divorce, moving elsewhere for work, etc. If players need to miss a session, they’re encouraged to describe what their character is doing at that time of life that called them away.</p>
<p>Players should keep in mind that they may not resolve something in each month - it may be a relationship issue, a character struggling to come to terms with some integral aspect of who they are, and so on; it may pop up in a future session, it may be a regret of theirs. We’ll quickly revisit relationship questions at the beginning of each session to see if characters want to change them (or if player attendance requires a change).<br>
<strong>-------------------------------------------</strong><br>
<strong>SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:</strong>  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet’s Community Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a><br>
<strong>RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:</strong>  12/13/2020, 19:00 Central Time<br>
<strong>SET UP INFO:</strong>  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the series starts.<br>
<strong>BREAKS:</strong>  2 five minute breaks<br>
<strong>RECORDED:</strong>  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube (eventually; everyone knows I’m slow with that stuff).<br>
<strong>PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:</strong>  No experience required, rules will be taught<br>
January<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrc7q8WjefMcvih-jC" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrc7q8WjefMcvih-jC</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrc9cw4-FUUmS54afh" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrc9cw4-FUUmS54afh</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcAjYcrQbDWHcSEEG" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcAjYcrQbDWHcSEEG</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcBlXPT4Cc8DsQfY8" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcBlXPT4Cc8DsQfY8</a></p>
<p>February<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcCkE8exJPxLI4Qu2" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcCkE8exJPxLI4Qu2</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcDnlYuDQ1Az4lpB8" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcDnlYuDQ1Az4lpB8</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcEmuu-BsJJ7RyHXD" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcEmuu-BsJJ7RyHXD</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcG7MQ5BNhe8nQASZ" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNrcG7MQ5BNhe8nQASZ</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-cambiar-las-estaciones-quarterly/6192/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-cambiar-las-estaciones-quarterly/6192/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 16:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6192-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-cambiar-las-estaciones-quarterly/6192.rss">Pasión de las Pasiones - Cambiar Las Estaciones Quarterly</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
