<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Alien Dark - GCOG: The Distress Signal</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-gcog-the-distress-signal/5616</link>
    <description>This session was organised as part of the Gauntlet RPG Community&#39;s Open Gaming Weekend (GCOG) (https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/).
The crew of the USCSS Omestra are woken from hypersleep by a distress signal from Mine Station Durin. Cartwright, the Corp Rep, insists they need to confirm there isn&#39;t a problem, even when the station claims the signal was sent in error.  She, along with Chief Engineer Littigan, Navigator Levalia and Science Officer McRea take one of the shuttles down to the mine to &#39;dot the I&#39;s &amp; cross the T&#39;s&#39;.  There&#39;s a shady senior executive, a worried colonial marshall, and their own Science Officer not telling the truth ... then this wierd crab like things drops on the bar in front of Littigan ...

https://youtu.be/D_fHrNhqI70</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 06:37:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-gcog-the-distress-signal/5616.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Alien Dark - GCOG: The Distress Signal</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This session was organised as part of the Gauntlet RPG Community’s Open Gaming Weekend (GCOG) (<a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/</a>).<br>
The crew of the USCSS Omestra are woken from hypersleep by a distress signal from Mine Station Durin. Cartwright, the Corp Rep, insists they need to confirm there isn’t a problem, even when the station claims the signal was sent in error.  She, along with Chief Engineer Littigan, Navigator Levalia and Science Officer McRea take one of the shuttles down to the mine to ‘dot the I’s &amp; cross the T’s’.  There’s a shady senior executive, a worried colonial marshall, and their own Science Officer not telling the truth … then this wierd crab like things drops on the bar in front of Littigan …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="D_fHrNhqI70" data-youtube-title="Alien Dark - GCOG: Distress Signal" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-gcog-the-distress-signal/5616/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-gcog-the-distress-signal/5616/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 06:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5616-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alien-dark-gcog-the-distress-signal/5616.rss">Alien Dark - GCOG: The Distress Signal</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
