<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132</link>
    <description>*The forest holds many treasures. Some of the most important ones are not made of delicate gold or carved marble. Rather, they are harvested, ground, mixed with various other herbs, and used as potions, poultices, or poisons.* 

@jasoncordova and I are putting together a standalone book for the Trophy RPG (the game and its many expansions are currently featured in each new issue of Codex). One of the things we’re going to do with this book is include numerous tables that help flesh out the world Trophy takes place in. Keeping with the spirit of Trophy as a community project, we’re going to be crowdsourcing many of the elements that go into these tables. We already have a number of these crowdsourcing threads underway, any of which you can still contribute to. They can be found in this master list:

&gt; https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-crowdsourcing-master-list/3011

For this installment, we&#39;re exploring the strange substances concocted from parts of the forest. We&#39;re looking for one type of contribution:

**Elixirs, tinctures, and herbal remedies discovered in the Forest of Kalduhr**

NOTE: Please avoid anything that feels like sexual predation or that is misogynistic in nature. We won’t print such things.

You can submit as many entries as you wish. By submitting here, you agree to let us use your contribution in the Trophy standalone book and PDF (you will be credited as a contributor). Submissions should be fairly brief (just a few sentences). Here are some examples:

&quot;Praised by innkeepers and despised by musicians, the deep violet berries of the whisperbush plant cause a temporary deafness when ingested.&quot;

&quot;Found growing along just one rocky stretch of the Naveh River, the tendril-covered sunburst mushroom must be harvested using metal gauntlets. Failing to do so is a painful mistake, as the mushroom voraciously consumes virtually any organic matter it is put into contact with.&quot;

&quot;The pale green stonefruit known as The Duchess&#39; Delight was the first plant from the forest to find a home in the fine gardens of Ambaret. Not only did it thrive as a cultivated plant, its soft, sweet flesh began providing an additional benefit. When fermented and distilled, the Delight emboldens the drinker, reducing fear, anxiety, and inhibition.&quot;

![potion-1249050_1920|333x500](upload://tdo3mycwNcXYzDP7mYCg9UuLEoK.jpeg)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:49:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Leonardo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/leonardo">@Leonardo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Crooked Apple is absolutely indistinguishable from any other apple, if anything it looks like a particularly tasty-looking one. In the first few bites, it tastes incredibly delicious. However, after a couple of minutes the mouth is engulfed in the most vile and foul taste ever experienced, which persists for weeks. This awful taste is described as thousand rotten carcasses left under the sun for months, Barsul sewers or even the smell of hell itself. It grows among normal apples only in Kalduhr, but a shady guild of merchants sells them to anyone with enough gold. How they are able to distinguish them from regular apples is a guarded trade secret and to this day their enterprise keeps cursing the rest of the world with this vile fruit.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/29</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 10:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ostrichmonkey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ostrichmonkey">@ostrichmonkey</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Blackvein is a cordyceps fungus that infects and grows inside blood-drinking insects. When it matures, the fruiting bodies spring dense and tangled from the body of the insect; a rich, dark, blood-pudding black. A skilled herbalist or apothecary can prepare a viscous liquid by filtering and denaturing the mycelia, removing enough of the toxins and spores to render it safe to imbibe. The liquid grants strength and endurance allowing one to push their body well past its breaking point. But if not prepared properly, the same black fungal strands that grow within the body to grant that strength begin to warp the mind. Infecting the brain and driving the user to consume blood and flesh.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 20:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@steinea]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/steinea">@steinea</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Sullivan’s Ichor</strong>. One pulverized rosehip, one vial of milkwood sap, one spoonful of saliva, and three drops of scholar’s ink, mixed together in water boiled over fire, will produce Sullivan’s Ichor. Those who imbibe this decoction will discover that they can read any writing placed before them–at the cost of whatever language they spoke prior to its consumption.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/27</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I original read this as [quote=“Joshua_Kershaw, post:25, topic:4132”]<br>
Yellow King’s Crown can be refined from the rare mutated golden PUPPIES<br>
[/quote] and I wasn’t sure to be creeped out or confused <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 19:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_Kershaw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_kershaw">@Joshua_Kershaw</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yellow King’s Crown can be refined from the rare mutated golden poppies that hide among their pastel cousins in the deeply isolated, hollowed glades of the Forrest of Kalduhr. They emerge only after a rain  bathed in moonlight. It is thought to increase one’s creativity. Coveted by less talented artists or those seeking a way to wrestle free of a creative slump. But does the inspiration come from within or without?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 17:31:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Lavender at the edge of the Old Kalduhr forest is famous for its pleasant smell and as the primary component of any local sleeping potion.</p>
<p>The local soft cheese sometimes include bits of wild sage. While delicious, it also works as a salve that can be applied to heal wounds faster.</p>
<p>Nearby taverns are known to muddle orange dandelions gathered from the forest into the mead when the adventurers return from the forest and ask to forget the terrifying experiences they survived.  It appears to work as these adventures return time and time again with more ghastly stories.</p>
<p>Milk thistle is a strange plant with purple flowers on top. When ground up and swallowed with the forest river water, it has been known to provide travelers with the ability to see in the pitch dark of a moonless woodland night.</p>
<p>The tiny perennial blue starflowers that grow between the weeds of the dark woods are known to prevent any illness, especially illnesses of the mind.</p>
<p>The bright orange nasturtiums to the east side of the trail are not to be trifled with!  Many have mistaken them for edible flowers only to realize their skin flakes off with a mere brush against the petals!</p>
<p>Grey oak bark scrapings from the massive trees in the middle of the forest are sometimes boiled with goat milk to create an elixir that hardens the drinker’s bones to withstand any blunt attack.</p>
<p>What devil spawn dosed those travelers with the tincture of yellow ivy!  Now they speak the evil infernal tongue!</p>
<p>The benzoin gum of the rare albino pine is so sticky that explorers apply it to leather gloves in order to free climb cliff faces and explore the caves of the forgotten peoples.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 23:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gabe">@Gabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>The Cinnamon Rose</strong> is little more than a legend, but the legend is powerful. They say that the pollen of this brown, desert-growing, flower can help a traveler go for days without water. Many a traveler have met their fate in search of this rose.</p>
<p><strong>Slipberries</strong> are nearly indistinguishable from blueberries until they are struck by moonlight when they glitter like sapphires. If a skilled alchemist concentrates the pigments in the berry’s skins, and boils those pigments with a sufficiently strong whiskey, they can create an elixir that grants temporary invisibility.</p>
<p>The fruit of a <strong>Silversap Pear</strong> tree is a sight to behold. The pear itself is a bland brown, however, when sliced open, the juice runs out like quicksilver and the seeds glitter like diamonds. Silversap Pear seeds are a good replacement for diamonds and the juice can be distilled into a very fine brandy rumored to bring all manner of luck.</p>
<p><strong>Granitewood</strong> is the hardest and densest wood that is known, but it only grows in the oldest forests and it grows extraordinarily slowly. A granitewood arrowhead or blade can pierce the strongest armor, and a door made of granitewood will outlast an army.</p>
<p><strong>Corpse Blossoms</strong> are a dingy looking flower. None will argue that. These small, wilted, grey-brown blossoms only grow where people have died and been left to rot naturally. When their essence is extracted into a precisely measured elixir, they can induce a temporary death-like state. The desired time can be calibrated based on the level of concentration and the imbiber’s size.</p>
<p><strong>Bluecap Mushrooms</strong> are unexpectedly common, so common that for a long time no thought was given to uncovering unusual properties. As it happens, the compounds that turn the mushrooms blue can be harvested, refined, and processed into bright blue inks that enable potent arcane enchantments.</p>
<p><strong>Fateweaver Lichen</strong> is a remarkably hearty thing. While it is difficult to find it has been seen in nearly every climate save the hottest deserts. When dried and powered, this substance can be smoked. If a user smokes just the right amount, it is said that they can see gain accurate premonitions of their future. Proper dosage can be difficult to calibrate and an overdose can be deadly.</p>
<p>Young shoots of the <strong>Flameleaf Fern</strong> are highly prized for their incendiary qualities. If their oils are extracted at just the right temperature, the extraction can be ignited to devastating effect. Unfortunately it requires a great quantity of these shoots that can only be harvested in the early spring.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/23</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>“The dew from a morning hopper,<br>
placed top a coin of fine copper,<br>
Add blood of a foal,<br>
And swallow it whole,<br>
A remedy for anything proper.”<br>
-The Unreliable Guide to This and That by Crezorg, Goblin pauper</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/22</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 17:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Maiden’s Youth is a thick, putrid sludge, which is rumored to give everlasting youth to those with a strong enough stomach to consume it daily. No one has a credible account of having experimented with the dosage, however, as it’s brewed from the highly illegal Hag’s Foot Fungus, a green foot-shaped tree ear which is both a potent narcotic and powerful hallucinogen.  The magistrate who pushed the legislation outlawing the fungus later retired amidst a foul scandal, when his wife disappeared and he sent his very young daughter to an asylum.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/21</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 08:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>(This is apparently now my daily exercise)</p>
<p>Homer’s Tobacco is, as the name might suggest, a leafy plant, with broad purplish leaves that give off a sticky resin when bruised or broken. It is pleasant when smoked, and dilates the perception of space and time, making hours pass like seconds, and kilometers pass like meters. It is therefore popular among nomads, especially those driving caravans cross country. Experienced users, however, will smoke it in shifts, as the impossibility of perceiving the real passage of time and space makes navigation impossible.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/20</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 05:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Lady’s slipper moths pollinate the giant lady’s slipper flowers, which bloom once a year in a stunning display of vibrant fuschia petals. While many think that the name “lady’s slipper” comes from the color and shape of the flowers, some know that the moths themselves actually make excellent slippers, allowing the wearer to move silently with ease as their footfalls are cushioned by the iridescent dust of the moths’ wings. However, this only works with freshly harvested moths, which means sliding your naked feet directly into the insect digestive juices. A few fabled burglars have ended their career by wearing said slippers a little too long while hiding from unanticipated attention.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 22:35:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You know you’re close to a patch of Dhoraldoldurl, or Imp’s Scale, when the bottoms of your feet begin to tickle and pop. The more experienced traveler knows the bony protrusions sprouting from the arms and legs are painful but will eventually fall off harmlessly. Only a true expert could brew the leaves however, into a hard and bitter drink to mutate flesh and expand bone.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/18</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 21:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@erdosain81]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erdosain81">@erdosain81</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Becomer flower’s exquisite violet petals, when properly rinsed, are highly sought out throughout the land; Carelessly plucking and carrying the whole flowers though is a dreaded act. The sages of Old Kalduhr say that Becomer pollen grains breathed in by two or more different hosts pit the hosts into a vicious competition; The creature that serves the ways of the Forest the best will survive; The loser or losers will slowly turn into a replica of the Winner creature. The exact frequency, nature and duration of the Becomer test is not widely known, though it is suspected that the 4 seasons themselves bend to the will and the whims of the Becomers. It is said that bees in the Forest were all different creatures before getting into contact with the Becomer Mother, a tree-sized flower breathing and expanding in the heart of the Forest. Some even say that fairies and homonculi are a variation of this competition, a cruel fate forced upon unsuspecting consumers of a forbidden Becomer potion, or upon careless herbalists too entranced by the Becomers’  violet petals to cover their face.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/17</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 19:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Dragonflies flit in the low brush throughout much of the swampier parts of the woods, their emerald bodies having some value in pigments and as decoration. However, occasionally, you will find a virulent yellow morph. These blond dragonflies are more vicious than their green counterparts, and the famous lepidopterist Augusta Shane has proven that they can subsist entirely on human blood. What is only rumored, however, is that eating these blond dragonflies can give you the ability to digest raw meat and smell blood yourself.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/16</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 17:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/signalstation">@signalstation</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Only young children from affluent families waste their time with Silver Begin-Again, a narrow-leafed deciduous plant with a bark that, when brewed and ingested as a tea, gives one the immediate impression that one had <em>just moments before</em> finished ingesting the tea. And yet the cup is full. Botanists say the temporal distortion is wholly chemical and passes quickly, but it’s a rite of passage for some (apparently) to sit and giggle at tea cups at least once on the path to adulthood.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/15</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 07:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Murkwine is brewed only by a collective of hirsute monks, living in dens at the edge of the Great Forest. No one outside of their collective has been able to divine the recipe, although its earthy taste suggests that mushrooms are a primary ingredient. Ingestion of even a small amount will induce a pleasant long-lasting intoxication; as such, it can be found for sale at most festivals. Lesser known is its combustive effect; it forms a large and oppressive cloud of smoke when burned, and a molotov made from the stuff provides excellent cover for the enterprising criminal.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/14</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 22:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Witch’s moss, which grows only in the shade of rowan trees which have been struck by lightning, is delightfully soft, and emits colorful sparks when gently stroked. It tastes foul, but ingesting it raw will cause your eyes to glow with similar sparks, and give you the ability to see at night. When boiled into a tea, it is a powerful hallucinogen, and is reputed to be the base ingredient for many spirit journeys.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/13</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 20:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Balm from bell shaped root of Bola Roka plant has long been used as a cure for all sorts of skin problems (acne, warts, eczema - you name it) by those who claim to be witches and warlocks. What’s not often touched upon is that it only makes skin <em>appear</em> to be healthy, with effects fading in a matter of hours and root cause exacerbated with each application of the balm. But sometimes this is exactly what you need.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/12</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 11:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/signalstation">@signalstation</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Beware the hospitality of hunters</em>, they say, <em>when traps are empty</em>. Travelers, roamers and cavesteaders have a rich shared lore, knowledge of the road. One of their cautionary tales is of poor folk, lured by a warm fire and the company of hunters, ingesting food or drink dosed with Houndmaker. A tincture of <em>donum altumfamii</em> (a white flower with black seeds), Houndmaker induces drooling, paralysis of the upper limbs, a sensitivity to scents, and a savage hunger. Those dosed are then pressed into service by the hunters to chase wildlife, desperate to feed, for as long as the effect lasts or until something living is laid low.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Crafted in secret by black market alchemists and prized by thieves and savvy merchants alike, a quick snuff of Gleaming powder causes one to temporarily smell gold. Its precise formula and quality varies widely, however, and side effects are common. Many are the tales of Gleam users who vanished into the dark places of the world, hoping to quench their unrelenting thirst for riches.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/10</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 23:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The eggs of giant forest birds which stalk the undergrowth of the Kalduhr are prized for their rich yolk, used in the brewing of Glow Nog. Spiced and sweetened, one sip grants renewed fortitude and bright eyes to travelers of dark paths. Take care to drink it sparingly, lest your glowing vitality become a beacon to the hungry spirits of the forest…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/9</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 05:41:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Apricot Sunrise is a gnarly orange root found under the oldest fruit trees in the Levasti valleys. It is said if the root is ground down and boiled with Beetroot and Onion, the drinkers can share dreams, visiting each others minds. Those who drink the soup too often may find themselves taking on the fears or dreams of those they share with.</p>
<p>A vial of Glistening Harmony will cure a lack of desire, be it apathy for work, verbal interaction, or bedroom endeavours. The mix consists of Mint Leaves, Silver powder, ripe Blueberries, some Chalk, and Honey from a hive over 6 years old. The correct recipe is one of the most sort after items in Naganeh, though several fake recipe’s are floating around that may lead to frequent bathroom visits.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/8</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The blue phoenix, <em>Dolorem azul</em>, is famously found roosting at the apex of conifers that have been stripped of their needles by some force. The bird itself is gamy, with stringy meat and generally unpleasant taste. However, the feathers, when pulverized, produce an irridescent pigment that can be mixed with human sweat to form a paint. Applying this paint directly to skin causes the painted area to become nearly invisible for a few minutes. Legend has it that ingesting the feathers raw has a longer, more complete, effect, but no one has reported success with this method; indeed, few have been willing to try.</p>
<p>Dracule’s carrot is a vibrant orange tuber that grows plentifully near crossroads, often identified by the similarly colored astaraceae flowers that bloom from the stems. It is delicious prepared most any way: sweet and nutty. Much like the common carrot, consuming too much of it causes the pigment to diffuse through your skin, tinging your flesh distinctly orange. However, this pigment is uniquely photosensitive, and becomes toxic when exposed to direct sunlight. As such, these carrots should only be consumed if you plan to travel exclusively at night.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/7</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 18:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There is a mushroom known as prohibolor, or colloquially as corpse fungus. It is putrescent purple, with a notable stench, and can often be found growing near rotted remains. Common wisdom is that the fungus can be used to form a poultice after being masticated into a paste. When applied to a bloody wound, the poultice will block pain completely. It is a remedy only used in dire circumstances, as, if the poultice is left on the wound for more than a few minutes, the wound will begin to fruit with similarly colored mushrooms.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/6</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 18:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>“The tincture is pungent and sweet to the nose, an acerbic flavor to the tongue, clear and blue to the eye. Its effects, unpleasant but occasionally useful, change with each new moon, growing more volatile the more cycles it’s seen.”<br>
– From a fragment of parchment torn from “Mog’s Guide to Fluids”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132/5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4132-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-elixirs-tinctures-and-herbal-remedies-from-old-kalduhr/4132.rss">Trophy: Elixirs, Tinctures, and Herbal Remedies from Old Kalduhr</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
