<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsterhearts 2 - Bad Influences</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-bad-influences/8265</link>
    <description>![Cal1|563x376](upload://imtVflSLCjisVnL4OKiSadJEuPr.jpeg) 

This is a 5 session series of [Monsterhearts 2 by Avery Adler](https://buriedwithoutceremony.com/monsterhearts). Being able to attend every session is ideal, but not required. You should RSVP to each session you wish to attend. No prior experience with the game is necessary. All rules will be taught.

**CONCEPT:** Monsterhearts 2 is a PbtA game about the messy lives of teenagers who are secretly monsters. It explores the terror and confusion of having a body that is changing without your permission. The monstrosity of these characters is literal: they are vampires, werewolves, witches, and more. But their monstrosity is also allegorical, standing in for experiences of alienation, shame, queerness, and self-destruction.

**AIM:** Everyone shares the same agenda: make each main character’s life not boring, keep the story feral, say what the rules demand, and say what honesty demands. It’s about exploring relationships and internal strife. While not exactly player-versus-player, it is certainly a game where characters hurt one another, make mistakes, and navigate social fallout.

**TONE:** Imagine a teen supernatural romance with elements of horror. The tone may move between comedic and serious, but melodrama will always be the constant. Media touchstones include Buffy the Vampire Slayer, Vampire Diaries, and The Chilling Adventures of Sabrina.

**SUBJECT MATTER:** Monsterhearts 2 explores some difficult themes: dysfunctional relationships, teen sexuality, coercive power, trauma, abuse, violence, and queer marginalization.

**SESSION LENGTH:** 3.5 hours.

**NUMBER OF PLAYERS**: 4 (a seat is being reserved for Max Airborne.)

**RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME**: 08/03/2022 - 17:00 Pacific time

**SET-UP:** We will use Zoom for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links and resources. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in play and we will use Lines and Veils and the [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg), as well as [Script Change](http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m) for safety tools.

*Images used for this event listing are by [Apriorii](https://www.deviantart.com/apriorii)*

[S1 - October 2, 2022](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8REfjVKnu9UkOTGMgt)
[S2 - October 9, 2022](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGTFtrRcZoIyQ48xq)
[S3 - October 16, 2022](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGaY3Ya-B2hhCL3x0)
[S4 - October 23, 2022](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGk0x-zxiatNeFBEm)
[S5 - October 30, 2022](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGxCisII5Y3nConrW)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 03:02:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-bad-influences/8265.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Monsterhearts 2 - Bad Influences</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blackfey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blackfey">@Blackfey</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><img src="//gauntlet-discourse-store.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/8/80b1bd8d521b560b4651364e4f7e27471d0d385d.jpeg" alt="Cal1" data-base62-sha1="imtVflSLCjisVnL4OKiSadJEuPr" width="563" height="376"></p>
<p>This is a 5 session series of <a href="https://buriedwithoutceremony.com/monsterhearts" rel="nofollow noopener">Monsterhearts 2 by Avery Adler</a>. Being able to attend every session is ideal, but not required. You should RSVP to each session you wish to attend. No prior experience with the game is necessary. All rules will be taught.</p>
<p><strong>CONCEPT:</strong> Monsterhearts 2 is a PbtA game about the messy lives of teenagers who are secretly monsters. It explores the terror and confusion of having a body that is changing without your permission. The monstrosity of these characters is literal: they are vampires, werewolves, witches, and more. But their monstrosity is also allegorical, standing in for experiences of alienation, shame, queerness, and self-destruction.</p>
<p><strong>AIM:</strong> Everyone shares the same agenda: make each main character’s life not boring, keep the story feral, say what the rules demand, and say what honesty demands. It’s about exploring relationships and internal strife. While not exactly player-versus-player, it is certainly a game where characters hurt one another, make mistakes, and navigate social fallout.</p>
<p><strong>TONE:</strong> Imagine a teen supernatural romance with elements of horror. The tone may move between comedic and serious, but melodrama will always be the constant. Media touchstones include Buffy the Vampire Slayer, Vampire Diaries, and The Chilling Adventures of Sabrina.</p>
<p><strong>SUBJECT MATTER:</strong> Monsterhearts 2 explores some difficult themes: dysfunctional relationships, teen sexuality, coercive power, trauma, abuse, violence, and queer marginalization.</p>
<p><strong>SESSION LENGTH:</strong> 3.5 hours.</p>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF PLAYERS</strong>: 4 (a seat is being reserved for Max Airborne.)</p>
<p><strong>RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME</strong>: 08/03/2022 - 17:00 Pacific time</p>
<p><strong>SET-UP:</strong> We will use Zoom for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links and resources. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> will be in play and we will use Lines and Veils and the <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">X-Card</a>, as well as <a href="http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change</a> for safety tools.</p>
<p><em>Images used for this event listing are by <a href="https://www.deviantart.com/apriorii" rel="nofollow noopener">Apriorii</a></em></p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8REfjVKnu9UkOTGMgt" rel="nofollow noopener">S1 - October 2, 2022</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGTFtrRcZoIyQ48xq" rel="nofollow noopener">S2 - October 9, 2022</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGaY3Ya-B2hhCL3x0" rel="nofollow noopener">S3 - October 16, 2022</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGk0x-zxiatNeFBEm" rel="nofollow noopener">S4 - October 23, 2022</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N8RGxCisII5Y3nConrW" rel="nofollow noopener">S5 - October 30, 2022</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-bad-influences/8265/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-bad-influences/8265/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 03:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8265-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-bad-influences/8265.rss">Monsterhearts 2 - Bad Influences</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
