<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753</link>
    <description>As I do near final-edits of my game (you can check it out [here](https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/seeking-feedback-hesitation-at-the-gate/3805/15)) I find myself removing a ton of references that were not actual rules, but best practices for roleplaying games in general. It occurs to me that there isn&#39;t really an ur-text (that I&#39;m aware of) on how to *play* ttrpgs. Because so much of the *how* is essentially bespoke tradition within every playgroup, it seems like every rulebook needs to either reinvent the wheel or just assume the reader knows how wheels work.

So it follows, do people think it would be valuable to have a micro-book on *how to play rpgs*?

I won&#39;t presume to be the authority, but I think it&#39;s possible to provide a mostly unbiased primer of how to play RPGs along with common tools to use for players and GMs alike. my vision is as follows

* Price is cheap to free, like $1 at most to ensure high proliferation
* Length is short with a summation that&#39;s 1-2 pages long for quick reference
* Presentation is very clear that the content is advice/philosophy and not one-true-way rules

Does this sound useful? Does it sound like blasphemy?

In the interest of collating the wide world of how we play RPGs, feel free to provide your own advice (try to limit to one sentence or aphorism) . Since the idea is to collect knowledge, please refrain from calling out any concept unless it would create an unsafe experience for players. If a piece of knowledge offends you, provide a counterexample.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 08:31:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@royblumenthal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/royblumenthal">@royblumenthal</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Here’s my attempt at a starter kit for the kind of document you might have in mind.</p>
<p>Add. Subtract. Remix. Maybe something can come out of this.</p>
<p>RULES &amp; TIPS</p>
<p>RULES<br>
Rule 1:<br>
We’re all playing a game together, for fun and enjoyment. As a player, your number 1 responsibility is to help everyone in your gaming session to have fun and enjoyment.</p>
<p>TIPS<br>
Tip A:<br>
Have fun. This isn’t a test. You might feel fear coming to your first gaming session. Think of that as excitement rather than fear. Turn fear into a prompt that takes you to fun and enjoyment. Everyone is looking for the same thing.</p>
<p>Tip B:<br>
Regardless of the exact roleplaying system your group is using, there is one thing common to all roleplaying games… You’re using rules to generate a story filled with characters, goals, and drama.</p>
<p>Tip C:<br>
A bit of preparation goes a long way. You might need paper. You might need dice. You might need a Jenga stack. You might need a computer with a microphone and camera. You might need a stable internet stream that can last for an hour or five hours. If you find out what you need before you start your session, you’ll find it so much easier to actually play the game.</p>
<p>Tip D:<br>
Sometimes you don’t have to know everything about the game system you’re playing. But you need to find that out in advance.</p>
<p>Tip E:<br>
Roleplaying games are almost always about improvising a story and characters within a world that everyone is co-creating. This requires a specific “adventure friendly” mindset. You need to embrace the idea of “Yes, and…” in order to get maximum fun and enjoyment. You also need to find a space in your brain to park and lock up the normal human impulse to say, “No, but…” to things you hear.</p>
<p>Imagine someone says, “I use my magic dust to heat up a coin. I need someone in our group to set the curtain on fire using my heated coin.”</p>
<p>The “No, but…” impulse has most of us thinking, “Huh? The coin isn’t hot enough. That’ll never work.” Or, “No, your coin is too small. My box of matches is way better.” See how this response squashes the fun and enjoyment?</p>
<p>The “Yes, and…” response is so much better at having everyone feel included, and at driving a narrative. The best responses to a character offering a suggestion is to pretend that what they’ve said is one hundred percent true to the world we’re all playing in, that it’s possible,  and that our characters are supporting each other. Rather say, “I grab your coin using my heat-resistant leather glove. I hear it sizzle a bit, and we all smell the tendril of smoke coiling off my thumb. Jendry and Blonk… Can you guys gather up the curtain, and make a little bird’s nest? Quick! This is burning my finger!”</p>
<p>See how we’re all immersed in the reality of the situation when we respond with “Yes, and…”?</p>
<p>Tip F:<br>
Don’t be THAT person. The negative Nelly. The Norman no-mates. The one that squashes things. Nobody actually like playing with THAT person. If you’re the only one talking in your group, you’re probably THAT person. If you look around, and nobody’s smiling except you, you’re probably THAT person.</p>
<p>Tip G:<br>
It’s not about being right. It’s about being in a group of people having fun and enjoyment together.</p>
<p>Tip H:<br>
Gaming isn’t about democracy. It’s about group consensus ruled over by a referee. Most roleplaying games have a Games Master, or Dungeon Master, or some other version of that concept. Some games are GM-free, or GM-lite. Regardless, there will come a time in a gaming situation where one character says, “Burn the curtains!” and another says, “We can’t!” In that moment, defer to someone else in the group to make the decision. Then carry on playing. Even if your decision wasn’t chosen. And don’t EVER say, “But the rules…” It’s almost always about RULINGS, not RULES. What’s this thing all about again? Yup… Fun and enjoyment.</p>
<p>Tip I:<br>
Safety. The group is responsible for the fun and enjoyment of everyone present. Support each other. Use safety tools to back away from content or situations that feel harmful to someone in the group. It doesn’t matter if YOU don’t think or feel or believe that the player feeling threatened or unsafe is actually experiencing that. It matters that you HONOUR their statement of discomfort. Just back away from the offending content. Play to have fun and enjoyment for everyone.</p>
<p>Tip J:<br>
We’re all geniuses. None of us are geniuses. We’re not here to prove anything to anyone. We’re here to… What…? Have fun and enjoyment.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/31</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 08:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="DeReel" data-post="25" data-topic="4753">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/dereel/40/3021_2.png" class="avatar"> DeReel:</div>
<blockquote>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> Regarding sharing spotlight and stuff, isn’t it already a bit storygamey, taking for granted “TTRPG as a conversation” perspective ?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I don’t know! What do you see as the danger in treating “TTRPGs as conversation”? It seems like a pretty foolproof assertion, to me (although I suppose there are forms of roleplaying which extend in different directions these days, like LARP play which has no dialogue - I participated in a LARP like this once [not sure I’d consider that “roleplaying”, really, but if someone feels otherwise I would happily concede to them]).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/30</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 23:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s really interesting, Gus!</p>
<p>I don’t disagree with anything you wrote there, but, at the same time, I wanted to share that my experience has been quite the opposite.</p>
<p>I have found that RPG circles which do not deal with “theory” tend to become quite specifically entrenched in their familiar patterns of thinking and playing. That’s where I’ve seen something like “insisting that games with character builds are for soulless robot children” and similar behaviours. That’s a statement that’s based in a sense of tribal identity, and to distinguish the in-group (“we play good games!”) from the out-group (“those idiots don’t know how to have fun properly!”).</p>
<p>What drew me to RPG theory was precisely the idea that there are different preferences and reasons for ways to design and ways to play - that there is not “one best way” - <em>that</em> was the main “revelation” of RPG theory which struck me and changed gaming quite dramatically for me. From a theory standpoint, it makes absolutely no sense to say “character builds are for [something negative]”, after all. Rather, you’d be looking for the purpose of “character building”, and what role it plays in the game and the play culture.</p>
<p>My experience has very much been that people who are interested in and aware of RPG theory tend to be more open-minded, easier to talk to, and easier to play with. It’s similar to how it can often be more fun to play games with people who all GM games, as well - a broader scope of understanding tends to be present.</p>
<p>You’re absolutely right that groups <em>discussing</em> theory online, on the other hand, do often, whether intentionally or inadvertently, “tend towards gate-keeping or snobbishness in some parts of the TTRPG community”. I suppose it’s hard to for groups avoid some of those human tendencies!</p>
<p>Anyway, I’m not disagreeing with you in any way. Just sharing my experience. It may be that different schools of thought in RPG theory land may have different tendencies, too. I have a feeling some groups actually develop theory in order to justify their play preferences (e.g. by giving derogatory names to ways of playing they don’t like). The theory I’ve always been drawn to, instead, is that which allows us to better understand a variety of game styles and modes.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Gus.L" data-post="27" data-topic="4753">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/gus.l/40/3198_2.png" class="avatar"> Gus.L:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s all a game, and it’s a game of make-believe so really anyone can play, and I think that may be what I still like about TTRPGs after so many years.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Indeed! So true.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/29</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 22:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It might be useful to disentangle various conflict sources so that we can better discuss which we have power to teach and/or enforce</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Interpersonal skills and social power dynamics (think two players dating) can’t be fixed with a game and games shouldn’t be written assuming they can mediate these things</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>RPG “philosophy” is bespoke to individual groups, cultures, and systems, so we shouldn’t presume to find one true way, but we should also encourage people to explain and discuss their own preferences</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>RPG play “techniques” may fall under the “philosophy” category depending on how broadly you define it but there surely must be some kinds of practices that can agreed upon as the “best” way to do things; for example using safety tools, even if there is disagreement on which tools are best.</p>
</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 17:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’d suggest that the friendship ending arguments might have been more “about” being in middle school then about TTRPGs?</p>
<p>There’s absolutely a space for TTRPG theory – hell I’ve written a hundred of pages of it in the last year – but I also think it’s important not to focus on that theory or get cocky about it when offering the hobby to newcomers.  There’s a real tendency towards gate-keeping and snobbishness in some parts of the TTRPG community and often it coalesces around perceptions that one needs specific esoteric knowledge to play or that choosing one playstyle or another is a sign of degeneracy or mental unfitness.  Whether it’s laughing at someone’s “improper” character build or insisting that games with character builds are for soulless robot children - none of that’s helpful.</p>
<p>It’s all a game, and it’s a game of make-believe so really anyone can play, and I think that may be what I still like about TTRPGs after so many years.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/27</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 16:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I can’t be the only person here who got into near-friendship-ending arguments in middle school BECAUSE we didn’t have any understanding of the finer points of the unstated parts of RPGs, can I?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/26</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 13:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree with that but with a personal nuance I want to add : important as they are, there are not so many things to set before play and Bankuei has already laid solid foundations for that.</p>
<p>Same page (to prevent one-true-way-ism), safe fun seem consensual enough.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> Regarding sharing spotlight and stuff, isn’t it already a bit storygamey, taking for granted “TTRPG as a conversation” perspective ?</p>
<p>Various styles, different leaflets is what I propose. Which is already a certain perspective. Argh, I cornered myself !</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/25</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That wasn’t quite the point I was making.</p>
<p>I think understanding the basics of roleplaying games is pretty simple. As you point out, kids can do it, and I don’t think anyone needs to watch more than a couple of minutes of an actual play video to grasp what’s going on.</p>
<p>However, I think there are a couple of points that can easily get lost there.</p>
<p>The first is that children actually have a big advantage over adults in that they’re used to negotiating how to play. Kids change the rules of their games all the time, whether it’s a game they just made up or something they’ve played a dozen times before. Adults aren’t as used to this, at least not in my experience, and tend to rely much more on established rules or external authority on how things are supposed to be done.</p>
<p>The second is that while the basics of roleplaying are easy to grasp, there are a lot of particulars that get negotiated in various ways and that can differ wildly from group to group - character vs. player knowledge, player vs. GM authority, rulings vs. rules, character death and so on. And since most people tend to stick with the same group, in their minds the way <em>they</em> play becomes <em>the</em> way to play.</p>
<p>So while I think it’s very easy to get up and running with a roleplaying game even for complete beginners, I also think that having advice available is a huge boon for players at all levels of experience. I don’t think we should portray being a GM as some kind of mystical ability that requires decades of experience, but being any kind of player in a roleplaying game, GM or otherwise, definitely is a skill that can be improved.</p>
<p>Similarly, developing the theories and vocabulary around roleplaying games can only be beneficial, but that doesn’t mean it should all be thrown at beginners as essential knowledge for how to play.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/24</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 09:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I like that a lot, Gus! Absolutely. It’s easy to lose the simple joy, sometimes. A much needed counterpoint!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 23:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s a good point.  One of the things I see sometimes (and perhaps have been guilty of from time to time) is a claim the TTRPGs, or sometimes just refereeing, game mastering them is a difficult and skilled task, and to me there’s something unproductively elitist in this.  I remember playing D&amp;D at the age of 8 and enjoying myself.  Was it the game I’d play 30 years later? Nah.</p>
<p>Was I an objectively good player or GM? I don’t know, and it doesn’t matter - I was playing a game and me and my friends were enjoying it.  Apparently it was a good enough experience that I’m still at it.</p>
<p>I think emphasis on the hidden rules, norms and ethics of play - anything beyond the basic gist of tell stories and roll dice sometimes when stuff is hard to figure out - and any emphasis on the mastery of it as a complex and important discipline misses something.  Playing TTRPGs is simple enough, and mystifying it with too much theorizing (which might seem odd given that I really enjoy over-thinking play) and too many rules of comportment (this is not a dig at safety techniques - which are important especially in public settings), best practices and instructions may drive people off.</p>
<p>For some reason contemporary TTRPG culture seems to be moving in a direction of holding up expertise (odd given how little our society respects it elsewhere), insisting that the experience is best enjoyed with a highly skilled practitioners, creating GM celebrities, and generally making it into something that 8 year old me would not have thought of as a fun activity on rainy weekend days. In this environment it seems helpful to counter that with the message that “This is easy, just use your imagination, you can’t really screw it up as long as you’re having fun and being decent to your friends. If you want more ideas there’s places to seek them out.”</p>
<p>I think that gets lost sometimes in the discourse.  Anyway, just being nostalgic and a cranky old man I guess.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/22</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 22:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s why you need advice. But I don’t think you need a text to tell you the basics of how roleplaying is done.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/21</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 22:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A long time ago, over on Story Games, we had a thread about ‘the ideal RPG curriculum’. I wrote a bit about what I think makes a great player. I’ll paste it here, as it might inspire some ideas or discussion:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I think the ‘ultimate roleplayer’, for me, would consist of three things (as a foundation):</p>
<ol>
<li>A good ability to communicate with others.</li>
</ol>
<p>This includes both the ability to express yourself and also the ability to notice when others are quiet or when they need to speak, and facilitating that. Listening skills, in short. Being aware when to speak and when to keep quiet, and how to help others do the same.</p>
<p>Likewise, being able to clearly express your interests and draw out other peoples’.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>The ability to “share” the toys of roleplaying.</li>
</ol>
<p>Knowing when to step into the spotlight, when to step back, and how to draw good play out of others. Being able to support another player when they need support (such as playing a villain when another player wants to be a hero, and being prepared to lose to them) and being able to challenge them when the situation demands it.</p>
<p>I believe that this may be the hardest thing about roleplaying games: our natural instinct is generally either to sit and listen (passively), or step in and take control of the entire process (like a railroading GM). For functional roleplaying/story gaming, a person needs to learn to occupy the middle space: to make contributions to play which always demand response from others - ideas which are incomplete, and require another to “fill in” the gaps. That’s where the game is born.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>A broad knowledge of different games, different people, and the understanding of how to adapt to each.</li>
</ol>
<p>A great player, in my opinion, is capable of understanding what a given game is about and then playing to that as well as possible, instead of trying to play every game the same way.</p>
<p>That player doesn’t try to “immerse in their character” in an intensive rules-heavy game which demands mastery of the rules, and knows to ignore the rules when they don’t contribute to what the group is trying to do (like a group which “hardly ever rolls the dice”).</p>
<p>Someone with a wide range of experience and the understanding that each game is its own beast* is my ideal player, and one of the things I look for in people I want to play with.</p>
<p>*: “Each game” could mean “each ruleset”, “each group”, or even “each session” or any other context. You almost certainly should play differently in a convention game with strangers than you would in a long-term home campaign with your older sister, for example.</p>
<p>…</p>
<p>There are other factors which enhance the experience: the ability to master rules quickly, a great knowledge of genre fiction, good acting skills, excellent “creative skills”, good vocal mimicry, art skills (painting minis, drawing maps, making costumes), excellent descriptive skills/language ability, the social savvy to organize groups, reliability (do you show up when you said you would), etc, etc,.</p>
<p>In my opinion, none of those are as fundamental. I’d happily play with a group of people with zero experience with, say, “fantasy fiction”, no acting skills, and no ability to remember rules, so long as they met the three above criteria.</p>
</blockquote>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/20</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 20:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Not just “aren’t usually explicit”… they may display or reinforce bad habits, bad ideas, or incorrect practices. Or, at best, contradict each other.</p>
<p>But the fact that they’re not explicit doesn’t help, layered on top of that! Many gamers, for example, claim they’re doing one thing, while doing another (e.g. any railroading or dice fudging practices, but also happens sometimes at a subconscious level - I once watched a D&amp;D campaign in progress, and there was a married couple playing. The wife said to the husband - who was the GM - “if you kill my character, I’m divorcing you!” He replied, “Hey, now, it’s up to the dice and your decisions!” We can see that they view the very same game they’re playing quite differently, and are emphasizing different aspects of the power dynamics in the play experience).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/19</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 20:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/anders">@Anders</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think this is a worthy endeavor, but I also think it’s been eclipsed by the fact that nowadays anyone who could access a general text on how to play roleplaying games could also go to YouTube and just watch other people play - in fact, I would guess that these days most people who are getting into the hobby but haven’t played yet have already done that.</p>
<p>However, general advice and best practices can still be very useful since those aren’t usually explicit in actual play videos.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/18</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 15:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@noah_t]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/noah_t">@noah_t</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just wanted to speak up and say how great this discussion is for my understanding of how rules &amp; advice can work together to create a culture of play at the table.</p>
<p>It’s also making me think about the type of advice that would be appropriate for a little “So you want to play RPGs” pamphlet. In the spirit of <a class="mention" href="/u/radmad">@Radmad</a>’s original question—I love how so many PBTA games (particularly those by creators of color, feminist &amp;/or queer designers) make players consider the social structures their characters are informed by.</p>
<p>I would (tentatively) propose that a Move like <strong>Bring their gender into it</strong> probably isn’t appropriate for every table or game. The particular women I game with, for instance, have to put up with enough misogyny in real life that they don’t always want that shit in their gaming.</p>
<p>However, it’s hard to think of a table/game that WOULDN’T benefit from some combination of Avery Alder’s <strong>Give everyone a messy life</strong> (“It’s important to remember that when these characters are off-screen they don’t just power down or go on standby”) and Robert Bohl’s <strong><a href="https://twitter.com/robertbohl/status/1234927412904890368" rel="nofollow noopener">Diversify monocultures</a></strong> (“Just as you are striving to make everyone a person, it is important that the troupe’s saga depicts real, breathing cultures rather than stereotypical ones”).</p>
<p>That would be my vote for inclusion in a general how-to text.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/17</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 20:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>All of these answers are valid :</p>
<ul>
<li>comments about the rules and examples in snappy incident propositions</li>
<li>comments and discussion in side frames</li>
<li>preliminary principles and howto chapter (or booklet or video)<br>
The decision depends on how “wordy” you and your reader are.</li>
</ul>
<p>To come back to OP, who would be the target audience? I like <a class="mention" href="/u/noah_t">@noah_t</a> 's idea to have various leaflets, each with a different topic and audience, like “So you want to be a GM…” or “So you want to play RPGs / close to home / with minis…”</p>
<p>I’d be eager to produce and discuss such articles free of rights allowing commercial use, leaving for others the care and trouble of finding the best way to publish them. Already (slowly) building a TTRPGWiki, this would complement it on the practical side, as Play is to Design.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 10:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Radmad" data-post="14" data-topic="4753">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/radmad/40/2161_2.png" class="avatar"> Radmad:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Each art is described in brief below. <strong>These descriptions are not exhaustive but should give sufficient description to comprehend their uses.</strong> If a situation calls for actions that do not fully fall within one art, either call on the most applicable art or the most appropriate personal bonds. Each art will also list potential <em>Specializations.</em> These lists are not exhaustive, feel free to come up with your own!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I think this particular example is more an issue about editing, rather than removing GM advice. You’re just like when when I published my first game - it’s too much text that gives nothing to the reader. The text is babbling.</p>
<p>“Show, don’t tell”, meaning - in this case - “Say how something is used, not that something exists”.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If a situation calls for actions that do not fully fall within [of the one] art [below], either call on the most applicable art or the most appropriate personal bonds.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is the only thing you need from the text above, with my addition in the text within brackets.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="Radmad" data-post="14" data-topic="4753">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/radmad/40/2161_2.png" class="avatar"> Radmad:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>But when I include notes like that in every rules blurb.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yeah, I felt that too when I wrote my published game, so I separated all the notes into a game master chapter in each chapter, where I described how the game master could use skills to create adventures. It worked, but it wasn’t ideal. Something I’m in awe over is how Robin D Laws creates game master advice in form of rules.</p>
<p>In <strong>Feng Shui</strong>, there is a rule that if the player says “KA-CHINK” and makes a shotgun reload movement, the shotgun makes +1 damage. That instead of actually giving this as an advice. Or if a player starts spitting out stats for a monster, that monster gets +5 on everything. This instead of actually giving the advice that revealing stats during a session makes the game boring.</p>
<p>In <strong>Esoterrorist</strong>, the investigator skills automatically succeeds. This instead of telling the game master that people shouldn’t roll to get clues, but the important part is instead of what players are doing with the clues.</p>
<p>It’s game advice disguised as rules.</p>
<p>This is what I mean with baking in the advice in a clear structure of play.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.urverkspel.com/vara-spel/oevriga-projekt" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">The Murder of Mr. Crow</a>, I intentionally made the lists of suspects and clues very limited, and I especially pointed out that the group should pick from this list. My intention was that, by making the list really narrow, the group <em>wanted</em> to break the rules. A fellow game designer thought I was bonkers when I told him that, but I don’t know if any group have actually followed the list.  All I gave were pointers, and then they took it from there.</p>
<p>This is what you can do with your Specializations. Just give them one or two <em>suggestions</em>, and let the group take it from there. You don’t need to explain that they can make up new ones.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/15</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 10:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Absolutely, let’s get concrete.</p>
<p>For example, take the following rules text, During editing I removed the bold text.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each art is described in brief below. <strong>These descriptions are not exhaustive but should give sufficient description to comprehend their uses.</strong> If a situation calls for actions that do not fully fall within one art, either call on the most applicable art or the most appropriate personal bonds. Each art will also list potential <em>Specializations.</em> These lists are not exhaustive, feel free to come up with your own!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The reasoning being that I want to encourage the players to collaborate and add onto the foundation the rules are providing. But when I include notes like that in every rules blurb (along with things like “but of course change modify or change X if you see fit”) it undermines the authority of the text. I want players to engage with the rules and feel comfortable tinkering with them, but I also need the rules to stand as a skeleton that the players can craft their own muscle around. I think the rules are stronger now because</p>
<p>A: the text is no longer clogged up with exceptions like <em>but don’t forget…</em> or <em>feel free to change if…</em></p>
<p>and</p>
<p>B: That overall sentiment has been summarized in a “how to run a game HatG” chapter</p>
<p>So now that kind of how to play philosophy is more GM focused, but I’m leaning on the idea that the GM for the game is the one who will read the rules front to back and then be teaching other people to play verbally. Considering this is how most games are taught, I’m trying to make this one teachable clearly and quickly.(based on playtests with strangers I’m optimistic that I’ve succeeded)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/14</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 23:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>While I agree that all that can be incorporated in the rules should be, like butter in a kouign amann, I also suppose Radmad has come to the conclusion that these bits don’t belong to the rules for some reason. I guess that’s a question for them : why don’t you think these advice fit in the rules ? Do they<br>
1- … crowd the layout ?<br>
2-… crawl out from behind your neat mechanics and swallow them in text ?<br>
3-… or what ?<br>
But I note that this is only indirectly answering OP.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/13</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 10:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Radmad" data-post="1" data-topic="4753">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/radmad/40/2161_2.png" class="avatar"> Radmad:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>As I do near final-edits of my game (you can check it out <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/seeking-feedback-hesitation-at-the-gate/3805/15">here </a>) I find myself removing a ton of references that were not actual rules, but best practices for roleplaying games in general. It occurs to me that there isn’t really an ur-text (that I’m aware of) on how to <em>play</em> ttrpgs.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Dunno if this is off topic, but I think this is a problem with most roleplaying games in general - the lack of structure of play. A boardgame have normally a pretty clear structure, starting by introducing a win condition and then describing the round(s). By introducing a win condition, the reader then understands why they should go through with the round. Anyways …</p>
<p>Why this never was a thing for roleplaying games - a clear procedure for how to play - can differ, but it’s probably because most of the early roleplaying games had a “do whatever you want, it’s your game” mentality over it. Other roleplaying games followed this mentality, and never created a clear structure of play, and even more game writers just copied the structure (character creation, world, rules) from the previous roleplaying games. We could see this with early Forge games; there were a “new” way of playing roleplaying games, but none understood how to play these games, because the writers followed the previous established writing pattern of <em>not</em> having a clear structure of play. The only thing the previous games had were a “What is roleplaying games” and a lacking “game master chapter”.</p>
<hr>
<p>My point is I think it’s a mistake of removing <em>how</em> to play this game. These “tips” should be incorporated in a structure of play, that the game master (or rule facilitator) should follow. In order to succeed with this, we need to be better at describing the win condition. What should the characters strive for? When is an adventure over? To be able to do this, we can’t create games where it’s up to the group itself to do whatever they want with the game. You should tell them. If it’s not they forte, then it’s not a game for them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/12</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 09:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@The_Bearded_Belgian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/the_bearded_belgian">@The_Bearded_Belgian</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I also had to think about the <a href="https://www.evilhat.com/home/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/The-Book-of-Hanz-Fate-Core-Thought-of-the-Day.pdf" rel="nofollow noopener">Book of Hanz</a> for Fate, which helped me tremendous with understanding the Fate system better. Some of the tips are generally for roleplaying, handling scenes and encounters, etc. Others are more system specific. All tend towards epic, action forward, story/character based gameplay.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/11</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 19:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We could, perhaps, imagine a text which includes topics or groups of techniques (e.g. “Safety and Consent”, “Collaborative Improvisation”, “Impartial Refereeing”, “Competitive Character Building”) and a guide on each section which tells you what games these techniques might be suited for, and where you might use them and where you might not.</p>
<p>I don’t believe such a document could ever be exhaustive, though; every new game and genre that gets created often calls for completely different techniques or advice.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/10</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Radmad" data-post="8" data-topic="4753">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/radmad/40/2161_2.png" class="avatar"> Radmad:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>This would also be a great way to collate safety tools.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yeah, I was actually thinking about the Consent in Gaming by Monte Cook Games as sort of a blueprint for any free pamphlet. I like the idea of writing about your own style and yes, this should include safety tools you employ while playing.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/9</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thank you for all the responses, I concur with what many people have posted. My shower epiphany is reaching for the stars. A complete “how to play RPGs” is probably not possible given the gamut of play styles that exist, but I can at least speak authoritatively on my own style. I’m really liking the idea of making a free pamphlet for general onboarding but that I can also reference in any game I make saying “if this your first RPG, check out this primer”</p>
<p>This would also be a great way to collate safety tools.</p>
<p>I will definitely keep everyone on the Gauntlet in the loop for how that goes, very interested to see how people respond to it. I’ll leave the door open in the this thread for further discussion though. Please continue the discussion on possible “how to play RPG” sources, best practices you may have, and your own project planning.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/8</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 01:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Airk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/airk">@Airk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t think you can do this “generically” because best practices for one game may be terrible practices for another.</p>
<p>This is why each game should/does have its own section on this topic.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753/7</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-4753-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-rpgs-putting-tribal-knowledge-in-one-place/4753.rss">How do you play RPGs? Putting tribal knowledge in one place</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
