<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672</link>
    <description>*The ramshackle village of Kormoran&#39;s Wheel sits between Fort Duhrin and the heart of old Kalduhr, just inside the edge of the forest. The residents of the Wheel make a healthy profit on the poor planning of the many treasure-hunters that pass through. It&#39;s said that nearly anything can be acquired here, though those purchases are often of questionable quality or otherwise... strange.*

@jasoncordova and I are putting together a standalone book for the Trophy RPG (the game and its many expansions are currently featured in each new issue of Codex). One of the things we’re going to do with this book is include numerous tables that help flesh out the world Trophy takes place in. Keeping with the spirit of Trophy as a community project, we’re going to be crowdsourcing many of the elements that go into these tables. We already have a number of these crowdsourcing threads underway, any of which you can still contribute to. They can be found in this master list:

https://discourse.funtimers.club/t/trophy-crowdsourcing-master-list/3011

For this installment, we&#39;re exploring the rough-and -tumble tent city of Kormoran&#39;s Wheel. We&#39;re looking for one type of contribution:

**The strange vendors of Kormoran&#39;s Wheel, and the even stranger items they sell**

NOTE: Please avoid anything that feels like sexual predation or that is misogynistic in nature. We won’t print such things.

You can submit as many entries as you wish. By submitting here, you agree to let us use your contribution in the Trophy standalone book and PDF (you will be credited as a contributor). Submissions should be fairly brief (just a few sentences). Here are some examples:

&quot;Eboj the cordage-maker can supply you with as much rope as you need, and his rope is the cheapest available in the Wheel. However, it&#39;s interwoven with a very particular ochre thread that comes from vines found deep in the woods. This thread only serves two masters: Eboj, and the forest Kalduhr.&quot;

&quot;The Fair Lady offers various tinctures and herbal compresses for dealing with injuries that occur far from the healing hands of a doctor. Her remedies are harvested not from her gardens, or even from the forest, but from the oozing, otherworldly funguses growing on the five faeborn she keeps drugged and caged in the root cellar under her cottage.&quot;

&quot;Though very few return from the forest, stories of those who do tell of the small idols they have carried with them through their journey. These pocket gods come from only one place: The Sisters&#39; Brother, a temple and clayworks. The proprietor—a goblin simply called &#39;Brother&#39;—is a true artist, and will offer to whisper a special blessing from your god just for you into a pocket-sized, hollow clay doll. It will not come without a sizeable &#39;donation&#39; to his temple.&quot;

![](upload://ioJGO1IOzpfXttpk6UzmUcYNSMy.jpeg)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 03:32:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>FYI.  I am totally using some of these items on this list for my play by forum random treasures.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 03:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@steinea]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/steinea">@steinea</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>The Runesmith</strong>. Just outside Kormoran’s Wheel there lives a Runesmith in a dingy tent. For a price, he will imprint an arcane mark upon your weapon–but to what end? Sometimes, a weapon will sprout roots and burrow its way into your arm. Sometimes, a weapon will send you into a deep and terrible slumber at the slightest touch of its hilt. And sometimes, a weapon will be imbued with searing flame, and you will burn a furious swathe into the black heart of the forest, the righteous hand of vengeance and ruin. Don’t have the money to pay the Runesmith for his handywork? Try one of the many discarded weapons that lie in the brush and mud around his shelter.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/31</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 18:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@GroupSoliloquy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/groupsoliloquy">@GroupSoliloquy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Even those with both eyes removed can’t miss the stall of Felligus, the dye merchant. You can smell the vinegar from twenty paces. He sells exotic pigments and stains from across all Kalduhr. “Look! A merry crimson, a regal beige, a foxy, prismatic yellow” he grins as he shoves skein after skein of threads into your hands. “One must not die looking a pauper!” The rain washes a iridescent slick into the gutter.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/30</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 14:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@GroupSoliloquy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/groupsoliloquy">@GroupSoliloquy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The ‘rope children’ who dart in and out of the thoroughfare know that all adventurers need their wares. With lengths of hemp and silken rope draped around their neck they are tough negotiators, often demanding a price above the market value. Yet, it is best to pay them, or you might find your purse missing when you go to buy that fancy hand-axe.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/29</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 14:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Alberto Hand is not just any tea specialist!  He sells only the rarest and most potent blends from his tea house on the northeast side of the central crossroad of Kormoran’s Wheel.</p>
<p>A full cup of his tea blend known as On Alert will not just keep the drinker up for their entire watch but also well after the delusions start.  A cup of his REST blend will help you regain your health but will also leave you paralyzed between 1 - 12 minutes.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 20:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_Kershaw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_kershaw">@Joshua_Kershaw</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Dr. Laszlo knows that to a trophy hunter on the brink of death, nothing on this plane is worth more than a <em>Dr. Laszlos Decoction of Restoration</em> (patent pending).<br>
His pharmacy sits on prime real estate at the eastern hub of Kormoran’s Wheel. Possessing excellent traffic patterns and favorable sight lines, it’s a simple, but well built shake structure, perfectly symmetrical outside and in. Above the bright red door hangs a shingle illustrated with two vials, one upright and full of red liquid, the other identical but  inverted and empty.<br>
A single draught of <em>Dr. Laszlos’s Decoction of Restoration</em> (patent pending) will restore the health and vitality of the clever consumer. But such magics demand counterpoise. As vigor is given to one hunter, so shall it be taken from another.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 19:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Alden Slabby sells the loveliest helmets with just a bit of gold in the middle of the crown. When the helmets are sold, he suggests the explorers take along his best guide for a tiny price.</p>
<p>Unfortunately,  for the many adventurers that have worn the helmets, the gold acts as a bullseye for the soft spot.  After the adventurers are slain,  the guide retrieves the helmets for Alden to repair and sell to more unsuspecting souls.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/26</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 21:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Beairstoboy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beairstoboy">@Beairstoboy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ioannes, the bookbinder, will bind you a unique book all your own: a Journal of the Journey that will fill its empty pages with each and every triumph and tribulation encountered in the Kalduhr. Every day the book will return to its owner, until the final day of the journey. The end of a tale is not always satisfying, but very final nonetheless. Ioannes has a large collection of beaten leather tomes from a multitude of authors.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 08:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@smythos]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/smythos">@smythos</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Don’t take up the offer by the traveling scholar. She offers lessons in rhetoric, arithmetic, ancient languages and a variety of other innocuous forms of erudition. She will take your coin, but the cost is not in gold. Knowledge without context is often … ruinous.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/24</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 17:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Kormoran’s newest vendor seems out of place in the mud and the filth all around them. But beaming from behind fine translucent silk Santina is happy to sell anyone interested a tiny chirping frog. Why anyone would want one has baffled the town and yet there Santina sits as chipper as ever, their frogs singing behind them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 19:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Jehaora the sailor sells shells and cockles from the Sea of Martyred Souls, and also - if asked - gold coins to the foolish or the desperate. For Gold floats on the Sea of Martyred Souls, each piece buoyed and infested with one of the ghosts who were drowned there long ago. If you buy the gold, you buy the unquiet soul as well, and it will inveigle itself into your dreams, into the lost thoughts between purpose and memory, into the frisson of deja vu.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/22</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 17:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There is an ornate clay jar, tightly corked and seemingly unbreakable, that shows up variously at different stalls across the market. It is on no shopkeep’s inventory, there is no mention of it in any ledger. However, when it appears suddenly on a new vendor’s shelf they all have the same policy, and have had for as long as they can remember: If you can open it, it’s yours. Now the villagers might believe it’s a prank between the shopkeeps, but they all agree that no one has been able to open that little jar, and wonder as to it’s contents.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/21</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 16:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Ask anyone and they will point you to a tall, wiry potter who goes by the name Ron. You can buy as many mugs and jars you want only one pot ever. He will adorn the pot with your name and never sell you another one. Don’t even try and trick him with a clever disguise - Ron remembers <em>everyone</em>. Pot is expensive and always comes with some tasty food inside. Eat it all and there’s no more; leave some in the pot before you got to bed and in the morning your entire ration is back. Few from the Kormoran’s Wheel village resisted temptation of eating the food at some point and those who still rely on their pot, keep it hidden from neighbors’ envious eyes.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 12:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@sednaqagaq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sednaqagaq">@sednaqagaq</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A four-armed woman with a tattooed throat and skin the color of curdled milk. She sells rituals. Scars. Beneath her furs there writhes the fruit of her ruin. For a price, a terrible price, she will take you into her tented manse and place your future in a jar. For safekeeping.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 20:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Naddiramiarach is the only store at the bottom of the well (or so boasts its owner, the diminutive Flimhock Dill). He shines a light on his wares for you to peer down at but the coins must be thrown down before the bucket, and your prize, ascend.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/18</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 19:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Buk Shagol is back in town with his cart of mysteries. He sells his bits and bobs and then goes to see what’s on offer from the other vendors. Without fail he leaves empty handed, however, muttering “not this year, never this year” under his breath.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/17</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 19:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blaine_Moore]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blaine_moore">@Blaine_Moore</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>As you wander the stalls, a paltry trinket catches your eye. You then dismiss it as uninteresting and quickly forget it. But then you see it again at another stall. By the third sighting, you are suspicious. By the seventh you are certain the trinket is following you, calling ever stronger to your wallet for sweet release. Can you resist the call of the beggar’s bauble long enough to escape the market?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/16</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 18:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/signalstation">@signalstation</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Should your purse come up short when a pretty bauble has caught your eye, or should a bout of haggling leave you dejected while some counter-polisher laughs at your besting, you may hear a soft voice offer to make the purchase on your behalf. Worry not. There’s no shop keep who’d let you accept this offer, even if you were tempted. Pelleck the Coin Bearer knows what they did, and why that coin is theirs forever. That coin, and none other.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 01:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Grandmother Nura never sleeps, but hangs gracefully in her glowing silk tent and sells lanterns to those who would venture into the dark forest. Soft lights to bring comfort, radiant lights for guidance, and cold lights which reveal things otherwise obscured. How do her lanterns maintain their light? Why do they seem to glow brighter when carried down certain paths?<br>
Each lantern comes with a simple warning - do not ever open it.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/14</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 15:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Do you hear that sound? It is Runik, playing their flutes for the spirits of this place. Some songs put the spirits at ease, others stir them to dance or drive them away. You will find many kinds of flutes for sale in the hollow tree where Runik lives. They have hollow orbs of clay with finger holes arranged just so, delicate flutes of fragrant wood, polished goat horns with a soothing timbre - and slender whistles of bone which seem to fit your hands perfectly, as if they want you to play them. Where does Runik find clay of that strange hue, and where do all the bones come from? If you are careful to observe the proper courtesies, perhaps Runik will tell you.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 14:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JMBosch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmbosch">@JMBosch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The ever-eager Olinfehr excitedly rushes to greet anyone demonstrating a passing glance at his table, grandly gesturing over the broken gear lovingly arranged on the finest cloth he can afford. If a customer shows the slightest interest in any item, he will breathlessly recite its entire history, complete with previous owners and memorable moments of use. The rare purchase will fill the buyer with good spirits, inspiration to wield the equipment, regardless of condition or accompanying shift in personality, and will thus begin the gradual return of its owner…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/12</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Well respected among goblin clans, the Zidaj family maintains an ironfruit grove just at the edge of the Wheel. The squat trees thrive in shade, protected from scavengers by a woven canopy of thorny briars. The fruits themselves are deep blue in color and have a faint metallic taste. A bite of ironfruit dulls the sense of fear, while consuming a whole fruit makes one numb and utterly heedless of danger. Wine of the fruit, if the rumors are true, inspires such a madness that those who taste it wander towards their doom with open arms, singing joyfully…</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/11</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 23:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blaine_Moore]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blaine_moore">@Blaine_Moore</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A strange store is left unattended. It consists of nothing more than a sign, a bowl with a few scant coins, and a stone tile upon which rests a massive mixed pile of artifacts decorated with the trappings of opulent wealth and bristling with occult energies. The sign reads simply, “Take a treasure leave a treasure. Tips appreciated. Beware thy greed.”<br>
Fresh blood pools upon the tile.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/10</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 19:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seanFsmith]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seanfsmith">@seanFsmith</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>Gohraj is a spindly woman of bulging eyes and sinew and skin so leathery it’s hard to tell where she ends and her tent begins. She makes a steady sale of outdated blueprints of Barsul Prison. The '43 medical wing is a favourite — it’s currently out of stock</p>
</blockquote>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/9</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 19:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Meyer’s Furs &amp; Hides, the largest stall at this end of the Wheel, bustles with activity. Cured skins strewn about on make-shift tables, the locals eagerly ferreting through them. Toward the back, Meyer himself does the tanning, humming joylessly in his work. Anyone spending even a moment perusing will see one of Meyer’s goons arrive, a dead adventurer from the forest slung over their shoulder. They throw it down on the pile next to Meyer, the buzzing flies momentarily dispersing from the stack of corpses.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/8</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 13:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3672-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672.rss">Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
