<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679</link>
    <description>We all love being a part of a great session. Sometimes it&#39;s the facilitator, but, for me, it&#39;s often another player who isn&#39;t the host or facilitator that really makes the session enjoyable. I fully believe being able to identify those things in others, will help us identify it in our selves, and help us improve. I want to be a better player.

Here are some things I&#39;ve noticed. I love it when others: 
1. Ask interesting questions. 
2. Give non interruptive feedback (laughter, clapping, dancing, squeeing, turning the body and focusing, etc)
3. Broadcast what you as the player want and what you want to do with the character
4. Are willing and enthusiastic about the incorporating the ideas of others. Being flexible with concepts, but also advocating for themselves to get something that wouldn&#39;t have happened without the different inputs.
5. Identify and when another player hasn&#39;t had spotlight in a while, and sets them up or somehow helps bring them back into focus. This could be stepping back, or getting them involved in the current thing, or setting up something the other character is uniquely qualified to do. It really helps if you know what the player and/or character wants. :wink: 
6. Are committed to the tone of the game. Whether it&#39;s whimsical, serious, dark, emotional, or comedic, being on tone and helping others stay on tone, even if it&#39;s just by leading through example.

Some of these I definitely got better at through being a GM, but whether I am a player or GM I really appreciate it when I see other players (including other GMs) do these things.

*Full disclosure this was inspired by a conversation at a recent convention around there being awards for GMs, yet no awards for being a Player. I wanted to think of what noticeable things you could use to assign a player award.*

What are some of the actions other players do that help make the session more enjoyable?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 20:40:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Here are a few things I didn’t spot in this thread.</p>
<ul>
<li>Willingness to be a game master.</li>
<li>Wanting to improve what they are bad at, or at least challenge themselves in some way.</li>
<li>Brings something to the table, instead of being served by the others.</li>
<li>Don’t try too hard all the time. Sometimes it’s good to do something boring with your character or obvious.</li>
</ul>
<p>“Be into it”, as <a class="mention" href="/u/maezar">@Maezar</a> mentioned cannot be stressed enough how important it is. Bring energy, because that will smear off on the others … up to a certain point anyway. See last point again. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/45</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 20:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dutch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dutch">@Dutch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A few larger-scale points come to mind, informed by my experiences doing improv with a wide variety of people:</p>
<ul>
<li>Quickly read, learn and adapt to the culture of play of a particular group.</li>
<li>Show interest in learning rules, source material and/or the general craft of playing narrative games.</li>
<li>Leave your personal issues aside for the duration of play. (“Check your baggage at the door”)</li>
<li>Know what you like and don’t like and opt in or out accordingly</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/44</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 17:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m pretty new to this forum, and just finding some wonderful threads like this one. Great to see so much top-notch discussion of practical gaming concerns!</p>
<p>This thread has covered a lot of ground, but I’ll add one player skill (or attitude) that I find really important:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you start playing a game, you examine and then learn to embody the particular stance and approach needed to play that game. (You do not simply attempt to play it the way you played some other game you have experience with in the past, in other words.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This might be a question of knowing how to interface with the game’s mechanics. It might be a question of seeing how the group handles in-character conversations, or how players face challenges.</p>
<p>Take a look at the rules, the structure, the relationships of the people involved, and the creative goals of the whole enterprise, and then play to that.</p>
<p>Sometimes it means understanding whether the game is about honest competition, screwing over your friends in order to win by any means necessary (cutthroat competition), or supporting everyone at all times. Sometimes it means mastering the rules and being able to make the right mechanical choices when your turn comes up. Sometimes it means noticing the attention to detail and doing your homework; at other times it’s noticing who looseness and creativity are valued here and letting go of your own attention to detail. Sometimes it means noticing that there’s one player at the table who always gets overlooked, and doing something about it.</p>
<p>But, in short, a good player takes in a new game and a new group and, first, observes and reads the vibe and the way it works. They do not assume that it’s just like something they played before.</p>
<p>They recognize that every combination of game-and-group takes its own form or its own ‘culture of play’, and, therefore should be played as its own particular, unique “instrument”. It may need a different “touch”, a different attitude, or a different perspective.</p>
<p>The player who recognizes the uniqueness of each game and each gaming situation and plays to its strengths is someone I am much more likely to enjoy playing with.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/43</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 07:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OrbWitch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/orbwitch">@OrbWitch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>My friends and I are making an actual play podcast right now, so being a good player is something we’ve talked a lot about. For me good players make strong choices that advance the plot and find ways to support other players in their own goals. Something I’ve had to learn is to not be precious about my character. I think of the Monsterhearts core principles a lot but specifically: Make your character’s life not boring. I don’t always have to make the safe choice. I can make the wrong choice on purpose because it’s interesting! Failure is interesting.</p>
<p>Unrelated to play specifically, but I always appreciate if players bring snacks, offer to host the game, help schedule games.</p>
<p>I am also delighted when players do things like draw their character, write 12 pages of backstory, make a pinterest board, playlist, etc. As a storyteller, it tells me that they are excited and engaged in the world we’re creating together.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/42</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 04:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Monsterhearts 2</em> retails for $25, or roughly the cost of 2 movie tickets.</p>
<p>A Player’s Handbook is $50, and that’s all you need as a player.</p>
<p>For one-shots and short campaigns, pbta is great in that players really only need their Playbook and the Moves in order to participate. At some point, though, it’s absolutely true one thing I see good players do is <em>buy the game</em> if it’s something we’re going to play more than a couple of times experimentally.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/41</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 15:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is such a great thread. I’ve picked up a lot from reading it, especially the aggressive muting when someone else is speaking.</p>
<p>One thought about players picking up the rules - players may not have ready access whether due to money or another factor. I had to order Monsterhearts 2 from my FLGS and it took about two weeks to arrive and cost about $20 or so. $25? Something like that. I’m aware Avery is all about access and actually has lower prices for folks who are struggling with money, but that isn’t true for, just as an example, D&amp;D.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/40</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 20:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Will_H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/will_h">@Will_H</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is a very context-dependent principle, but I am always thankful when another player makes a decision when the party is stuck in prevarication. This can obviously be a bad thing if it removes agency or is rather arbitrary, but even beyond the meta level of keeping things moving it can be a great part of the narrative.</p>
<p>For example, it can be entirely character-driven for 2/3 of your group to be stuck in caution, weighing each possibility and not settling on a good choice - then the more impulsive character just cuts straight through to a resolution, for better or worse. To cite an example from the last 2 hours <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/39</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 21:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MorganMontazh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/morganmontazh">@MorganMontazh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>These may have been here already and I missed them, but things I love:</p>
<ul>
<li>Address your character actions to everybody at the table, not just the GM / MC. (I like to visualize this as, “speaking to the center of the table.”)</li>
<li>Make sure every player gets a chance to have their character determine the main “approach” to a problem, and when they do, look for ways for your character to support that instead of undermining it. (Relevant mostly for party-based games.)</li>
<li>Once your character has gotten what they need in a scene, look for “resolving actions” that will set the scene up to be closed elegantly, or make room for other characters to move the scene in a new direction.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond that, as everybody else says, supporting other characters (and their players!) is what’s all about. The MC has to be the fan of all the PCs, but the players should try to be fans of all the PCs too!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/38</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 04:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think the idea behind “absorb the rules and use them vigorously” is that system matters and when you understand and engage fully with the rules piece, everyone is more likely to have interesting fun. I totally agree that this isn’t essential, and many rules sets (or no rules set at all) get out of the way gracefully, but if the game asks you to understand it, understanding it leads to better outcomes.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/37</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 17:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Will_H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/will_h">@Will_H</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was just pushing for a +1 to my rolls, it’s all just powergaming <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/36</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 09:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@whodo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/whodo">@whodo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So I feel like I might need to clarify on my original post a bit. That thought has mostly come from two aspects that I have experienced repeatedly. I mostly play trad games so it may be that the dynamics work differently with indie games where the balance of expectations/power dynamics are different.</p>
<p>The first aspect is the assertion that its ok for a player to not put in any time outside the session but that its expected from the GM. It just wouldn’t fly if a GM showed up with a rule book and they’d not read a single page of the rules. With trad games especially there is an unspoken expectation that the GM will, at a minimum, have spent the time to learn the game so I don’t feel it is unreasonable to expect the players to do the same. If they’re really adverse to doing it outside of the game then put some time aside during game time. Make it part of session 0 or set aside the first 15 minutes of a session to go over rules/make notes etc.</p>
<p>The second aspect is related to the actual play experience. I’ve run campaigns and listened to APs where even by the end of the campaign there was a player (sometimes more than 1) who still couldn’t follow even the base mechanics. So I could have been clearer in my original post - I wasn’t necessarily talking about complete system mastery but the core mechanics, such as how to make an attack roll in D&amp;D or the specifics of the ability you use every session. Not knowing that 2 sessions in to a new campaign? Fine. Not knowing that 20 sessions in and having to get the GM to walk you through it <em>again</em>, not so fine (as you might be able to tell this is a personal bugbear of mine).</p>
<p>So directly responding to your question - Yes, I think a willingness to learn the system is a mark of a good player, especially in trad games where there is an assumption that the GM will be required to do a lot of work outside of sessions.</p>
<p>Is there a difference between traditional and indie expectations? Yes and no. I think indie games often do a better job of distributing responsibilities, which is helped by the fact that they also tend towards simpler rulesets. There is still an expectation though that the GM/facilitator/whoever brings the game to the group will know all the rules in advance and be able to teach them so you could run into the same issue of players not learning them over time.</p>
<p>Aside - I think it is also something where developers could do a lot to help by including core system reference/cheat sheets for the players - my experience with PbtA games is that while the playbook format can be overwhelming at first having a list of all the moves in front of each player is ultimately a massive help in grasping character intricacies.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/35</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 08:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Maezar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maezar">@Maezar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Cooperate.<br>
Show up on time.<br>
No phones or computers.<br>
Be into it.<br>
Take good notes.<br>
Imagine.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/34</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 23:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sam">@Sam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>Is willingness to deeply grasp a game’s system/setting/genre a characteristic of a good player (especially when doing so means investing effort outside of a live game session)?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Personally, I think that yes, this is a characteristic of good players, but not a necessary one. Like, you can be a great player without doing this, but it’s helpful if you do do it. And a little bit goes a long way - even just daydreaming about your character and the world on the commute over to game night does wonders for getting you in the mood and sparking ideas.</p>
<p>But this is super group dependent. And game dependent. I really don’t want to have to sit around and wait for people to take their turn in 5e combat, but it’s a little easier if a player is skating by in a PBTA game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/33</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 23:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@disquisition]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/disquisition">@disquisition</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m of the mind that you can’t play your character well if you don’t know the rules. Usually that just means the rules they’re likely to interact with directly (if I’m a playing a barbarian, I don’t need to know how the paladin’s lay on hands works, but if I don’t know how rage works then something’s wrong, etc).</p>
<p>That isn’t always necessarily the fault of the player though—plenty of people get sold on games without understanding the level of buy-in needed (great thread on addressing that <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/supplementing-cats-what-does-a-given-rpg-ask-of-its-players/1461">here</a>). Ideally though, the players will understand the amount of work needed to get up to speed, and then do it (or back out).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/32</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 22:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@atminnie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/atminnie">@atminnie</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I love this thread. I have a question.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/whodo">@whodo</a> mentioned taking time between sessions to “learn what your character can do…how their character works mechanically”<br>
<a class="mention" href="/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> listed “absorb the rules and use them vigorously.”</p>
<p>Is willingness to deeply grasp a game’s system/setting/genre a characteristic of a good player (especially when doing so means investing effort outside of a live game session)?</p>
<p>I’ve noticed that a number of systems or settings I’m interested in exploring aren’t really feasible these days (at least among my groups) because even great players are generally averse to demands that go beyond live session time. Is this just a difference between traditional and less traditional games’ expectations of player responsibility? Or is it really just a matter of age (as in, older players stereotypically have less time to spare on the hobby)?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/31</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 22:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Henning]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/henning">@Henning</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You people are plain <strong>amazing</strong>. There is so much brilliant advice in this thread.<br>
I’d like to add another level to the “be bold/play interesting” dimension (excuse the profanity):</p>
<p><strong>Embrace the suck!</strong></p>
<p>It is allright to feel disapointet, frustrated and even angry - as long as it is feelings about your PC, that you’re <em>sharing</em>. It’s actually exciting and powerful, that RPGs enable us to feel this way. Embrace your failures, embrace the loss of narrative choice and embrace that your feelings might actually be inconvient.<br>
<em>Obviously this is not about feelings, that are actually hurting you as a person - the player. This is about emotions concerning solely the character and its role in the fiction.</em><br>
Enjoy the drama unfolding, enjoy the tragedy you get to experience from within the safe space, we strive to create collaboratively. It is part of the amazing ride you’re in for. And it will lead you to new places, you’d never have gone, if you stayed in control all the time.<br>
EDIT: So it is not just about playing bold and risky beforehand - but also about celebrating the negative consequences, that arise through this playing style.</p>
<p>My principle for this kind of emotional buy-in is: <em>Identify with the character, don’t identify the character with you.</em> (I’d be happy to have a native speaker rephrase this in a little more ‘poetic’ manner.)</p>
<p><em>EDIT: I also think GMing and playing in GMless games, teaches you a lot about the love for failure.</em></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/30</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 16:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@inarvan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/inarvan">@inarvan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="19" data-topic="1679" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/shane/40/186_2.png" class="avatar"> shane:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>The non-interruptive feedback is something I think you get really good at when playing Gauntlet Hangouts games. You mute yourself all the time but also not being in the room with others means you can visibly clap, shake your fists, bring your hands to your mouth in shock, etc. All of that is <em>super</em> motivating for the people with the spotlight. You see it in the little squares in the corner and it just amps you up.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is so true. Some of the coolest moments in the games I’ve played have been seeing everyone’s expressions, applause, etc. when the onscreen player is doing cool stuff.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/29</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 15:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sam">@Sam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Jmstar already mentioned this in his excellent list, but I want to underline how much I appreciate it when players have clear in-character goals. Having a goal means you’ve taken the time to understand your character to at least a base level, and it gives the session propulsion from the get-go. And if you have a clear goal, it makes spotlighting you easier, both as a GM and as another player. Even if it’s something small, something that would be the C-plot on an hour long TV drama, I want to know what my fellow players want so I can think about how to help them get it or complicate their efforts.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/28</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 04:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@disquisition]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/disquisition">@disquisition</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Everything here is great, the only thing I’d add is:</p>
<p><strong>Take NPCs seriously.</strong> Try to understand their motives, work with them, against them, love them, hate them, whatever. The specifics depend largely on the tone of the game, just don’t be the player who’s yawning (or rolling their eyes) when the GM is bringing it with an NPC.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/27</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 01:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@juhanaonparas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/juhanaonparas">@juhanaonparas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>In our community, playing your character with your heart is highly valued. Emotionally identifying with the character and what happens in the game, but also playing them with an eye to human foibles big and small. (Sometimes called playing to lose.) When I think of who I want to play with, this is a very important consideration.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/26</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 20:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Crom]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/crom">@Crom</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>this is basically what I came here to post</p>
<p>players who take responsibility for helping flesh out the world and each others’ characters make the game so much more fun- and an MC can only do so much, sometimes</p>
<p>ps: I’m going to start using the MC term cuz I love its parallel in throwing parties/conferences thanks!!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 15:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is one of reasons I think the online character keeper is so great. Since you can see each character’s stats and such it means you know how to play to them.</p>
<p>I am a fan of using Flags in lots of games…</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="http://walkingmind.evilhat.com/2015/09/07/from-bonds-to-flags/" target="_blank" title="02:29PM - 07 September 2015">The Walking Mind – 7 Sep 15</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/427a827e1b53c708ab0698ed1fac2195d6c45b98.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="200" height="200">

<h3><a href="http://walkingmind.evilhat.com/2015/09/07/from-bonds-to-flags/" target="_blank">From Bonds to Flags</a></h3>

<p>Random bit of Dungeon World tech, inspired by a brilliant idea from Judd Karlman’s 1st Quest. When playing with a changing cast of characters, the bond list gets torn to tatters pretty fast. …</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/24</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christopher_Gmelch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christopher_gmelch">@Christopher_Gmelch</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I love this thread! So much good food for thought!</p>
<p>Something I experienced lately, which I liked a lot:<br>
I played Montster of the Week for the first time, and didn’t have the slightest clue about game mechanics. There was this other great player, who had my characters abilities in mind when engaging with my character to trigger a passive move. I found this very helpful, as i’d have completely missed it.</p>
<p>I find this also true for triggering other character flags out of the natural flow of the conversation. Framing scenes for flags is great, but managing to do this in the normal flow is next level for me.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/23</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 08:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@elStiko]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/elstiko">@elStiko</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Freaked me out the first time it happened at my table, because I wasn’t prepared for such assistance. I wish I’d been able to use it more, and pick up hints, but I was reeling.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/22</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 08:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are things you see good players do?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@tomes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/tomes">@tomes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oh my gursh! So much good advice here. So yah, a lot of what’s said above. And to <a class="mention" href="/u/jasoncordova">@jasoncordova</a>’s point about ‘aggressively muting’, that practice online has made me much better about being cognizant of that at the meat-space table, and ensuring I leave space for others to inhabit!</p>
<p>I’m definitely 100% into players asking other players questions about their characters, especially if the player is new or shy or not engaged yet… little things like “oh, how does that look?” or “wow, how does that make you feel?” I mean, it’s sort of what the characters would try to notice about each other in the story, so it just feels on point, and makes me feel like the characters are really connected to each other as a “party” in the narrative.</p>
<p>I’ll add that I love adding a little bit of larping to the table. I don’t mean anything too flagrant or over-the-top (well, depending on the game; sometimes flagrant and over the top is exactly what’s needed)… but just simple things that come up in play that can be given a physical characteristic at the table, or even online. This could be mannerisms, or pretending to smoke a pipe or cigar if that’s in character, or reaching over and putting a jacket on another player because we are supporting the character in a similar manner in the narrative, and so on.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679/21</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 04:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1679-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-things-you-see-good-players-do/1679.rss">What are things you see good players do?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
