<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380</link>
    <description>Continuing the discussion from [Discussion of X-card issues](https://discourse.funtimers.club/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/25):

I want to talk about holding space for trauma and being empathetic at the table. I thought it should be a separate thread from the original post. 

[quote=&quot;William_Nichols, post:25, topic:1346&quot;]
We generally use a couple of modifications at the table:

* Do NOT tell us why you x-carded. We use this rules variant for a reason: Some folks in our extended group have used the x-card as a springboard to discuss real trauma and, well: [We are not Therapists ](http://www.bluestockings.ca/2018/06/we-are-not-therapists-gaming-and-trauma.html?spref=gp&amp;amp;m=1).
* Generally, if it’s a matter of tone or tenor, we’ll say “Try it a different way”. I’ve been on both sides of this, and it’s a great way (for us) to signal that something doesn’t fit the expected tone, but isn’t actively harmful to anything other than the game.

I’ve been asked for clarification on the first point. Without discussing other people’s trauma: I have absolutely seen people use tapping the x-card to sprint in 20 minutes on the abuse they’ve suffered. I want to help my friends, but some of these discussions have been so difficult that I’ve needed to x-card them. They quickly crossed our established lines and veils and as they were regarding the x-card, we’ve felt powerless to stop it.
[/quote]

I definitely agree that we are not therapists and that in most games a game session isn&#39;t the best place for working through trauma, especially without consent of the other players.

However, I do think we need a space for empathy at the table. My thinking here is especially influenced by this post, [PTSD, access to role-playing games, and the Luxton technique by P.H. Lee](http://briebeau.com/thoughty/2019/03/the-luxton-technique-by-p-h-lee/). To quote from it:

&gt; Fundamentally, these meta-techniques center the status quo — the goal is to “deal with” the triggering event, or the triggered person, and then return to regular play as if the interruption had never happened. I submit that, due the nature of PTSD, this approach is fundamentally flawed.
&gt;
&gt;Once I have been triggered, I am in a traumatic experience. No amount of care or concern or comfort or accommodation can untrigger me. The question is not “how do we return Lee to the status quo?” or “how can we stop Lee from having a traumatic experience?” because those goals are impossible. The question is “what kind of traumatic experience is Lee going to have?” It can either be a damaging experience — one that reinforces the trigger and my PTSD — or it can be a healing experience — one that lets me recontextualize the trigger and its part of the trauma into my normal psyche.
&gt;
&gt;Denial and social pressure to “return to normal” are damaging experiences.
&gt;
&gt;Acknowledgement, empowerment, and story-building are healing experiences.
&gt;
&gt;I believe that, in principle,  **good techniques for dealing with PTSD in role-playing games will avoid damaging experiences and center healing experiences.**

How do we respect the boundaries and needs of everyone at the table in regards to trauma? 

One worry that I have as well is accidentally reinforcing the stigma around talking about trauma. Other players aren&#39;t your therapists, but I also believe that people should be able to speak freely about their trauma if they want to.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:41:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ll be thinking about it and will report back if I come to any conclusions! Thanks again for helping shape this discussion.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/14</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 12:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BeckyA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There was nothing in your tone at all - I was merely worried about you reading an assumption into my tone.  But if you have any more thoughts on this with all your professional experience I would really value hearing them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/13</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 08:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I didn’t take it that way at all, Becky! I apologize if my tone came across as at all attacking or anything–I think I was really in a certain mindset after reading We Are Not Therapists and I’m sure that came across in my tone. I really appreciate this discussion; working in group therapy I think a lot about group theory and how groups function and so I end up thinking a lot about how games could be used in a therapeutic context and how gaming groups are similar to and different from therapy and other groups. Bringing up the concept of trauma is an important element of that and it’s giving me a lot to think about.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/12</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is fantastic, and explains quite a bit of what bothers me regarding the expectation of helping with other people’s trauma.</p>
<p>There’s a part you alude to: this is labor. It’s work. It’s skilled work, requiring experience and preferably a degree. It does not seem reasonable to expect our friends to do labor, especially consistently.</p>
<p>Similar and less fraught example: my group rotates who hosts because hosting is labor and affects other people in your household. We go not expect anyone to do it constantly, and this labor is a necessary part of an in-person game.</p>
<p>We should be at least as cognizant when asking people to make a space for trauma that it is <em>hard work</em> and, generally, not our friends job.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/11</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BeckyA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks for replying and I’m sorry if I implied that as a professional it ought to be your job - because you are right that it should not.</p>
<p>Thank you for all your thoughts on this - I think it is really helpful and useful for helping me to work through this.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/10</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jexjthomas]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jexjthomas">@jexjthomas</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So, probably important to say first off, I <em>am</em> a therapist. It’s my job. And I am trained and specialized in working with survivors of trauma and utilizing trauma-informed care. I am probably better equipped than most to facilitate a “healing experience” at a gaming table.</p>
<p>But it’s still not my job.</p>
<p>When I’m running a game, I’m not a therapist. I’m certainly not my table’s therapist, and our sessions aren’t group therapy. There are all sorts of ethical reasons why me acting as a therapist or being expected by my table to act as one is inappropriate. Now, that’s not to say that I would just shut off my skills or not work to take care of someone at my table who is triggered or needs help. I do think it’s a table’s responsibility to <em>take care of each other.</em> Taking care of each other, however, is not the same as creating a “healing experience.”</p>
<p>I read Lee’s post, and I’m glad they made it. There’s a lot of really important stuff in there, particularly about the dangers of using one-size-fits-all tools which can create conflicting access needs. But I do wonder if there aren’t some unrealistic expectations about how tables should respond. I think it was especially interesting reading it back-to-back with bluestocking’s <a href="http://www.bluestockings.ca/2018/06/we-are-not-therapists-gaming-and-trauma.html?spref=gp&amp;m=1" rel="nofollow noopener">We Are Not Therapists</a> which I thought explored some really important facets of consent at the table. The Luxton Technique as written seems like a powerful and useful framework, but I’m wary of any tool that might attempt to force a group to be a captive audience in a conversation they themselves might find triggering or simply didn’t consent to being part of.</p>
<p>At one of my jobs (because as a young mental health professional you’ve gotta hustle, and generally cobble together several part-time jobs to get by) I facilitate general mental health therapy groups. People struggling with all sorts of mental health concerns, with a great diversity of diagnoses, are all working together to learn coping skills and talk about what’s going on in their lives and how it’s affecting them. Unsurprisingly, many of those folks have experienced trauma–almost everyone has experienced some of what we sometimes call the “small-t” traumas (not an actual clinical term, but a useful distinction in certain ways), and a higher than average (compared to the general population) who’ve experienced the “big-T” ones. But in these groups, we shy away from direct discussion of the traumas themselves, because we’ve seen entire groups of six, seven, eight people get triggered and dysregulated by the discussion. We’re not trauma therapy, so we ask that folks not dive into the specifics of their trauma histories. Talk about how it’s affecting them, talk about being triggered, but try to avoid anything that might trigger others. We don’t specifically talk about consent (though maybe we should) but I think that’s part of it too–unloading your trauma on someone else is a <em>lot</em> to ask of them, and it’s not always a fair ask.</p>
<p>For the most part, it works pretty well. When it’s clear someone has a need for trauma-specific therapy, we will work with them one-on-one or make referrals as appropriate. Sometimes someone is just going to unload, though, and maybe they need that, and in the moment it’s hard for them to think about things like consent and triggering others. And it’s always messy and it always requires a ton of processing as a group, facilitated by professional therapists.</p>
<p>So what I think I keep coming to in this discussion is sort of–what is a fair ask? If unloading ends up being something that even professionals can have a hard time working through with the other members of the group, I think it’s a fair boundary–that one can specifically discuss being triggered by something, but it’s not cool to unload or attempt to unpack your trauma history, because even if you feel safe doing so it doesn’t mean it’s safe for the other people at the table.</p>
<p>That, to me, seems like a reasonable boundary, but I wonder if it would still trigger Lee’s feelings of being shut down, of being told they can’t talk about it. I see how that is damaging and the discussion of why the x-card might be a harmful tool for some folks made a lot of sense to me. But how do we figure that out? How would we say, it’s not fair to expect us to create a “healing environment” for you, because we are not trained in doing so, or we have our own stuff, and so on.</p>
<p>And part of the appeal with particularly something like the x-card or lines and veils, but also support flower, OK check in, etc. is that they’re pretty easy to explain and use, and that they’re versatile and easy to sort of “plug and play.” The Luxton technique, is, well, not. Or at least the “frank discussion” part, and any expectation that the table becomes a captive audience (though I’m not clear whether that’s actually a built-in component or not?) And it feels like a really big ask, especially for a casual group. Maybe if you’re going in with the expectation that you’re going to play a game that explores trauma, and everyone is comfortable with each other to a greater degree than probably any of my groups have ever been with each other, and there are folks in the group who are skilled at this kind of thing, then I think it’s appropriate. But I don’t know if it makes sense as a general tool for most tables. I don’t know. I’m definitely curious to hear others’ thoughts on that. Maybe I’m underestimating my tables. I do know that we would be having a very different kind of discussion before playing Monsterhearts or Bluebeard’s Bride than we do before Dungeon World or Monster of the Week.</p>
<p>I feel like I’ve written a ton here but not actually come to any actual conclusion. Which is sometimes part of the process too, but not always helpful. I think my main takeaways are that expecting the other people at our tables to create “healing experiences” is an unrealistic and unfair expectation, but it’s not unrealistic or unfair to expect we take care of each other. I think the discussion then is what that looks like, and how best to do that, and that’s going to vary with every table and every game.</p>
<p>What does “holding space for trauma” mean in that context, then?  I think it means that we work carefully to not create <em>invalidating</em> experiences or environments but establish reasonable and realistic boundaries around what we are capable of in terms of taking care of each other. Because what I’m capable of as a therapist at my job is different than what I’m capable of at a game table with my friends. And it’s important to recognize that and figure out what that really means.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/9</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 03:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="6" data-topic="1380">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/morganmontazh/40/922_2.png" class="avatar"> MorganMontazh:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Thanks for this phrasing — it’s such a great way of stating the guiding principle of safety.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Thanks. It’s not original to me. I am positive I’ve heard this reinforced by <a class="mention" href="/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> and others. It is a pretty important central conceit, and one I try to bring to work and other endeavors.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MorganMontazh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/morganmontazh">@MorganMontazh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="5" data-topic="1380">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/william_nichols/40/530_2.png" class="avatar"> William_Nichols:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>In every game, we make sure to say: You are more important than the game.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Thanks for this phrasing — it’s such a great way of stating the guiding principle of safety.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks; I think you are exactly right to have this be a new thread.</p>
<p>In every game, we make sure to say: You are more important than the game.</p>
<p>I think there’s three broad categories that all merit difference responses from the table:</p>
<ol>
<li>Being taken unawares by your own trauma.</li>
<li>Intentionally playing towards material that is personally dangerous for you, without informing the table beforehand.</li>
<li>The table knowingly and willfully playing with difficult themes, and hitting something that harms one or more players.</li>
</ol>
<p>There is room for differences, but here’s how I’ve typically handle these:</p>
<ol>
<li>Stop the game, help your friend. Play with this friend again.</li>
<li>Stop the game, help your friend. At a safe time, discuss with the person about how to improve their communication to better safeguard everyone at the table.</li>
<li>Stop the game, help your friend. Consider avoiding that subject in future games, because your friend is more important than the game.</li>
</ol>
<p>I think we confuse the short-term issue of dealing with a particular issue that came up with long-term issue of dealing with a player who (seemingly) intentionally and willfully harms themselves at the table, thus centering the attention to their trauma.</p>
<p>And, while this is all from personal experience, it very few people who do this.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/5</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BeckyA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I want to go slow on this discussion because I have a lot of conflicting feelings about ensuring people are safe and making sure that fun is subordinate to that safety and yet I also agree that we are not therapists.  In the situation that Lee describes - I’m not sure what I would do.  I would acknowledge it for definite, I might want to stop the game to get that person some help, or remind them of the open door policy and continue the game.  I’m not really sure.</p>
<p>However, I would be utterly uncomfortable with the idea that I am now supposed to provide a healing experience for that trauma reaction.  Not because I don’t have good intentions but because I (and most other people I know) would be so woefully un-prepared for the task - it is completely outside my skillset.</p>
<p>I think there is a world of difference between not allowing someone to talk about a traumatic thing that happened in the context of explaining why they want to x-card something and wanting the random strangers at the table to facilitate a healing experience that they (likely) have no ability to provide.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:24:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Luiz]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/luiz">@Luiz</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree with João. Also, everyone has different degrees of trauma, and while one player might have the need to share so they can move forward, another might be at a point where they can stop at the X-card and be ok, but hearing about another person’s experience will trigger them.</p>
<p>A lot of us play games so we can get a break from reality, and having to stop your moment of reprieve to do heavy emotional labor for someone might be asking too much.</p>
<p>It’s a complicated situation for sure, I’m glad you brought this up</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seaandsailor]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seaandsailor">@seaandsailor</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Unless playing with close friends or people I have known for a long time, I think discussing other people’s traumas can overstep peoples boundaries and needs really quick. I think trauma needs to be acknowledged and people should empathize with whoever was triggered. The person who was triggered has to decide if they need to step out to seek care or if they’re ok, but not expect the session will halt and everyone will start talking about their trauma. Some people might not be at the right headspace to do that, or not willing to do so.</p>
<p>Now, if people join a game knowing beforehand that some topics of the game might be challenging to some of the players and decide they want this to be a healing experience in case that happens, I’m all in. Not really sure how to frame this before a game starts… sounds easier if you’re playing with long-time friends or people with the right skills for dealing with trauma.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@noellarh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/noellarh">@noellarh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/25">Discussion of X-card issues</a>:</p>
<p>I want to talk about holding space for trauma and being empathetic at the table. I thought it should be a separate thread from the original post.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="25" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/william_nichols/40/530_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/25">Discussion of X-card issues</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p>We generally use a couple of modifications at the table:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do NOT tell us why you x-carded. We use this rules variant for a reason: Some folks in our extended group have used the x-card as a springboard to discuss real trauma and, well: <a href="http://www.bluestockings.ca/2018/06/we-are-not-therapists-gaming-and-trauma.html?spref=gp&amp;m=1" rel="nofollow noopener">We are not Therapists </a>.</li>
<li>Generally, if it’s a matter of tone or tenor, we’ll say “Try it a different way”. I’ve been on both sides of this, and it’s a great way (for us) to signal that something doesn’t fit the expected tone, but isn’t actively harmful to anything other than the game.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve been asked for clarification on the first point. Without discussing other people’s trauma: I have absolutely seen people use tapping the x-card to sprint in 20 minutes on the abuse they’ve suffered. I want to help my friends, but some of these discussions have been so difficult that I’ve needed to x-card them. They quickly crossed our established lines and veils and as they were regarding the x-card, we’ve felt powerless to stop it.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I definitely agree that we are not therapists and that in most games a game session isn’t the best place for working through trauma, especially without consent of the other players.</p>
<p>However, I do think we need a space for empathy at the table. My thinking here is especially influenced by this post, <a href="http://briebeau.com/thoughty/2019/03/the-luxton-technique-by-p-h-lee/" rel="nofollow noopener">PTSD, access to role-playing games, and the Luxton technique by P.H. Lee</a>. To quote from it:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Fundamentally, these meta-techniques center the status quo — the goal is to “deal with” the triggering event, or the triggered person, and then return to regular play as if the interruption had never happened. I submit that, due the nature of PTSD, this approach is fundamentally flawed.</p>
<p>Once I have been triggered, I am in a traumatic experience. No amount of care or concern or comfort or accommodation can untrigger me. The question is not “how do we return Lee to the status quo?” or “how can we stop Lee from having a traumatic experience?” because those goals are impossible. The question is “what kind of traumatic experience is Lee going to have?” It can either be a damaging experience — one that reinforces the trigger and my PTSD — or it can be a healing experience — one that lets me recontextualize the trigger and its part of the trauma into my normal psyche.</p>
<p>Denial and social pressure to “return to normal” are damaging experiences.</p>
<p>Acknowledgement, empowerment, and story-building are healing experiences.</p>
<p>I believe that, in principle,  <strong>good techniques for dealing with PTSD in role-playing games will avoid damaging experiences and center healing experiences.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>How do we respect the boundaries and needs of everyone at the table in regards to trauma?</p>
<p>One worry that I have as well is accidentally reinforcing the stigma around talking about trauma. Other players aren’t your therapists, but I also believe that people should be able to speak freely about their trauma if they want to.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1380-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380.rss">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
