<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611</link>
    <description>I&#39;m still relatively new to playing games online, and getting used to character keepers. I really appreciate the idea of being able to see everyone&#39;s character details on one page.  Given that screen space is a premium, and some games have a lot of detail per character (I&#39;m looking at you DW-and-variants)... I&#39;m thinking about how they might be optimized. (Not that I necessarily have the technical chops do this... but maybe someone who does will be inspired?)

I&#39;m sort of picturing a version of a character keeper where each player has their own &quot;page&quot; with their full character sheet, but it also has a &quot;heads-up&quot; display with the important stuff from the other PCs.  And the GM gets a big picture view with everyone&#39;s most-important-to-the-GM stuff.

So...

What do you find most important/useful to see on a character keeper ***about your OWN character***?  

What do you find most important/useful to see ***about OTHER players&#39; characters***?

When you&#39;re GMing, what do you find most important/useful to see in ***a single place about ALL the characters***?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 16:07:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I prefer all the PCs on the same tab so much that when tweak a Keeper the first thing I do is copy the PC top line for names into all the other pages. Every Keeper should do this, especially on the notes page.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 16:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1611-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611.rss">What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Christo]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christo">@Christo</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I actually prefer them all on the same tab,  both as a player and GM. It makes it so much easier to, at a glance,  see what relationships or moves the players want to bring into play. As a player,  it also makes it easier for me to build my character to complement the other characters for a more interesting story.</p>
<p>I always put a spot for a character image at the top because that really helps me visualize them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 22:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1611-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611.rss">What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeremy_Strandberg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>From my limited personal experience, answers would be:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Most useful about MY character</strong>:  as much as possible, really (stats/traits, moves/powers, etc.). Particularly things that change on the regular (e.g. HP, conditions, inventory, spells prepped).  For a game I’m familiar with, a quick list of the moves/powers/traits would suffice… ideally with an ability to expand/hover/jump to the details.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Most useful about OTHERS’ characters</strong>:  Name, pronouns. Picture (though with ability to shrink/collapse?).  Role-playing hooks for how to interact with them (e.g. flags, bonds, keys, drives).  Conditions or other significant, temporary states.  Less important but nice:  abbreviated stat array (so I can tell who’s good/bad at things).  Maybe the names and triggers of moves/powers (but not full effect), to help watching out for when they might apply.  Their inventory, specific powers, XP, spells prepared, etc. are at the bottom of the list, I think.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>As GM, most useful about EVERYONE’s characters</strong>:  I don’t really know, as I don’t have enough experience. My gut says name/pronouns/look/collapsible picture.  Roleplaying hooks (flags/bonds/keys/drives/etc.).  Conditions, current harm/HP.  List of moves + triggers, but not full effects.  If tracking inventory, maybe level of load (e.g. 8 out of 12 or “Light load”) but no more.  Maybe a list of important NPCs/relationships.</p>
</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1611-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611.rss">What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeremy_Strandberg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m still relatively new to playing games online, and getting used to character keepers. I really appreciate the idea of being able to see everyone’s character details on one page.  Given that screen space is a premium, and some games have a lot of detail per character (I’m looking at you DW-and-variants)… I’m thinking about how they might be optimized. (Not that I necessarily have the technical chops do this… but maybe someone who does will be inspired?)</p>
<p>I’m sort of picturing a version of a character keeper where each player has their own “page” with their full character sheet, but it also has a “heads-up” display with the important stuff from the other PCs.  And the GM gets a big picture view with everyone’s most-important-to-the-GM stuff.</p>
<p>So…</p>
<p>What do you find most important/useful to see on a character keeper <em><strong>about your OWN character</strong></em>?</p>
<p>What do you find most important/useful to see <em><strong>about OTHER players’ characters</strong></em>?</p>
<p>When you’re GMing, what do you find most important/useful to see in <em><strong>a single place about ALL the characters</strong></em>?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 14:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1611-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-aspects-of-a-character-keeper-do-you-find-most-useful-during-play/1611.rss">What aspects of a Character Keeper do you find most useful during play?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
