<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>L5R: Spring Festival of the Topaz Academy</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/l5r-spring-festival-of-the-topaz-academy/2866</link>
    <description>The session is scheduled for 3 hours.

The session will be recorded. Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.

Character creation should be handled before the first session a player joins.

*“Go forth and conquer in the name of Heaven; only then you may sit at my side.”* 

*Lord Onnotangu*

Welcome to the Emerald Republic, a coligation of free peoples fighting for democracy, liberty and self-determination in a world under the control of divine tyrants. 

Some highlights about his alternate setting for L5R:

**The Kami Never Fell:**  Lord Moon has send his children forth into the world to conquer and remake it in the image of his Heavenly Court. 

**Rokugan is besieged by the Kami:**  The Dragon Hegemonies founded by the Kami constantly threaten the mortal inhabitants of the Emerald Republic by military, cultural and economic means. 

**Mortals, not humans:**  The Emerald Republic fully accepted nonhuman mortal species into their tapestry, as well as humans of different ancestries that came there escaping the wrath of the Kami. 

**Divinity, not Gods:**  The teachings of Shinsei, the hatred of Tengoku and the abundance of supernatural bloodlines: all these factors led to mortals developing their own ways to interact with the spiritual world. 

**Crownless Kingdoms, No Great Clans:**  Instead of founding Great Clans, each Kami created their own kingdom. They evolved into the five hegemonies and the five cantons of the Republic. 

*Tsuma is like many of the smaller communes between the bustling cities of the Emerald Lands and the Scorpion League. However, the noble families that hold sway of these lands during the rule of dragons gave their estates to the education of the next generations in arts -- a tradition still mantained by their distant descendants and those locals of artistic or scholarly bent.*

*Every year, communes, clans and people across the Republic send their brightest youths - specially those with ambitions for Senatorial and Assembly positions - to Tsuma. During a week-long festival, they will show their skills and talents, champion their community and hopefully earn the much-desired title of Topaz Blossom that has been associated with promising individuals ; the connections they establish on this event will serve them well, and maybe get them a position in the federal institutions Republic or at the very least to enroll in Tsuma Academy.*

This game abides by the Gauntlet Inclusivity Policy. The X-Card and Lines&amp;Veils will be in use as well as any other safety tool players deem necessary.



[date=2019-09-28 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFcYwar4Uxuw53gjmH
[date=2019-10-05 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFccXBS1CGM_xmGgAd
[date=2019-10-12 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFckgGYEK2swC9aja3
[date=2019-10-19 time=20:00:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFcyK99Ct1lMhXEg_S</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 15:23:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/l5r-spring-festival-of-the-topaz-academy/2866.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>L5R: Spring Festival of the Topaz Academy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Ludovico_Alves]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ludovico_alves">@Ludovico_Alves</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The session is scheduled for 3 hours.</p>
<p>The session will be recorded. Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.</p>
<p>Character creation should be handled before the first session a player joins.</p>
<p><em>“Go forth and conquer in the name of Heaven; only then you may sit at my side.”</em></p>
<p><em>Lord Onnotangu</em></p>
<p>Welcome to the Emerald Republic, a coligation of free peoples fighting for democracy, liberty and self-determination in a world under the control of divine tyrants.</p>
<p>Some highlights about his alternate setting for L5R:</p>
<p><strong>The Kami Never Fell:</strong>  Lord Moon has send his children forth into the world to conquer and remake it in the image of his Heavenly Court.</p>
<p><strong>Rokugan is besieged by the Kami:</strong>  The Dragon Hegemonies founded by the Kami constantly threaten the mortal inhabitants of the Emerald Republic by military, cultural and economic means.</p>
<p><strong>Mortals, not humans:</strong>  The Emerald Republic fully accepted nonhuman mortal species into their tapestry, as well as humans of different ancestries that came there escaping the wrath of the Kami.</p>
<p><strong>Divinity, not Gods:</strong>  The teachings of Shinsei, the hatred of Tengoku and the abundance of supernatural bloodlines: all these factors led to mortals developing their own ways to interact with the spiritual world.</p>
<p><strong>Crownless Kingdoms, No Great Clans:</strong>  Instead of founding Great Clans, each Kami created their own kingdom. They evolved into the five hegemonies and the five cantons of the Republic.</p>
<p><em>Tsuma is like many of the smaller communes between the bustling cities of the Emerald Lands and the Scorpion League. However, the noble families that hold sway of these lands during the rule of dragons gave their estates to the education of the next generations in arts – a tradition still mantained by their distant descendants and those locals of artistic or scholarly bent.</em></p>
<p><em>Every year, communes, clans and people across the Republic send their brightest youths - specially those with ambitions for Senatorial and Assembly positions - to Tsuma. During a week-long festival, they will show their skills and talents, champion their community and hopefully earn the much-desired title of Topaz Blossom that has been associated with promising individuals ; the connections they establish on this event will serve them well, and maybe get them a position in the federal institutions Republic or at the very least to enroll in Tsuma Academy.</em></p>
<p>This game abides by the Gauntlet Inclusivity Policy. The X-Card and Lines&amp;Veils will be in use as well as any other safety tool players deem necessary.</p>
<p><span data-date="2019-09-28" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2019-09-28T18:00:00Z UTC">2019-09-28T18:00:00Z</span> Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFcYwar4Uxuw53gjmH" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFcYwar4Uxuw53gjmH</a><br>
<span data-date="2019-10-05" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2019-10-05T18:00:00Z UTC">2019-10-05T18:00:00Z</span> Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFccXBS1CGM_xmGgAd" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFccXBS1CGM_xmGgAd</a><br>
<span data-date="2019-10-12" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2019-10-12T18:00:00Z UTC">2019-10-12T18:00:00Z</span> Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFckgGYEK2swC9aja3" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFckgGYEK2swC9aja3</a><br>
<span data-date="2019-10-19" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2019-10-19T18:00:00Z UTC">2019-10-19T18:00:00Z</span> Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFcyK99Ct1lMhXEg_S" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LmFcyK99Ct1lMhXEg_S</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/l5r-spring-festival-of-the-topaz-academy/2866/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/l5r-spring-festival-of-the-topaz-academy/2866/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 15:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2866-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/l5r-spring-festival-of-the-topaz-academy/2866.rss">L5R: Spring Festival of the Topaz Academy</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
