<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Crossroads Carnival: A Town called Tomorrow (September)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crossroads-carnival-a-town-called-tomorrow-september/2632</link>
    <description>![Save%20the%20date|500x500](upload://uDiE16XGJZ8AwPPkmKzKkFdock7.jpeg) )

&gt; *Dust swirls and dry wind shout their cursed heat upon the husked lands of man. Upon them, nothing grows. Nothing Will. &quot;Famine hast come&quot; cry the faithful in desperation, &quot;the end shall soon follow&quot;. They are not wrong. Yet, solace comes. Not in feed or miracles. For it wears stripes and patched shoes, wielding the scent of burnt oil and lard. The Carnival arries. Birthing hope from misery.*

**Crossroads Carnival: A Town called Tomorrow**  is a series that will run for 2.5 hours during the wednesdays of September. Signing in all session is not required, but greatly encouraged. Sessions will be streamed live and recorded, for the use of the author at a later date. This series will include playtest material. You&#39;ll be asked to provide feedback on said material after the conclusion of a session in which you&#39;ve participated.

**On the Game Itself:**  Crossroads Carnival is a Powered by the Apocalypse game placing the players in Dust Bowl America. The Great Depression is in full swing, and the world is going to hell. In their desperation the rubes turn to every sort of dark magic and eldritch being to save themselves and theirs. The players assume the roles of carnival performers who are as real creatures of myth and legend during the night as they are performers during the day. They work to halt the advent of darkness, while fighting the prejudices and hatred of the people they are trying to save.

**Content Warning:**  As described by the game itself  *&quot;Crossroads Carnival contains abuse of all kinds (physical, emotional, and sexual), shaming, violence, animal abuse, and almost every kind of othering (being treated like you don’t belong in society)&quot;.*  However, safety tools will be in full effect throughout this series to ensure the safety of the participants.

* The  **X-Card**  and  **O-Card**  will be in effect.
* **Lines and Veils**  will be discussed and established before the game begins.
* The  **Open Door**  policy will be in effect.
-----
* [Session 1/3](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjvRi3RI237t1HyUK8X)[date=2019-09-11 time=19:30:00 timezone=&quot;America/Panama&quot;]
* [Session 2/3](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjvRsYCB7HgS3xA1sXh)[date=2019-09-18 time=19:30:00 timezone=&quot;America/Panama&quot;]
* [Session 3/3](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjvS88mYUHP6TNrF-8l)[date=2019-09-25 time=19:30:00 timezone=&quot;America/Panama&quot;]</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 16:08:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crossroads-carnival-a-town-called-tomorrow-september/2632.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Crossroads Carnival: A Town called Tomorrow (September)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dolan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dolan">@Dolan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/d6b283dba872aaac063e42913213a540259c64ff.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/uDiE16XGJZ8AwPPkmKzKkFdock7.jpeg?dl=1" title="Save%20the%20date" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/d/d6b283dba872aaac063e42913213a540259c64ff_2_500x500.jpeg" alt="Save%20the%20date" data-base62-sha1="uDiE16XGJZ8AwPPkmKzKkFdock7" width="500" height="500" srcset="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/d/d6b283dba872aaac063e42913213a540259c64ff_2_500x500.jpeg, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/d/d6b283dba872aaac063e42913213a540259c64ff_2_750x750.jpeg 1.5x, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/d/d6b283dba872aaac063e42913213a540259c64ff_2_1000x1000.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/d/d6b283dba872aaac063e42913213a540259c64ff_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Save%20the%20date</span><span class="informations">1080×1080 402 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div> )</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Dust swirls and dry wind shout their cursed heat upon the husked lands of man. Upon them, nothing grows. Nothing Will. “Famine hast come” cry the faithful in desperation, “the end shall soon follow”. They are not wrong. Yet, solace comes. Not in feed or miracles. For it wears stripes and patched shoes, wielding the scent of burnt oil and lard. The Carnival arries. Birthing hope from misery.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Crossroads Carnival: A Town called Tomorrow</strong>  is a series that will run for 2.5 hours during the wednesdays of September. Signing in all session is not required, but greatly encouraged. Sessions will be streamed live and recorded, for the use of the author at a later date. This series will include playtest material. You’ll be asked to provide feedback on said material after the conclusion of a session in which you’ve participated.</p>
<p><strong>On the Game Itself:</strong>  Crossroads Carnival is a Powered by the Apocalypse game placing the players in Dust Bowl America. The Great Depression is in full swing, and the world is going to hell. In their desperation the rubes turn to every sort of dark magic and eldritch being to save themselves and theirs. The players assume the roles of carnival performers who are as real creatures of myth and legend during the night as they are performers during the day. They work to halt the advent of darkness, while fighting the prejudices and hatred of the people they are trying to save.</p>
<p><strong>Content Warning:</strong>  As described by the game itself  <em>“Crossroads Carnival contains abuse of all kinds (physical, emotional, and sexual), shaming, violence, animal abuse, and almost every kind of othering (being treated like you don’t belong in society)”.</em>  However, safety tools will be in full effect throughout this series to ensure the safety of the participants.</p>
<ul>
<li>The  <strong>X-Card</strong>  and  <strong>O-Card</strong>  will be in effect.</li>
<li>
<strong>Lines and Veils</strong>  will be discussed and established before the game begins.</li>
<li>The  <strong>Open Door</strong>  policy will be in effect.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjvRi3RI237t1HyUK8X" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 1/3</a><span data-date="2019-09-11" data-time="19:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Panama" data-email-preview="2019-09-12T00:30:00Z UTC">2019-09-12T00:30:00Z</span>
</li>
<li>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjvRsYCB7HgS3xA1sXh" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 2/3</a><span data-date="2019-09-18" data-time="19:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Panama" data-email-preview="2019-09-19T00:30:00Z UTC">2019-09-19T00:30:00Z</span>
</li>
<li>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-LjvS88mYUHP6TNrF-8l" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 3/3</a><span data-date="2019-09-25" data-time="19:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/Panama" data-email-preview="2019-09-26T00:30:00Z UTC">2019-09-26T00:30:00Z</span>
</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crossroads-carnival-a-town-called-tomorrow-september/2632/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crossroads-carnival-a-town-called-tomorrow-september/2632/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 16:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2632-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crossroads-carnival-a-town-called-tomorrow-september/2632.rss">Crossroads Carnival: A Town called Tomorrow (September)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
