<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Once More Into the Void - Thursdays 18:30 GMT in May</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/once-more-into-the-void-thursdays-18-30-gmt-in-may/6957</link>
    <description>*Once, you were a crew of smugglers, ne&#39;er-do-wells, scoundrels with a heart of gold, getting into and out of scrapes with the heavy-handed authorities. Maybe you started a revolution. Maybe you caused an the Grand Reptile&#39;s empire to fall. You made some money, that&#39;s for sure, and got a few scars, some more sexy than others.*

*Then you split up, maybe you just wanted peace, or your own island, or you were a functionary in the newly-minted alliance for freedom or something like that. Maybe you were just fed up with everyone&#39;s bullshit. You&#39;ve avoided each other ever since, so it&#39;s probably the last one.*

*But now your old Captain is back with a final mission. Your old enemy, the Grand Reptile, appears to be back, and they seem to be stronger - and richer - than ever. You need to confront them, take them down, or finally figure out what it was all about. Are you with the Captain?*

This is a game of Once More Into the Void, by Jamile Nedjadi. It&#39;s been financed on Kickstarter recently, but a playable version is already out, so we&#39;ll use this (unless a newer version appears,) We&#39;ll aim for three session so we&#39;ll have enough time to develop the characters and the setting - it&#39;s possible that we finish in two sessions, but we&#39;ll talk about that if &amp; when it happens.

The default setting for Once More Into the Void is a science-fiction-setting, so we&#39;ll go with that. Everything else we&#39;ll just make up during the session. It&#39;s a gm-ful game, so I&#39;ll facilitate and guide, but I&#39;ll play a character as well.

Kalum will be a guest star for these games.

Being able to attend all sessions is ideal but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.

No experience is needed; everything will be taught in the game.

**Venue** : Zoom

**Contact** : Players will receive an e-mail to check in about a week before the start of the game.

We will discuss Content, Aim, Tone, and Safety Tools in the first sessions. We will use Lines &amp; Veils, the X-Card, and the Open Door policy, and I will prepare a character keeper as a shared document.

The  **Gauntlet Code of Conduct**  will be in effect for this gam **e**  (https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html)!

Session 1: [date=2021-07-08 time=20:30:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fTyjwwGBykBSuaAd3
Session 2: [date=2021-07-15 time=20:30:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fUCDi0muxcQkokwdr
Session 3: [date=2021-07-22 time=20:30:00 timezone=&quot;Europe/Berlin&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fUJvAcRcI7cl33_rn</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 15:31:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/once-more-into-the-void-thursdays-18-30-gmt-in-may/6957.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Once More Into the Void - Thursdays 18:30 GMT in May</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SabineV5]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Once, you were a crew of smugglers, ne’er-do-wells, scoundrels with a heart of gold, getting into and out of scrapes with the heavy-handed authorities. Maybe you started a revolution. Maybe you caused an the Grand Reptile’s empire to fall. You made some money, that’s for sure, and got a few scars, some more sexy than others.</em></p>
<p><em>Then you split up, maybe you just wanted peace, or your own island, or you were a functionary in the newly-minted alliance for freedom or something like that. Maybe you were just fed up with everyone’s bullshit. You’ve avoided each other ever since, so it’s probably the last one.</em></p>
<p><em>But now your old Captain is back with a final mission. Your old enemy, the Grand Reptile, appears to be back, and they seem to be stronger - and richer - than ever. You need to confront them, take them down, or finally figure out what it was all about. Are you with the Captain?</em></p>
<p>This is a game of Once More Into the Void, by Jamile Nedjadi. It’s been financed on Kickstarter recently, but a playable version is already out, so we’ll use this (unless a newer version appears,) We’ll aim for three session so we’ll have enough time to develop the characters and the setting - it’s possible that we finish in two sessions, but we’ll talk about that if &amp; when it happens.</p>
<p>The default setting for Once More Into the Void is a science-fiction-setting, so we’ll go with that. Everything else we’ll just make up during the session. It’s a gm-ful game, so I’ll facilitate and guide, but I’ll play a character as well.</p>
<p>Kalum will be a guest star for these games.</p>
<p>Being able to attend all sessions is ideal but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend.</p>
<p>No experience is needed; everything will be taught in the game.</p>
<p><strong>Venue</strong> : Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong> : Players will receive an e-mail to check in about a week before the start of the game.</p>
<p>We will discuss Content, Aim, Tone, and Safety Tools in the first sessions. We will use Lines &amp; Veils, the X-Card, and the Open Door policy, and I will prepare a character keeper as a shared document.</p>
<p>The  <strong>Gauntlet Code of Conduct</strong>  will be in effect for this gam <strong>e</strong>  (<a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a>)!</p>
<p>Session 1: <span data-date="2021-07-08" data-time="20:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-07-08T18:30:00Z UTC">2021-07-08T18:30:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fTyjwwGBykBSuaAd3">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fTyjwwGBykBSuaAd3</a><br>
Session 2: <span data-date="2021-07-15" data-time="20:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-07-15T18:30:00Z UTC">2021-07-15T18:30:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fUCDi0muxcQkokwdr">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fUCDi0muxcQkokwdr</a><br>
Session 3: <span data-date="2021-07-22" data-time="20:30:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="Europe/Berlin" data-email-preview="2021-07-22T18:30:00Z UTC">2021-07-22T18:30:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fUJvAcRcI7cl33_rn">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M_fUJvAcRcI7cl33_rn</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/once-more-into-the-void-thursdays-18-30-gmt-in-may/6957/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/once-more-into-the-void-thursdays-18-30-gmt-in-may/6957/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 15:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6957-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/once-more-into-the-void-thursdays-18-30-gmt-in-may/6957.rss">Once More Into the Void - Thursdays 18:30 GMT in May</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
