<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hometown Holidays: Falling Leaves And Falling In Love</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hometown-holidays-falling-leaves-and-falling-in-love/7607</link>
    <description>https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MoqtdVh8dsqlttkkDZJ

Thursday, November 25th 2021, 1:00 p.m. Central time (depending on daylight saving time, this should be 6 or 7 p.m. in the UK, and 7 or 8 p.m. in the EU)

**NUMBER OF SESSIONS:**  1

**DURATION:**  3 hours

**NUMBER OF PLAYERS:**  4

**CONTENT WARNING:**  This game basically allows players to act out a Hallmark Channel holiday movie. As such, there shouldn&#39;t be any violence or drug usage. This game is intended to be gentle, perhaps a little silly, and as the developer notes, &quot;inclusive of all races, faiths, disabilities, and sexual identities and orientations. The movies this game parodies are typically Christmas-themed and predominantly starring straight able-bodied white people; by no means does your story have to fit these parameters. Please tailor the experience as you see fit for the comfort and enjoyment of you and your friends.&quot;

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

&quot;It’s the holiday season once again in your quaint small town. There are carols to be sung, decorations to be hung, and charming small businesses to be run. But with all of this holly-jolly hubbub, who has time for love? If only there was an equal-parts gorgeous and bland idiot to show you what this time of year is all about... As it turns out, there is!

However, you are not the only one looking for love ... and this town ain’t big enough for all of you (it’s a small town, remember). Flirt, blunder, and trope your way to romance and earn your single chaste kiss with the dazzling dullard of your dreams.&quot;

I unironically watch and enjoy Hallmark Channel movies. They&#39;re as formulaic as it&#39;s possible to get, and yet there&#39;s something compelling about them. They&#39;re calming, and gentle, and yet I want to see other stories told in this framework. Hometown Holidays was one of the most delightfully off-kilter games I saw in ZineQuest 3, and I&#39;ve been waiting for the holiday season to get it to the table (I hope the summer and spring movie rules that I begged for during the campaign come along eventually). Hometown Holidays allows, and in my reading, actively encourages players to break the mold of Hallmark Channel movies but tell similarly gentle, trope-filled stories with the characters you want to see.

Please join me in creating a light-hearted, silly, playful, and above all else,  *fun*  story about flirting, crushes, and love during the holidays.

-----------------------------------------------------------------------------

**SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:**  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet&#39;s Community Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html

**RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:**  11/18/2021 23:00 Central Time

**SET UP INFO:**  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately two days before the game.

**BREAKS:**  2 five minute breaks

**RECORDED:**  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.

**PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:**  No experience required, rules will be taught.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 06:43:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hometown-holidays-falling-leaves-and-falling-in-love/7607.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hometown Holidays: Falling Leaves And Falling In Love</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MoqtdVh8dsqlttkkDZJ" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MoqtdVh8dsqlttkkDZJ</a></p>
<p>Thursday, November 25th 2021, 1:00 p.m. Central time (depending on daylight saving time, this should be 6 or 7 p.m. in the UK, and 7 or 8 p.m. in the EU)</p>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF SESSIONS:</strong>  1</p>
<p><strong>DURATION:</strong>  3 hours</p>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF PLAYERS:</strong>  4</p>
<p><strong>CONTENT WARNING:</strong>  This game basically allows players to act out a Hallmark Channel holiday movie. As such, there shouldn’t be any violence or drug usage. This game is intended to be gentle, perhaps a little silly, and as the developer notes, “inclusive of all races, faiths, disabilities, and sexual identities and orientations. The movies this game parodies are typically Christmas-themed and predominantly starring straight able-bodied white people; by no means does your story have to fit these parameters. Please tailor the experience as you see fit for the comfort and enjoyment of you and your friends.”</p>
<hr>
<p>"It’s the holiday season once again in your quaint small town. There are carols to be sung, decorations to be hung, and charming small businesses to be run. But with all of this holly-jolly hubbub, who has time for love? If only there was an equal-parts gorgeous and bland idiot to show you what this time of year is all about… As it turns out, there is!</p>
<p>However, you are not the only one looking for love … and this town ain’t big enough for all of you (it’s a small town, remember). Flirt, blunder, and trope your way to romance and earn your single chaste kiss with the dazzling dullard of your dreams."</p>
<p>I unironically watch and enjoy Hallmark Channel movies. They’re as formulaic as it’s possible to get, and yet there’s something compelling about them. They’re calming, and gentle, and yet I want to see other stories told in this framework. Hometown Holidays was one of the most delightfully off-kilter games I saw in ZineQuest 3, and I’ve been waiting for the holiday season to get it to the table (I hope the summer and spring movie rules that I begged for during the campaign come along eventually). Hometown Holidays allows, and in my reading, actively encourages players to break the mold of Hallmark Channel movies but tell similarly gentle, trope-filled stories with the characters you want to see.</p>
<p>Please join me in creating a light-hearted, silly, playful, and above all else,  <em>fun</em>  story about flirting, crushes, and love during the holidays.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:</strong>  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet’s Community Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a></p>
<p><strong>RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:</strong>  11/18/2021 23:00 Central Time</p>
<p><strong>SET UP INFO:</strong>  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately two days before the game.</p>
<p><strong>BREAKS:</strong>  2 five minute breaks</p>
<p><strong>RECORDED:</strong>  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.</p>
<p><strong>PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:</strong>  No experience required, rules will be taught.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hometown-holidays-falling-leaves-and-falling-in-love/7607/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hometown-holidays-falling-leaves-and-falling-in-love/7607/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 06:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7607-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hometown-holidays-falling-leaves-and-falling-in-love/7607.rss">Hometown Holidays: Falling Leaves And Falling In Love</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
