<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>[Let&#39;s Go To Magic School] Help with two Playbook moves</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lets-go-to-magic-school-help-with-two-playbook-moves/8514</link>
    <description>Hello y&#39;all who walk the gauntlet,

since you were very helpful already, when I presented two basic moves, I&#39;d like to share in your wisdom now, concerning two playbook moves. I&#39;m making a game about kids at a magic school. 

The thing is, after several one shots and one longer campaign, now one took them ever.

They are also kinda samey.

Current versions:

    Sucker for Rules (The Studious One)
     When you admonish someone about the school rules, roll +Virtue. On a hit, they will hesitate in what they are doing and you take +1 forward against them. On a 10+, you may choose to make them suffer.

     Outsider Perspective (The Upstart)
     When you point out an injustice or absurdity in the school&#39;s society, roll +Worldliness. On a 7-9, choose one. On a 10+, you get both: 
      - They must stop to explain themselves or suffer. 
      - They mark inspiration, if they heed your call.
    
Now for the Studious One, I&#39;m thinking:

     Sucker For Rules
     When you quote the rules, you may give any one person making it so (including yourself) +1 forward.

That&#39;s simple and effective. I found that having at least some bonus moves, isn&#39;t bad. The two I have, have been quite popular. Is the phrasing good? Am I overlooking something?

For the Outsider Perspective, I&#39;m not so sure. I kinda like the idea of having characters of this playbook comment on the School. It&#39;s basically the Harry Potter playbook. Giving someone Inspiration (XP) is a pretty powerful effect, as it&#39;s the only move in the game that does so.

Should I just play this up? Turn it into more wide eyed wonder? What do you think.

@SabineV5</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 08:58:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lets-go-to-magic-school-help-with-two-playbook-moves/8514.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>[Let&#39;s Go To Magic School] Help with two Playbook moves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@holothuroid]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/holothuroid">@holothuroid</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello y’all who walk the gauntlet,</p>
<p>since you were very helpful already, when I presented two basic moves, I’d like to share in your wisdom now, concerning two playbook moves. I’m making a game about kids at a magic school.</p>
<p>The thing is, after several one shots and one longer campaign, now one took them ever.</p>
<p>They are also kinda samey.</p>
<p>Current versions:</p>
<pre><code>Sucker for Rules (The Studious One)
 When you admonish someone about the school rules, roll +Virtue. On a hit, they will hesitate in what they are doing and you take +1 forward against them. On a 10+, you may choose to make them suffer.

 Outsider Perspective (The Upstart)
 When you point out an injustice or absurdity in the school's society, roll +Worldliness. On a 7-9, choose one. On a 10+, you get both: 
  - They must stop to explain themselves or suffer. 
  - They mark inspiration, if they heed your call.
</code></pre>
<p>Now for the Studious One, I’m thinking:</p>
<pre><code> Sucker For Rules
 When you quote the rules, you may give any one person making it so (including yourself) +1 forward.
</code></pre>
<p>That’s simple and effective. I found that having at least some bonus moves, isn’t bad. The two I have, have been quite popular. Is the phrasing good? Am I overlooking something?</p>
<p>For the Outsider Perspective, I’m not so sure. I kinda like the idea of having characters of this playbook comment on the School. It’s basically the Harry Potter playbook. Giving someone Inspiration (XP) is a pretty powerful effect, as it’s the only move in the game that does so.</p>
<p>Should I just play this up? Turn it into more wide eyed wonder? What do you think.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/sabinev5">@SabineV5</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lets-go-to-magic-school-help-with-two-playbook-moves/8514/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lets-go-to-magic-school-help-with-two-playbook-moves/8514/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8514-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/lets-go-to-magic-school-help-with-two-playbook-moves/8514.rss">[Let&#39;s Go To Magic School] Help with two Playbook moves</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
