<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Girl Underground: Halloweenland (4 sessions, October, Fridays 6pm US Central)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-underground-halloweenland-4-sessions-october-fridays-6pm-us-central/7380</link>
    <description>This is for a four-session run of **Girl Underground** , scheduled for 6:00pm US Central time on Fridays in October *with the exception of 10/15 (GCOG weekend)* . Prior experience with Girl Underground is not expected (rules will be taught during and throughout play). I will send out a group email about a week before the first session to confirm everyone’s intent to play and to provide set-up and invitation details.

This particular run of Girl Underground will follow a curious Girl who, on Halloween night, finds herself spirited away into a wondrous, festive &quot;Halloweenland&quot; full of dreadful and horrifying terrors she must overcome to find her way home. Luckily, the Girl has found friends she can rely on, and who rely on her in turn. These friends may range from friendly-yet-scary monsters, to talking black cats and mysterious owls, to lost and lonely ghosts, to any other number of Halloween-themed denizens of the underground.

**Essentially, it&#39;s Girl Underground, but Halloween flavor and with just a hint of horror while staying mostly PG-rated. Touchstones include *Nightmare Before Christmas, Coraline* , and *American McGee&#39;s Alice.***

Because of the type of story Girl Underground tells, we go into it knowing the Girl will achieve her goals and make it home. What we play to find out is how she does it, and what she learns about herself while underground. The other world she finds herself in represents that space between childhood and adulthood--a strange and surprising time where she can discover who she is and what she believes.

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIKrGeI3jWLVm7VH30

Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjILTejCEMZ90xWX9XQ

Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIM4YSJBMmYxauS9yP

Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIMNWhCydk5sS2wwRC

**System :** Girl Underground

**Duration :** Four 3-hour sessions

**Breaks :** Short breaks at the top of each hour-ish (5-10 minutes)

**Venue :** Zoom

**Recording :** With permission from all participants before and after the session

**Attendance :** Open door policy applies--no pressure if you can&#39;t attend every session! Just remember to un-RSVP from any sessions you drop from.

**Safety :** Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.

This game will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the calendar posting and send me a heads-up. All-access sign-up opens on September 15 at Midnight US Central time.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 05:47:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-underground-halloweenland-4-sessions-october-fridays-6pm-us-central/7380.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Girl Underground: Halloweenland (4 sessions, October, Fridays 6pm US Central)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@David_S]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/david_s">@David_S</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is for a four-session run of <strong>Girl Underground</strong> , scheduled for 6:00pm US Central time on Fridays in October <em>with the exception of 10/15 (GCOG weekend)</em> . Prior experience with Girl Underground is not expected (rules will be taught during and throughout play). I will send out a group email about a week before the first session to confirm everyone’s intent to play and to provide set-up and invitation details.</p>
<p>This particular run of Girl Underground will follow a curious Girl who, on Halloween night, finds herself spirited away into a wondrous, festive “Halloweenland” full of dreadful and horrifying terrors she must overcome to find her way home. Luckily, the Girl has found friends she can rely on, and who rely on her in turn. These friends may range from friendly-yet-scary monsters, to talking black cats and mysterious owls, to lost and lonely ghosts, to any other number of Halloween-themed denizens of the underground.</p>
<p><strong>Essentially, it’s Girl Underground, but Halloween flavor and with just a hint of horror while staying mostly PG-rated. Touchstones include <em>Nightmare Before Christmas, Coraline</em> , and <em>American McGee’s Alice.</em></strong></p>
<p>Because of the type of story Girl Underground tells, we go into it knowing the Girl will achieve her goals and make it home. What we play to find out is how she does it, and what she learns about herself while underground. The other world she finds herself in represents that space between childhood and adulthood–a strange and surprising time where she can discover who she is and what she believes.</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIKrGeI3jWLVm7VH30" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIKrGeI3jWLVm7VH30</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjILTejCEMZ90xWX9XQ" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjILTejCEMZ90xWX9XQ</a></p>
<p>Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIM4YSJBMmYxauS9yP" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIM4YSJBMmYxauS9yP</a></p>
<p>Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIMNWhCydk5sS2wwRC" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MjIMNWhCydk5sS2wwRC</a></p>
<p><strong>System :</strong> Girl Underground</p>
<p><strong>Duration :</strong> Four 3-hour sessions</p>
<p><strong>Breaks :</strong> Short breaks at the top of each hour-ish (5-10 minutes)</p>
<p><strong>Venue :</strong> Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Recording :</strong> With permission from all participants before and after the session</p>
<p><strong>Attendance :</strong> Open door policy applies–no pressure if you can’t attend every session! Just remember to un-RSVP from any sessions you drop from.</p>
<p><strong>Safety :</strong> Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, Open Door Policy. Tools can be modified throughout the game to suit player needs.</p>
<p>This game will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p>If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the calendar posting and send me a heads-up. All-access sign-up opens on September 15 at Midnight US Central time.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-underground-halloweenland-4-sessions-october-fridays-6pm-us-central/7380/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-underground-halloweenland-4-sessions-october-fridays-6pm-us-central/7380/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 05:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7380-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/girl-underground-halloweenland-4-sessions-october-fridays-6pm-us-central/7380.rss">Girl Underground: Halloweenland (4 sessions, October, Fridays 6pm US Central)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
