<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Crowdfunding Collection #180, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/22 and 09/06</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-180-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-22-and-09-06/7368</link>
    <description>I present to you the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://teylen.blog/2021/09/06/crowdfunding-collection-180/&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Crowdfunding Collection #180, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/22 and 09/06&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.

Finally, as I am back home, I finished the quite opulent list covering two weeks. Let’s have a look.

The ttrpg &lt;b&gt;Picaresque Roman: A Requiem for Rogues&lt;/b&gt;, is my personal favorite. The game originates from Japan, and LionWing publishing offers a translation of its most recent 5th edition of the game published by Group SGR. In regards to its system the rpg utilizes a simple 2d6 mechanic, which is quite common among Japanese indie games, and adds elements of ‚Hidden Traitor‘ games to the my as seen in games of Werewolf, Mafia and the like. This results in the aspect, that at the end of a session there are winners and losers. In regards of the world, the game offers a richly described contemporary metropol as its setting setting, where players assume the roles of scoundrels, inspired by videogames like Yakuza and Persona. There’ll be plenty of scenarios, the artworks and illustrations are top notch, I like the setting and I collect games from Japan that that got translated as well as games with a „mafia theme“ – thus I am a very, very enthusiastic backer. I recommend that you’ll take a look at it as well, and join the project. Focussing on a more somber, serious approach &lt;b&gt;The Price of Coal&lt;/b&gt; is a narrative game exploring the chores and challenges miners in West Virgina face from 1921 to 1924. The workes tried to fight for a secure work enviroment, better pay and the ability to unionized. Considering that the town was owned by the mining company, it resulted in martial law being proclaimed, the workers rising and eventually the US army intervening with lethal force. The game is designed to be played with 3 to 5 players, with each player playing two characters, and a card deck for conflict resolution. The game aims to keep people aware of this specific part of US american, which I find a commendable aim. Check the project out! Stepping away from history, or a distinct setting, &lt;b&gt;The BURST System&lt;/b&gt; offers a genre and setting agnostic system with the boundaries of a zine. The system is designed in a way, to allow gamers to create a world in the blink of an eye and explore it with a fast 2d6 system. While it doesn’t feature stunning illustration, I consider the argument to rather focus on availabilty and not being to expensive fine arguments. Plus, in line with this thinking, the game will be released as CC-BY-SA. It’s a nice little project and I recommend having a look at it.
Moving onto the fantasy games, I’ll start with &lt;b&gt;Briar and Bramble&lt;/b&gt;. The game offers you the opportunity to play as intelligent, yet not anthropmorphic, animals. Focusing on exploring the English countryside, creating communities and being able to play all kind of animals. Considering that works like Animals of Farthing Wood and Watership Down were inspirations to the game, it isn’t like totally heartwarming. The ttrpg is available for free, in its totally for download, and the project aims to really only fund a the print run, which I consider a solid goal and hope it will make it (it needs some help though). &lt;b&gt;Down we Go&lt;/b&gt; is a more traditional fantasy game, in the style of Old School roleplaying games. The exploration of the depth under the city Infinopolis is facilitated by a ruleslight system, that utilizes d20 and 6. The game offers fascinating illustrations and presents the city of Infinopolis as a full setting. I do recommend you check the project out, and support it. It seems cool. &lt;b&gt;Driven into Darkness&lt;/b&gt; is quite bright in comparison. Yet, once you get used to it, you&#39;ll find a d20 system, which among many features offers simultanous combat. The various aspects of the game are presented, and interesting. Take a look for yourself. Then there’s &lt;b&gt;Fantasy Apocalypse 1000&lt;/b&gt;. It isn’t as much a pure fantasy game, but designed to enable games in all kind of genres. I couldn’t bring myself to dig through the wall of texty campaign description, and thus you’ll have to check it out, if you so desire.
Moving onto the horror ttrpg, let’s start with &lt;b&gt;Gravemire&lt;/b&gt;, a game that takes a deep dive into the Louisiana Bayous. Set in about 1894 it presents the setting with additional supernatural elements. Having watched the excellent video, digged through the illustration and read the vivid descriptions I’ve got a feel for the kind of horror the game is going for, and feel somewhat in love with it. [It’s a bit like the opening for True Blood, without the vampires] The system is d12 based and a unique creation by its author. There are elements I am not exactly a fan of – like freeform skill creation – yet it offers quite interesting aspects like downtime. I am very tempted to back the project, got it on my watch list, and recommend you’ll take a look. The other horror game is &lt;b&gt;SURVIVE THIS! What Shadows Hide&lt;/b&gt;. With it’s core book it offers horror within a contemporary setting, inspired by X-Files, Supernatural and Hellboy. The second book offers a sourcebook to add Lovecraft inspired horror into the mix. Well, the cover reminds me of the show Hannibal, and you’ll be able to play as vampires or ghosts – among a host of other creatures. Thus I am in, alas, for I am in Germany, only at a digital level.
&lt;b&gt;ANKUR – Kingdom of the gods&lt;/b&gt; is a Science Fantasy ttrpg, which aims to finance it’s second print run, and basically its second edition on top. The setting jumps of kinda egypt into space, and has ancient myths as one of it’s building blocks. In regards to the mechanic, you’ll find a rulelight d12 roll under system, which is modular and thus can be adjusted to once needs. Considering the creators have had successul previous projects, I recomment it. I don’t think &lt;b&gt;Stars Without Number RPG&lt;/b&gt; needs a recommendation of mine. The popular OSR based Science Fiction setting and system aims to finance an offset print, and just that. If you like physical books, and you want to get a good OSR-SF-RPG, this project is a no-brainer.. go and back it.
There’s a single gamebook in the list called &lt;b&gt;Golemcraft&lt;/b&gt;. While the Kickstarter description doesn’t tell one a lot, it offers an Itchi io concept demo.
Of course there are more interesting projects. Fans who look for a spiritual successor to the famous Dark Sun setting, for D&amp;D 5E, should have a look at &lt;b&gt;Red Dawn: Into The Dawnlands&lt;/b&gt;. You’ll find that Mark Rein-Hagen chimed in with a D&amp;D 5E setting of his own: &lt;b&gt;The Curse of BloodStone Isle&lt;/b&gt;. It offers a first look at the Lostlorn setting and includes vampires. Yet considering the „experience“ that was the I Am Zombie project, I’ll be keeping my distance from the project. I may not keep my distance from &lt;b&gt;The Oracle Issue 15&lt;/b&gt;, which offers system neutral material focused on Caravans and Travellers – considering that my backing of The Oracle Issue 14 offers a delightful experience. Take a look. Another interesting magazine is &lt;b&gt;Junction City&lt;/b&gt;, offering system neutral content for it’s horror adventures. Delving into the sourcebooks, I am quite very tempted to back the &lt;b&gt;Herbalist’s Primer&lt;/b&gt;. It offers description of (realworld) plants, to be used by Magicians, Worldbuilders, Alchemist and GMs. Very vool! As is the idea of the &lt;b&gt;Custom Bestiary&lt;/b&gt;, which offers illustrations, and leaves rooms for the „reader“ to add their own text, stats and stuff. In regards to supplements for system, &lt;b&gt;Stingers &amp; Spores&lt;/b&gt; enriches Savage World with material to play high-fantasy insects and &lt;b&gt;Historica Arcanum: The City of Crescent&lt;/b&gt; offers advice how to create alternative history settings based on cultures of the Near East for D&amp;D 5E. While I am tempted to back the Historica Arcanum, I couldn’t resist the &lt;b&gt;Adaptable Encounters for D&amp;D 5E&lt;/b&gt;. A buck for enriching D&amp;D games with encounters? I am in. Then there are beautiful dice like the &lt;b&gt;Metal Space Dice&lt;/b&gt; and fascinating projects like the Dungeon helper – which aims to turn minis into basically Amibos with their own interactive D&amp;D sheet.
You’ll find these projects, and many more, here:

&lt;b&gt;English Crowdfundings&lt;/b&gt;

3 Roleplaying Games
4 Fantasy Roleplaying Games
2 Horror Roleplaying Games
2 Science Fiction Roleplaying Games
1 Gamebook
1 Setting
6 D&amp;D 5E Settings
6 Magazines
2 Sourcebooks
2 System Specific Sourcebooks
6 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebooks
3 Adventures
6 D&amp;D 5E Adventures
4 Dice Projects
7 Accessoires
2 Deck of Cards
1 Comic
2 Enamel Pins
1 Actual Play
4 Various RPG Projects
3 Games with RPG aspects
&lt;b&gt;
French Crowdfundings&lt;/b&gt;

1 Solo(Roleplaying?)Game
1 Magazin
1 YouTube Series

&lt;b&gt;Danish Crowdfundings&lt;/b&gt;

1 Roleplaying Game

Article: https://teylen.blog/2021/09/06/crowdfunding-collection-180/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:00:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-180-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-22-and-09-06/7368.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Crowdfunding Collection #180, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/22 and 09/06</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the new <a href="https://teylen.blog/2021/09/06/crowdfunding-collection-180/" rel="nofollow noopener"><b>Crowdfunding Collection #180, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/22 and 09/06</b></a>.</p>
<p>Finally, as I am back home, I finished the quite opulent list covering two weeks. Let’s have a look.</p>
<p>The ttrpg <b>Picaresque Roman: A Requiem for Rogues</b>, is my personal favorite. The game originates from Japan, and LionWing publishing offers a translation of its most recent 5th edition of the game published by Group SGR. In regards to its system the rpg utilizes a simple 2d6 mechanic, which is quite common among Japanese indie games, and adds elements of ‚Hidden Traitor‘ games to the my as seen in games of Werewolf, Mafia and the like. This results in the aspect, that at the end of a session there are winners and losers. In regards of the world, the game offers a richly described contemporary metropol as its setting setting, where players assume the roles of scoundrels, inspired by videogames like Yakuza and Persona. There’ll be plenty of scenarios, the artworks and illustrations are top notch, I like the setting and I collect games from Japan that that got translated as well as games with a „mafia theme“ – thus I am a very, very enthusiastic backer. I recommend that you’ll take a look at it as well, and join the project. Focussing on a more somber, serious approach <b>The Price of Coal</b> is a narrative game exploring the chores and challenges miners in West Virgina face from 1921 to 1924. The workes tried to fight for a secure work enviroment, better pay and the ability to unionized. Considering that the town was owned by the mining company, it resulted in martial law being proclaimed, the workers rising and eventually the US army intervening with lethal force. The game is designed to be played with 3 to 5 players, with each player playing two characters, and a card deck for conflict resolution. The game aims to keep people aware of this specific part of US american, which I find a commendable aim. Check the project out! Stepping away from history, or a distinct setting, <b>The BURST System</b> offers a genre and setting agnostic system with the boundaries of a zine. The system is designed in a way, to allow gamers to create a world in the blink of an eye and explore it with a fast 2d6 system. While it doesn’t feature stunning illustration, I consider the argument to rather focus on availabilty and not being to expensive fine arguments. Plus, in line with this thinking, the game will be released as CC-BY-SA. It’s a nice little project and I recommend having a look at it.<br>
Moving onto the fantasy games, I’ll start with <b>Briar and Bramble</b>. The game offers you the opportunity to play as intelligent, yet not anthropmorphic, animals. Focusing on exploring the English countryside, creating communities and being able to play all kind of animals. Considering that works like Animals of Farthing Wood and Watership Down were inspirations to the game, it isn’t like totally heartwarming. The ttrpg is available for free, in its totally for download, and the project aims to really only fund a the print run, which I consider a solid goal and hope it will make it (it needs some help though). <b>Down we Go</b> is a more traditional fantasy game, in the style of Old School roleplaying games. The exploration of the depth under the city Infinopolis is facilitated by a ruleslight system, that utilizes d20 and 6. The game offers fascinating illustrations and presents the city of Infinopolis as a full setting. I do recommend you check the project out, and support it. It seems cool. <b>Driven into Darkness</b> is quite bright in comparison. Yet, once you get used to it, you’ll find a d20 system, which among many features offers simultanous combat. The various aspects of the game are presented, and interesting. Take a look for yourself. Then there’s <b>Fantasy Apocalypse 1000</b>. It isn’t as much a pure fantasy game, but designed to enable games in all kind of genres. I couldn’t bring myself to dig through the wall of texty campaign description, and thus you’ll have to check it out, if you so desire.<br>
Moving onto the horror ttrpg, let’s start with <b>Gravemire</b>, a game that takes a deep dive into the Louisiana Bayous. Set in about 1894 it presents the setting with additional supernatural elements. Having watched the excellent video, digged through the illustration and read the vivid descriptions I’ve got a feel for the kind of horror the game is going for, and feel somewhat in love with it. [It’s a bit like the opening for True Blood, without the vampires] The system is d12 based and a unique creation by its author. There are elements I am not exactly a fan of – like freeform skill creation – yet it offers quite interesting aspects like downtime. I am very tempted to back the project, got it on my watch list, and recommend you’ll take a look. The other horror game is <b>SURVIVE THIS! What Shadows Hide</b>. With it’s core book it offers horror within a contemporary setting, inspired by X-Files, Supernatural and Hellboy. The second book offers a sourcebook to add Lovecraft inspired horror into the mix. Well, the cover reminds me of the show Hannibal, and you’ll be able to play as vampires or ghosts – among a host of other creatures. Thus I am in, alas, for I am in Germany, only at a digital level.<br>
<b>ANKUR – Kingdom of the gods</b> is a Science Fantasy ttrpg, which aims to finance it’s second print run, and basically its second edition on top. The setting jumps of kinda egypt into space, and has ancient myths as one of it’s building blocks. In regards to the mechanic, you’ll find a rulelight d12 roll under system, which is modular and thus can be adjusted to once needs. Considering the creators have had successul previous projects, I recomment it. I don’t think <b>Stars Without Number RPG</b> needs a recommendation of mine. The popular OSR based Science Fiction setting and system aims to finance an offset print, and just that. If you like physical books, and you want to get a good OSR-SF-RPG, this project is a no-brainer… go and back it.<br>
There’s a single gamebook in the list called <b>Golemcraft</b>. While the Kickstarter description doesn’t tell one a lot, it offers an Itchi io concept demo.<br>
Of course there are more interesting projects. Fans who look for a spiritual successor to the famous Dark Sun setting, for D&amp;D 5E, should have a look at <b>Red Dawn: Into The Dawnlands</b>. You’ll find that Mark Rein-Hagen chimed in with a D&amp;D 5E setting of his own: <b>The Curse of BloodStone Isle</b>. It offers a first look at the Lostlorn setting and includes vampires. Yet considering the „experience“ that was the I Am Zombie project, I’ll be keeping my distance from the project. I may not keep my distance from <b>The Oracle Issue 15</b>, which offers system neutral material focused on Caravans and Travellers – considering that my backing of The Oracle Issue 14 offers a delightful experience. Take a look. Another interesting magazine is <b>Junction City</b>, offering system neutral content for it’s horror adventures. Delving into the sourcebooks, I am quite very tempted to back the <b>Herbalist’s Primer</b>. It offers description of (realworld) plants, to be used by Magicians, Worldbuilders, Alchemist and GMs. Very vool! As is the idea of the <b>Custom Bestiary</b>, which offers illustrations, and leaves rooms for the „reader“ to add their own text, stats and stuff. In regards to supplements for system, <b>Stingers &amp; Spores</b> enriches Savage World with material to play high-fantasy insects and <b>Historica Arcanum: The City of Crescent</b> offers advice how to create alternative history settings based on cultures of the Near East for D&amp;D 5E. While I am tempted to back the Historica Arcanum, I couldn’t resist the <b>Adaptable Encounters for D&amp;D 5E</b>. A buck for enriching D&amp;D games with encounters? I am in. Then there are beautiful dice like the <b>Metal Space Dice</b> and fascinating projects like the Dungeon helper – which aims to turn minis into basically Amibos with their own interactive D&amp;D sheet.<br>
You’ll find these projects, and many more, here:</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>3 Roleplaying Games<br>
4 Fantasy Roleplaying Games<br>
2 Horror Roleplaying Games<br>
2 Science Fiction Roleplaying Games<br>
1 Gamebook<br>
1 Setting<br>
6 D&amp;D 5E Settings<br>
6 Magazines<br>
2 Sourcebooks<br>
2 System Specific Sourcebooks<br>
6 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebooks<br>
3 Adventures<br>
6 D&amp;D 5E Adventures<br>
4 Dice Projects<br>
7 Accessoires<br>
2 Deck of Cards<br>
1 Comic<br>
2 Enamel Pins<br>
1 Actual Play<br>
4 Various RPG Projects<br>
3 Games with RPG aspects<br>
<b><br>
French Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Solo(Roleplaying?)Game<br>
1 Magazin<br>
1 YouTube Series</p>
<p><b>Danish Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Roleplaying Game</p>
<p>Article: <a href="https://teylen.blog/2021/09/06/crowdfunding-collection-180/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2021/09/06/crowdfunding-collection-180/</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-180-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-22-and-09-06/7368/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-180-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-22-and-09-06/7368/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7368-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-180-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-22-and-09-06/7368.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #180, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/22 and 09/06</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
