<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pasión de las Pasiones - El Ruido Nuevo</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-el-ruido-nuevo/6153</link>
    <description>**NUMBER OF SESSIONS:**  4 sessions total, being able to attend each session is strongly requested, you must RSVP to each session.
**DURATION:**  3 hours
**NUMBER OF PLAYERS:**  3, a seat is being reserved for Jesse Abelman
**CONTENT WARNING:**  This game may include drinking, light drug usage, and other similar behaviors that people in their mid-20s might participate in. There may be moments of interpersonal conflict, but it is unlikely that conflict will go beyond a fist fight. If players consent, there may be themes of romance/sexual tension between player-controlled characters, and/or player and GM-controlled characters, but anything more explicit than a passionate kiss or embrace will be veiled.
**-------------------------------------------**
&quot;Listen, you  *could*  go to that record store in the mall, but let&#39;s be blunt - you know they don&#39;t have anything  *cool*  there. There&#39;s nothing  *new* , you know? It&#39;s just the same stuff you hear on XPOP. But  *here*  ... well.  *Here*  it&#39;s a different story. Now let&#39;s see what we can do about finding you something  *good*  ...&quot;
Ruido Nuevo is the fiercely,  *proudly*  independent record store in Ciudad Soñando. It&#39;s where you go to find imports, bootlegs, out-of-print albums, the newest and latest, the records you hear about when the coolest people you know mention them in passing ... and it&#39;s an utter disaster of a business. If the record shop on Sunday is a kind of church for you, then Ruido Nuevo is the miracle that makes believers because it&#39;s a wonder that it hasn&#39;t closed down permanently. But hey, it&#39;s still early in the day so who knows what could happen? And Los Químicos Tóxicos is supposed to do an in-store ... if they remember. Then there are those two kids who you know are shoplifting, but haven&#39;t caught. And ... oh hell, the store is supposed to open in 5 minutes and you aren&#39;t even out of bed yet ...
**-------------------------------------------**
**SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:**  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet&#39;s Community Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html
**RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:**  12/06/2020, 20:00 Central Time
**SET UP INFO:**  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the series starts.
**BREAKS:**  2 five minute breaks
**RECORDED:**  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube (eventually; everyone knows I&#39;m slow with that stuff).
**PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:**  No experience required, rules will be taught.

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdsvigkoPD3iNYQbc
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLduDbSX-l2emiYAll
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdvLVbtxYWFu49OAK
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdwQN4AMRdyE0k77-</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 01:04:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-el-ruido-nuevo/6153.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Pasión de las Pasiones - El Ruido Nuevo</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>NUMBER OF SESSIONS:</strong>  4 sessions total, being able to attend each session is strongly requested, you must RSVP to each session.<br>
<strong>DURATION:</strong>  3 hours<br>
<strong>NUMBER OF PLAYERS:</strong>  3, a seat is being reserved for Jesse Abelman<br>
<strong>CONTENT WARNING:</strong>  This game may include drinking, light drug usage, and other similar behaviors that people in their mid-20s might participate in. There may be moments of interpersonal conflict, but it is unlikely that conflict will go beyond a fist fight. If players consent, there may be themes of romance/sexual tension between player-controlled characters, and/or player and GM-controlled characters, but anything more explicit than a passionate kiss or embrace will be veiled.<br>
<strong>-------------------------------------------</strong><br>
“Listen, you  <em>could</em>  go to that record store in the mall, but let’s be blunt - you know they don’t have anything  <em>cool</em>  there. There’s nothing  <em>new</em> , you know? It’s just the same stuff you hear on XPOP. But  <em>here</em>  … well.  <em>Here</em>  it’s a different story. Now let’s see what we can do about finding you something  <em>good</em>  …”<br>
Ruido Nuevo is the fiercely,  <em>proudly</em>  independent record store in Ciudad Soñando. It’s where you go to find imports, bootlegs, out-of-print albums, the newest and latest, the records you hear about when the coolest people you know mention them in passing … and it’s an utter disaster of a business. If the record shop on Sunday is a kind of church for you, then Ruido Nuevo is the miracle that makes believers because it’s a wonder that it hasn’t closed down permanently. But hey, it’s still early in the day so who knows what could happen? And Los Químicos Tóxicos is supposed to do an in-store … if they remember. Then there are those two kids who you know are shoplifting, but haven’t caught. And … oh hell, the store is supposed to open in 5 minutes and you aren’t even out of bed yet …<br>
<strong>-------------------------------------------</strong><br>
<strong>SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:</strong>  This session will use a lengthy list of Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet’s Community Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a><br>
<strong>RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:</strong>  12/06/2020, 20:00 Central Time<br>
<strong>SET UP INFO:</strong>  We will use Streamyard for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the series starts.<br>
<strong>BREAKS:</strong>  2 five minute breaks<br>
<strong>RECORDED:</strong>  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube (eventually; everyone knows I’m slow with that stuff).<br>
<strong>PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:</strong>  No experience required, rules will be taught.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdsvigkoPD3iNYQbc" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdsvigkoPD3iNYQbc</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLduDbSX-l2emiYAll" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLduDbSX-l2emiYAll</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdvLVbtxYWFu49OAK" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdvLVbtxYWFu49OAK</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdwQN4AMRdyE0k77-" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNLdwQN4AMRdyE0k77-</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-el-ruido-nuevo/6153/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-el-ruido-nuevo/6153/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 01:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6153-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/pasion-de-las-pasiones-el-ruido-nuevo/6153.rss">Pasión de las Pasiones - El Ruido Nuevo</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
