<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852</link>
    <description>Are there ways to turn GM Prep into a miniature &quot;game&quot; in and of itself? I got the idea by playing around of the the &quot;Hand of Fate&quot; card game that was recently released. It was a 4 v 1 game, with one player taking on a roll of an antagonistic sort of dungeon master. How it would work is he would play a turn to manipulate things, develop enemies, introduce threats, and then we would each take a turn in exploring the world he was constructing and changing. It was a very unique, asynchronous experience and my friend playing the &quot;GM&quot; was having as much of a blast preparing the game as we were playing it.

My current thought is that after a given RPG session, the GM would sit down with some &quot;rules&quot; and a board of some sort, and play a little board-game-like &quot;turn&quot; as the antagonists. At the end of which, he&#39;d have shifted the &quot;state&quot; of the game, reacted to the player&#39;s actions during the session, and generated a refreshed game state. I know there&#39;s lots of games and advice that recommend the GM &quot;think about what the antagonists are doing&quot;, but I think it would be interesting to see it played out with the rules and mechanics of a board game, rather than just relying on a GM&#39;s sense of &quot;what should happen next.&quot;

Has something similar been done before? I&#39;d love to hear of place I could draw inspiration for this!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 12:46:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Palm to face. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=9" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:">Yes. Sounds cool though. I have downloaded it myself</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 12:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Did you mean <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-in-your-one-shot-kit/3691/24?u=rickard" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">my own post</a>?  <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> I know my game have been featured in <a href="https://parallelpodcast.tumblr.com/post/130751986230/the-murder-of-mr-crow-a-small-game-and-big-news#notes" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">a pod cast</a> (awesome discussion around the game) and people have added the game to GameboardGeek, and even played it <a href="https://rpggeek.com/thread/1335885/murder-mr-crow-ic" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">on their forum</a> without any influence from my side. Quite cool, actually.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 09:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/rickard">@Rickard</a>, FYI…there is another thread on here that mentions The Murder of Mr. Crow as a great go to one-shot game in and of itself!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/26</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 20:17:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You could certainly use Mythic GM emulator for this.  You as the “Player” ask the system Yes / No questions about the environment and antagonists.  The odds change to more likely to a yes after every No and less likely for a yes after ever Yes response.  Assuming you don’t ask about PC level conflicts this would work great.</p>
<p>There are also several GMs that use Rory’s story dice for inspiration on Youtube.</p>
<p>Along the lines of Microscope, Kingdom works well to create histories.  Possibly it could be rigged to work 1 player.</p>
<p>I suspect that you could play some single player Ironsworn and use your story to create interesting prep for a multiplayer game.  You could even have the players follow / eventually rescue / avenge / destroy your single player character as an NPC!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/25</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 19:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DanFelder]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/danfelder">@DanFelder</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks. It’s been a lot of fun. I feel it’s a great way to address multiple player types at the table too. You can basically play a narrative-centric game by GMing for a group of tactical players. So if you’re the one guy in the group that likes that experience while the others want to go hack and slash in D&amp;D or a more tactical OSR experience you can still get the experience you want.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/24</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Proto]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/proto">@Proto</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s really really cool. I think it’s super interesting that you brewed up a narrative-centric system to help run a more tactical game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/23</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 15:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DanFelder]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/danfelder">@DanFelder</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is exactly what I’m working on for one of my side-projects, and it’s how I was able to run 50 sessions in about 3 months. My goal the whole time through was to treat myself, the GM, like a player and design accordingly.</p>
<p>For me, I modeled my fun less off a strategy game and more off the fun of an adventure boardgame like Tales of the Arabian Nights, Betrayal at House on the Hill, Eldritch Horror and similar, mixed with a narrative-based game experience (similar to a player’s experience in dungeon world, or even something looser like fiasco).</p>
<p>My experience was in drawing cards and rolling on tables during the session, discovering what event the players walked into just as they did. I had no idea there was a mad witch with a split personality in my world until moments before the players did. The moment she came into the setting, she was there to stay. Just as I enjoy an adventure boardgame by going around the board, drawing cards and seeing what happens - I get to do this for the events my players roll. Then I get to use that event as an improv prompt to create a story-rich scene for them (similar to a player’s experience in a narrative-based, story-building RPG).</p>
<p>At the end of the session I generally build my new “characters” as threats - inspired by the threat packs in Beyond the Wall: Further Afield. At the end of each session I can choose to activate one of these threats, activate multiple ones at the cost of giving players advantages or opportunities, or roll to chance activating various threats (as beyond the wall does).</p>
<p>This mix of discovering-as-we-adventure with discovered-event-serves-as-basis-for-story-improv works great. I get to basically play the equivalent of a narrative story-building RPG while GMing for a group of tactically minded players.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/22</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 05:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jason_Kottler]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jason_kottler">@Jason_Kottler</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/b-design/wicked-ones" rel="nofollow noopener">Wicked Ones KS</a> (you’re gonna have to hurry if you want in on it) is a FitD RPG that reminds me of Dungeon Lords. It generates a dungeon as part of play. One of the last stretch goals included a solo mode that creates a dungeon as its output. I imagine that I would love to generate the dungeon as a solo game (or you know, in regular play) and then use that dungeon for a more traditional crawl (probably with another group but maybe it would be so meta the group would get a kick out of it?)!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 23:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Shortaaron]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shortaaron">@Shortaaron</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I second <a class="mention" href="/u/shane">@shane</a> and the Star w/o Number prep. The “Counterweight” season of Friends at the Table uses Sw/oN to move pieces for their play of MechNoir and Sprawl. But that kind of intense systemitization may yield an alternate game rather than something interstitial or preparatory. What you’ve designed looks like a lot of fun, and I’d have to spend more time looking at the details, but at first glance it would feel more like playing a solo game rather than gamified prep. If that’s what you’re going for, then this is fantastic and fun.</p>
<p>Moving more toward the prep side than the game side, combining a series of question prompts, roll tables, and so on may do some of this work. I’m working on a kind of template like the 7-3-1 model to normalize my prep that I’m trying to move in this direction. Right now it’s just a list: Three plot lines running in the background that will impact the characters’ world, Four npcs with motives that relate to these happenings, three strange encounters/creatures related to these happenings, two locations.</p>
<p>Alternatively, The Ultimate RPG Character Backstory Guide does this for characters. There are some exercises that are certainly translatable to plot.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/20</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 06:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@APM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/apm">@APM</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a>, This is a very interesting concept! I have sort of a minigame prep thing going on for my pbta game Middle World. It’s more of a procedure than an actual game but I feel that it definitely would count towards lonely fun for the GM.</p>
<p>You create 2 or 3 factions and make a few choices for each (are they driven by tradition/industry? Do they have strength/wealth or magic? Do they corrupt/destroy/restrict or invade?) guided by your choices you establish the factions’ dark schemes - plans of 3-6 steps that start with a kicker and end with either chaos or stagnating order. That has been very inspiring and fun to do!</p>
<p>Also I have a mapmaking procedure in my Swedish game Fornsaga that is supposed to help players make the map as they explore it in game. But I have many times found pleasure in using it to create premade maps that instead are handed to the players when they begin to play.</p>
<p>Random tables could also work sort of as a mini game for the GM to play with in advance. But maybe you’re strictly referring to prep between sessions?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/19</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 05:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>To answer the OP, I’ve been using  a scenario writing model <a href="https://gnomestew.com/game-mastering/gming-advice/the-fish-tank-as-a-mystery-2/" rel="nofollow noopener">for creating a murder mystery</a> for a few years, which I took and made into a two page game called <a href="https://www.urverkspel.com/vara-spel/oevriga-projekt" rel="nofollow noopener">The Murder of Mr. Crow</a>. You can actually play the game with yourself to create a murder mystery, and then play that scenario with your players.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/18</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 22:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>That’s interesting, I’ve heard of similar things where the idea is if you pay someone to do something intrinsically fun, paying them for it will make less sense. If you can find the link, I’d be interested in reading up.</p>
</blockquote>
<aside class="onebox wikipedia">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overjustification_effect" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">en.wikipedia.org</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:170/128;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/6/6c092f1436631b643464d953c3c0851417a4beb1.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overjustification_effect" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Overjustification effect</a></h3>

<p>The overjustification effect occurs when an expected external incentive such as money or prizes decreases a person's intrinsic motivation to perform a task. Overjustification is an explanation for the phenomenon known as motivational "crowding out." The overall effect of offering a reward for a previously unrewarded activity is a shift to extrinsic motivation and the undermining of pre-existing intrinsic motivation. Once rewards are no longer offered, interest in the activity is lost; prior intri...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox wikipedia">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_evaluation_theory" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">en.wikipedia.org</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    

<h3><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_evaluation_theory" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Cognitive evaluation theory</a></h3>

<p>Cognitive evaluation theory (CET) is a theory in psychology that is designed to explain the effects of external consequences on internal motivation. Specifically, CET is a sub-theory of self-determination theory that focuses on competence and autonomy while examining how intrinsic motivation is affected by external forces in a process known as motivational "crowding out."
 CET uses three propositions to explain how consequences affect internal motivation:
 Many empirical studies have given at lea...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="1qJvS8v0TTI" data-youtube-title="What is Positive Psychology?" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/17</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 22:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thanks again to all the suggestions people have made, I’ve checked a few other systems out, and they’ve certainly got my noggin joggin’. I’ve started to put together the “meta-game” system for my own game, which is designed to function as a sort of inter-session “GM Turn” (similar to what Stars Without Number does).</p>
<p>The question I’m running into now is, is it too much? Will potential GM’s be turned off by the amount of work I’m asking them to do, just to simulate how the enemies in the game react to and try to counter the players? If anyone is feeling charitable, I’d appreciate you taking a look and letting me know what you think. <a href="http://bit.ly/2J6sSTU" rel="nofollow noopener">http://bit.ly/2J6sSTU</a></p>
<p>I also was considering how much randomization / set up I should include for the “game world”. Should I have the GM create everything, possibly with randomizers, or should I ship the game with a “default world” that is already pre-configured?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/16</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 16:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CthulhuBen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cthulhuben">@CthulhuBen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Actually, using Intermittent reinforcement schedules as the basis of Operant conditioning as a tool for shaping human behaviour through play has proven anything by ineffective (see gambling addiction). From Overwatch to WOW to grandblue, it is the default tool of maintaining engagement by players.<br>
Even in the sphere of getting people to do every day tasks, Intermittent reinforcement schedules are a great way to promote behaviours, if used correctly.</p>
<p>The problem with most of the “gamification” apps is that they are poorly designed, not that the technique is ineffective.</p>
<p>Given that the term Gamify has significant baggage, so it is almost certainly more fruitful to talk about Systematising prep.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 06:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Von_Bednar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It is possible I misread the thread, mostly basing it on this bit here:</p>
<aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-post="1" data-topic="852">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/erikthebearik/40/837_2.png" class="avatar"> ErikTheBearik:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>How it would work is he would play a turn to manipulate things, develop enemies, introduce threats, and then we would each take a turn in exploring…</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Looking at it now, I might have misread it and might have been posting about the wrong thing. The dirty dungeon technique I mentioned earlier is basically a collaborative dungeon prep, which can be expanded into session prep. So I was just piggy backing on that…</p>
<p>I still feel that if you make it into a game/puzzle for yourself it is not really harmful as the gamification companies try to push down our throats <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=6" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/14</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 02:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So <a class="mention" href="/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> when you say</p>
<blockquote>
<p>collaborative session prep</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Do you mean doing session prep with the rest of the gaming group? That isn’t something I have run into all that much personally and would be intrigued to hear more.</p>
<p>I sense what in general is being discussed here (and I am happy to be corrected) is that for some people prep is pretty boring and they do it because they have to, not because they enjoy it. Somehow making a game out of it or the like makes it less boring and more interesting.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/13</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 02:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Von_Bednar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t think we talk about the same idea of gamification here.</p>
<p>While the recent gamification trend for mundane tasks was indeed proven ineffective, I think the idea here is “adding rules to make collaborative session prep possible.” I don’t think we talk about the trendy gamification with scoring, winners and losers in this thread - or at least I haven’t read this topic this way.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/12</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 01:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@LeviKornelsen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/levikornelsen">@LeviKornelsen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Kim Lam and I wrote <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/268040/Gazetteer-A-Gygaxian-Storygame" rel="nofollow noopener">Gazetteer,</a> a play-by-post that also generates material for an old school-ish tabletop adventure.</p>
<p>So there’s, y’know, that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/11</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CthulhuBen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cthulhuben">@CthulhuBen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It relates pretty explicitly to  skinner boxing, but that is what is generally meant when people refer to gamification.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/10</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s interesting, I’ve heard of similar things where the idea is if you pay someone to do something intrinsically fun, paying them for it will make less sense. If you can find the link, I’d be interested in reading up.</p>
<p>I’m guessing this might have more to do with “gamify” apps, things like ChoreQuest and whatnot?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/9</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 23:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CthulhuBen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/cthulhuben">@CthulhuBen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Just a heads up, while I can’t at a glance find the link, there is some evidence that gamifying things which we consider to have intrinsic value, can undermine our sense that the thing in question has value and make it more frustrating in the long run.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/8</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 23:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jholloway]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jholloway">@jholloway</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes, I was going to mention Stars Without Number as well. The same is true for the other games in that … series? … like Silent Legions. I don’t know that GM prep in Kevin Crawford games is necessarily “gamified” but I think it’s close to it. Sometimes I just generate planets or sectors for the heck of it.</p>
<p>Again, I don’t know it’s a game per se, but some years ago I found an old copy of Everway in a charity shop for £2. I’ve never played the game, but I used the cards in designing my fantasy setting. I just doodled a map, put it on the table and started putting down cards on it. The cards work very well for this purpose because they could be either literal or symbolic. This maze full of vultures could mean a twisty, dangerous political landscape full of opportunistic enemies – or it could mean a literal maze full of vultures!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/7</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 07:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Stars Without Number</em> has “The Faction Turn” where the GM will work through a little mini-game of sorts to figure out all the stuff that is going on in the galaxy and how the PCs have affected it after which they know what all the other factions are up too and how they view the PCs.</p>
<p>The LotFP module <em>Scenic Dunsmouth</em> gamifies the entirety of the prep for the adventure: you roll a bunch of dice on a piece of paper to generate the layout of the town and the numbers of the dice tell you things as well. You then use playing cards to populate the buildings. It’s pretty awesome since nobody’s Dunsmouth will ever be the same as someone else’s. It was the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/fear-of-a-black-dragon/scenic-dunnsmouth" rel="nofollow noopener">inaugural module</a> covered on the Fear of a Black Dragon podcast.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/6</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 02:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Von_Bednar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>For a group “GM prep” activity, my first thought was to take John Wick’s Dirty Dungeon, and expand on it. It seems the video describing the technique is no longer available, but you can find it explained <a href="http://www.enworld.org/forum/showthread.php?310157-John-Wick-The-Dirty-Dungeon" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a> and applied to <a href="http://www.story-games.com/forums/discussion/19705/dungeon-world-legwork-john-wicks-dirty-dungeons-as-a-basic-move" rel="nofollow noopener">DW here</a>.</p>
<p>I can see using this approach of giving players some sort of bonus to acting on obstacles they introduced themselves for more than just fleshing out a dungeon.</p>
<p>If this feels a little too free-form, you can always incorporate some randomizer that the player needs to incorporate. I know people are using tarot cards, but I am pretty partial to just getting a some random magic the gathering cards from one of the online databases like <a href="https://scryfall.com/random" rel="nofollow noopener">this one here</a>. I actually used magic cards this way to do my own GM prep (<a href="http://level27geek.blogspot.com/2014/07/magic-random-creature-adventure.html" rel="nofollow noopener">as seen in this inactive blog of mine</a>).</p>
<p>You can draw X cards to the table, and go around the table letting player choose a card and based on it changing the world/narrative.</p>
<p>If mtg theme doesn’t fit with your games, you can always use some other CCG, roll some <a href="https://www.storycubes.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Rory’s Story Cubes</a> or find something even better <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=6" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gamifying GM Prep</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>These are all great, thanks a lot folks!</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="3" data-topic="852">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/bill_white/40/696_2.png" class="avatar"> Bill_White:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Traveller’s world generation sub-systems provide referees with “lonely fun” as they create the places the PCs will visit next, but that’s only responsive to PC actions to the extent that they keep moving.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Haha, this one jumped out at me as an oddly fun one. I was definitely the “accountant” in my last Traveller game, sitting down to try and figure out how much we could make for freight shipping, passengers, or buying goods on spec. I loved looking at a sector map and imagining all the fun and exciting book-keeping I could do to pay down our ship-mortgage.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 17:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-852-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gamifying-gm-prep/852.rss">Gamifying GM Prep</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
