<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiasco: Business Casual</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fiasco-business-casual/7351</link>
    <description>    Uh… we have sort of a problem here. Yeah. You apparently didn’t put one of the new coversheets on your TPS reports. Yeah. You see, we’re putting the cover sheets on all TPS reports now before they go out. Did you see the memo about this?
    Yeah. I’ve got the memo right here, but, uh, uh, I just forgot. But, uh, it’s not shipping out until tomorrow, so there’s no problem.
    Yeah. If you could just go ahead and make sure you do that from now on, that will be great. And uh, I’ll go ahead and make sure you get another copy of that memo. Mmmm, Ok?
    - Office Space

This is a one shot of Fiasco, the GMless story game by Jason Morningstar, published by Bully Pulpit Games, in which players take turns to frame and then play out scenes. We will be playing with the Business Casual playset from the American Disasters supplement.

Touchstones: Office Space, The Office (TV), The IT Crowd (IT), Cedar Rapids, Extact

Rules will be taught as we play.
I will contact players via email one week prior to confirm attendance.

Fiasco is inspired by cinematic tales of small-time capers gone disastrously wrong – particularly films like Blood Simple, Fargo, The Way of the Gun, Burn After Reading, and A Simple Plan. You’ll play ordinary people with powerful ambition and poor impulse control. There will be big dreams and flawed execution. It won’t go well for them, to put it mildly, and in the end it will probably collapse into a glorious heap of jealousy, murder, and recrimination. Lives and reputations will be lost, painful wisdom will be gained, and if you are really lucky, your guy just might end up back where they started.

Concept: Coworkers in an Office building not getting along, getting ahead, getting even or just trying to get their work done.
Aim: To create a hilarious, tangled, trainwreck of a story which the players will enjoy but the characters certainly won&#39;t.
Tone: Black comedy
Subject Matter: Office workers, managers, coworkers, IT people, HR, corporate and TPS reports
Safety Tools: Gauntlet Code of Conduct, X Card, Lines and Veils, Open Door
Venue: Zoom

[https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MicCnQWTb9sEB2dFnAr](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MicCnQWTb9sEB2dFnAr)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 20:58:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fiasco-business-casual/7351.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Fiasco: Business Casual</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@gareththegeek]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gareththegeek">@gareththegeek</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <pre><code>Uh… we have sort of a problem here. Yeah. You apparently didn’t put one of the new coversheets on your TPS reports. Yeah. You see, we’re putting the cover sheets on all TPS reports now before they go out. Did you see the memo about this?
Yeah. I’ve got the memo right here, but, uh, uh, I just forgot. But, uh, it’s not shipping out until tomorrow, so there’s no problem.
Yeah. If you could just go ahead and make sure you do that from now on, that will be great. And uh, I’ll go ahead and make sure you get another copy of that memo. Mmmm, Ok?
- Office Space
</code></pre>
<p>This is a one shot of Fiasco, the GMless story game by Jason Morningstar, published by Bully Pulpit Games, in which players take turns to frame and then play out scenes. We will be playing with the Business Casual playset from the American Disasters supplement.</p>
<p>Touchstones: Office Space, The Office (TV), The IT Crowd (IT), Cedar Rapids, Extact</p>
<p>Rules will be taught as we play.<br>
I will contact players via email one week prior to confirm attendance.</p>
<p>Fiasco is inspired by cinematic tales of small-time capers gone disastrously wrong – particularly films like Blood Simple, Fargo, The Way of the Gun, Burn After Reading, and A Simple Plan. You’ll play ordinary people with powerful ambition and poor impulse control. There will be big dreams and flawed execution. It won’t go well for them, to put it mildly, and in the end it will probably collapse into a glorious heap of jealousy, murder, and recrimination. Lives and reputations will be lost, painful wisdom will be gained, and if you are really lucky, your guy just might end up back where they started.</p>
<p>Concept: Coworkers in an Office building not getting along, getting ahead, getting even or just trying to get their work done.<br>
Aim: To create a hilarious, tangled, trainwreck of a story which the players will enjoy but the characters certainly won’t.<br>
Tone: Black comedy<br>
Subject Matter: Office workers, managers, coworkers, IT people, HR, corporate and TPS reports<br>
Safety Tools: Gauntlet Code of Conduct, X Card, Lines and Veils, Open Door<br>
Venue: Zoom</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MicCnQWTb9sEB2dFnAr" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MicCnQWTb9sEB2dFnAr</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fiasco-business-casual/7351/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fiasco-business-casual/7351/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 20:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7351-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fiasco-business-casual/7351.rss">Fiasco: Business Casual</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
