<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Apocalypse Keys: A Peek Through the Door</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-a-peek-through-the-door/8435</link>
    <description>*Note: For the first 24 hours, please only sign up if you have not played in one of my games in the last 6 months or so. These sessions are All-Access right away. Attendance at all 3 sessions is preferred.*

Session 1: Tuesday, 25 October
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0dqSdG1KCV813Khe

Session 2: Tuesday, 1 November
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0o0wOE6ITzqSNP4Y

Session 3 Tuesday, 8 November
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0xWFdp9RWgZ5wsKq

**Apocalypse Keys**

Apocalypse Keys is a tabletop roleplaying game about monsters holding back the apocalypse. Apocalypse Keys is a game of emotional connection, complicated relationships, unpredictable mysteries, larger than life apocalyptical threats, and the brightest hope in the darkest despair. You are monsters bound by fate, love, and power.  *Apocalypse Keys*  asks you to play characters who are conflicted and complex, each yearning to connect meaningfully to the monsters and humans around them. They are terrifying and monstrous, but they are also aching and human. To play  *Apocalypse Keys*  means playing vulnerable characters in a position to hurt and be hurt. 

**Thematically the game focuses on:**  Forestalling the Apocalypse, Solving Mysteries, Wrestling with Power, Emotional Entanglements, Your Power Will Likely Lead to Your Ruin.

**For this session we will use the pre-generated characters in the Kickstarter preview materials. (The Summoned, The Surge, The Shade, The Last)**

The hope is that this will allow us to pursue 2 mysteries in 3 sessions and end in a satisfying, if unresolved, place.

I will send a reminder 1 week before the session. Rules will be taught.

**CW:**  This game deals with mature themes such as the end of the world, supernatural forces, and the occult. Some concepts lean into experiences that you may find parallel with racism and marginalization. We will use safety tools to help ensure your enjoyment of the game. But it’s also okay to not play this game.

**System**  : Apocalypse Keys

**Duration**  : 3 Hours

**Breaks**  : 5-10 minutes approximately on the hour

**Venue**  : GM’s Zoom

**Recording**  : No

**Safety**  : Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, and open door policy. Tools can be changed to suit the players. This game will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 18:50:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-a-peek-through-the-door/8435.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Apocalypse Keys: A Peek Through the Door</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gabe">@Gabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>Note: For the first 24 hours, please only sign up if you have not played in one of my games in the last 6 months or so. These sessions are All-Access right away. Attendance at all 3 sessions is preferred.</em></p>
<p>Session 1: Tuesday, 25 October<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0dqSdG1KCV813Khe" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0dqSdG1KCV813Khe</a></p>
<p>Session 2: Tuesday, 1 November<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0o0wOE6ITzqSNP4Y" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0o0wOE6ITzqSNP4Y</a></p>
<p>Session 3 Tuesday, 8 November<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0xWFdp9RWgZ5wsKq" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-NDP0xWFdp9RWgZ5wsKq</a></p>
<p><strong>Apocalypse Keys</strong></p>
<p>Apocalypse Keys is a tabletop roleplaying game about monsters holding back the apocalypse. Apocalypse Keys is a game of emotional connection, complicated relationships, unpredictable mysteries, larger than life apocalyptical threats, and the brightest hope in the darkest despair. You are monsters bound by fate, love, and power.  <em>Apocalypse Keys</em>  asks you to play characters who are conflicted and complex, each yearning to connect meaningfully to the monsters and humans around them. They are terrifying and monstrous, but they are also aching and human. To play  <em>Apocalypse Keys</em>  means playing vulnerable characters in a position to hurt and be hurt.</p>
<p><strong>Thematically the game focuses on:</strong>  Forestalling the Apocalypse, Solving Mysteries, Wrestling with Power, Emotional Entanglements, Your Power Will Likely Lead to Your Ruin.</p>
<p><strong>For this session we will use the pre-generated characters in the Kickstarter preview materials. (The Summoned, The Surge, The Shade, The Last)</strong></p>
<p>The hope is that this will allow us to pursue 2 mysteries in 3 sessions and end in a satisfying, if unresolved, place.</p>
<p>I will send a reminder 1 week before the session. Rules will be taught.</p>
<p><strong>CW:</strong>  This game deals with mature themes such as the end of the world, supernatural forces, and the occult. Some concepts lean into experiences that you may find parallel with racism and marginalization. We will use safety tools to help ensure your enjoyment of the game. But it’s also okay to not play this game.</p>
<p><strong>System</strong>  : Apocalypse Keys</p>
<p><strong>Duration</strong>  : 3 Hours</p>
<p><strong>Breaks</strong>  : 5-10 minutes approximately on the hour</p>
<p><strong>Venue</strong>  : GM’s Zoom</p>
<p><strong>Recording</strong>  : No</p>
<p><strong>Safety</strong>  : Lines &amp; Veils, X-card, and open door policy. Tools can be changed to suit the players. This game will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-a-peek-through-the-door/8435/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-a-peek-through-the-door/8435/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 18:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8435-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/apocalypse-keys-a-peek-through-the-door/8435.rss">Apocalypse Keys: A Peek Through the Door</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
