<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Enchanting Mundania</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/enchanting-mundania/7729</link>
    <description>Hello,
 @Deckard told me about Sidewalkia (Alyson Grauer) and I didn&#39;t want to derail the thread, but I like these games where you enchant reality a lot. There are many of them and in a way, contemporary settings do this (ever been slightly afraid of being watched in the dark streets after a session of Chtulluh or Vampire ?). So I&#39;ll ask about someting more specific: techniques for enrolling passer bys in a physical public place. 

Safety techniques, games, wild dreams: a brainstorm always begins as a catalogue, we&#39;ll see what comes out of it.

Safety techniques: from Killer the assassination game. Don&#39;t impose yourself, don&#39;t put anyone at risk, don&#39;t give anyone reasons to start a fight or put you in jail. 

Games: flashmob can be sort of that, also Read/play games (Sean Patrick Caine), Casual games for casual hikers (Harry Josephine Giles), Walking the Furtuire (Randy Lubin), barter hunt (you have a number of worthless items and must barter with passer bys until you have a whole different set of items)

Techniques: 
- captive audience (vehicle, elevator, hike, queuing, etc.)
- funny disguise, congeniality, spotting &quot;open&quot; people
- scape alteration: road sign, chalk drawing, decorative item (photo frame, bird cage, plant), audio, last enrolled is hyped (hype snowball), audience circle
- enrollment prop : empty photo frame, funny hat, magic wand, water pistol, menu/leaflet etc. clear tone &amp; contract
- low barrier for entry (physical and cognitive), no win/lose, a good sense of personally vs socially acceptable limits</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:40:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/enchanting-mundania/7729.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Enchanting Mundania</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello,<br>
<a class="mention" href="/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> told me about Sidewalkia (Alyson Grauer) and I didn’t want to derail the thread, but I like these games where you enchant reality a lot. There are many of them and in a way, contemporary settings do this (ever been slightly afraid of being watched in the dark streets after a session of Chtulluh or Vampire ?). So I’ll ask about someting more specific: techniques for enrolling passer bys in a physical public place.</p>
<p>Safety techniques, games, wild dreams: a brainstorm always begins as a catalogue, we’ll see what comes out of it.</p>
<p>Safety techniques: from Killer the assassination game. Don’t impose yourself, don’t put anyone at risk, don’t give anyone reasons to start a fight or put you in jail.</p>
<p>Games: flashmob can be sort of that, also Read/play games (Sean Patrick Caine), Casual games for casual hikers (Harry Josephine Giles), Walking the Furtuire (Randy Lubin), barter hunt (you have a number of worthless items and must barter with passer bys until you have a whole different set of items)</p>
<p>Techniques:</p>
<ul>
<li>captive audience (vehicle, elevator, hike, queuing, etc.)</li>
<li>funny disguise, congeniality, spotting “open” people</li>
<li>scape alteration: road sign, chalk drawing, decorative item (photo frame, bird cage, plant), audio, last enrolled is hyped (hype snowball), audience circle</li>
<li>enrollment prop : empty photo frame, funny hat, magic wand, water pistol, menu/leaflet etc. clear tone &amp; contract</li>
<li>low barrier for entry (physical and cognitive), no win/lose, a good sense of personally vs socially acceptable limits</li>
</ul>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/enchanting-mundania/7729/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/enchanting-mundania/7729/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 10:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7729-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/enchanting-mundania/7729.rss">Enchanting Mundania</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
