<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Myriad Islands: Tomb of the Volcano Queen (Old-School Essentials)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/myriad-islands-tomb-of-the-volcano-queen-old-school-essentials/7736</link>
    <description>*This is for three sessions of Old-School Essentials in March (Thursdays 7 PM GMT)*

---

Hidden among the  **Myriad Islands**  lies the volcanic island  **Nimyros.**  Once a mighty island-state, ruled by the queen  **Viperia**  – a powerful sorceress whose influence ranged all the way to  **Takhmim**  and  **Kryfada**  – it is now a remote, mostly uninhabited place. The volcano is now inactive and its queen lies in a tomb ruled by a secret order of goat-people. Travellers rarely visit Nimyros, because the  **Great Blue Sea**  seemingly offers more lucrative adventures. You, however, have discovered that there might be more to Nimyros than meets the average rumour mill.

**Myriad Islands**  is a homebrew medieval fantasy setting inspired by the Mediterranean Sea and the classical cultures that dwelt around it.

---

**Old-School Essentials**  is a restatement of the popular B/X edition of the most popular fantasy game, with a focus on treasure-hunting, dungeon crawling, wilderness exploration, and peril.

Rules Knowledge is not required -- everything will be taught at the game.

We will play the game with a selection of Advanced Fantasy classes, together with some custom ones. For example, there are no elves, dwarves, etc. Instead we, will have two non-human classes available:  *Goat-People*  and  *Otter-People.*

---

**Duration:**  3 hours

**Breaks:**  Two 5 minute breaks at the top of each hour.

**Safety Tools:**  X-Card, Lines &amp; Veils, Open Door Policy. This event will follow the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct.](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html)

**Venue:**  GM&#39;s Zoom for video/audio and Owlbear Rodeo for maps &amp; tokens.

**Recording:**  The session will not be recorded.

Participants will be sent more information a week before the game.

**Open Access: Thursday, 13 january @ 12:00 GMT**

----

Session 1: https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2dMmOLORn3_o-LkDW
Session 2: https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2dZrZq4SnseaFEcov
Session 3: https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2fNdpWgqqs2z6RMVQ</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:18:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/myriad-islands-tomb-of-the-volcano-queen-old-school-essentials/7736.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Myriad Islands: Tomb of the Volcano Queen (Old-School Essentials)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dankusan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dankusan">@dankusan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>This is for three sessions of Old-School Essentials in March (Thursdays 7 PM GMT)</em></p>
<hr>
<p>Hidden among the  <strong>Myriad Islands</strong>  lies the volcanic island  <strong>Nimyros.</strong>  Once a mighty island-state, ruled by the queen  <strong>Viperia</strong>  – a powerful sorceress whose influence ranged all the way to  <strong>Takhmim</strong>  and  <strong>Kryfada</strong>  – it is now a remote, mostly uninhabited place. The volcano is now inactive and its queen lies in a tomb ruled by a secret order of goat-people. Travellers rarely visit Nimyros, because the  <strong>Great Blue Sea</strong>  seemingly offers more lucrative adventures. You, however, have discovered that there might be more to Nimyros than meets the average rumour mill.</p>
<p><strong>Myriad Islands</strong>  is a homebrew medieval fantasy setting inspired by the Mediterranean Sea and the classical cultures that dwelt around it.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Old-School Essentials</strong>  is a restatement of the popular B/X edition of the most popular fantasy game, with a focus on treasure-hunting, dungeon crawling, wilderness exploration, and peril.</p>
<p>Rules Knowledge is not required – everything will be taught at the game.</p>
<p>We will play the game with a selection of Advanced Fantasy classes, together with some custom ones. For example, there are no elves, dwarves, etc. Instead we, will have two non-human classes available:  <em>Goat-People</em>  and  <em>Otter-People.</em></p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Duration:</strong>  3 hours</p>
<p><strong>Breaks:</strong>  Two 5 minute breaks at the top of each hour.</p>
<p><strong>Safety Tools:</strong>  X-Card, Lines &amp; Veils, Open Door Policy. This event will follow the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct.</a></p>
<p><strong>Venue:</strong>  GM’s Zoom for video/audio and Owlbear Rodeo for maps &amp; tokens.</p>
<p><strong>Recording:</strong>  The session will not be recorded.</p>
<p>Participants will be sent more information a week before the game.</p>
<p><strong>Open Access: Thursday, 13 january @ 12:00 GMT</strong></p>
<hr>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2dMmOLORn3_o-LkDW" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2dMmOLORn3_o-LkDW</a><br>
Session 2: <a href="https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2dZrZq4SnseaFEcov" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2dZrZq4SnseaFEcov</a><br>
Session 3: <a href="https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2fNdpWgqqs2z6RMVQ" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntletcalendar.com/event-detail/-Mt2fNdpWgqqs2z6RMVQ</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/myriad-islands-tomb-of-the-volcano-queen-old-school-essentials/7736/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/myriad-islands-tomb-of-the-volcano-queen-old-school-essentials/7736/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7736-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/myriad-islands-tomb-of-the-volcano-queen-old-school-essentials/7736.rss">Myriad Islands: Tomb of the Volcano Queen (Old-School Essentials)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
