<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Alice is Missing (Oct 6th)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alice-is-missing-oct-6th/7419</link>
    <description>Alice is Missing is a silent role-playing game about the disappearance of Alice Briarwood, a high school junior in the small town of Silent Falls.

After character creation, the game is played live and without verbal communication. Players inhabit their character for the entirety of the 90-minute play session, and instead of speaking, send text messages back and forth to the other characters in a group chat, as well as individually. They explore their relationships with each other and Alice while also trying to figure out where Alice may be. The game regularly creates new information and plot events through the use of card reveals that occur at scheduled times.

**Content Warning:**  Alice is Missing inherently deals with topics of lack of agency, death, grief, helplessness, loss, tense family dynamics, and violence. Player discretion is advised.

**Media Touchstones:**  Life Is Strange, Gone Home, Oxenfree, Firewatch, Twin Peaks

**Safety Tools:**  X-Card, Lines and Veils, Open Door

**Code of Conduct:**  This event adheres to the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct

**Technology:**  Discord

**Signups**: One seat is being saved for José Feito, who initially requested this game. RSVPs open to all on 9/26 at 1:30pm Eastern. For the first 24 hours, please only signup if you haven&#39;t played Alice is Missing before.

I will send links and further information in an email one week before the game. 

*This post stolen from Mark W who stole it from Donogh.

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MkIheUUneQazG0vwqYx</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 17:33:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alice-is-missing-oct-6th/7419.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Alice is Missing (Oct 6th)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MPelletier]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mpelletier">@MPelletier</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Alice is Missing is a silent role-playing game about the disappearance of Alice Briarwood, a high school junior in the small town of Silent Falls.</p>
<p>After character creation, the game is played live and without verbal communication. Players inhabit their character for the entirety of the 90-minute play session, and instead of speaking, send text messages back and forth to the other characters in a group chat, as well as individually. They explore their relationships with each other and Alice while also trying to figure out where Alice may be. The game regularly creates new information and plot events through the use of card reveals that occur at scheduled times.</p>
<p><strong>Content Warning:</strong>  Alice is Missing inherently deals with topics of lack of agency, death, grief, helplessness, loss, tense family dynamics, and violence. Player discretion is advised.</p>
<p><strong>Media Touchstones:</strong>  Life Is Strange, Gone Home, Oxenfree, Firewatch, Twin Peaks</p>
<p><strong>Safety Tools:</strong>  X-Card, Lines and Veils, Open Door</p>
<p><strong>Code of Conduct:</strong>  This event adheres to the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</p>
<p><strong>Technology:</strong>  Discord</p>
<p><strong>Signups</strong>: One seat is being saved for José Feito, who initially requested this game. RSVPs open to all on 9/26 at 1:30pm Eastern. For the first 24 hours, please only signup if you haven’t played Alice is Missing before.</p>
<p>I will send links and further information in an email one week before the game.</p>
<p>*This post stolen from Mark W who stole it from Donogh.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MkIheUUneQazG0vwqYx" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MkIheUUneQazG0vwqYx</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alice-is-missing-oct-6th/7419/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alice-is-missing-oct-6th/7419/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 17:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7419-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/alice-is-missing-oct-6th/7419.rss">Alice is Missing (Oct 6th)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
