<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership in Belonging Outside Belonging</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338</link>
    <description>_The Pack is a Belonging Outside Belonging game about domestic dogs who form a pack after they wake up to find all the humans gone. You play to survive and to find out what happened to the humans._

Conventional wisdom says that a pack of dogs has an &quot;alpha,&quot; who is dominant over the rest of the pack. (According to wikipedia, this isn&#39;t strictly true, but it is apocrypha that&#39;s widely accepted.)

I&#39;ve been thinking about adding a mechanism to Belonging Outside Belonging that elevates one character to a leadership (&quot;alpha&quot;) role. That role isn&#39;t necessarily permanent, and other pack members can challenge the alpha&#39;s dominance.

**How well do you think something like this would work at the table?**

&gt; At the beginning of the session, there&#39;s a separate pile of 3 tokens called the **dominance pile**.
&gt; 
&gt; Pack members would all have access to the following moves:
&gt; 
&gt; - Weak move: Obey the command of the alpha against your better judgement
&gt; - Neutral move: Disobey a command that would cause you distress or harm 
&gt; - Strong move: Assert dominance over the alpha so other pack members see (physically overpowering the alpha or disobeying a reasonable command)
&gt; 
&gt; Whomever holds the Alpha role would have access to these moves:
&gt; 
&gt; - Win a challenge to dominance = put a token in the dominance pile
&gt; - Flub an important decision = take a token from the dominance pile
&gt; - Fail to give direction at an important moment = take a token from the dominance pile
&gt; 
&gt; When the dominance pile is empty, the character must give up the Alpha role.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 15:43:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Leadership in Belonging Outside Belonging</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Axxroytovu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/axxroytovu">@Axxroytovu</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is pretty interesting, and definitely a different direction to take BOB. I don’t think there’s an inherent reason this wouldn’t work, but I have some reservations.</p>
<ol>
<li>Adding a second currency might just make the game more complicated. BOB is beautiful in its simplicity and ease of use, and breaking up the game more by having a second currency might not play out how you want it.</li>
<li>BOB already has a mechanic for changing playbooks around! Maybe instead of “setting elements” you have “pack roles” with more stringent pick up/put down conditions. Whenever the Alpha cedes to another’s authority, they must put down the Alpha playbook. Whenever a dog does something incredibly stupid they pick up the Pup playbook. Whenever a dog protects one of their own at steep cost, pick up the Guardian playbook.</li>
<li>Definitely read Bite Marks, which is a great game that already includes a rotating Alpha role. Maybe you can take some inspiration from there.</li>
</ol>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 15:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5338-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338.rss">Leadership in Belonging Outside Belonging</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Leadership in Belonging Outside Belonging</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think Yes it will work but. It’s only one gauge and. From my perspective it lacks canine we-ness. That is : it reads things from outside the pack. Like, some have named it “simulation vs emulation”.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 15:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5338-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338.rss">Leadership in Belonging Outside Belonging</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Leadership in Belonging Outside Belonging</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><em>The Pack is a Belonging Outside Belonging game about domestic dogs who form a pack after they wake up to find all the humans gone. You play to survive and to find out what happened to the humans.</em></p>
<p>Conventional wisdom says that a pack of dogs has an “alpha,” who is dominant over the rest of the pack. (According to wikipedia, this isn’t strictly true, but it is apocrypha that’s widely accepted.)</p>
<p>I’ve been thinking about adding a mechanism to Belonging Outside Belonging that elevates one character to a leadership (“alpha”) role. That role isn’t necessarily permanent, and other pack members can challenge the alpha’s dominance.</p>
<p><strong>How well do you think something like this would work at the table?</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>At the beginning of the session, there’s a separate pile of 3 tokens called the <strong>dominance pile</strong>.</p>
<p>Pack members would all have access to the following moves:</p>
<ul>
<li>Weak move: Obey the command of the alpha against your better judgement</li>
<li>Neutral move: Disobey a command that would cause you distress or harm</li>
<li>Strong move: Assert dominance over the alpha so other pack members see (physically overpowering the alpha or disobeying a reasonable command)</li>
</ul>
<p>Whomever holds the Alpha role would have access to these moves:</p>
<ul>
<li>Win a challenge to dominance = put a token in the dominance pile</li>
<li>Flub an important decision = take a token from the dominance pile</li>
<li>Fail to give direction at an important moment = take a token from the dominance pile</li>
</ul>
<p>When the dominance pile is empty, the character must give up the Alpha role.</p>
</blockquote>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 12:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5338-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/leadership-in-belonging-outside-belonging/5338.rss">Leadership in Belonging Outside Belonging</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
