<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>GCOG: Against the Dark Conspiracy</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-against-the-dark-conspiracy/7136</link>
    <description>Marrakesh ... the team&#39;s Sparks, Hanna, has set up a van&#39;s fake breakdown to enable former NSA Analyst, Eli to keep eye&#39;s on both the hotel where their target is staying and the team of local &#39;watchers&#39; who are also watching it. meanwhile former Lisky Bratva Burglar, Jan sips tea while waiting for the right moment to get past the receptionist, and ex-Navy Seal Assassin, Calder, gets the drop on the senior watcher. There&#39;s an &#39;engine fire&#39; with associated smoke screen, a frightened journalist to save, and a smooth exfiltration that leaves someone known to Calder fuming in the van&#39;s exhaust fumes ... then a suspicious health charity, an archaeological dig at a Transylvanian, and tense intra-team relations before a shadow emerges from the pit ...

https://youtu.be/ixfhZ8mcOq4</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:52:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-against-the-dark-conspiracy/7136.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>GCOG: Against the Dark Conspiracy</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alun_R]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alun_r">@Alun_R</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Marrakesh … the team’s Sparks, Hanna, has set up a van’s fake breakdown to enable former NSA Analyst, Eli to keep eye’s on both the hotel where their target is staying and the team of local ‘watchers’ who are also watching it. meanwhile former Lisky Bratva Burglar, Jan sips tea while waiting for the right moment to get past the receptionist, and ex-Navy Seal Assassin, Calder, gets the drop on the senior watcher. There’s an ‘engine fire’ with associated smoke screen, a frightened journalist to save, and a smooth exfiltration that leaves someone known to Calder fuming in the van’s exhaust fumes … then a suspicious health charity, an archaeological dig at a Transylvanian, and tense intra-team relations before a shadow emerges from the pit …</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="ixfhZ8mcOq4" data-youtube-title="GCOG Against the Dark Conspiracy" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-against-the-dark-conspiracy/7136/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-against-the-dark-conspiracy/7136/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7136-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gcog-against-the-dark-conspiracy/7136.rss">GCOG: Against the Dark Conspiracy</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
