<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280</link>
    <description>In thinking about this post [https://discourse.funtimers.club/t/choosing-price-as-a-design-element/1210/18](http://Choosing Price As Design), 

I wonder: How do we measure the success of a product, an event, author, or a publisher?

There are a lot of models in our little community. A lot of different events, cultures, conventions, publishing houses, etc. A lot of these seem to have different intentions. Some examples off the top of my head:

1. authors and publishers that intentionally and meaningfully publish women and PoC in an attempt to make gaming more diverse.
2. An author who uses harassment as a advertising strategy, and generates a reasonable amount of cash before being excused from the community. _[ Probably the least said on this one the better, but it is a model.]_
3. Talented people designing games and living in poverty and near-poverty, reliant upon the continued investment of a community built off DIY principles.
4. A DIY camping and gaming event that meets every year, has some ups and downs and generates a lot of community love while relying on all volunteer labor. (BTW: campnerdly.org, reg is open)
5. A con company that uses a lot of volunteer and near-volunteer labor, that espouses and lives values of inclusivity
6. A con company that has large scale cons for thousands of people while generating boatloads of cash for the investor class.
7. A community&#39;s expensive, well-designed, and well-modded forums intended to advance a community spirit and spread a particular cool culture of gaming.
8. a gaming table that uses it&#39;s own material and is diverged from all published material over the past decade.

These are not meant to be exhaustive nor inclusive; there are more models and I have intentionally fictionalized these to highlight the differences. These are *not* meant to refer to specific people and organizations, but to highlight the difference in models. And in particular, these are not meant to cast aspersions at anyone (well, one. You are not him.)

Which of these can be called successful? What are the relevant components to these being successful? Is there a difference between a successful business and a successful community? If so, what is it?

Can an organization consistently be both a successful community and a successful business?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 12:33:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, it was intentionally an extreme case to have one we could all agree on. This line in the sand where we can basically all say (especially here): “This is a type of strategy that the community defines as failure, no matter what the individual says.”</p>
<p>Which is to say: There are some types of personal success that are judged as failure by the community. Figuring out where that line meaningfully is is much harder, but now we have a fairly concrete (while attempting to not actually name names) of how the personal and community can differ on success.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/64">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/64</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 12:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-64</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s a rather extreme case, but considering some recent controversies with a certain individual it’s entirely in line with what I’m saying. DrivethruRPG’s less than adequate handling of the situation is exactly the kind of response fostered by the current culture.</p>
<p>But the majority cases I’m talking about do not involve malice, for example in regards to the recent Trophy contest, one user expressed concern that another was excited and wanted to publish the incursions. It struck me as weird; I can understand where they’re coming from of not wanting to slippery slope into churning out assembly line incursions, but when it manifests itself as actively discouraging people from pursuing success or larger recognition it doesn’t give me the impression of a community that supports and platforms one another.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/63">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/63</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 11:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-63</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>So for an example, <a class="mention" href="/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> that I listed in the OP: a creator who uses harassment as an advertising strategy could consider themselves to be personally successful (made the moneys), but the community may consider them to be a failure (because harassment is bad).</p>
<p>Is that along the lines of what you mean by success being personally defined being toxic?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/62">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/62</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 02:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-62</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think I am failing to distinguish between if we are talking about success as a <em>personal</em> factor or success as a <em>cultural</em> one. I’m not trying to shame anyone’s personal choice, but as a community/culture/industry we should have a definition of what success looks like, and I feel at minimum it should be a living wage.</p>
<p>So when someone states their personal definition of success, be it publishing, homebrewing, hacking, just making a functional game, etc. I don’t see anything wrong with that. What irks me is when people respond negatively or try to shame others for trying to/being excited about monetizing their work. I think we should respect and encourage anyone’s effort to try and support themselves with their art (this is not the same as someone trying to <em>maximize monetary gain from their art</em>).I think that if we want the ttrpg creator community to grow , we need some kind of measure of who is and isn’t succesful so we can focus efforts towards helping those who are struggling.</p>
<p>When I use the word “toxic” I am not trying to insult any individual’s choice. What I am trying to say is that when “success is personally defined” is the majority definition of “success” in this industry, it doesn’t allow underprivileged creators in, it doesn’t encourage a tighter knit community, and it doesn’t protect the community from bad actors. That is not to say that community members aren’t actively doing all these things, but I feel the overall culture is agnostic to these issues because it values Independence over Community</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/61">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/61</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-61</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m not sure where confusion stems from. My reading is that Radmad 1) agrees that there are modalities of success (this is what Alex talks about above) but 2) measurement within each mode is not subjective or personal.</p>
<p>This second part is a pretty sound argument if you consider the topmost mode of success: ttrpg that pays all you bills and then some. In current climate it is super hard to get from being unknown to being sustainable through ttrpg if you don’t have something that pays your bills along the way. In other words: if you don’t have the money already I guess it sucks to be you. Personal measure of success here really boils down to saying “you need monies to make monies” which is sadly true but reinforcing this may be labeled toxic indeed.</p>
<p>IDK if I agree with him 100% but talking about modalities of success really only hides the fact that success is not for everyone and we should focus on figuring out how to change that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/60">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/60</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 22:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-60</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The element that I disagree with is the assertion that ‘success is personally defined’ is toxic. I think that is taking an offensive potshot at an alternative position to his own.</p>
<p>The person who has been procrastinating at getting a game published because they feared failure? For them success is legitimately getting it done. The person who has produced a game about a subject they care deeply about even though they know it will have limited appeal? For them success is getting it to their tiny audience. The person who just wants to create some things that some other people may enjoy? For them success is knowing that other people are playing and enjoying it.</p>
<p>By saying that their personally defined success is toxic is invalidating them. I think it is a gatekeeping attitude that is bad for the hobby as a whole and personally damaging to people in those kinds of position.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/59">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/59</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 21:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-59</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thank you <a class="mention" href="/u/radmad">@Radmad</a>! That’s a well put together position.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/alex">@Alex</a>: Do you have questions about Radman’s position? Do you disagree with it? If so, can you tell us why?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/58">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/58</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 20:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-58</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is a fantastic point!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/57">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/57</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-57</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="55" data-topic="1280">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/radmad/40/2161_2.png" class="avatar"> Radmad:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t think creating more business around ttrpgs will taint the culture in nearly the same way it has for videogames. ttrpgs have far less anonymity shielding and most of the industry leaders are far more conscious of maintaining a safe and inclusive culture.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>FWIW the primary reason for the predatory characteristic of (AAA) video game landscape seems to be the systemic elimination of authorship. You no longer have “faces” of games created, instead you have vaguely defined teams of studios. This doesn’t seem to be the case with ttrpg and even commercial endeavors of largest publishers are associated with a well established designer or few.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/56">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/56</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 18:06:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-56</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I will try to summarize without repeating myself. I don’t think there is anything wrong or shameful without choosing not to monetize your pastime. I am  aware that when you add “making money” to your hobby formula it changes it, and for a lot of people that would take the joy out of it. <em>But</em> if we want ttrpgs to be more than a cottage industry (yes there are a few large scale companies, but they are not anywhere near the norm) we need to encourage and reward creators. There have been amazing strides in improving the <em>social</em> culture of ttrpgs, but not nearly as much in the way of the <em>economic</em> culture (Patreon and Kickstarter are the most notable, I would also nominate DrivethruRPG/itchIO but I don’t think they’re driving the ttrpg culture in any way close to what Steam did for videogames).</p>
<p>IMO I don’t think creating more business around ttrpgs will taint the culture in nearly the same way it has for videogames. ttrpgs have far less anonymity shielding and most of the industry leaders are far more conscious of maintaining a safe and inclusive culture. There will certainly be growing pains, but it won’t be the first or last time ttrpgs have to deal with culture problems.</p>
<p>To address <a class="mention" href="/u/alex">@Alex</a> comment, I’m not really sure how he’s getting that I’m calling for a standardization of creation/distribution practices. I am trying to be as straightforward and literal as I can be when I say “anyone <em>should be able to</em> make a living wage from making ttrpgs”, not <em>everyone needs to</em>.</p>
<p>I stand by my comment that a culture of “success is personally defined” is subtly toxic. It’s a statement that maintains the current status quo of providing the greatest affordance to those who already have a stable income and sufficient leisure time to create zero sum to value negative art. I get that that is not what is intended when people state it, but I don’t think it’s the kind of philosophy that encourages someone who can barely make ends meet to sacrifice their minimal or nonexistent free time on something that will <em>lose them</em> money. The suffering artist is a romantic notion but it’s not fair to inflict it on others or insist it’s more honorable than being a slave to your audience.</p>
<p>I also think it’s a false dichotomy to state that if you’re against completely decentralized defintions of success you’re for only one kind of success. I’m all for letting people pursue their passion as they see fit, but there should be a <em>minimum</em> viability and that viability should be a living wage.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/55">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/55</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 01:51:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-55</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a class="mention" href="/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> and <a class="mention" href="/u/alex">@Alex</a> seem to have very different views here, and I’d for sure love to tease out what they both think the other is saying.</p>
<p>If we do that, I want to make sure all of us follow the principle of charity – that is, that we assume our interlocutor is a decent person, and try to make sure we understand what they mean.</p>
<p>To that end: Can both of you explain your views? Are you both interested in determining why the other persons view is so far removed from your own?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/54">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/54</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 23:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-54</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="33" data-topic="1280">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/radmad/40/2161_2.png" class="avatar"> Radmad:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If I may add something to justify this thread resurrection, I think that so many people having the attitude that “success is personally defined” is subtly toxic to the overall community and industry.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>For the record I 100% disagree with this assertion. What is toxic is to try to make one size fit everyone.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/53">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/53</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 20:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-53</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alex">@Alex</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I would argue that someone underpricing their games is bad because it generates an expectation about the viable cost of games in general, and the knock on effect of that is that it becomes much more difficult for people who are trying to make a living from it.</p>
<p>Consider the impact of phone AppStores, which have driven down the price of software so that customers shy away from paying more for their software than a coffee chain charges for their take away coffee. Some developers get viral success and make a business, some move to a subscription model, some find that they can’t justify it as a full time job.</p>
<p>Whether or not someone is producing and selling ttrpg material as a full time job, setting prices is something that can impact people beyond yourself, and is something that shouldn’t be done lightly.</p>
<p>Cheers</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/52">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/52</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 20:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-52</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/wilhelm">@Wilhelm</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Over the years my games have become prettier and prettier as I get to combine long tail sales from more and more stuff to fund the artwork for each new project. Artwork being the only thing in publishing I can’t do reasonably well myself.</p>
<p>From my point of view Wilhelm’s Games is a highly successful undertaking.  It has reached its goals ten years running.  The definition of success for Wilhelm’s Games is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Give me an audience for my game writing.</li>
<li>Make enough money to support the publishing of the games I write, including the purchase of artwork.</li>
<li>Never turn a profit.</li>
<li>Never have a revenue in excess of ~$3000 in a year.</li>
</ul>
<p>The bottom two combined allow me to skip taxation and book-keeping as the Swedish revenue service considers it a hobby.</p>
<p>Since I have that revenue ceiling I haven’t made anything a kickstarter, which would give me more conventional success. Managing the financial side of things would take the enjoyment out of it for me.</p>
<p>I wouldn’t feel comfortable intentionally running my game design projects at a financial loss, even if I know people who do. But having the games pay for themselves is fine.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/51">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/51</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 19:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-51</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I probably wouldn’t if I had <em>no chance</em> of recouping the cost. I treat those published products as business and do not buy art that I cannot pay for with the gross revenue. It’s irresponsible as a business owner and I take that part of it seriously.</p>
<p>I’ve spent $50 on custom art for my personal D&amp;D character though. So I do that kind of thing occasionally.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/50">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/50</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 21:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-50</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We are deviating a bit from the main topic, which is ok.</p>
<p>To maybe help:<br>
<a class="mention" href="/u/adam">@Adam</a>: would you have spent the money on art of you had no chance of recouping the cost?</p>
<p>My guess is the real answer is yes, and that you build games not for the extrinsic reward of money, but for intrinsic motivations.</p>
<p>Let me know if that is correct.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/49">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/49</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 21:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-49</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Good question. The main speaker at the seminar was the guy that created Eclipse Phase.  He pointed out that products directed towards players always sell better than products directed towards GMs. I took this to mean that for more trad style games the priority is something like this:</p>
<p>Player handbooks &gt; complete rulebooks &gt; DM guides &gt; modules / settings &gt; add-on rules.  Quick start rules are generally given away free to generate interest so I am not sure where they fall into this.</p>
<p>It seems to me that you would be modeling Quickstart + mini- adventure for free and then rules for purchase.  It seems like this could work but I always wonder how anyone cuts out enough of the Quickstart to be worth buying the full rules while also leaving in enough to make it work.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/48">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/48</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 20:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-48</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BlakeRyan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blakeryan">@BlakeRyan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>yep i’m with Adam, I spent $300 on stock art and i’d at least like to break even.</p>
<p>On that topic, some people act like stock art is bad, i disagree. drivethru has some great stock art, ranging from $2 to $150 each.</p>
<p>The key is finding several pieces of similar style so you give your product a style and tone.</p>
<p>The other side of charging for products is they have funded me buying other games.</p>
<p>Money from Don’t pay the Ferryman has bought me Impulse Drive, The Veil, Warhammer 4e, The Dark Eye, Monster Hearts, Vagabonds of Dyffud and Blades in the Dark.</p>
<p>Buying those helped the community, and reading those helped me define what I want, what I can adjust and what I don’t want-in my game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/47</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 20:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-47</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/radmad">@Radmad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="45" data-topic="1280">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/deckard/40/2412_2.png" class="avatar"> Deckard:</div>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>free stuff gets more downloads (but not necessarily more plays)</li>
<li>paid stuff gets more money</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Am I insane in thinking I can get both if I offer an adventure module with enough rules to play for free and have it direct people to a core rulebook that costs money?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/46</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 19:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Deckard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/deckard">@Deckard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I agree completely!  I would argue that this is more than anecdotal.  The sunk cost fallacy is real.  It is a major reason that Gloomhaven is ranked # 1 on <a href="http://boardgamegeek.com" rel="nofollow noopener">boardgamegeek.com</a>.  Who spends $120 on a board game and then doesn’t get it to the table?  Very few.</p>
<p>In my personal version of this, I feel like I waste money if I pay for $15 or more for a game (tt-rpg or board game) that I have never played.  Meanwhile, if I do not use free material, I think “Who cares?  It was free anyway.” I also feel like a lot of the free stuff on <a href="http://drivethrurpg.com" rel="nofollow noopener">drivethrurpg.com</a> is ashcan stuff.  It may not be true but that is the feeling you get from free stuff.</p>
<p>In addition, I can always re-sell physical games and books I don’t use for at least $5 and charge shipping.  If it was a PDF, I can’t re-sell it, so if I bought it for more than $10, I am going to try to get this game played.</p>
<p>I also see examples that if you have the reputation for quality games and books, then you can sell them for $100+ sight unseen and do fine.  My example is Monte Cook’s Invisible Sun.  Until that game was sold, no one knew anything about it except the writer and that they were beautifully bound books, and yet he sold out.  Maybe it is great but no one knew that when they pre-ordered it.</p>
<p>Here are some hints I heard at a <a href="http://drivethrurpg.com" rel="nofollow noopener">drivethrurpg.com</a> seminar a few years back that:</p>
<ul>
<li>free stuff gets more downloads (but not necessarily more plays)</li>
<li>paid stuff gets more money</li>
<li>PWYW on this site gets you less downloads and less money.</li>
</ul>
<p>PWYW may work well if you have built your own site and reputation up but maybe not great on the biggest download site.</p>
<p>In addition, it was suggested, when you launch your game offer a limited time sale…perhaps even for $0.00.  This gives people the perception of value and scarcity.  Then, if your product is good, word may spread by word of mouth, and then the regular price can be supported.</p>
<p>I would also personally add, that this approach also gives game developers a chance to reward playtesters and friends that have followed and supported your work without completely devaluing the work on the game.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/45</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 19:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>(I realize now that “why charge” / “because it’s a business” is a sort of circular argument, but sorta isn’t, too.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/44</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 15:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Adam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/adam">@Adam</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="40" data-topic="1280">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/william_nichols/40/530_2.png" class="avatar"> William_Nichols:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>if you are not making much from the PDFs, why charge at all? That is: why is charging for PDFs essential?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I can answer for myself: I spend money to make my products and I’d like to break even at least. Further, though, it’s a <em>business</em> and I need to make a profit.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/43</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 14:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Anecdotally at least, people are more likely to engage with a product they’ve paid for than one they’ve been given. So if you want people to play your stuff, charging for it makes that more likely in my experience.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/42</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 13:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JasonT]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasont">@JasonT</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I can’t speak for Blake, but I have been pretty closely following the “why charge at all?” conversation around the industry/community, and just started offering my games as pay-what-you-want rather than as free. (And I am likely to start setting minimum prices for some games in the future.) Some food for thought:</p>
<p><strong>(1) Charging money for high-quality products and services combats the common expectation that RPGs “should” be free or cheap.</strong></p>
<p>I personally disagree with the position that individual creators have a moral imperative to charge for their own self-published products—sometimes, adding money to the equation actually damages your ability to take pleasure in an activity for its own sake, and most of us regard RPGs as a hobby, and a source of pleasure. That’s why my very short games are still available free: It’s a hobby for me, and refocusing on it as a business would make me unhappy. But I do think that <em>working</em> for free or cheap for other publishers undercuts people competing for jobs they actually need, and I also believe that putting a price tag on products with high production values (including professional art and graphic design) helps popularize the idea that <em>if you want good-looking RPGs, you need to pay for them.</em> (I’m still wrestling internally with the implications of this for games with poor production quality but brilliant game design. The game design is worth something, too! But I don’t think it’s unreasonable that the average customer has no interest in paying for access to my unedited Google Docs.)</p>
<p><strong>(2) Sales offer a metric to measure “success” that’s more meaningful than downloads, and easier to track than actual use in play.</strong></p>
<p>This is the reason I finally relented and started accepting money via pay-what-you-want offerings, even though I dread what it will do to me when it’s time to prepare my taxes. I want to know how my games are being received, what people like to play, which of my designs are worth expanding on to contribute more to the hobby and find people with similar tastes to enjoy games with. Free downloads are nice to track, but effectively meaningless if you want to get a sense of who’s even read your game, let alone played it. (How many free games do <em>you</em> have sitting unread on your hard drive?) A game that somebody has paid for, however, is a game that is more likely to be read (if for no other reason than that the buyer wants to get their money’s worth), and being read is a prerequisite to being played.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong—I really appreciate that my first month of game sales have covered half of my Metatopia registration already! But for a designer with a day job, the earnings from sales are kind of incidental compared to the sales’ significance as a metric vaguely reflecting player interest.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/41</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 12:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>That’s awesome Blake, thanks you.</p>
<p>A follow up question: if you are not making much from the PDFs, why charge at all? That is: why is charging for PDFs essential?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280/40</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1280-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/measure-of-success-publishing-cons-etc/1280.rss">Measure of Success: Publishing, Cons, etc</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
