<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346</link>
    <description>Hi everyone.

I&#39;ve seen various discussions all over the internet about problems with the X-card.  I&#39;m aware of most of them such as it being a blunt tool, people being dismissive of it at the table and reducing its value.  I definitely agree that it is useful only as part of a wider conversation and safety culture - not as a substitute.

However I&#39;ve also heard people talking about how it is abused and that having it at a table can make things worse.  I&#39;ve never seen this in practice - I&#39;m British, I play with mostly British people and I&#39;ve never seen someone use the X-card to push limits in games.  I&#39;m wondering if this is a cultural thing and there is some problem with the X-card I&#39;m not seeing because I&#39;m not at the gaming tables where it happens.  

For clarity this is not about people ignoring the x-card or arguing back when it is invoked or demeaning it with jokes.  This is about people who push limits too far when the card is on the table that otherwise they probably wouldn&#39;t have done.

Would you be comfortable sharing examples of how having the X-card at a table has actually made it less safe rather than more safe.  I&#39;m trying to get a sense of what that would look like as I think about safely more widely.

[Edited to add: can I have first hand knowledge and examples - for the reasons stated below].

Thank you</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 08:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Thomas_Junk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/thomas_junk">@Thomas_Junk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thank you! This is really helpful!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/45</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 08:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@APM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/apm">@APM</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m afraid I don’t have any experiences with the xcard making the table less safe. I hope to bring something useful to the conversation nonetheless because I think safety mechanics are important and I’ve been thinking about them for some time.</p>
<p>I feel as if the issues with the xcard comes from whether the group is comfortable with using the card or not. If there’s a risk that the card doesn’t get used even though someone needs it, there is also the risk of people pushing harder and the risk that someone won’t object even though they feel like doing so.</p>
<p>Also you learn by doing. When you feel discomfort you might end up not using the card because it’s a new thing that you have yet to feel comfortable using. I believe it’s best to try it out early on, on minor things, to get a feel for how it works and affects the game and the group.</p>
<p>Feeling “this kinda ruins the fun for me” is a valid reason to use the xcard. That’s the whole point - you need to feel that any reason is valid. You should never have to motivate your use of the xcard even for yourself. Because that might lead you to think that you don’t have the right to use it, even though you really would benefit from it.</p>
<p>A very fitting metaphor came up on a thread on story games once:</p>
<p>A person said that the xcard is only supposed to be used in case of psychological harm, and said that it was just like a preference of food in comparison to an allergy: “I don’t like peanuts” compared to “I’m allergic to peanuts”. I happen to be allergic to certain foods and quickly realised that there is always a nuance to these things (with food as well as gaming experiences). I’m allergic to apples and nuts for example, but not to the extent that I die from eating them. My throat simply itches a whole lot. So, how bad a reaction is needed for me to use the x-card? I would definitely have a more pleasant meal if my throat didn’t start itching from it. So do I have the right to request “no nuts and raw apples”?</p>
<p>I argue that it doesn’t matter how bad a reaction you’re having because that question in itself is countering the card’s purpose. If you feel that “this ruins the experience for me” - then use the xcard if you want to change it. Simple as that. You get to trust your feelings however irrational.</p>
<p>I have used the xcard myself  and I couldn’t really put my finger on why I felt the way I did. It was when we suggested that a PCs child was abused in school by his teacher (another PC) and we started discussing whether the child had said anything about it or not to his parent. We settled on that the child was abused but that it was all out in the open and that all parties knew about it. For me it was vital that we made this change, even though I couldn’t motivate even to myself why at that time.</p>
<p>I have also had one time when I didn’t use the card though I realised in hindsight that I should have done so. (It’s important to teach players that they can change their minds by the way.)</p>
<p>I think that it all comes down to the question whether people dare using it or not when they need to. If players would happen to push harder when the xcard is on the table, that’s not really an issue as long as the other players feel free to use the xcard when the game is moving close to their personal boundaries.</p>
<p>[a little self promotion to finish off with]<br>
I have tackled this by making my own cards that are supposed to be used a lot (with an o-side to show approval and appreciation). <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/279093/Traffic-Lights-ENG?cPath=32371_32906" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/279093/Traffic-Lights-ENG?cPath=32371_32906</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/44</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 05:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MorganMontazh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/morganmontazh">@MorganMontazh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="41" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/pseudo310/40/520_2.png" class="avatar"> Pseudo310:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>So we were unable to respond to this player’s use of the X-card. The X-card user can clarify, but you cannot ask for clarification. Does that make sense?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Safety tools have a function that supersedes the way the rules are worded, which is, as <a class="mention" href="/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> put it in another thread, making sure the players feel more important than the game. If a player is clearly using one of those tools in bad faith, to do something other than protect the safety of themselves or others at the table, having a conversation about their behavior is not only permissible, but necessary.</p>
<p>There are rules about climbing ropes to keep people safe off the ground, but if somebody is using your climbing rope to tie somebody up, the rules might change a bit.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/43</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 22:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Dissonance]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dissonance">@Dissonance</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think “what is being x-ed” is a necessary and allowed question, though. So some clarification is allowed.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/42</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 18:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Pseudo310]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/pseudo310">@Pseudo310</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What I meant by my quote was this from the X-card document:</p>
<blockquote>
<ol start="6">
<li>It doesn’t matter why.</li>
</ol>
<p>No judgement. No questioning.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So we were unable to respond to this player’s use of the X-card. The X-card user can clarify, but you cannot ask for clarification. Does that make sense?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/41</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 18:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Mathias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mathias">@Mathias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This already exists, it is called the O-Card, written by Kira Magrann and it is also referenced in John Stavropoulos’ X-Card document.</p>
<p>Here is a good compilation of these tools by <span class="mention">@rpgnatalie</span> on Twitter:<br>
<aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/rpgnatalie/status/1029139930851762176" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_images/1135023561662271489/_nhA1Q83_400x400.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/rpgnatalie/status/1029139930851762176" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Natalie the Knife (rpgnatalie)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> I wrote a compilation of support tools for ttrpgs! it's also got thoughts from me on how support works, why we should do it, and how to do it effectively.

some of the tools are well known, some are less well known, some are tools I wrote just for it.

<a target="_blank" href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1T-4diHGaxlOy-N76rYmqYvLXkSV-dp_L3lSMZvb8Qqg/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">docs.google.com/document/d/1T-…</a>
</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/rpgnatalie/status/1029139930851762176" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">10:57 PM - 13 Aug 2018</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewbox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 260
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewbox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 150
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
</p>
<p>Just so we don’t re-hash or re-invent the wheel. It’s also with proper attributions and a living document.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/40</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 19:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MorganMontazh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/morganmontazh">@MorganMontazh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Meta-game discussion of this nature is always so good! Though I wouldn’t want to frame it in terms of, “I’m worried this might get X-Carded.” Maybe a “Push” card? Like, “I was interested in pushing / exploring this issue or relationship, how does the table feel?” (It could be potentially dangerous content, but it could also be an arc tied in within another character, or anything else.) Players spend so much time discussing tactics and strategy out of character, so why not discuss story and themes?</p>
<p>I’d just want to make sure it wasn’t something that made people feel like they were put on the spot to justify saying no to an idea, or worse, feel that accepting an idea in theory up front meant a player was waiving the right to object via X-Card later.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/39</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 17:54:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="36" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/transalaskan/40/178_2.png" class="avatar"> transalaskan:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I think more of the problem is in expecting the X-card being present to make play safe instead of expecting players to try to look out for each other.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yes, I sometimes also have this feeling that people assume “we have the X-card on the table, so everything is cool”.<br>
This may distract from using other useful techniques, like talking boundaries in the beginning (lines + veiles), paying attention to each other and I find especially <strong>Debriefing</strong> is not used enough outside of larp/freeform.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/38</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 06:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It might be neat to have a “question” card, or maybe include in the spiel the idea that you can say “hey, I was thinking of doing this, anybody want to X-card it?”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/37</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 06:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@transalaskan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/transalaskan">@transalaskan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I can’t speak to whether having the X-card on the table itself made people push harder—I can’t get inside anyone’s head—but I’ve had several games, mostly at cons, where the X-card was introduced as a token nod to safety and people <em>seemed</em> to take that as an excuse to play however they liked since the others could always go for the X-card. (Similar things happen with Lines sometimes, where players will keep introducing things just barely shy of the line or not explicitly included in the line phrasing.)</p>
<p>I’ll not list examples because this is a public forum, but basically any game that’s started with a dismissive/discouraging safety tool intro like “this is the x-card, it probably won’t come up” is likely to have content problems and to have pushback when people do try to use the X-card, in my experience.</p>
<p>Sort of an aside: One thing I don’t see nearly enough of—especially but not exclusively at cons—is people checking with the other players <em>before</em> doing something instead of leaning on “well they could X it.” I think more of the problem is in expecting the X-card being present to make play safe instead of expecting players to try to look out for each other.</p>
<p>(I <em>will</em> list an example of that last paragraph. At a con once, a facilitator turned to me and said “I think this character might misgender yours, is that okay with you or would that be too much?” Asking without expectation of agreement can make all the difference there, and it didn’t lean on me to both sit through it and then X it.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/36</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 23:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>(redundant entry, have deleted it)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/35</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 21:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Mathias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mathias">@Mathias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Quick note, the up-to-date version of that blog post and under P.H. Lee’s name can be found here on <a class="mention" href="/u/briebeau">@BrieBeau</a>’s site:<br>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://i0.wp.com/briebeau.com/thoughty/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-ThoughtyC_text-1.png?fit=32%2C32" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="http://briebeau.com/thoughty/2019/03/the-luxton-technique-by-p-h-lee/" target="_blank" title="08:31PM - 14 March 2019" rel="nofollow noopener">Thoughty – 14 Mar 19</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://i0.wp.com/briebeau.com/thoughty/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/cropped-ThoughtyC_text-1.png?fit=512%2C512" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="500" height="500">

<h3><a href="http://briebeau.com/thoughty/2019/03/the-luxton-technique-by-p-h-lee/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">PTSD, access to role-playing games, and the Luxton technique by P.H. Lee</a></h3>

<p>This post was originally posted on G+ by P.H. Lee on August 28, 2017. It was a significant influence on updates to the Script Change RPG toolbox, and is an essential read in regards to addressing s…</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<br>
(It’s also referenced in <a class="mention" href="/u/noellarh">@noellarh</a>’s post and thread about Holding Space for Trauma at the Table mentioned above.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/34</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 20:08:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Thought I’d share this as I’m doing more research on safety tools, as they feel relevant to the discussion.</p>
<p><a href="https://plus.google.com/u/2/117301572585814320386/posts/DTaEThFLZAR" rel="nofollow noopener">Ben Lehman’s Luxton Technique</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/33</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 19:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yeah, I guess it was played more as “Oh, I can’t do <em>this</em> particular thing, what about <em>this</em> other one?” with each avenue being it’s own X-carding. Maybe I should have explained better what I was X-Carding? I’m not sure what I should have said short of “leave my character the fuck alone.” But in a game where like… the whole point of it is interconnections between characters it can be hard to do that.</p>
<p>Thank you all for the support and feedback, though <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/32</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 17:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MorganMontazh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/morganmontazh">@MorganMontazh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="28" data-topic="1346">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/erikthebearik/40/837_2.png" class="avatar"> ErikTheBearik:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Problem is, someone else was playing a character who was the father of the kid, and kind of kept pushing the angle of “lets get back together, I can save your kid from this horrible situation, etc etc.” I X-carded it a few times but in the end I just had to walk away cuz I didn’t want to play a woman who was beholden to a man to literally save her life.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Not only does it sound like this table did not understand how to adjust the fiction once a particular topic has been X-Carded, but it also sounds like an overall violation of your consent by this other individual. They wanted you (through your character) to participate in a narrative arc with their character that you were not interested in participating in. Not OK, and once it was clear that table wasn’t going to respect your right to consent, walking away was probably the only option left. I’m sorry that happened to you.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/31</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BeckyA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It might be that ‘trauma simulator’ games aren’t your thing and that is cool.  But frankly the problem looks like</p>
<blockquote>
<p>X-carded it a few times</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Because once you used the X-card the first time that should have been the end of that plot - that person should not be continuing to push it and the MC of the game (or the rest of the table in a GMless game) should have had your back. I’m sorry they didn’t.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@noellarh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/noellarh">@noellarh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>reading your post, to me, seems like the problem was the other player. They should have respected what you wanted to do.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/29</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ErikTheBearik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/erikthebearik">@ErikTheBearik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’ll add in a personal anecdote. It was the only time I played in a game that used an X-Card, and it soured me on it a bit, but I still think the X-card overall has merit.</p>
<p>I was assigned to play a character who was essentially a prostitute in revolutionary France with a young daughter. I wanted to play her as a lesbian who did what she had to do to pay the bills, which was backed up in the fiction. Problem is, someone else was playing a character who was the father of the kid, and kind of kept pushing the angle of “lets get back together, I can save your kid from this horrible situation, etc etc.” I X-carded it a few times but in the end I just had to walk away cuz I didn’t want to play a woman who was beholden to a man to literally save her life.</p>
<p>Part of me thinks the problem was mostly that I was playing a “trauma simulator” game, and it turns out I really don’t enjoy those, especially in Convention settings.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 16:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@noellarh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/noellarh">@noellarh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I want to talk more about this, but thought it should go in a different thread so I created this topic: <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/holding-space-for-trauma-at-the-table/1380?u=noellarh" class="inline-onebox">Holding Space for Trauma at the Table</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MorganMontazh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/morganmontazh">@MorganMontazh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t think the X-Card encourages reckless play. I think reckless play is something that arrives externally, and can influence the way people interact with everything at the table, including safety tools.</p>
<p>I once had a game that moved into very uncomfortable territory that I, for one, was not comfortable with. (Monsterhearts, and I was MC’ing.) We stopped / slowed down when it happened, and then followed up with more conversation after the game. At the time, the player whose character had gone places we didn’t want to go, made a reference to, “Well, somebody could have X-Carded.” That said, I don’t believe that they were deliberately playing <strong>to</strong> the X-Card. I think that the issue would have come up regardless, based on the subject matter of the game, the particular narrative elements that were already in place, and the personalities at our table. I do, however, now include a, “Just because it’s there doesn’t mean we have to play to it,” disclaimer when introducing the X-Card.</p>
<p>Also, to be clear, I think everybody was behaving in good faith at our table, and the player in question really was just following the agenda and principles of their character and the story. We were a D&amp;D group playing our first game of Monsterhearts, and just hadn’t ever needed to think about safety in those ways before.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 15:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@William_Nichols]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/william_nichols">@William_Nichols</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We generally use a couple of modifications at the table:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Do NOT tell us why you x-carded. We use this rules variant for a reason: Some folks in our extended group have used the x-card as a springboard to discuss real trauma and, well: <a href="http://www.bluestockings.ca/2018/06/we-are-not-therapists-gaming-and-trauma.html?spref=gp&amp;m=1" rel="nofollow noopener">We are not Therapists</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Generally, if it’s a matter of tone or tenor, we’ll say “Try it a different way”. I’ve been on both sides of this, and it’s a great way (for us) to signal that something doesn’t fit the expected tone, but isn’t actively harmful to anything other than the game.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve been asked for clarification on the first point. Without discussing other people’s trauma: I have absolutely seen people use tapping the x-card to sprint in 20 minutes on the abuse they’ve suffered. I want to help my friends, but some of these discussions have been so difficult that I’ve needed to x-card them. They quickly crossed our established lines and veils and as they were regarding the x-card, we’ve felt powerless to stop it.</p>
<p>So, blanket rule change. This is probably further than most groups need.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 12:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shane">@shane</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>A recommendation: periodically go back and re-read John’s X-Card <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">page</a>. It is sometimes updated as he finds additional clarifications necessary. Some of the questions about how it is supposed to work are explained there. These safety tools are not static. (<a class="mention" href="/u/briebeau">@BrieBeau</a> regularly updates the <a href="http://briebeau.com/thoughty/script-change/" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change</a> site.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 10:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@BeckyA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beckya">@BeckyA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think a clear distinction is valuable - because this is a fairly universal tool and one of its strengths is that it is clear and simple to use.</p>
<p>The level of narrative editing for preference rather than safety is something which is more of a ‘same page issue’ - i.e. many games have narrative editing rules as a part of the game and others do not and that is a deliberate design choice.  I cannot imagine it going well if someone tried to use the X-card to nix a bad dice roll in a traditional or OSR style game.  Because that use would change the game that everyone had sat down to play together.  Whereas the original use of the X-card is a) about safety and b) shouldn’t change the nature of the game but merely edit out a small piece of the narrative which is hurtful.</p>
<p>I should add in general I’ve used the X-card and seen it used.  Only in a couple of occasions but in all cases it was valuable, interrupted something from getting out of hand and felt like a really great addition.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 09:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>One thing I might have issues with:<br>
Some people I know/play with like to also use the X-Card not only for safety reasons but also as a tool for narrative preference.<br>
So, when some content comes up in roleplaying that doesn’t bother them at all, they just prefer a different narrative, they use the X-card - just for content editing.<br>
While this might be a neat narrative tool for some games, personally I’d like to have a clear distinction between safety tools and narrative tools.<br>
How do you feel about this?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 06:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Discussion of X-card issues</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@beepeegee]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beepeegee">@beepeegee</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Yes, it’s important to make that distinction. In fact, I find it very important to talk about <em>what exactly</em> was the thing that made you feel uncomfortable so it can be edited out/modified.<br>
You just don’t need to talk and should definitely not be pressured into talking about <em>the reason why</em> it is disturbing you.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346/21</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 06:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-1346-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/discussion-of-x-card-issues/1346.rss">Discussion of X-card issues</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
