<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Back Again From the Broken Land</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/back-again-from-the-broken-land/6117</link>
    <description>**Please Note:** I&#39;d like to give newer players a chance to sign up for this game, so if you have played a number of games with the Gauntlet recently I&#39;d ask for a day&#39;s grace before signing up. I will also be holding one seat for this game in reserve for any newer members who have not yet had a chance to play a game as part of the Gauntlet. Please let me know if you are in this position and have not managed to sign up for this game. If I have no takers a week out from the start of the series, I will add in the next player on the waitlist.

This is a run of Back Again From The Broken Land, a game by Leah and Alexi Sargeant featured in Codex: Home, the current issue of the [Codex magazine](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/codex-magazine.html). It is a PbtA game of small adventurers sharing stories on a long walk home. The series will be 3 sessions long, and due to the nature of the game I would ask that players only sign up if they can make best efforts to attend all three sessions. Sessions will be three hours in length. General sign-ups will be available in 72 hours time (November 20th). We will be using [Zoom](https://zoom.us/) for our sessions. This session will be recorded, and may be released on Youtube with the consent of all participants.

*You are little people who walked into a big war. The Doomslord&#39;s forces were gathered in the Broken Lands, and for some reason your small fellowship played a key role in their fall. Now, laden with stories to tell and burdens to bear, you set off on the journey home. But the Doomslord&#39;s Hunters are still out there , and it&#39;s a long way to walk... Back again from the Broken Land.*
The game is inspired by Lord of the Rings, and you will all take on the role of small adventurers returning to their home in a high fantasy world after a legendary victory. We will learn what happened, how you have changed, and what you carry with you still.

Content Warnings: The game is not primarily one about conflict, but the threat of violence is still present in the game. It deals with the after effects of war, and in particular how it has touched the lives of your characters, in particular unresolved issues they still face. It can also feature occasional moments of powerlessness in the face of insurmountable foes. We will have a discussion on tone and content before the game begins, as well as establishing Lines &amp; Veils to provide a comfortable play experience. This game will take place under the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) and the safety tools [Script Change ](http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m) and [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg) will be in use. I will aim to get in touch with participants through either the Gauntlet Slack or email a week in advance of the game to confirm attendance and provide play materials.

[Session 1](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MMMJhf_B5HcYz1w82Yr) [date=2020-12-01 time=20:00:00 format=LLLL timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;] → [date=2020-12-01 time=23:00:00 format=LLLL timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;]
[Session 2](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MMMJvE3DztxXztn_xaw) [date=2020-12-08 time=20:00:00 format=LLLL timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;] → [date=2020-12-08 time=23:00:00 format=LLLL timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;]
[Session 3](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MMMK4--Fut_Rk-G2uYC) [date=2020-12-15 time=20:00:00 format=LLLL timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;] → [date=2020-12-15 time=23:00:00 format=LLLL timezone=&quot;Europe/London&quot;]</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 17:58:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/back-again-from-the-broken-land/6117.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Back Again From the Broken Land</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DavidMorrison]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/davidmorrison">@DavidMorrison</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Please Note:</strong> I’d like to give newer players a chance to sign up for this game, so if you have played a number of games with the Gauntlet recently I’d ask for a day’s grace before signing up. I will also be holding one seat for this game in reserve for any newer members who have not yet had a chance to play a game as part of the Gauntlet. Please let me know if you are in this position and have not managed to sign up for this game. If I have no takers a week out from the start of the series, I will add in the next player on the waitlist.</p>
<p>This is a run of Back Again From The Broken Land, a game by Leah and Alexi Sargeant featured in Codex: Home, the current issue of the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/codex-magazine.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Codex magazine</a>. It is a PbtA game of small adventurers sharing stories on a long walk home. The series will be 3 sessions long, and due to the nature of the game I would ask that players only sign up if they can make best efforts to attend all three sessions. Sessions will be three hours in length. General sign-ups will be available in 72 hours time (November 20th). We will be using <a href="https://zoom.us/" rel="nofollow noopener">Zoom</a> for our sessions. This session will be recorded, and may be released on Youtube with the consent of all participants.</p>
<p><em>You are little people who walked into a big war. The Doomslord’s forces were gathered in the Broken Lands, and for some reason your small fellowship played a key role in their fall. Now, laden with stories to tell and burdens to bear, you set off on the journey home. But the Doomslord’s Hunters are still out there , and it’s a long way to walk… Back again from the Broken Land.</em><br>
The game is inspired by Lord of the Rings, and you will all take on the role of small adventurers returning to their home in a high fantasy world after a legendary victory. We will learn what happened, how you have changed, and what you carry with you still.</p>
<p>Content Warnings: The game is not primarily one about conflict, but the threat of violence is still present in the game. It deals with the after effects of war, and in particular how it has touched the lives of your characters, in particular unresolved issues they still face. It can also feature occasional moments of powerlessness in the face of insurmountable foes. We will have a discussion on tone and content before the game begins, as well as establishing Lines &amp; Veils to provide a comfortable play experience. This game will take place under the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a> and the safety tools <a href="http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change </a> and <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">X-Card</a> will be in use. I will aim to get in touch with participants through either the Gauntlet Slack or email a week in advance of the game to confirm attendance and provide play materials.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MMMJhf_B5HcYz1w82Yr" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 1</a> <span data-date="2020-12-01" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2020-12-01T20:00:00Z UTC">Tuesday, December 1, 2020 8:00 PM</span> → <span data-date="2020-12-01" data-time="23:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2020-12-01T23:00:00Z UTC">Tuesday, December 1, 2020 11:00 PM</span><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MMMJvE3DztxXztn_xaw" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 2</a> <span data-date="2020-12-08" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2020-12-08T20:00:00Z UTC">Tuesday, December 8, 2020 8:00 PM</span> → <span data-date="2020-12-08" data-time="23:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2020-12-08T23:00:00Z UTC">Tuesday, December 8, 2020 11:00 PM</span><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MMMK4--Fut_Rk-G2uYC" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 3</a> <span data-date="2020-12-15" data-time="20:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2020-12-15T20:00:00Z UTC">Tuesday, December 15, 2020 8:00 PM</span> → <span data-date="2020-12-15" data-time="23:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-format="LLLL" data-timezone="Europe/London" data-email-preview="2020-12-15T23:00:00Z UTC">Tuesday, December 15, 2020 11:00 PM</span></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/back-again-from-the-broken-land/6117/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/back-again-from-the-broken-land/6117/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 17:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6117-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/back-again-from-the-broken-land/6117.rss">Back Again From the Broken Land</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
