<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ex-Capes: The Golden Aged PLAYTEST</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ex-capes-the-golden-aged-playtest/6660</link>
    <description>Gerry used to be faster than a speeding bullet.

Lucille used to be more powerful than a locomotive.

Shawn used to leap tall building in a single bound.

And you? You used to be the world&#39;s greatest goddamn detective.

But that was a long time ago. For one reason or another, you&#39;ve all hung up your capes, tossed out your cowls, and traded your spandex for sweat pants. The hero business is for the young, the dumb, and the idealistic. You&#39;re not any of those any more.

But sometimes someone comes to you with a problem and you can&#39;t turn them away. You can&#39;t say no, even though you&#39;re retired. Even though you may not be welcome in that world any more. Your powers may have faded, or maybe they&#39;ve gotten unreliable, but when the chips are down you know that age, cunning, and desperation can sometimes triumph over youth, power, and confidence. Hopefully today is one of those days...

*Ex-Capes*  is a hack of  *Brindlewood Bay*  where you&#39;ll play retired super-heroes (and maybe even villains!) who end up helping people in their neighborhood solve problems that their background as Capes makes them uniquely equipped to handle. As you progress, you&#39;ll start to uncover an underlying plot that poses an existential threat that no one else realized is coming, so it&#39;ll be up to you to figure it out and deal with it.

***This is a playtest.***

*Please only sign up if you&#39;re comfortable with playing a game that&#39;s still in development.*  I&#39;ll be asking for feedback, rules may change on the fly, and we may or may not get the chance to explore the broader setup beyond individual sessions in this first month of play. I&#39;d prefer folks who can make a good-faith effort to be available for all 4 May sessions so they can provide session-to-session feedback. Familiarity with inspirational source material, especially  *Astro City Tarnished Angel* ,  *Powers* , and  *The Boys*  will be helpful but is not required.

There will be a total of 4 seats, 1 is being held for Chris Newton.

***I will record these sessions for feedback*** , but will not post them unless I receive consent form all players.

We&#39;ll use Safety Tools including Lines &amp; Veils, Script Change, and Open Door to help keep the game fun. This event is run according to [The Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct.](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html)

***CW: Crime investigation, including murder; aging and grief; PTSD from involvement in interpersonal violence, first response, and possibly witnessing mass-casualty events as depicted in superhero comics.***

4 Session Tuesday evenings in May at 8:00 PM Eastern time.
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAeXlbC305521ubGGS
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAel7aEIkX0r8GAI4c
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAexhDwrwsVKZmBXT5
https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAfOSoLwZQ27AiVoxV

-Jim Crocker</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 07:56:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ex-capes-the-golden-aged-playtest/6660.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Ex-Capes: The Golden Aged PLAYTEST</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@JimLikesGames]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jimlikesgames">@JimLikesGames</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Gerry used to be faster than a speeding bullet.</p>
<p>Lucille used to be more powerful than a locomotive.</p>
<p>Shawn used to leap tall building in a single bound.</p>
<p>And you? You used to be the world’s greatest goddamn detective.</p>
<p>But that was a long time ago. For one reason or another, you’ve all hung up your capes, tossed out your cowls, and traded your spandex for sweat pants. The hero business is for the young, the dumb, and the idealistic. You’re not any of those any more.</p>
<p>But sometimes someone comes to you with a problem and you can’t turn them away. You can’t say no, even though you’re retired. Even though you may not be welcome in that world any more. Your powers may have faded, or maybe they’ve gotten unreliable, but when the chips are down you know that age, cunning, and desperation can sometimes triumph over youth, power, and confidence. Hopefully today is one of those days…</p>
<p><em>Ex-Capes</em>  is a hack of  <em>Brindlewood Bay</em>  where you’ll play retired super-heroes (and maybe even villains!) who end up helping people in their neighborhood solve problems that their background as Capes makes them uniquely equipped to handle. As you progress, you’ll start to uncover an underlying plot that poses an existential threat that no one else realized is coming, so it’ll be up to you to figure it out and deal with it.</p>
<p><em><strong>This is a playtest.</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Please only sign up if you’re comfortable with playing a game that’s still in development.</em>  I’ll be asking for feedback, rules may change on the fly, and we may or may not get the chance to explore the broader setup beyond individual sessions in this first month of play. I’d prefer folks who can make a good-faith effort to be available for all 4 May sessions so they can provide session-to-session feedback. Familiarity with inspirational source material, especially  <em>Astro City Tarnished Angel</em> ,  <em>Powers</em> , and  <em>The Boys</em>  will be helpful but is not required.</p>
<p>There will be a total of 4 seats, 1 is being held for Chris Newton.</p>
<p><em><strong>I will record these sessions for feedback</strong></em> , but will not post them unless I receive consent form all players.</p>
<p>We’ll use Safety Tools including Lines &amp; Veils, Script Change, and Open Door to help keep the game fun. This event is run according to <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">The Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct.</a></p>
<p><em><strong>CW: Crime investigation, including murder; aging and grief; PTSD from involvement in interpersonal violence, first response, and possibly witnessing mass-casualty events as depicted in superhero comics.</strong></em></p>
<p>4 Session Tuesday evenings in May at 8:00 PM Eastern time.<br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAeXlbC305521ubGGS" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAeXlbC305521ubGGS</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAel7aEIkX0r8GAI4c" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAel7aEIkX0r8GAI4c</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAexhDwrwsVKZmBXT5" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAexhDwrwsVKZmBXT5</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAfOSoLwZQ27AiVoxV" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MVAfOSoLwZQ27AiVoxV</a></p>
<p>-Jim Crocker</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ex-capes-the-golden-aged-playtest/6660/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ex-capes-the-golden-aged-playtest/6660/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 07:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6660-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ex-capes-the-golden-aged-playtest/6660.rss">Ex-Capes: The Golden Aged PLAYTEST</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
