<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Stewpot (July one-shot)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stewpot-july-one-shot/7162</link>
    <description>Stewpot is a GMless game by Takuma Okada about a group of retired fantasy adventurers running a tavern together. “You&#39;ll be scrambling to cook something edible with random ingredients, bartending for troubled souls, calming down a tavern brawl, going shopping for all the things a tavern needs, and more in a variety of slice-of-life scenes.”

The game is based on the Firebrands framework, but no rules knowledge is expected and we’ll all learn the rules together during play.

We’ll be using Lines and Veils, the X Card, and the Open Door as safety tools, and the game will run under the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html. 

This will be a one-shot played over StreamYard, with short breaks on the hour. I&#39;ve scheduled it for four hours, but we might finish up earlier depending how things play out. I’ll record and post the session if all players consent.

Open access time for signups is 4pm 11 July AEST.

Signup: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Me3ghm1Z_pOQ77nA1bp</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 06:00:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stewpot-july-one-shot/7162.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Stewpot (July one-shot)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sandy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sandy">@Sandy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Stewpot is a GMless game by Takuma Okada about a group of retired fantasy adventurers running a tavern together. “You’ll be scrambling to cook something edible with random ingredients, bartending for troubled souls, calming down a tavern brawl, going shopping for all the things a tavern needs, and more in a variety of slice-of-life scenes.”</p>
<p>The game is based on the Firebrands framework, but no rules knowledge is expected and we’ll all learn the rules together during play.</p>
<p>We’ll be using Lines and Veils, the X Card, and the Open Door as safety tools, and the game will run under the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a>.</p>
<p>This will be a one-shot played over StreamYard, with short breaks on the hour. I’ve scheduled it for four hours, but we might finish up earlier depending how things play out. I’ll record and post the session if all players consent.</p>
<p>Open access time for signups is 4pm 11 July AEST.</p>
<p>Signup: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Me3ghm1Z_pOQ77nA1bp" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-Me3ghm1Z_pOQ77nA1bp</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stewpot-july-one-shot/7162/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stewpot-july-one-shot/7162/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 06:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7162-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stewpot-july-one-shot/7162.rss">Stewpot (July one-shot)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
