<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016</link>
    <description>Playing with The Gauntlet has taught me that asking good leading questions is often make or break for a game. Asking correct questions can set the game for a success and asking bad or too little questions makes the game plain normal.

How do you ask proper leading questions?
Where do you draw inspiration for them?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 01:17:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>RPG Chat</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Warriormonk]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/warriormonk">@Warriormonk</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Perhaps too late to the discussion but I’m surprised nobody said anything about <em>player expectations</em>, as in what the players expect from the game and setting whenever they hear certain keywords. This is the best source of input for the GM and a really good starting point to get the creativity of the whole group of players to start flying away in the same direction.</p>
<p>It’s really a simple method: pay attention to the player’s choices on their character sheet and <strong>ask them about those choices</strong>. Like, if a player choose to play a ranger elf, that player has already visualized ho elves are and why there are rangers among them, either if she’s the only ranger among them or the last elf in the setting. Or the opposite, both are excellent points to start a conversation. It’s like getting to know anybody after all, you will get that person talking a bit more if you ask them about him/herself than if you start making assumptions about that person and telling them about what you think of them.</p>
<p><em>(which ends up being cool if your assumptions stroke the ego of the player, as in “your character is famous for something he did, what is it?”. It ends up being ok if you make bad assumptions upon a bad dice roll, as in “you rolled a 5 on charisma, why does this NPC thinks what you just said was an insult?”. And it ends up being aggressive when you make assumptions that destroy player’s expectations, as (maybe) in “Who killed your sensei?”. It’s not like players can’t adapt and improvise something, but if you see them take a pause you probably put them on the spot because you just killed some expectations and now they have to readjust.)</em></p>
<p>Back to player’s choices: the trick to keep things under control (because believe me: once you start asking the players about how they envision this or that about their character <em>they won’t stop talking</em>) is to ask, oracle the dice if they fly too high and link whatever they say to another PC or NPC. Let’s go step by step:</p>
<p>-Ask the player about their character. If they choose a dwarf ask her how are dwarves like, what do they do for a living, what are they famous for, where do they live (it works best if players also create the important spots on the setting map). So far things may be just color until you ask the player how do they fare with other people - this question may create a whole front and make dwarves important to the story, especially if they don’t get along with strangers, are too rich or powerful.</p>
<p>-How powerful are they? If you think players are creating advantages or just going too far, oracle the dice, the higher the result the more truth there is in whatever they say. Just roll in the open so everyone can see if what the player said was true or just exaggeration proper of a dwarf. I forgot to mention that before asking anything to the players I explain them that whetever they create will be <strong>what their characters know</strong> which may or may not be actually true and would be up to them to find it out, if they want.</p>
<p>-Link everything: whenever a player is talking too much don’t be afraid to interrupt him and link whatever they said to another PC to give another player the chance to give you more input, building upon whatever has been said before. If one player says dwarves don’t get along with other people ask the one playing the elf what legends do they tell about Dwarves, get them to talk to each other to confirm and create more lore. Ask them how did they become friends (which is another good assumption, saves time and avoids PvP)</p>
<p>Meanwhile, listen. Everything can and will be used against them.</p>
<p>Bonds may be trickier, I tend to use a random table to give players some inspiration and let them detail those bonds further. It’s enough for each PC to have one bond with another PC until the whole group is linked. Each character also needs a bond with one front at least, or with the main villain. A shared hate can get them going as well as any common objective.</p>
<p>Perhaps the trick is to ask the characters for lore about themselves? Not sure if I should put it that way.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/26</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 01:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DeReel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dereel">@DeReel</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I was searching the internet and found this thread : and I love it.</p>
<p>What strikes me as a specific use that I haven’t seen here is to ask questions where the assumption is meta, saying : “this is something your character can’t control”. So of course, if you have little control in the game, well that stings.</p>
<p>By meta I mean : ok, the question has a narrative interest, requires safety calibration, etc. All of this is true and very useful. But at the player level, we’re also saying : things from our past, a great deal of your environment, and a big chunk of our emotional responses (your hand is shaking, your stomach gargles, these little things) : we just don’t chose them. And to me, in game, it feels really liberating to keep experiencing agency through all that. So I like that kind of questions for this.</p>
<p>(Writing this, what strikes me, is how calibrating for safety is really : deigning balanced encounters, only from a narrative, dramatic, emotional perspective. That is : if the constraint is too strong, the experience is a downer. Well, maybe just showing that player agency lives through it is enough. Anyway, that’s a different topic.)</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 19:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>Sometimes, establishing questions are a really wonderful way to figure out a leading question to ask. “Is your mother dead?” is a great question, but it’s not a leading question. If the PC is in a mansion owned by someone they’re trying to convince to something (funding a quest, freeing a prisoner, whatever), you might ask “as you’re waiting in the sitting room, what on the mantle over the fireplace reminds you of your dead mother?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>OK, in that case, I’m not into leading questions at all, mostly because there is no way of structuring them. You can go from from small things to ridiculous large ideas:</p>
<p>• “Tell me why the world is falling apart?”<br>
• “Tell me something about what you character discovered about particle mass”<br>
• “Tell me your point of view of the correlation between lebens raum and today’s right wing movement.”</p>
<p>The OP should had been asked in that case: “why are we asking leading questions?”</p>
<p>For me, I have a playstyle where the players can make up pretty anything, as long as it makes sense (given the setting and situation; which the group have agreed upon), and I have techniques to make them comfortable in having a larger influence than just their character. I also play a lot of <em>collaborative storytelling</em>, and when someone is describing – for example – the surroundings when setting a scene, I can ask them “Has it rained?”. I pretty much wants it to rain, but I have had people saying “No, but it’s snowing” or “No, it’s actually quite sunny” and having them taking a stand. Either way will satisfy me.</p>
<p>I do ask leading questions like yours if it’s during character creation. It’s basically trying to hook the players into something interesting. If they don’t bite, I leave it at that. My biggest concern, however, is that your “mum portrait” example is forcing the player to make it interesting, because you do that while playing. That’s taking it too far, for me. I have been doing that myself, and gotten bad feedback afterwards from players, and I have been in situations where someone else have put me in the spot by doing that. (I play in all sorts of groups, often at convention so it’s almost always different participants doing that.)</p>
<p>So … I stopped doing that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/24</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 14:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Von_Bednar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>You sure can!</p>
<p>I just chose the above approach based on my group, but each group and each player will be different. For me this was the “safest” way of getting them familiar with such narrative game approach. Start will small details, build upwards.</p>
<p>Some of my players were not comfortable breaking the traditional GM/Player split, so I chose to just build up slowly for everyone, so no one feels left out. It worked for our group, you might find a different approach works for you <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>I think I should have specified that my advice was just that - advice. You might need to tweak it, so it works with your group <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/23</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dunadhaigh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dunadhaigh">@dunadhaigh</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>If you have trad players, can’t you start out with leading questions that <em>grant them agency</em> traditionally reserved for GMs? Let them declare facts about the environment and the world at large for a bit before you ask questions that push on their agency over their PC.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 02:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Von_Bednar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-post="19" data-topic="2016">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jeremy_strandberg/40/460_2.png" class="avatar"> Jeremy_Strandberg:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Not sure I agree with this as a rule. I think all of the following are legit…</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I agree that those are legit, however I wouldn’t use them for a trad player who is just getting used to narrative style of play. Of course “your mileage may vary” depending on the players, but I will just follow <a class="mention" href="/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a>’s advice - you want to work them up to it.</p>
<p>We all play in our bubbles. Gauntlet players will have a high “narrative inteligence,” but not all groups will have that. I encountered players who come from a very trad approach with an antagonistic GM and they feel threathened when you start declaring stuff about the only thing they can control in the game world. So I have put it in the original post as a fail safe. I will edit that post to make it more clear <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/21</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 20:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-21</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think that crossing the line with questions like that can be totally legit, yes, but may be something you’ll want to avoid at first with players who aren’t used to that kind of thing. Work up to it, in other words.</p>
<p>I wrote a bit on framing questions in different ways over in this other thread:</p>
<aside class="quote quote-modified" data-post="33" data-topic="2005">
  <div class="title">
    <div class="quote-controls"></div>
    <img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/paul_t/40/1825_2.png" class="avatar">
    <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/effectiveness-of-painting-the-scene/2005/33">Effectiveness of "Painting the Scene"?</a> <a class="badge-wrapper  bullet" href="/c/rpg-chat"><span class="badge-category-bg" style="background-color: #0088CC;"></span><span style="" data-drop-close="true" class="badge-category clear-badge" title="Chat about actual play of, prepping to play, and running of LARPs and RPGs.">RPG Chat</span></a>
  </div>
  <blockquote>
    I think the way you frame or present the prompt can make a great difference to some people, too. 
Are you answering “in-character”, or not? What imaginary senses are you using? 
Let’s take this example: 

You could frame this in a variety of ways. Do you say, “The waiters aren’t just waiters; what else are they?” That puts a lot of authorial responsibility on the player’s plate. There are lots of possible “wrong” answers (“They’re clowns!”), but a lot of room to add a twist to the story and take…
  </blockquote>
</aside>

<p>I’d recommend reading the whole thread, as well, as it covers this topic really thoroughly!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/20</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 16:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-20</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jeremy_Strandberg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jeremy_strandberg">@Jeremy_Strandberg</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="17" data-topic="2016">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/von_bednar/40/549_2.png" class="avatar"> Von_Bednar:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Don’t make assumptions about the player character. Doing so might make the player feel that they are loosing some agency to the GM.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Not sure I agree with this as a rule. I think all of the following are legit:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Assuming/asserting a relationship or experience. “Ranger, when was the last time you crossed the Whitebone Desert?” “Thief, there’s this big burly dude named Rath coming at you, murder in his eyes, what’d you do to piss him him so badly?”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Asking questions that assert/assume an event that obviously must have happened based on established fiction. “So, Thief… Who was the first person you murdered? No no, I didn’t ask about the first death you caused. Who was the first person you <em>murdered</em>, Mr McStabby?”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>As a hard move, especially on something like a missed Spout Lore or Open Your Brain, asking a question that assumes all sorts of bad, problematic stuff. “A 4, huh? Well, yeah, you know plenty about this mutagenic quicksilver stuff… what terrible experience did you have with it and why does it still wig you out so badly?”</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>All of these push the line of player agency/ownership, but I think they’re all really effective and still appropriate. The trick is to keep the assertions/assumptions in line with the character-as-established. And also be willing to let (and encourage) players to push back a bit if go too far.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/19</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 16:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-19</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@calris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/calris">@calris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Some folks have pointed out that <em>yes/no</em> questions are often bad leading questions. I agree, but they can also be great leading questions and are a good way to minimize pressure on the PCs’ improv skills.</p>
<p>For example, “is it raining?” can be bad because it might not lead anywhere. If the player says “no” what is the follow up? But, in the context of travel, “is it a dry season?” can be great, because both “yes” and “no” have interesting follow ups (yes: “so how are you finding water?” and no: “so how are you dealing with the rain, mud, and possible flooding?”).</p>
<p>I actually really like “staging” a leading question by starting with something very simple and concrete that is easy to answer, and once the player answers and gets their creative juices flowing, asking them to follow up with a more open-ended question next. But I agree that yes/no questions that will potentially “dead end” are not so useful.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/18">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/18</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 15:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-18</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Von_Bednar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/von_bednar">@Von_Bednar</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I am running a PbtA game for a group of players used to very trad RPGs, so I will share some of my experience with asking leading questions with people who are not not used to the conventions of narrative gaming.</p>
<p>Players used to the traditional roles of narrative ownership (player/GM) might not be as comfortable improvizing facts in a game outright. You might want to build up to big, open-ended leading questions.</p>
<p>A good first step in asking leading questions is <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/paint-the-scene" rel="nofollow noopener">Jason’s paint the scene</a> technique. If you look it at closer, it is still the GM telling players facts about the game world, but in a form of a question. Then it only asks them to add some cool details. Those details are insignificant in a grand scale, so the players will not worry that they might “break the game.”</p>
<p>Once your player are comfortable in adding detail to the scene at hand, you can start asking them questions that their characters should/could know. This is where asking class/background specific questions would come. After all, who better to know about the side effects of magic than the wizard, or where you can hide for a day in the city than a vampire?<br>
Use the assumption and question setp that <a class="mention" href="/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/4">writes about</a>, but with a caveat. Be careful when making assumptions about the player character. Doing so might make the player feel that they are loosing some agency to the GM. Of course this will all depend on how well you know the player. To be on the safe side, I usually try to find an assumption that still gives facts about the game world, and a question that makes the character feel special and highlights their expertise. I still keep the scope of those questions relatively “local.” If you imagine setting book for your game, they might or might not be mentioned in a paragraph.</p>
<p>Only when the player feels comfortable with answeing those questions, I would move to asking leading questions that have a big impact on the narrative/setting. By those questions I mean things that would create new cultures, places, how X works in the narrative. In our setting book analogy, those would be the things that could have multiple paragraphs or a chapter. A new city state, an existance of dragons, customs of they fey kingdom.</p>
<p>Hope that this helps someone. It took me a while to realize that you should tweak the questions to the comfort level with taking narrative ownership of each player.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/17">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/17</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 15:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-17</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@darren]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/darren">@darren</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I think the only problem with this is that yes/no questions aren’t really leading questions. They’re just questions establishing some fact. Those don’t really build anything – a GM could just as easily and validly state “It’s raining. You’re all wet.” So I would ask “why hasn’t it rained here in awhile?” That way the rain is established, but what the player offers is background to that setting detail.<br>
This butts up against avoiding improvisation, but I think still constructs a better question than “What kind of weather is it?” (I agree that’s bad.) Ideally, your leading question gives whomever you’re asking enough foundation to make the improvisation easier. e.g. “it hasn’t rained because there’s been a drought.” Then you could ask “how long was the drought?” etc.</p>
<p>Sometimes, establishing questions are a really wonderful way to figure out a leading question to ask. “Is your mother dead?” is a great question, but it’s not a leading question. If the PC is in a mansion owned by someone they’re trying to convince to something (funding a quest, freeing a prisoner, whatever), you might ask “as you’re waiting in the sitting room, what on the mantle over the fireplace reminds you of your dead mother?” That’s a leading question (assuming the death of the PC’s mother had already been established) because it presumes a lot that’s in the scene – that there is something on the mantle and that that thing is familial in nature. This does double duty by saying something about the PC’s past and also something about the person who lives in the space. e.g. “There’s a deer’s head mounted above the fireplace. My mother was the hunter in the family.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/16">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/16</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 06:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-16</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Rickard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/rickard">@Rickard</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Don’t put your players on the spot by having them improvise:</p>
<p>Good leading question:<br>
• Is it raining?</p>
<p>Bad leading question:<br>
• What kind of weather is it?</p>
<p>What I think is important, and WHY you should even use leading questions, is to create something together with your players.</p>
<p>“Is your mother dead?” gives more than “What’s your relation to your mother?” because you <em>offer</em> something to that player.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/15">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/15</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 13:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-15</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jtreat3]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jtreat3">@jtreat3</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m designing one or more games around the leading question, so I’ve been working on how to teach the skill. (Also, check out For the Queen.) Here’s what I’ve got, briefly:</p>
<p>Leading Questions serve the purpose of sharing narrative agency with your fellow players, creating a more collaborative story that invests everyone. Any question will do that and the reason we want to use leading questions is to support players answering them. “What happens next” is a question so broad as to paralyze most respondents in most contexts. “Who started the fire that breaks out” and “What puts the entire block in immediate danger” are much better because they <em>offer</em> something players can build on.</p>
<p>When a GM in a standard RPG would tell the players what happens next, what they see, or whatever, we can instead ask a leading question. The formula here is to figure out one option—whatever you would’ve said as a standard GM—and offer half of that instead, leaving room for your partner to fill in the other half. It’s fine if they say what you would have, but they never will… assuming your question wasn’t so leading as to box them out of a choice.</p>
<p>These questions somehow grant you just as much power as GM fiat, and the art behind them is just as nuanced, but you grant so much more agency to your partners in play, and can replace hours of prep with genuine surprise and excitement, on your part.</p>
<p>Instead of “Thunderbird is shocked to find the mastermind behind the controls is… her father” which is some pretty good storytelling, ask “How is Thunderbird deeply related to the mastermind behind the controls?” The vast majority of possible answers are just as good, and many are just better: “It’s… it’s my twin!” “It’s my wife. I thought she was dead!”</p>
<p>Again, whatever you would state as a GM in this moment, share half of that in the form of a question. “You walk into a room full of dwarves. What were they all focused on that you interrupted?” “The amulet gives you constant visions of your father. What strength does it lend you? Which part of yourself do you hide away?” “You hack into the mainframe and find the dirt you need. How does it incriminate Senatron?”</p>
<p>The second big approach comes from attentive curiosity. We’re all following the story, wondering about the mysteries afoot (and there will always be mysteries in a shared narrative game). There’s a question on your mind. “How can the Duke be the killer when he was next to me at the ball all night?” “Sure Nanuk took the ice wand, but why?” “Wait, where are we right now?” Ask it. That’s a great question, guaranteed. If it’s one you think others know the answer to, don’t embellish the question, just get the answer so we’re all on the same page. If it’s not, make it a leading question (because it’s not real helpful to ask over-broad questions): “Who might want to frame the Duke?” or “What did you notice was off about the Duke and why wasn’t I hearing you at the time?” “What evil does Nanuk think he can only undo with the ice wand?” or “Who made Nanuk take the ice wand, and what do they have over him?” “We’re in the deepest chamber of the Orbital Temple. What’s its purpose?” or “We’re at Yagslak’s Hopper. What’s the crowd here to see?”</p>
<p>Sometimes you catch yourself asking a yes/no question, or one with just one answer. Just rephrase it. We do that all the time in live human conversation. “Is Trogdar going to get aw–How does Trogdar get away?” Nice save. Sometimes we’ll ask a too-broad question. Just follow it up with context. Trust me, you’ll have time while your friend’s mind reels at the possibilities. “Who’s behind the door? Uh, you hear clinking and clattering and a faint cursing.”</p>
<p>Be mindful of which part you make concrete and which part you leave fluid. Don’t ask “When will the lost souls be reunited” if you’re not fine with “right now,” “never,” and everything in between. Try “what event will signify the lost souls reunification today” or whatever time frame you’re counting on. If you care that a character is overcome but adversity, but not how, ask “how does Megatron bring Optimus to his knees” rather than “how does Megatron’s mind-magnet affect Optimus?”</p>
<p>My final pointer is a reminder that really interesting leading questions hit the same notes that really interesting narrative interactions do: No one cares what shape the key to the chest is, but you can make us feel something by revealing <em>why</em> the princess locked her heart away. Get to the character-defining personal motivations, and relationship-altering events.</p>
<p>What makes this story human?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/14">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/14</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 19:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-14</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Ari_Tobias]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ari_tobias">@Ari_Tobias</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="4" data-topic="2016">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/curubethion/40/200_2.png" class="avatar"> Curubethion:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>The question. It’s the gap of knowledge that you’re asking the player to fill in. There’s the assumption, and then there’s this unknown space they answer with a question. It should be big enough that the player is getting meaningful input, but it can’t be too big, or it’ll be overwhelming. Here, I like to err on the side of big, and if they look like they’re getting stuck, I’ll rephrase the question to be more specific.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Late to the party, but wanted to jump in with a random recommendation - playing Spyfall (the board game) honestly really helped me hone this skill. Because you <em>have</em> to figure out how to ask questions that are the right “size” - ie big enough to allow the other player to give an answer that provides plausible deniability, but specific enough force them to provide useful information.</p>
<p>Agree with everything else said above, but also wanted to add - another other type of leading question I like is forcing players to make a choice to give additional color to previous decisions they’ve made, like, if they’ve designed a character that’s just generically family-focused, I might ask, “What’s more important to your character - being a good wife or being a good mother?” Then the followup “Why?” is just a gimme <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Another conversational hack that I use in my daily life as well as GMing, is the all purpose “What do you mean?” as well as “Can you give me an example?” after a player makes any broad or abstract statement. Those are more open-ended than leading, but I’ve found them SUPER useful for getting more conversational “threads” you can then pull on for more specific lines of inquiry.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/13">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/13</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 17:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-13</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gulix]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gulix">@Gulix</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="11" data-topic="2016">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/jasonlutes/40/728_2.png" class="avatar"> jasonlutes:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Invariably, simple questions lead to bigger or deeper questions, and the answers provide plenty of fodder for reincorporation. I guess it boils down to a GM principle along the lines of, “Be curious about the characters and their world.”</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>That! A good leading question should <em>lead</em> to other questions.</p>
<p>Also, as I’m a lazy GM, when I ask question, I tend to ask the player to help me build the world. “You got to Greenmile village. Last time you went there, a new shop was starting. What was it? Is it still there? …”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/12</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 08:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-12</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasonlutes]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasonlutes">@jasonlutes</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I don’t know if they qualify as “leading” questions, but my approach is pretty basic: I cultivate curiosity about the PCs and the world, and ask questions based on my curiosity. At the outset that means asking surface questions about PC appearance and belongings (“How are you dressed?” “What does your sword look like?”), which lead to background details (“When was the last time you took a bath?” “Who made your sword?”), and later relationship/emotional stuff (“How do you feel about Olaf after he said you smell terrible?” “Who was the last person you killed with that sword, and how did you feel about it?”</p>
<p>Invariably, simple questions lead to bigger or deeper questions, and the answers provide plenty of fodder for reincorporation. I guess it boils down to a GM principle along the lines of, “Be curious about the characters and their world.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-11</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="8" data-topic="2016">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/gulix/40/1677_2.png" class="avatar"> Gulix:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Do not ask question that can be answered by Yes/No for a start. And push some information into the Question.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Yeah, I think this is very important; yes/no answers end the question, other answers can suggest further lines of thought. The classic “Five W’s and an H” work well here: “What did you…”, “When did you…”, “Where did you…”, “Who did you…”, “Why did you…”, and “How did you…”.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/10</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 16:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-10</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@inarvan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/inarvan">@inarvan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I usually look to the genre presumptions as both guides and contrasts. If a character is playing into a genre trope, I’ll ask what makes the character different from the baseline version. Sometimes I’ll load the question too: “What makes your wizard different from those other magic-users? Why are you The Wizard, as opposed to just another magician?”</p>
<p>When I’m in my elements of choice (like weird fantasy, modern urban fantasy, or superhero stuff), I will pull from the genre media to paint comparisons and contrasts with the questions if I can. "This person sounds a lot like a Mercy Thompson kind of conflicted werewolf to me. What parts of being a werewolf do they enjoy, in spit of themselves? What parts of their human lives actually disturb them more than being a werewolf does?</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/9</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 13:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-9</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gulix]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gulix">@Gulix</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="1" data-topic="2016" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/pawel/40/1670_2.png" class="avatar"> Pawel:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Playing with The Gauntlet has taught me that asking good leading questions is often make or break for a game. Asking correct questions can set the game for a success and asking bad or too little questions makes the game plain normal.</p>
<p>How do you ask proper leading questions?<br>
Where do you draw inspiration for them?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Do not ask question that can be answered by Yes/No for a start. And push some information into the Question.</p>
<ul>
<li>What did you lose last time you went here? (implies the character been there and lost something)</li>
</ul>
<p>As the other, listen to what have already been brought around the table.</p>
<p>Also, you can ask questions with bias, like a word that could have several meaning. Let the door open for the answerer to input anything he wants.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/8</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 10:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-8</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Judd]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/judd">@Judd</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>With class-based games I like to think about the class and what their role is in the world.</p>
<p>Cleric: Have you ever married two people or given last rites or named a baby?</p>
<p>If there is something the character is good at, ask about who taught them how to do that. RPG’s need more relationships between student and teachers because so few games demand character learn from teachers. If they are good at something, they’ve probably failed a bunch in order to get that good. Ask about those failures and how they dealt with that, ask about their greatest success.</p>
<p>If they aren’t sure, drop it and move on. Let them marinate on them. Sometimes I’ll ask a question, drop it and the person will e-mail me a week later or mention that they’ve been thinking about it in-between games and suddenly the answer came to them.</p>
<p>I’ve found that the secret of asking good questions is to listen very carefully to what folks are saying.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/7</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 06:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-7</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Small addendum to my previous: PbtA games often include a bunch of leading questions in the character creation process, specifically that bit where you’re establishing bonds between characters. Check those out, mull them over, ask yourself how they work, dissect them, see how they constrain but give freedom.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 04:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-6</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Another resource that helped me think about leading questions. Those dumb wirters’ books on character and characterization. I hate Orson Scott Card, but before I realized what a terrible person he was, I read his <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elements-Fiction-Writing-Characters-Viewpoint/dp/0898799279" rel="nofollow noopener">Characters &amp; Viewpoint</a></em> book which gave me lots of ideas for questions about characters. There are lots of books like that and they often provide shopping lists of characterization questions. Since those are the most important kinds of leading questions for me, those proved useful.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:25:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Curubethion]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/curubethion">@Curubethion</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I really don’t know, to be honest! Somewhere in my milieu, I picked up lots of different tricks for asking leading questions, absorbing them from different examples.</p>
<p>I do think that you can boil them down into two parts:</p>
<ol>
<li>The assumption. This is a stricture that you impose on the players, and it forms the groundwork for the question you’re about to ask. Your assumption has to be substantial, or else the question won’t spark inspiration or drive the story forward. However, your assumption can’t be so substantial that it strips major agency away from the player. Learning where the line is definitely requires experience, and it won’t be the same for everyone; I like to start a bit on the small side and then lean into players progressively more.</li>
<li>The question. It’s the gap of knowledge that you’re asking the player to fill in. There’s the assumption, and then there’s this unknown space they answer with a question. It should be big enough that the player is getting meaningful input, but it can’t be too big, or it’ll be overwhelming. Here, I like to err on the side of big, and if they look like they’re getting stuck, I’ll rephrase the question to be more specific.</li>
</ol>
<p>Don’t forget that you can totally reword the question or try again if it’s not working out the way you first phrased it, so it’s okay if you’re not 100% certain that you’re doing it right. Try, experiment, you’ll get it right in time. Make mistakes, get messy, etc.</p>
<p>Sometimes, the question has a preface which acts as an assumption. “You recognize Iceshatter from your past. What was the ambition you remember her always chasing?” Even then, notice how there’s also an assumption baked into the question? The question itself presumes that she has an ambition that she used to chase with some degree of seriousness.</p>
<p>I guess for me, the key is cultivating that attitude of presumption, which requires a certain willingness to benignly impose your will on the story in a small way which still lets players steer it in their own direction. I think understanding just how much players are able to push the story in their own direction is helpful here. Sure, you’re telling them something that you presume, but they’re also telling you something that’s true about this character.</p>
<p>And remind them during play that they can always veto something. You’re also free to ask “would that make sense?” if you’re not sure.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@EricVulgaris]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ericvulgaris">@EricVulgaris</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Honestly this is the hardest part of GMing. I don’t think there’s a way to cheat this process.</p>
<p>The most generic, milquetoast answer is: If you’re doing pbta rely on your principles and agenda and do what the scene demands.</p>
<p>In reality it’s just the same answer to how to be an interesting conversationalist. /shrug</p>
<p>just gotta rely on playing a lot, reading a lot, watching a lot of movies, and probably being more aggressive with scene framing.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 15:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The art of asking leading questions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>From watching Rich, I realized that the best leading questions, especially during character creation, are like interview questions. I try to frame it in my head like that: what would be of interest to an audience, what might surprise them? I’ve listened to interviewer on podcasts and the like trying to pay attention to that. Paul F. Tompkins on the <em>Spontaneanation</em> podcast starts each episode with a guest interview. They’re great and I recommend listening to those segments.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 13:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2016-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-art-of-asking-leading-questions/2016.rss">The art of asking leading questions</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
