<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Urban Shadows 2E: Gauntlet Empire City:Everybody&#39;s Going Uptown</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/urban-shadows-2e-gauntlet-empire-city-everybodys-going-uptown/6068</link>
    <description>The northern Manhattan neighborhoods of Washington Heights and Inwood, far from the glitz of Times Square. are home to diverse ethnic and religious communities. Most famously, the large community of Dominican immigrants, but the bodegas of Broadway are nestled right up next Korean groceries, Kosher restaurants, and stores catering to the large number of immigrants from the former Soviet Union. These communities don&#39;t stop at the water, but extend out to the surrounding areas of the South Bronx and the suburbs of Bergen County, NJ. And of course, it&#39;s not just human communities that live in the shadow of the George Washington Bridge. Werewolves, Vampires, Wizards, Trolls (of course!) and magical folk of every sort jockey for position. It&#39;s rarely quiet uptown.

This is a series of 4 games of Urban Shadows 2e on Thursday evenings in January at 8PM Eastern US Time as a part of the Gauntlet&#39;s Empire City shared world. Empire City is a set of loosely interconnected Urban Supernatural games that take place in New York and its surrounding areas. This game will be centered in Washington Heights/Inwood Manhattan, but may extend into the surrounding and related communities of the South and West Bronx, and Northern New Jersey. No prior knowledge or experience of the setting is required Session one will consist largely of character creation and building out our comunities. We will be using the Urban Shadows 2E quickstart, along with whatever additional materials are released before January.

I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Rules will be taught. Sessions will run up to three and a half hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils, script change and the X-Card for safety tools. All Access Sign up begins 11/11/2020 at noon

If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.

Session 1: 1/7/2021

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcwgtly1X0rkjKzrKW

Session 2: 1/14/2021

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcwxWbbeKM3RE49aeW

Session 3: 1/21/2021

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcxutEu9BJiTdzYMQj

Session 4: 1/28/2021

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcy3Ctb-Hu0ey5jfKc</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 17:50:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/urban-shadows-2e-gauntlet-empire-city-everybodys-going-uptown/6068.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Urban Shadows 2E: Gauntlet Empire City:Everybody&#39;s Going Uptown</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jesseabe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jesseabe">@Jesseabe</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The northern Manhattan neighborhoods of Washington Heights and Inwood, far from the glitz of Times Square. are home to diverse ethnic and religious communities. Most famously, the large community of Dominican immigrants, but the bodegas of Broadway are nestled right up next Korean groceries, Kosher restaurants, and stores catering to the large number of immigrants from the former Soviet Union. These communities don’t stop at the water, but extend out to the surrounding areas of the South Bronx and the suburbs of Bergen County, NJ. And of course, it’s not just human communities that live in the shadow of the George Washington Bridge. Werewolves, Vampires, Wizards, Trolls (of course!) and magical folk of every sort jockey for position. It’s rarely quiet uptown.</p>
<p>This is a series of 4 games of Urban Shadows 2e on Thursday evenings in January at 8PM Eastern US Time as a part of the Gauntlet’s Empire City shared world. Empire City is a set of loosely interconnected Urban Supernatural games that take place in New York and its surrounding areas. This game will be centered in Washington Heights/Inwood Manhattan, but may extend into the surrounding and related communities of the South and West Bronx, and Northern New Jersey. No prior knowledge or experience of the setting is required Session one will consist largely of character creation and building out our comunities. We will be using the Urban Shadows 2E quickstart, along with whatever additional materials are released before January.</p>
<p>I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Rules will be taught. Sessions will run up to three and a half hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils, script change and the X-Card for safety tools. All Access Sign up begins 11/11/2020 at noon</p>
<p>If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.</p>
<p>Session 1: 1/7/2021</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcwgtly1X0rkjKzrKW" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcwgtly1X0rkjKzrKW</a></p>
<p>Session 2: 1/14/2021</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcwxWbbeKM3RE49aeW" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcwxWbbeKM3RE49aeW</a></p>
<p>Session 3: 1/21/2021</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcxutEu9BJiTdzYMQj" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcxutEu9BJiTdzYMQj</a></p>
<p>Session 4: 1/28/2021</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcy3Ctb-Hu0ey5jfKc" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MLcy3Ctb-Hu0ey5jfKc</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/urban-shadows-2e-gauntlet-empire-city-everybodys-going-uptown/6068/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/urban-shadows-2e-gauntlet-empire-city-everybodys-going-uptown/6068/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 17:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6068-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/urban-shadows-2e-gauntlet-empire-city-everybodys-going-uptown/6068.rss">Urban Shadows 2E: Gauntlet Empire City:Everybody&#39;s Going Uptown</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
