<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsterhearts 2: Kingsport 1894</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1894/2561</link>
    <description>**Please give priority to players who have never been in a Kingsport game before.**

**Kingsport, Massachusetts, 1894...**

The slow decline of the town from the age of its prosperity has begun. Shipbuilding orders dry up as merchants turn to steel hulled ships. More and more of the nation&#39;s trade is being carried by a few large merchant lines. Even the fishing has dropped off.

But in the foggy streets and gaslight parlors of Kingsport, the party has never been so gay. Art and style are valued over everything, and even if you&#39;re a monster you can be strikingly beautiful. Until one day the transformative power of art becomes deadly real...

Kingsport 1894 is the next chapter in the ongoing Kingsport series, which look at historical events in the context of HP Lovecraft&#39;s seaside New England town. I&#39;ll be running four Wednesday sessions in September 2019, exploring Gilded Age inequality, conspiracies, and the nature of art during the Decadence.

September 4 at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2LLXxZq
September 11 at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2xFX9Dz
September 18 at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2G4Fiuy
September 25 at 7:30 pm EDT: https://bit.ly/2G4XEMh

I&#39;m holding one spot for my frequent collaborator, the wonderful Seraphina Malizia. The total amount of Mythos content will be decided upon as a group. I&#39;ll provide the historical context as necessary.

This game will touch upon subjects including death, poverty, inequality, the unknowability of the truly transcendent, and how beauty is only the beginning of terror.

Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. This session will be around 3 hours long, and I&#39;ll be recording it for inclusion in the Gauntlet video roundup. We will be using the X-card, lines and veils, and the open door policy. For more information on the Gauntlet&#39;s safety tools, please refer to our Inclusivity Policy on the website (http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html).</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:23:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1894/2561.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Monsterhearts 2: Kingsport 1894</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@AviatrixCat]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/aviatrixcat">@AviatrixCat</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Please give priority to players who have never been in a Kingsport game before.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Kingsport, Massachusetts, 1894…</strong></p>
<p>The slow decline of the town from the age of its prosperity has begun. Shipbuilding orders dry up as merchants turn to steel hulled ships. More and more of the nation’s trade is being carried by a few large merchant lines. Even the fishing has dropped off.</p>
<p>But in the foggy streets and gaslight parlors of Kingsport, the party has never been so gay. Art and style are valued over everything, and even if you’re a monster you can be strikingly beautiful. Until one day the transformative power of art becomes deadly real…</p>
<p>Kingsport 1894 is the next chapter in the ongoing Kingsport series, which look at historical events in the context of HP Lovecraft’s seaside New England town. I’ll be running four Wednesday sessions in September 2019, exploring Gilded Age inequality, conspiracies, and the nature of art during the Decadence.</p>
<p>September 4 at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2LLXxZq" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2LLXxZq</a><br>
September 11 at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2xFX9Dz" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2xFX9Dz</a><br>
September 18 at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2G4Fiuy" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2G4Fiuy</a><br>
September 25 at 7:30 pm EDT: <a href="https://bit.ly/2G4XEMh" rel="nofollow noopener">https://bit.ly/2G4XEMh</a></p>
<p>I’m holding one spot for my frequent collaborator, the wonderful Seraphina Malizia. The total amount of Mythos content will be decided upon as a group. I’ll provide the historical context as necessary.</p>
<p>This game will touch upon subjects including death, poverty, inequality, the unknowability of the truly transcendent, and how beauty is only the beginning of terror.</p>
<p>Being able to attend each session is ideal, but not required. You must RSVP to each session you wish to attend. This session will be around 3 hours long, and I’ll be recording it for inclusion in the Gauntlet video roundup. We will be using the X-card, lines and veils, and the open door policy. For more information on the Gauntlet’s safety tools, please refer to our Inclusivity Policy on the website (<a href="http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-inclusivity-policy.html</a>).</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1894/2561/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1894/2561/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:23:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2561-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/monsterhearts-2-kingsport-1894/2561.rss">Monsterhearts 2: Kingsport 1894</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
