<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gauntlet Reading Club: CosmoKnights/Thirsty Sword Lesbians</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-cosmoknights-thirsty-sword-lesbians/7143</link>
    <description>This event is based off an experiment run by David Morrison earlier this year, and I am cribbing a lot of his explanation here. Sundays in September and October, I’ll be running a combined book club and series of game sessions based on the book we have read. The first session is to discuss the book we have read together, our thoughts on it, and what we can draw from it to bring into a roleplaying game. For this run, I have chosen the first volume of [CosmoKnights by Hannah Templer](https://www.cosmoknights.space/book-one) as the book, and this will be followed by a series of [Thirsty Sword Lesbians by April Kit Walsh](https://www.evilhat.com/home/thirsty-sword-lesbians/). This first session will accommodate more members than a standard roleplaying session, and anyone who wants to read the book and join us for this is welcome, but it will be expected anyone joining for this is familiar with the book. This book club session will be scheduled for three hours as will the rest of the series, though it is unlikely we will use the full amount of time for this. We will be using Streamyard for our discussion. This session will be recorded, and may be released on Youtube with the consent of all participants. 

The roleplaying series following this will by necessity be limited to a regular group size. Please note that participation in the initial “book club” session - or at least having read the book in advance - will be a requirement for playing in the game.  A seat has been reserved for David Morrison. 

*Pan&#39;s life used to be very small. Work in her dad&#39;s body shop, sneak out with her friend Tara to go dancing, and watch the skies for freighter ships. It didn&#39;t even matter that Tara was a princess... until one day it very much did matter, and Pan had to say goodbye forever. Years later, when a charismatic pair of off-world gladiators show up on her doorstep, she finds that life might not be as small as she thought. On the run and off the galactic grid, Pan discovers the astonishing secrets of her neo-medieval world... and the intoxicating possibility of burning it all down.*

Once we get into the game itself we will be drawing on the thematic inspiration of the book rather than specific plot points, and we will have a discussion on tone and content, as well as establishing Lines &amp; Veils to provide a comfortable play experience. This game will take place under the [Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) and the safety tools [Script Change ](http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m) and [X-Card](http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg) will be in use. I will aim to get in touch with participants through either the Gauntlet Slack or email a week in advance of the game to confirm attendance and provide play materials.

[Session 1](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWKakO8PySrrnTkNzC)
[Session 2](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWMiDOafy2pYD7MmlO)
[Session 3](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWO67aeduTGewhEzbI)
[Session 4](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWN8le7bdddK93fS80)
[Session 5](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWNTLxZx6xCceKCW5b)
[Session 6](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWNm6cHmkZkOT5RsWy)
[Session 7](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWOOH5ROAZgWR2jpMw)
[Session 8](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWOjTmK7QrXO_Ux9r8)
[Session 9](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWOhTAZ0JgAeGfrQGY)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 09:40:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-cosmoknights-thirsty-sword-lesbians/7143.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Gauntlet Reading Club: CosmoKnights/Thirsty Sword Lesbians</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@OnlyAnAlligator]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/onlyanalligator">@OnlyAnAlligator</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This event is based off an experiment run by David Morrison earlier this year, and I am cribbing a lot of his explanation here. Sundays in September and October, I’ll be running a combined book club and series of game sessions based on the book we have read. The first session is to discuss the book we have read together, our thoughts on it, and what we can draw from it to bring into a roleplaying game. For this run, I have chosen the first volume of <a href="https://www.cosmoknights.space/book-one" rel="nofollow noopener">CosmoKnights by Hannah Templer</a> as the book, and this will be followed by a series of <a href="https://www.evilhat.com/home/thirsty-sword-lesbians/" rel="nofollow noopener">Thirsty Sword Lesbians by April Kit Walsh</a>. This first session will accommodate more members than a standard roleplaying session, and anyone who wants to read the book and join us for this is welcome, but it will be expected anyone joining for this is familiar with the book. This book club session will be scheduled for three hours as will the rest of the series, though it is unlikely we will use the full amount of time for this. We will be using Streamyard for our discussion. This session will be recorded, and may be released on Youtube with the consent of all participants.</p>
<p>The roleplaying series following this will by necessity be limited to a regular group size. Please note that participation in the initial “book club” session - or at least having read the book in advance - will be a requirement for playing in the game.  A seat has been reserved for David Morrison.</p>
<p><em>Pan’s life used to be very small. Work in her dad’s body shop, sneak out with her friend Tara to go dancing, and watch the skies for freighter ships. It didn’t even matter that Tara was a princess… until one day it very much did matter, and Pan had to say goodbye forever. Years later, when a charismatic pair of off-world gladiators show up on her doorstep, she finds that life might not be as small as she thought. On the run and off the galactic grid, Pan discovers the astonishing secrets of her neo-medieval world… and the intoxicating possibility of burning it all down.</em></p>
<p>Once we get into the game itself we will be drawing on the thematic inspiration of the book rather than specific plot points, and we will have a discussion on tone and content, as well as establishing Lines &amp; Veils to provide a comfortable play experience. This game will take place under the <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct</a> and the safety tools <a href="http://tinyurl.com/nphed7m" rel="nofollow noopener">Script Change </a> and <a href="http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg" rel="nofollow noopener">X-Card</a> will be in use. I will aim to get in touch with participants through either the Gauntlet Slack or email a week in advance of the game to confirm attendance and provide play materials.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWKakO8PySrrnTkNzC" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 1</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWMiDOafy2pYD7MmlO" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 2</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWO67aeduTGewhEzbI" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 3</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWN8le7bdddK93fS80" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 4</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWNTLxZx6xCceKCW5b" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 5</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWNm6cHmkZkOT5RsWy" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 6</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWOOH5ROAZgWR2jpMw" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 7</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWOjTmK7QrXO_Ux9r8" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 8</a><br>
<a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MdWOhTAZ0JgAeGfrQGY" rel="nofollow noopener">Session 9</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-cosmoknights-thirsty-sword-lesbians/7143/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-cosmoknights-thirsty-sword-lesbians/7143/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 09:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7143-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-reading-club-cosmoknights-thirsty-sword-lesbians/7143.rss">Gauntlet Reading Club: CosmoKnights/Thirsty Sword Lesbians</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
