<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>NGC: School of Hard Knocks (Masks PbtA)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-school-of-hard-knocks-masks-pbta/5148</link>
    <description>&lt;!-- @page { margin: 0.79in } P { margin-bottom: 0.08in } A:link { so-language: zxx } --&gt;

Gauntlet Comics: School of Hard Knocks

Fridays in June/July at 1 pm CDT / 1900 GMT

Welcome to Gauntlet City. The home of the Gauntleteer, the home of more super hero teams and team ups than you can really imagine. It&#39;s no wonder we&#39;ve been on the losing end for so long. With this program I plan to end that.

With this program we shall rise to the top and carve out a niche for ourselves. Success comes in inches before it can turn into miles after all.

You&#39;re lucky to be a graduate, you now get to put your training to the test. It&#39;s the final test and worth most of your grade. Don&#39;t screw this up.

* Domina Carnifex

Welcome to Gauntlet Comics and it&#39;s time for an imprint of Masked Mustelid Comics! We here at Masked Mustelid like exploring the realms of comics that are cutting edge and show different perspectives. This iteration will focus on villains of New Gauntlet City in the modern age who have been training at the School of Hard Knocks aka SOHK (pronounced sock, like the old Westian sound effect), a prestigious program that has been designed to perfect the practice of villainy. This is not a place for selfish actions or leaving your teammates behind for heroes to capture. By learning to act in concert with other villains you should be able to take on heroes years your senior and stand up to those upstart youthful brats who constantly pick on you.

You are in one of the first graduating classes of the School of Hard Knocks, pieced together because you help cover up deficiencies in other teammates. With the files the schools has on the heroes of the past mixed with your prowess the world is open for you to carve a niche for yourself in the city of super heroes.

This game is heavily based on Villains United, The Secret Six, and the Thunderbolts style of comics. I want to have fun playing villains and humanize them rather than demonize heroes. If you&#39;ve always wanted to rename the Brotherhood of Evil Mutants because their goals didn&#39;t seem that bad then this is the game for you.

Session 1: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6Qep6CNtAMuIzRhj-a

Session 2: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfMYwdFIzEiTIxyQA

Session 3: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfVhGkF6tsB0GHsPd

Session 4: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfcwhXQyX5QsLwxnz

Session 5: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfoUui-7BzCKzHJGW

Session 6: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfxsP_JZbzzdu5a72

Session 7: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6Qg6e-MK_28iYeU7Yc

Session 8: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QgFH3kCX551UwWN1D

Session 9: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QgOnX2O6AWTkwryt_</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 18:03:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-school-of-hard-knocks-masks-pbta/5148.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>NGC: School of Hard Knocks (Masks PbtA)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Ferret]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ferret">@Ferret</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Gauntlet Comics: School of Hard Knocks</p>
<p>Fridays in June/July at 1 pm CDT / 1900 GMT</p>
<p>Welcome to Gauntlet City. The home of the Gauntleteer, the home of more super hero teams and team ups than you can really imagine. It’s no wonder we’ve been on the losing end for so long. With this program I plan to end that.</p>
<p>With this program we shall rise to the top and carve out a niche for ourselves. Success comes in inches before it can turn into miles after all.</p>
<p>You’re lucky to be a graduate, you now get to put your training to the test. It’s the final test and worth most of your grade. Don’t screw this up.</p>
<ul>
<li>Domina Carnifex</li>
</ul>
<p>Welcome to Gauntlet Comics and it’s time for an imprint of Masked Mustelid Comics! We here at Masked Mustelid like exploring the realms of comics that are cutting edge and show different perspectives. This iteration will focus on villains of New Gauntlet City in the modern age who have been training at the School of Hard Knocks aka SOHK (pronounced sock, like the old Westian sound effect), a prestigious program that has been designed to perfect the practice of villainy. This is not a place for selfish actions or leaving your teammates behind for heroes to capture. By learning to act in concert with other villains you should be able to take on heroes years your senior and stand up to those upstart youthful brats who constantly pick on you.</p>
<p>You are in one of the first graduating classes of the School of Hard Knocks, pieced together because you help cover up deficiencies in other teammates. With the files the schools has on the heroes of the past mixed with your prowess the world is open for you to carve a niche for yourself in the city of super heroes.</p>
<p>This game is heavily based on Villains United, The Secret Six, and the Thunderbolts style of comics. I want to have fun playing villains and humanize them rather than demonize heroes. If you’ve always wanted to rename the Brotherhood of Evil Mutants because their goals didn’t seem that bad then this is the game for you.</p>
<p>Session 1: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6Qep6CNtAMuIzRhj-a" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6Qep6CNtAMuIzRhj-a</a></p>
<p>Session 2: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfMYwdFIzEiTIxyQA" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfMYwdFIzEiTIxyQA</a></p>
<p>Session 3: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfVhGkF6tsB0GHsPd" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfVhGkF6tsB0GHsPd</a></p>
<p>Session 4: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfcwhXQyX5QsLwxnz" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfcwhXQyX5QsLwxnz</a></p>
<p>Session 5: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfoUui-7BzCKzHJGW" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfoUui-7BzCKzHJGW</a></p>
<p>Session 6: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfxsP_JZbzzdu5a72" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QfxsP_JZbzzdu5a72</a></p>
<p>Session 7: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6Qg6e-MK_28iYeU7Yc" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6Qg6e-MK_28iYeU7Yc</a></p>
<p>Session 8: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QgFH3kCX551UwWN1D" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QgFH3kCX551UwWN1D</a></p>
<p>Session 9: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QgOnX2O6AWTkwryt_" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-M6QgOnX2O6AWTkwryt_</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-school-of-hard-knocks-masks-pbta/5148/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-school-of-hard-knocks-masks-pbta/5148/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 18:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5148-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ngc-school-of-hard-knocks-masks-pbta/5148.rss">NGC: School of Hard Knocks (Masks PbtA)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
