<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fading Suns: Pax Alexius</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fading-suns-pax-alexius/8198</link>
    <description>**For the first 24 hours, please only sign up if you haven&#39;t yet had a chance to play a Gauntlet session or haven&#39;t played with me as a game facilitator on the regular calendar.**

This is for four sessions of  ***Fading Suns: Pax Alexius*** , a game of gothic space fantasy, happening Tuesday evenings in September (US Eastern). As of this writing, there’s a Bundle of Holding with the core books for the game available. We will be trying out the system. To make things easier, I will be putting together a set of pre-gens for the major archetypes. You’ll be able to choose and tweak those. In session one we’ll assign characters, talk safety, establish relationships, and get to playing.

One seat is being reserved.

***From Wikipedia:*** *The action is set in the Known Worlds, a future medieval-analogue empire built on the remains of a previous, more sophisticated human space-faring civilization. The atmosphere is strongly reminiscent of Frank Herbert&#39;s Dune and of the Hyperion stories by Dan Simmons, but is influenced by many other science fiction and horror books and movies as well, including the Cthulhu Mythos. The Known Worlds are a very superstitious and dangerous place. Power is administered by five major Noble Houses, five major guilds within the Merchants League, and six major sects of the Universal Church of the Celestial Sun.*

*Note: there are a couple of elements of the setting (inquisitorial torture, slavery) which we will be eliding or ignoring.*

Rules will be taught, though familiarizing yourself with the setting beforehand would be helpful. We will use Zoom for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Sessions will run up to three hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The [Gauntlet Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html) will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils and the X-Card for safety tools.

If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.

S1 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TKHYlVxccvy4lDN2c
S2 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TKfH7DHaRsHp-QWxL
S3 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TLVKIItz8wHcGGHHG
S4 https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TLnATiWAKvZvMtlwO</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 15:11:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fading-suns-pax-alexius/8198.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Fading Suns: Pax Alexius</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>For the first 24 hours, please only sign up if you haven’t yet had a chance to play a Gauntlet session or haven’t played with me as a game facilitator on the regular calendar.</strong></p>
<p>This is for four sessions of  <em><strong>Fading Suns: Pax Alexius</strong></em> , a game of gothic space fantasy, happening Tuesday evenings in September (US Eastern). As of this writing, there’s a Bundle of Holding with the core books for the game available. We will be trying out the system. To make things easier, I will be putting together a set of pre-gens for the major archetypes. You’ll be able to choose and tweak those. In session one we’ll assign characters, talk safety, establish relationships, and get to playing.</p>
<p>One seat is being reserved.</p>
<p><em><strong>From Wikipedia:</strong></em> <em>The action is set in the Known Worlds, a future medieval-analogue empire built on the remains of a previous, more sophisticated human space-faring civilization. The atmosphere is strongly reminiscent of Frank Herbert’s Dune and of the Hyperion stories by Dan Simmons, but is influenced by many other science fiction and horror books and movies as well, including the Cthulhu Mythos. The Known Worlds are a very superstitious and dangerous place. Power is administered by five major Noble Houses, five major guilds within the Merchants League, and six major sects of the Universal Church of the Celestial Sun.</em></p>
<p><em>Note: there are a couple of elements of the setting (inquisitorial torture, slavery) which we will be eliding or ignoring.</em></p>
<p>Rules will be taught, though familiarizing yourself with the setting beforehand would be helpful. We will use Zoom for our sessions. I’ll email all players about a week before the first session with the necessary links. Sessions will run up to three hours. We will plan to record, but I will confirm this with the players. The <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html">Gauntlet Code of Conduct</a> will be in play and we will use Lines &amp; Veils and the X-Card for safety tools.</p>
<p>If you sign up and your availability changes, please remember to drop from the site and give me a heads up.</p>
<p>S1 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TKHYlVxccvy4lDN2c">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TKHYlVxccvy4lDN2c</a><br>
S2 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TKfH7DHaRsHp-QWxL">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TKfH7DHaRsHp-QWxL</a><br>
S3 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TLVKIItz8wHcGGHHG">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TLVKIItz8wHcGGHHG</a><br>
S4 <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TLnATiWAKvZvMtlwO">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-N6TLnATiWAKvZvMtlwO</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fading-suns-pax-alexius/8198/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fading-suns-pax-alexius/8198/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 15:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8198-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/fading-suns-pax-alexius/8198.rss">Fading Suns: Pax Alexius</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
