<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Anyone Can Wear the Mask (One Shot 7/24 10:30am PT/17:30 UTC)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/anyone-can-wear-the-mask-one-shot-7-24-10-30am-pt-17-30-utc/7077</link>
    <description>[Anyone Can Wear The Mask](https://jeffstormer.itch.io/mask) is a high level, cinematic role playing game by Jeff Stormer about a superhero, a supervillain, and their city. Throughout play, we’ll record the adventures of a great hero as they defend their city, stand up to those in power, and eventually confront a terrible nemesis.

One of the players will be the hero. The hero will describe how they overcome threats to the city and its people. The hero will describe the people they save, and the people they don&#39;t. They may lose someone or something important to them, and they may be brought low by the villain. But in the end, they&#39;ll rise up, stand tall, and defeat the villain in the final battle.

One of the players will be the villain. The villain will describe the threats that the hero will have to overcome. They will track the hero&#39;s injuries and setbacks, but also their greatest successes. Ultimately, they&#39;ll be defeated at the hands of the hero.

I&#39;ll portray the city and all the ordinary people in it. And I&#39;ll help lift up the hero when they’re at their lowest, so they can continue protecting everyone within their power. (I will also facilitate the game.)

I am saving a seat for Lloyd. This is a second session this month-- the first is on 7/6, this one scheduled to run at a more UK and Euro friendly time. They are both one-shots and completely independent of each other, there is no need to sign up for both. 

NUMBER OF SESSIONS: 1. This is a one-shot game.

DURATION: 3 hours

NUMBER OF PLAYERS: 3 (including myself)

CONTENT WARNING: Themes of loss, violence

SAFETY TOOLS IN USE: We will use Lines and Veils, the X-Card, and the Open Door Policy. This session will also adhere to [The Gauntlet&#39;s Community Code of Conduct](https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html).

SET UP INFO: We will use my Zoom for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the game starts.

BREAKS: Two breaks of approximately 5-10 minutes.

RECORDED: If all participants consent (also only posted if all consent).

PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED: No experience required, rules will be taught

[https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MbnTnSn1LXMPkQ612h9](https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MbnTnSn1LXMPkQ612h9)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 01:22:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/anyone-can-wear-the-mask-one-shot-7-24-10-30am-pt-17-30-utc/7077.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Anyone Can Wear the Mask (One Shot 7/24 10:30am PT/17:30 UTC)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@John_Glass]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/john_glass">@John_Glass</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><a href="https://jeffstormer.itch.io/mask" rel="nofollow noopener">Anyone Can Wear The Mask</a> is a high level, cinematic role playing game by Jeff Stormer about a superhero, a supervillain, and their city. Throughout play, we’ll record the adventures of a great hero as they defend their city, stand up to those in power, and eventually confront a terrible nemesis.</p>
<p>One of the players will be the hero. The hero will describe how they overcome threats to the city and its people. The hero will describe the people they save, and the people they don’t. They may lose someone or something important to them, and they may be brought low by the villain. But in the end, they’ll rise up, stand tall, and defeat the villain in the final battle.</p>
<p>One of the players will be the villain. The villain will describe the threats that the hero will have to overcome. They will track the hero’s injuries and setbacks, but also their greatest successes. Ultimately, they’ll be defeated at the hands of the hero.</p>
<p>I’ll portray the city and all the ordinary people in it. And I’ll help lift up the hero when they’re at their lowest, so they can continue protecting everyone within their power. (I will also facilitate the game.)</p>
<p>I am saving a seat for Lloyd. This is a second session this month-- the first is on 7/6, this one scheduled to run at a more UK and Euro friendly time. They are both one-shots and completely independent of each other, there is no need to sign up for both.</p>
<p>NUMBER OF SESSIONS: 1. This is a one-shot game.</p>
<p>DURATION: 3 hours</p>
<p>NUMBER OF PLAYERS: 3 (including myself)</p>
<p>CONTENT WARNING: Themes of loss, violence</p>
<p>SAFETY TOOLS IN USE: We will use Lines and Veils, the X-Card, and the Open Door Policy. This session will also adhere to <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">The Gauntlet’s Community Code of Conduct</a>.</p>
<p>SET UP INFO: We will use my Zoom for the event. Players should expect a reminder email approximately one week before the game starts.</p>
<p>BREAKS: Two breaks of approximately 5-10 minutes.</p>
<p>RECORDED: If all participants consent (also only posted if all consent).</p>
<p>PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED: No experience required, rules will be taught</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MbnTnSn1LXMPkQ612h9" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MbnTnSn1LXMPkQ612h9</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/anyone-can-wear-the-mask-one-shot-7-24-10-30am-pt-17-30-utc/7077/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/anyone-can-wear-the-mask-one-shot-7-24-10-30am-pt-17-30-utc/7077/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7077-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/anyone-can-wear-the-mask-one-shot-7-24-10-30am-pt-17-30-utc/7077.rss">Anyone Can Wear the Mask (One Shot 7/24 10:30am PT/17:30 UTC)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
