<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Small Changes to Forums</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/small-changes-to-forums/8250</link>
    <description>We&#39;ve made a small change (long overdue) to the Forums, setting up a distinct channel for Gauntlet Publishing. This will be the place to discuss all Gauntlet Publishing games and releases: The Between, Brindlewood Bay, Trophy, Codex, etc. We&#39;ll make sure to announce new things (like new issues of Codex) here. 

You may notice some old topics popping up in the recent topics list; that&#39;s because we moved a number of threads over there. We have a few other small clean up changes coming (like some better pinned messages with easier contact info). .</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 20:00:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Announcements</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/small-changes-to-forums/8250.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Small Changes to Forums</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@edige23]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/edige23">@edige23</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We’ve made a small change (long overdue) to the Forums, setting up a distinct channel for Gauntlet Publishing. This will be the place to discuss all Gauntlet Publishing games and releases: The Between, Brindlewood Bay, Trophy, Codex, etc. We’ll make sure to announce new things (like new issues of Codex) here.</p>
<p>You may notice some old topics popping up in the recent topics list; that’s because we moved a number of threads over there. We have a few other small clean up changes coming (like some better pinned messages with easier contact info). .</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/small-changes-to-forums/8250/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/small-changes-to-forums/8250/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 20:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8250-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/small-changes-to-forums/8250.rss">Small Changes to Forums</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
