<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Farrier&#39;s Bellows - Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061</link>
    <description>It&#39;s a new episode of The Farrier&#39;s Bellows, and while it may be Spring where you are, but it&#39;s cold in Winter Wood--best to stay inside where it&#39;s safe.
In this week&#39;s episode, we talk Clint Krause&#39;s _Don&#39;t Walk In Winter Wood_, a wonderfully minimalist game of folkloric fear and Colonial American Horror. We talk about tone and how to make it work at your table, as well as the benefits of a system that gets out of the way and lets you do your thing. 
Bundle up tight and get close to the fire, things are about to get spooky.

https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-farriers-bellows/dont-walk-in-winter-wood</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 02:05:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Announcements</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The Farrier&#39;s Bellows - Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@zwGarth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/zwgarth">@zwGarth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Having not played <em>CD</em> or <em>Trophy</em> (which I understand has some <em>Cthulhu Dark</em> DNA), I can’t speak much to the similarities or differences. It sounds like they definitely have some similarities, though, and from your breakdown it sounds like <em>CD</em> might have a little more meat to it as a game that gives you some narrative and mechanical control. What I think <em>DWIWW</em> does so well is give you a very small, neat package to tell ghost stories in. IMO I don’t think you’re missing a design idea behind <em>DWIWW’s</em> Cold Points. Its super stripped down, which is naturally going to cut down on what it can do as a game and will definitely not be for everyone. But for a small game that you can play <em>really</em> easily around a campfire, I enjoyed it immensely. Like you said, the death spiral of the increasing Cold points isn’t as interesting or mechanically useful as Insight seems to be, but for that neat simplicity it’s definitely something I’m into.<br>
All that said, I have a great desire to play <em>Cthulhu Dark</em> and <em>Trophy</em> now. That same horror of <em>DWIWW</em> with a little more mechanical meat to it is definitely something I could get behind.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061/3</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 02:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2061-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061.rss">The Farrier&#39;s Bellows - Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Farrier&#39;s Bellows - Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gerrit]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gerrit">@Gerrit</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>As I have played both Cthulhu Dark and Don’t walk in Winter Woods I find it interesting to look how similar and yet so different the resolution mechanism of the two games are. The episode shortly touched that topic.</p>
<p>DwiWW rolls a d6<br>
CD rolls highest of up to 3d6 (one basic, one for specialized, one for the risk of gaining Insight)</p>
<p>DwiWW target is higher than current Cold<br>
CD is against a separate d6 roll</p>
<p>In DwiWW, Cold is increasing and hence tasks more often go wrong towards the end of the game.</p>
<p>In CD, tasks become more dangerous in the fiction and hence the use of the extra Insight die more likely.</p>
<p>A Cold of 6 is the end of the character.<br>
An Insight of 6 is the end of the character.</p>
<p>I have to say, the increasing probability of failure in DwiWW isn’t doing much for me. I prefer keeping the change of threat level on a fictional level.</p>
<p>Am I missing a design idea behind it?</p>
<p>Insight though is designed fabulously: especially with the extra twist of being able to reduce Insight again in exchange of decreasing the “insight of the rest of the world” is the simplest and yet most elegant mechanism I have seen to reflect what is going on in cthulhoid horror stories. The temptation to take this extra die to survive the situation but risking your sanity in exchange is a powerful decision to be made towards the final acts of a CD session.</p>
<p>EDIT: corrected game’s name.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 15:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2061-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061.rss">The Farrier&#39;s Bellows - Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Farrier&#39;s Bellows - Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@zwGarth]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/zwgarth">@zwGarth</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It’s a new episode of The Farrier’s Bellows, and while it may be Spring where you are, but it’s cold in Winter Wood–best to stay inside where it’s safe.<br>
In this week’s episode, we talk Clint Krause’s <em>Don’t Walk In Winter Wood</em>, a wonderfully minimalist game of folkloric fear and Colonial American Horror. We talk about tone and how to make it work at your table, as well as the benefits of a system that gets out of the way and lets you do your thing.<br>
Bundle up tight and get close to the fire, things are about to get spooky.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-farriers-bellows/dont-walk-in-winter-wood" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">THE GAUNTLET</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/1X/a6c66cedaeb3537ae24b8c81713b1b12c9a17fc4.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="500" height="500">

<h3><a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/the-farriers-bellows/dont-walk-in-winter-wood" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Don't Walk in Winter Wood</a></h3>

<p>The Farrier's Bellows is a production of Zack W., Diana, and Zack B. </p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2061-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-farriers-bellows-dont-walk-in-winter-wood/2061.rss">The Farrier&#39;s Bellows - Don&#39;t Walk in Winter Wood</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
