<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Crowdfunding Collection #115, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/04 and 08/18</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-115-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-04-and-08-18/2937</link>
    <description>I present to you the new [URL=&#39;https://teylen.blog/2019/08/19/crowdfunding-collection-115/&#39;][B]Crowdfunding Collection #115, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/04 and 08/18.[/B][/URL]. Which I will be posting more regularly :slight_smile: 

After having been to the RatCon convention, there are no fewer than 66 projects.
First I’d like to briefly address the two German language ones. [B]Dungeon Crawl Classic[/B] is being translated by System Matters and I am tempted; despite the artwork. Fans of The Dark Eye and Cthulhu should check out [B]Sandy Petersen’s Cthulhu Mythos für das Schwarze Auge[/B] which combines the unlikely pair.
Onto the English projects, I am quite enticed by the Patreon of [B]Samjoko Publishing[/B] for creating the [B]Babel Magazine[/B]. The magazine offers English translations from tabletop rpgs from all over the world, an exciting endeavor, which got me to join the projects in the second I learned of it.
If you like gm-less story games, you should have a look at [B]Dusk to Midnight[/B]. The game puts the players in the role of mech-soldiers doomed to be on the loosing side of a war, while not necessarily ending in tragedy. I consider the setting interesting, the zine-format as nifty and backed it. Another interesting setting, in my opinion,  is offered by [B]Titans Trail[/B]. The combination of Mecha, Kajiu und Victoriana, basically putting Pacific Rim and Dowtown Abbey into a mixer does sound intriguing enough that I got an eye on it. In comparison the setting of [B]USAGI YOJIMBO[/B] is almost traditional. As traditional as a samurai tale with anthropomorphic animals can be. The setting is based on the Manga by the same name and the new edition does got fitted with the PbtA-engine. Which sounds quite cool. I haven’t read the „For the Crown and the Dragon“ novel by Stephen Hunt, sollten yet if you did – or like „weird historical fantasy“ – you might take a look at the [B]Crown and Dragon[/B] Kickstarter, which fits it with the Savage World system. [B]The Realm of the Gateway[/B] offers an original setting that spans and combines science fiction and fantasy covering various genres. If you are curious, you can check out the base rules on DTRPG. Back to a Story Game, [B]Collateral Damage[/B] puts you in the role of the side-characters in an action scenario. This can cover various genres, as long as there is action, and the main goal is to make it out alive. The game aims to provide a fast one-shot experience and does sound fascinating.
There are as well two Break Kickstarter campaigns. [B]Carbyne Jungle[/B] has an interesting setting of mixing science fiction and fantasy while offering three distinctly different play modes that can still be utilized in one game with each other. Which sounds like quite a feat and spiked my interest. Then there’s [B]Broken![/B] which doesn’t have either a setting or a system, but lets backers vote on it via their pledges, which I find quite strange.
Of course there are other projects, like the D&amp;D sourcebooks [B]The Islands &amp; Aswangs Book[/B], offering an insight into Filipino myth and folklore, and [B]Witchcraft: Magic of Hereva[/B], for the fans of the web comic. There are many cool sourcebooks to help you build your setting or city like [B]Magical Industrial Revolution[/B], [B]City Builder[/B] and [B]Maps: Buildings, Castles and Dungeons[/B].
Well, there are many more sourcebooks, adventures, dice and many many other projects, see for yourself:

[B]English Crowdfundings[/B]

6 Role-Playing Games
2 Break Kickstarter Role-Playing Games
1 Patreon
1 Setting
4 Sourcebooks
3 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebooks
2 Pathfinder Sourcebooks
1 Adventure Box
6 Adventures
5 Dice Projects
4 Single-Dice Projects
1 Digitale Dice Projects
1 Coin Project
1 Playingcard Project
3 Dice Accessoires (Trays, Trackers)
3 Dice Accessoires (Containers)
1 Accessoire
4 Enamel Pins
2 Map Projects
2 Software Projects
7 Various RPG Projects
4 Various Games with RPG Elements

[B]German Crowdfundings[/B]

1 Role-Playing Game
1 Sourcebook

Article: [URL]https://teylen.blog/2019/08/19/crowdfunding-collection-115/[/URL]</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 19:07:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Hype</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-115-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-04-and-08-18/2937.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Crowdfunding Collection #115, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/04 and 08/18</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the new <a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/08/19/crowdfunding-collection-115/" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener"><span class="bbcode-b">Crowdfunding Collection #115, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/04 and 08/18.</span></a>. Which I will be posting more regularly <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>After having been to the RatCon convention, there are no fewer than 66 projects.<br>
First I’d like to briefly address the two German language ones. <span class="bbcode-b">Dungeon Crawl Classic</span> is being translated by System Matters and I am tempted; despite the artwork. Fans of The Dark Eye and Cthulhu should check out <span class="bbcode-b">Sandy Petersen’s Cthulhu Mythos für das Schwarze Auge</span> which combines the unlikely pair.<br>
Onto the English projects, I am quite enticed by the Patreon of <span class="bbcode-b">Samjoko Publishing</span> for creating the <span class="bbcode-b">Babel Magazine</span>. The magazine offers English translations from tabletop rpgs from all over the world, an exciting endeavor, which got me to join the projects in the second I learned of it.<br>
If you like gm-less story games, you should have a look at <span class="bbcode-b">Dusk to Midnight</span>. The game puts the players in the role of mech-soldiers doomed to be on the loosing side of a war, while not necessarily ending in tragedy. I consider the setting interesting, the zine-format as nifty and backed it. Another interesting setting, in my opinion,  is offered by <span class="bbcode-b">Titans Trail</span>. The combination of Mecha, Kajiu und Victoriana, basically putting Pacific Rim and Dowtown Abbey into a mixer does sound intriguing enough that I got an eye on it. In comparison the setting of <span class="bbcode-b">USAGI YOJIMBO</span> is almost traditional. As traditional as a samurai tale with anthropomorphic animals can be. The setting is based on the Manga by the same name and the new edition does got fitted with the PbtA-engine. Which sounds quite cool. I haven’t read the „For the Crown and the Dragon“ novel by Stephen Hunt, sollten yet if you did – or like „weird historical fantasy“ – you might take a look at the <span class="bbcode-b">Crown and Dragon</span> Kickstarter, which fits it with the Savage World system. <span class="bbcode-b">The Realm of the Gateway</span> offers an original setting that spans and combines science fiction and fantasy covering various genres. If you are curious, you can check out the base rules on DTRPG. Back to a Story Game, <span class="bbcode-b">Collateral Damage</span> puts you in the role of the side-characters in an action scenario. This can cover various genres, as long as there is action, and the main goal is to make it out alive. The game aims to provide a fast one-shot experience and does sound fascinating.<br>
There are as well two Break Kickstarter campaigns. <span class="bbcode-b">Carbyne Jungle</span> has an interesting setting of mixing science fiction and fantasy while offering three distinctly different play modes that can still be utilized in one game with each other. Which sounds like quite a feat and spiked my interest. Then there’s <span class="bbcode-b">Broken!</span> which doesn’t have either a setting or a system, but lets backers vote on it via their pledges, which I find quite strange.<br>
Of course there are other projects, like the D&amp;D sourcebooks <span class="bbcode-b">The Islands &amp; Aswangs Book</span>, offering an insight into Filipino myth and folklore, and <span class="bbcode-b">Witchcraft: Magic of Hereva</span>, for the fans of the web comic. There are many cool sourcebooks to help you build your setting or city like <span class="bbcode-b">Magical Industrial Revolution</span>, <span class="bbcode-b">City Builder</span> and <span class="bbcode-b">Maps: Buildings, Castles and Dungeons</span>.<br>
Well, there are many more sourcebooks, adventures, dice and many many other projects, see for yourself:</p>
<p><span class="bbcode-b">English Crowdfundings</span></p>
<p>6 Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Break Kickstarter Role-Playing Games<br>
1 Patreon<br>
1 Setting<br>
4 Sourcebooks<br>
3 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebooks<br>
2 Pathfinder Sourcebooks<br>
1 Adventure Box<br>
6 Adventures<br>
5 Dice Projects<br>
4 Single-Dice Projects<br>
1 Digitale Dice Projects<br>
1 Coin Project<br>
1 Playingcard Project<br>
3 Dice Accessoires (Trays, Trackers)<br>
3 Dice Accessoires (Containers)<br>
1 Accessoire<br>
4 Enamel Pins<br>
2 Map Projects<br>
2 Software Projects<br>
7 Various RPG Projects<br>
4 Various Games with RPG Elements</p>
<p><span class="bbcode-b">German Crowdfundings</span></p>
<p>1 Role-Playing Game<br>
1 Sourcebook</p>
<p>Article: <a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/08/19/crowdfunding-collection-115/" data-bbcode="true" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2019/08/19/crowdfunding-collection-115/</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-115-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-04-and-08-18/2937/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-115-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-04-and-08-18/2937/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 19:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-2937-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-115-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-08-04-and-08-18/2937.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #115, including every tabletop rpg project started between 08/04 and 08/18</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
