<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sixth Ring: Culture</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767</link>
    <description>There&#39;s a new episode of The Sixth Ring out today! In this one, we add a new AP segment, Desperate &amp; Doomed. Come meet @Judd&#39;s character, Wod Dum, as they begin exploring The Huntsman&#39;s Manor by @Natalieash.  This episode also features a discussion of play culture, a review of Court of the Radiant King by Nicholas Masyk, a discussion about portraying fantasy cultures, and magic items inspired by Greek mythology (including mine, which suffers somewhat from the fact I previously misunderstood the armor refresh rules, haha). Check it out: 

https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/trophy-podcast/sixth-ring-culture</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 03:08:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Announcements</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The Sixth Ring: Culture</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Judd]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/judd">@Judd</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Woven on the Loom</p>
<p>Jason rocks out with two magical items inspired by Greek myth.<br>
<strong>The Goatskin Shield</strong><br>
This goatskin shield is embroidered with images associated with battle and stained red with blood. It can be marked twice. It can only be repaired at a temple dedicated to a war god or at the church of a Sister associated with battles; the repair may come at the cost of 1 Gold, as usual, or something else entirely.</p>
<p><strong>Eye of the Grey Witches</strong><br>
Holding this smoky glass orb to your forehead will show you the Weakness of a named monstrosity. However, the Monstrosity is able to see you, as well,; when you next engage it in Combat, take an extra Weak Point.</p>
<p>Eventually, someone is going to die and their treasure-hunter friends might want to bring them back. If your Death Gate needs a guardian, Judd has you covered.</p>
<p>Cerberus:</p>
<p>It might be a three-headed dog, it might be three doors in an incursion meant to entice you away from walking into the Deathlands, or a snake with more heads than anyone can count.</p>
<p>Endurance: 12</p>
<ol>
<li>Two heads bite into your body, tearing your flesh and your soul apart like a ragdoll.</li>
<li>One head bites and shakes, causing you to drop everything.</li>
<li>All of the heads bite at once, ripping a spell from the air and eating it like a treat.</li>
<li>The immense body blocks a portal.</li>
<li>Summons the ghost of someone you killed.</li>
<li>Licks up your blood.</li>
</ol>
<p>Defenses: Scion of legendary monsters. Can smell its prey a world away.</p>
<p>Weakness: Wearing a funerary mask, Wearing a funerary shroud, holding two coins for Charon, Sewing one’s lips shut</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 03:08:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5767-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767.rss">The Sixth Ring: Culture</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Sixth Ring: Culture</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@jasoncordova]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jasoncordova">@jasoncordova</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>There’s a new episode of The Sixth Ring out today! In this one, we add a new AP segment, Desperate &amp; Doomed. Come meet <a class="mention" href="/u/judd">@Judd</a>’s character, Wod Dum, as they begin exploring The Huntsman’s Manor by <a class="mention" href="/u/natalieash">@Natalieash</a>.  This episode also features a discussion of play culture, a review of Court of the Radiant King by Nicholas Masyk, a discussion about portraying fantasy cultures, and magic items inspired by Greek mythology (including mine, which suffers somewhat from the fact I previously misunderstood the armor refresh rules, haha). Check it out:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/trophy-podcast/sixth-ring-culture" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/trophy-podcast/sixth-ring-culture</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 17:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-5767-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-sixth-ring-culture/5767.rss">The Sixth Ring: Culture</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
