<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Unincorporated: Vigil Creek Nature Preserve (December 12 &amp; 19)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-vigil-creek-nature-preserve-december-12-19/6149</link>
    <description>[date=2020-12-12 time=12:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNGNXyTYDMKLBSULX_f
[date=2020-12-19 time=12:00:00 timezone=&quot;America/New_York&quot;] https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNGNqT3wMm3WTLmpZYS

Vigil Creek is nothing special, on a map. A muddy, tree-lined river, too shallow for anything but canoes and tubes, running through scrubby hills in the middle of nowhere. But plants and animals live in that water, and in the narrow forest beside it, that are found nowhere else. That&#39;s why you&#39;re here. You and your few co-workers live and work on the preserve, studying and at least trying to protect it.

The problem is, there are stories about this place. Weird lights, spooky sounds, ghostly figures. Lots of places collect stories like that. It was just harmless fun, until something happened a month ago. Now, conspiracy nuts, cryptid hunters, UFOlogists, and aspiring Youtube ghost-hunters have descended on your home.

How do you get rid of them? Do you even want to? Are they even, maybe, _right_? We&#39;ll play to find out.

Unincorporated is a GMless, kind-of-PBTA-adjacent game about small-town drama. Or, in this case, small-park drama. This is a playtest of a new setting playbook, so there might be a few bugs to work out. Since everyone&#39;s schedule is weird in December, I&#39;m going to try to make this a very episodic 2-shot, so you can attend either or both sessions and get something more or less story-shaped. At least, that&#39;s the plan.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 13:44:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-vigil-creek-nature-preserve-december-12-19/6149.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Unincorporated: Vigil Creek Nature Preserve (December 12 &amp; 19)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bethany_H]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bethany_h">@Bethany_H</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><span data-date="2020-12-12" data-time="12:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/New_York" data-email-preview="2020-12-12T17:00:00Z UTC">2020-12-12T17:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNGNXyTYDMKLBSULX_f" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNGNXyTYDMKLBSULX_f</a><br>
<span data-date="2020-12-19" data-time="12:00:00" class="discourse-local-date" data-timezone="America/New_York" data-email-preview="2020-12-19T17:00:00Z UTC">2020-12-19T17:00:00Z</span> <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNGNqT3wMm3WTLmpZYS" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MNGNqT3wMm3WTLmpZYS</a></p>
<p>Vigil Creek is nothing special, on a map. A muddy, tree-lined river, too shallow for anything but canoes and tubes, running through scrubby hills in the middle of nowhere. But plants and animals live in that water, and in the narrow forest beside it, that are found nowhere else. That’s why you’re here. You and your few co-workers live and work on the preserve, studying and at least trying to protect it.</p>
<p>The problem is, there are stories about this place. Weird lights, spooky sounds, ghostly figures. Lots of places collect stories like that. It was just harmless fun, until something happened a month ago. Now, conspiracy nuts, cryptid hunters, UFOlogists, and aspiring Youtube ghost-hunters have descended on your home.</p>
<p>How do you get rid of them? Do you even want to? Are they even, maybe, <em>right</em>? We’ll play to find out.</p>
<p>Unincorporated is a GMless, kind-of-PBTA-adjacent game about small-town drama. Or, in this case, small-park drama. This is a playtest of a new setting playbook, so there might be a few bugs to work out. Since everyone’s schedule is weird in December, I’m going to try to make this a very episodic 2-shot, so you can attend either or both sessions and get something more or less story-shaped. At least, that’s the plan.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-vigil-creek-nature-preserve-december-12-19/6149/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-vigil-creek-nature-preserve-december-12-19/6149/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 13:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6149-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-vigil-creek-nature-preserve-december-12-19/6149.rss">Unincorporated: Vigil Creek Nature Preserve (December 12 &amp; 19)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
