<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125</link>
    <description>*We revere the Sisters, women from the near-mythical Age of Saints whose works are lodestars of goodness and virtue. The Sisters order our lives: we erect churches to honor them, we hold feast days in their name, and we seek their blessings for hearth and home. But how much do we truly know about them, about the women behind the saintly shrouds? There are some historians who suggest the stories we tell of the Sisters are little better than fairytales, that many of these saints have a dark and complicated history that has been whitewashed over the centuries. A few scholars suggest these women never existed at all, that the entities we venerate as saints are, in fact, demons who use the trappings of religion to control us. No matter the truth, we must at least acknowledge that light cannot exist without dark.* 

@jesseross and I are putting together a standalone book for the Trophy RPG (the game and its many expansions are currently featured in each new issue of Codex). One of the things we’re going to do with this book is include numerous tables that help flesh out the world Trophy takes place in. Keeping with the spirit of Trophy as a community project, we’re going to be crowdsourcing many of the elements that go into these tables. We already have a number of these crowdsourcing threads underway, any of which you can still contribute to. They can be found in this master list:

https://discourse.funtimers.club/t/trophy-crowdsourcing-master-list/3011

For this installment, we’re learning about the Sisters, saints whose veneration comprises most of the religion in the world of Trophy. We’re looking for one type of entry here, though each entry needs to have key pieces of information:

**The Sisters**
* Name of the Sister 
* The profession or organization she is the patron saint of
* At least 1 rite that group performs to honor her
* A dark, little-known aspect of the Sister or her history

NOTE: Please avoid anything that feels like sexual predation or that is misogynistic in nature. We won’t print such things.

You can submit as many entries as you wish. By submitting here, you agree to let us use your contribution in the Trophy standalone book and PDF (you will be credited as a contributor). Submissions should be fairly brief (just a few sentences). Here are some examples:

“Evelyn the White, patron saint of doctors and nurses, is routinely honored by the wearing of pristine, white garments. While she is today associated with saving lives, during her time, which was the bleak Era of Occlusion, she was known for the exact opposite: mercy killings to those left desperate by the apocalyptic wars that defined those years.”

“Clarithe, patron saint of glassblowers, is worshipped in only one place: the Cathedral of Light in Ambaret, an artistic marvel of delicate glass sculptures. But few know the true story: long ago, a wealthy man was so distraught by the death of his wife, Clarissa, he had artisans build a glass replica of her body, inside of which were arranged her bones and internal organs, a grotesque that was then displayed for any and all to see. Over the centuries, this tale became warped, until the glass ‘Clarissa’ became the saint ‘Clarithe,’ who so admired the glassblowers, she commissioned them to create a reliquary for her parts after she died.”

“The woodsmen who venerate St. Fyonne hold a feast in her name before felling a particularly old tree. This rite is significantly tamed from Fyonne’s time, when she required that any tree taken from the forest to serve man must be balanced with the sacrifice of an equivalently old person who was given over to be feasted upon by beasts.” 
![cathedral-2498996_960_720|690x459](upload://LHi6Gk6dSDl66o90iOqaZPm9D9.jpeg)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 20:33:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The four chosen sisters stand, apparently sculpted by water from the red sandstone walls of an arroyo deep in the Mahai’i Desert. Among the smooth curves protruding from the dry walls you can just make out the forms of four hooded women, their heads bowed together in prayer. When the walls wet with rain, their faces glow wetly red, and their tear tracks are the last to dry in any drought. No humans venerate them, but red marrow of fresh cracked bones is almost always present at their feet, left as offerings by the scavenger canids of the area. The arroyo itself is home to ancient foxes and coyotes, fed by the elk who wander down in search of water in dry months.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/46</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 20:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-46</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Gus.L]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/gus.l">@Gus.L</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>St. Bier, parton of lost causes, draftees and bastards is not well respected. She came to holiness during the 100 days of rule by the Profane Pretender, when the bastard son of the dying king bullied his way to brief power with the acquiescense of religous radicals and the support of the town bands.  Bier (whose name is unknown) was a young woman who the Pretender claimed as a holy muse. Struck with an assassin’s arrow, she lingered, carried on a bier of sticks by the Pretender’s ragged army, dying. In her last days her fevered touch cured wounds and eased the pain of the deluded commoners who flocked to the Pretender’s banner before his eventual defeat and quartering at the hands of the hierarchy and nobility.</p>
<p>An apostate saint, Bier is honored in woodland shrines of mud and sticks and on crude pewter medals around the necks of conscripts. She is said to intercede often, but her gifts are weak: easing suffering but never averting death. Her worship is secretly fervent among the guildhall bands - the rich burghers disguising it as that of less heretical saints - noting Bier only by arrow and branch designs on altars and ikons.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/45</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 19:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-45</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ostrichmonkey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/ostrichmonkey">@ostrichmonkey</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>St. Erisse is said to walk the places at the wayside, between, and atwixt. She watches over travelers, vagabonds, and forgotten wanderers. You pray to her when you cross a threshold, a boundary, or border. You burn fragrant incense when embarking on a voyage to gain her blessing, or let a drop of blood and swear an oath when you lose sight of the road. You ignore her voice in your mind when she softly whispers for you to join her; to join her in her court of unwinding halls, to wander eternally with the rest of the forever lost.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/44</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 20:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-44</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@kir]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/kir">@kir</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The small and elitist Guild of the Bookbinders owes its existence to St. Amelia. Their industrious patron and true guardian of knowledge is claimed to have come to Ambaret from a distant island. Amelia brought with her nothing except from a sturdy brass needle, and is said to have slept only four hours a night for all her life, working until all her fingers bled. Her books, as beautiful as long-lasting, contain ancient history, magic formulae and laws penned by the best scribes of the time. Apprentices complete their education by donating their First Vellum, an empty book, to the cause of St. Amelia. Only the Bookbinders are to know that the spine of the First Vellum has to contain a stripe of the apprentice’s skin before considered worthy by Amelia.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/43</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 20:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-43</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@PercyPropa]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/percypropa">@PercyPropa</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Saint Xiaoyu is the patron saint of planners, those who demarcate roads and create spaces and places. The opening of any path along the land, whether a dirt path between squalid towns or a cobblestone road laid down in the city, must be dedicated in her name and honoured with sacrifice. It is said that those who die by vehicle collision or roadside accidents have been executed by Xiaoyu’s will.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/42</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 04:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-42</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blaine_Moore]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blaine_moore">@Blaine_Moore</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sister Anamartia is the patron saint of redemption and penance. Her ardent followers are marked by their burgundy robes, and the black masks that prove they bear no witness to sins past or present, pursuing their tenet to guide sinners to an ever more righteous path. In chapels devoted to her, it is common practice for the congregation to wash their hands in blood, an act meant to symbolically hide their sins. Usually sheep’s blood is used, but her priests are known to bleed any animal that is available to perform the right. Due to her popularity with criminals and other unsavory folks, she has been known as the Mother of Sinners going back to the very first texts. Scholars are uncertain if there is any connection between mentions of Sister Anamartia as the Mother of Sinners and another more shrouded figure known as the Mother of Sin.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/41</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 23:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-41</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@steinea]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/steinea">@steinea</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>Sister Amser</strong>. The patron saint of wayfarers, Sister Amser is said to meet the lonely and weary in their times of greatest need, sharing with them her fire and food and a little mulled wine. Devotees of the wandering sister take great care in their preparations for the road so that they might not out of foolishness deprive another of Amser’s comfort. Amser’s faithful are known by their black, waxen cloaks, funearal attire that wards both the elements and the loss of beloved companions, so that no more will be lost to the forest–as was the saint’s sister so many years ago.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/40</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 18:32:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-40</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Juan]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/juan">@Juan</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>It is great cause of sorrow in the formerly prosperous market town of Avayyal that their beloved Teccla was adopted by the Guild of Torturers as the sisterly object of their veneration. Throughout Kalduhr very few shrines dedicated to her have not been desecrated by, most people assume, resentful members of the populace, possibly from among those unfortunate enough to have been subject to the attentions of the Guild. But there are some who whisper that it is, in fact, the Torturers who deface the effigies of their patron, as one of the secret rites performed during their rare conclaves.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/39</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 22:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-39</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blaine_Moore]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blaine_moore">@Blaine_Moore</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sister Valencia, also known as the Lady of Repose, is the patron saint of philosophy, scholars, and thoughtful contemplation. Though wise and knowledgeable, she was not given to answering questions; however, she was known to spend her days listening to supplicants presenting their theories to her and then asking a single question that would enlighten the supplicant and cause them to tear their treatises in twain and start anew. In more modern times, it is a rite for all serious scholars to burn a copy of their most recent work before starting a new one. Scholars whisper in hushed tones about who among them she will find unworthy and condemn to backbreaking menial labour rather than the career in the arts they each see as their due.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/38</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 06:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-38</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We all know the low things that follow death: the maggots and the carrion beetles and the vultures. If observed, it’s apparent that they have complicated rituals and procedures for dissecting a corpse, unknown to us. These rituals venerate a sister, with a name unknowable to people, whose existence is known only because some farmers following lost livestock have seen a bald woman watching them, clothed in a drab grey robe that crawls over her form like maggots over a 3-day-old corpse.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/37</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 20:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-37</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Blaine.c.martin]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/blaine.c.martin">@Blaine.c.martin</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Saint Aceroe, commonly called Sister Stinkhorn, is the patron saint of mushrooms, dung sweepers, and pawnbrokers. It is said, in life, she was a dyer of fabric, known for fabrics whose colors were so vibrant they evoked ecstasy in any who gazed upon them. The final, lost color Aceroe created was so powerful a local constable murdered her to possess the fabric.</p>
<p>On Sister Stinkhorn’s feast day, devout followers eat a small bit of psychoactive mushroom and try to recreate the lost color of Aceroe.</p>
<p>Darker legends have it that Aceroe discovered a shade of amber that could take over minds and that her earliest followers were a cult of zombies created by a monk wearing robes of that very color.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/36</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 15:34:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-36</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@darkliquid]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/darkliquid">@darkliquid</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sister Caite, patron of wet-nurses and milk-siblings, is honored by new mothers collecting their milk and offering it to a neighbours child. While today she is called upon to help mothers and babies in need, less is known about how she kidnapped the children of struggling mothers to raise as her own.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/35</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 13:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-35</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Beairstoboy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/beairstoboy">@Beairstoboy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Agnitti, the Patron Saint of Lost Children, is mainly worshipped by the close-knit communities near Kalduhr. In these homes and villages near the dark woods, they celebrate the Feast Day of Agnitti by wrapping ribbons around the trunks of old trees that will lead the lost home. Lost children who’ve returned home will often talk of ribbon trails that led deeper into the forest, and the dim lights of distant torches following the paths.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/34</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 06:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-34</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@maenad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/maenad">@maenad</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>To venerate Saint Sinestra is illegal in most cities, as her daughters are famous for being pickpockets and cat burglers. Some cities try a different approach, giving orphanages extra coin for each girl they take in, to avoid any falling to the streets and into her church. Still, her followers hardly struggle for recruitment, though they never take adults - and no adults are ever seen among their number. In the church, there’s a rumor that you “ascend” when you reach majority, which mostly seems to mean having a dream, gathering your most prized takes, and giving everyone the slip to walk into the woods alone.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/33</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 02:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-33</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrTrollhands]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrtrollhands">@MrTrollhands</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sister Vestra is the patron of fishermen, sailors and all whose livelihood is bound to the ocean. Many sing to her for protection from storms or to call the fish to their nets. Some coastal settlements honor her during the festival of Greentide with elaborate offerings bound in woven effigies. Few folks question why some ships are spared while others seem to run aground upon the very shores of those who worship her. After all, they say, the sea must have it’s due.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/32</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 18:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-32</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>No one speaks the name Yadyck anymore, the sister of the forest loam. Her followers rich mulch is sprinkled across their fecund fields, but none will share in their silent harvest.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/31</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 19:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-31</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Joshua_Kershaw]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/joshua_kershaw">@Joshua_Kershaw</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>-Sister Livinia<br>
-Patron saint of travelers and traders<br>
-Hundreds of small shrines to Livinia line the roads of the realm. Though they vary in design and depiction, every one is based around a small but functional lantern. It is a grave indiscretion to pass an unlit lantern without topping the oil reservoir and relighting the wick.<br>
-It has become a game, spotting the roadside shrines. Each has a name, though different to many. -Each has a story, be it legend or familiar. Points of safety. Beacons in the night. These roads are the safest in all the kingdoms. The blessing of Livinia for certain. Pragmatically, the very presence of light along with the simple act of vigilant observation helps prevent beasts and highwaymen catching Levinia’s travelers unaware. The blessings of The Sisters take many forms.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/30</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 16:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-30</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/signalstation">@signalstation</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Humming Woods know only one Queen, but they’ve seen Sisters come and go. Sister Anpeth of Sweet Words. Sister Dunyajk of Easy Birth. Sister Ellyellun the Paper Thin. Most of these names have been forgotten. Only the Sun-Striped Clade, beloved devotees of Sister Mephera, walk the woods now, wreathed in soporific smoke and traveling in bumbling paths, incense tracing strange patterns in the air in their wake. Members of the Clade may be identified to outsiders by their blackened hands, scarred and dense from holding the burning braziers without protection. Mephera offers all the protection they truly need.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/29</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 05:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-29</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@iamiragrace]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/iamiragrace">@iamiragrace</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>From a land far off, a traveler hunches in Milnen’s Tap in Fort Durin. For a drink they’ll tell you of a far off sister of the stars who watches over the darkness in all of us. Before you go they hand you a copper crescent and mutter “Nia drink this kindness in and have satisfaction.”</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 22:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-28</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>As one other note, I played The Flocculent Cathedral with Jim during GauntletCon, and he referred to a Concordance in the Cathedral itself which listed all of the Sisters and the crimes they committed which resulted in their presence (for lack of a better word) in the Cathedral. I hope that can get worked in somehow when working on the section about the Sisters. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/27</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 21:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-27</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The Sister of Agony is the patron saint of those who try to heal, whether they’re successful or not. Those who follow her find beauty in her glistening, bloodsoaked visage and pay tribute to her by taking the impossibly sharp knife found at her shrines and cutting themselves with it, leaving their fresh blood for her in case she needs more. The Sister of Agony teaches her adherents there is no healing without pain … and she ensures there is plenty of suffering for all.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/26</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 21:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-26</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/dominik">@dominik</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Sisters Patricia and Erika, literal and religious sisters, patrons of oppressed and insurgents, venerated wherever people struggle against organized tyrrany and suffer unjustified hardships. Their main place of cult is a relatively unknown Chapel of the Lakes found at the edges of Ambaret. For reasons seemingly forgotten people offer teeth in Patricia and Erikas honor. Their secret however makes it pretty clear: toothless from countless organized street fights, these brawny sisters were common occurrence in towns around the region, brawling for money, beating men and women to a pulp. Money, they claimed, was being raised for good cause but very few dared to ask what cause exactly that would be.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/25</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 12:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-25</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>With most statues of Ota, the clockmaker’s saint, she stands with one finger raised, perhaps to punctuate the time or point to the sun. Horologists honor Ota by putting a small gear over the finger, like a ring. They’ll keep this gear polished to a shine, fearing that an unhappy Sister will spoil their mechanisms. According to the myth, she emerged from the desert in the Ruhlota Wastes, gifting the nomads there the very first gear and spring mechanism. The truth is the nomads invented the clock mechanism themselves, to determine the pattern of Ota’s visits when she would capture and feast on someone’s soul. This process kept her young while aging the victim.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/24</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 01:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-24</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Bakers leave a drop of oil in every corner of their kitchen to ensure Sister Sufgonyot imbues their fried dough with bouquets of sumptuous flavor. Some bakers do this daily, but all bakers do it when they have a major undertaking like a wedding or coronation cake, even though it is common knowledge Sufgonyot prefers fried treats. In fact, in ancient times she was the patron of oil expeller pressers, not bakers. The tradition started as a memorial to the first army to lay siege to Old Fort Duhrin, who fell when the defenders poured boiling oil down on them.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/23</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-23</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: The Sisters</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@brownorama]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/brownorama">@brownorama</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>With the blessing of Baristaava, the roaster’s beans exude a flavor celebrated by both coffee novices and aficionados alike. Even years after learning the delicate art of preparing the seeds of the Quoquo tree, bean roasters struggle to earn her favor. She may be honored by roasting beans in small batches in a solid gold pan. In truth, she will only give her blessing if the roaster burns their own flesh on the hot pan before filling it with beans.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125/22</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-3125-22</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-the-sisters/3125.rss">Trophy: The Sisters</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
