<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cthulhu Deep Green: Operation FULMINATE (one shot)</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-deep-green-operation-fulminate-one-shot/6249</link>
    <description>Note: One spot is reserved for a player new to the Gauntlet; please DM me if you’ve played less than three games here and would like to join this one.

&quot;In Cthulhu Deep Green, players take on the role of shadowy agents of  **The Conspiracy**  as they fight to maintain the veil of secrecy standing between the public and the horrors that reside just beyond human comprehension.&quot; The rules are based on Cthulhu Dark and Trophy Dark, adapted to take a story-focused approach to otherwise more trad modern horror scenarios. In this session I plan to run Operation FULMINATE from the Delta Green Handler&#39;s Guide: A six-year-old boy has been found in a national park 40 years after he vanished there, but he appears not to have aged in the intervening decades. Soon mundane authorities will arrive to investigate, so you have just 24 hours to identify and eliminate any unnatural threat.

This is a horror game with a dark tone, and is likely to include peril and possibly harm to children and other innocent parties. The game will run under the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct (https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html), and use safety tools including Lines and Veils, the X Card and the Open Door Policy.

The session will run on StreamYard with breaks on the hour starting 9am 31/12/20 AEDT, recording only with consent from all players. We&#39;ll use RollWithMe for dice and a google sheet character keeper. No rules knowledge is expected and I’ll teach the game during play. 

This game will open to the public for sign up at 9.30am on 12/21/20 AEDT.

Sign-up link: https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MOm_jqLnwVGfwqvTsEL</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 21:32:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-deep-green-operation-fulminate-one-shot/6249.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Cthulhu Deep Green: Operation FULMINATE (one shot)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Sandy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sandy">@Sandy</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Note: One spot is reserved for a player new to the Gauntlet; please DM me if you’ve played less than three games here and would like to join this one.</p>
<p>“In Cthulhu Deep Green, players take on the role of shadowy agents of  <strong>The Conspiracy</strong>  as they fight to maintain the veil of secrecy standing between the public and the horrors that reside just beyond human comprehension.” The rules are based on Cthulhu Dark and Trophy Dark, adapted to take a story-focused approach to otherwise more trad modern horror scenarios. In this session I plan to run Operation FULMINATE from the Delta Green Handler’s Guide: A six-year-old boy has been found in a national park 40 years after he vanished there, but he appears not to have aged in the intervening decades. Soon mundane authorities will arrive to investigate, so you have just 24 hours to identify and eliminate any unnatural threat.</p>
<p>This is a horror game with a dark tone, and is likely to include peril and possibly harm to children and other innocent parties. The game will run under the Gauntlet Community Code of Conduct (<a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a>), and use safety tools including Lines and Veils, the X Card and the Open Door Policy.</p>
<p>The session will run on StreamYard with breaks on the hour starting 9am 31/12/20 AEDT, recording only with consent from all players. We’ll use RollWithMe for dice and a google sheet character keeper. No rules knowledge is expected and I’ll teach the game during play.</p>
<p>This game will open to the public for sign up at 9.30am on 12/21/20 AEDT.</p>
<p>Sign-up link: <a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MOm_jqLnwVGfwqvTsEL" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-MOm_jqLnwVGfwqvTsEL</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-deep-green-operation-fulminate-one-shot/6249/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-deep-green-operation-fulminate-one-shot/6249/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 21:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-6249-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/cthulhu-deep-green-operation-fulminate-one-shot/6249.rss">Cthulhu Deep Green: Operation FULMINATE (one shot)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
