<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Stay Frosty: Operation Black Nova, Tuesday, 6/22/21 at 1 p.m. Central Time</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stay-frosty-operation-black-nova-tuesday-6-22-21-at-1-p-m-central-time/7087</link>
    <description># For the first 24 hours, please only RSVP if you are in the U.K./E.U.

**NUMBER OF SESSIONS:**  1

**DURATION:**  3 hours

**NUMBER OF PLAYERS:**  4 (a seat is being reserved for Will H.)

**CONTENT WARNING:**  This game will include violence (graphic violence can be veiled) and PC death is on the table. It may include smoking/alcohol/drugs, body horror, religious zealotry, interrogations (torture can be veiled), and themes of murder/suicide/genocide/xenocide/extinction level events. 

-------------------------------------------

“All right, you trigger-happy bulletheads, eyes forward, ears open! Some science vessel called the Null Spectrum sent a distress call 15 minutes ago because there’s a … let me see here … a gravitic anomaly near Tonantzin … you know, that planet where all the eggheads you bullied for being smart went? The one where they’re all rich and happy and go to sleep in nice, soft beds, while you drag your asses across the galaxy shooting plants and animals that want to eat you and eat cold slop and fight over the top bunk so Hadathen’s farts don’t drift down and smother you in your sleep? Anyway, command says it’s our turn to respond to the call. Apparently, this thing has already destroyed six ships. Stay frosty on this one … I don’t want us to be seventh  *or*  eighth.”

The Null Spectrum, a science vessel from Tonantzin, has sent a distress call due to a gravitic anomaly which has already destroyed six ships. The Null Spectrum’s force shields are the only thing protecting it, and they’re on the verge of failing. Can you save the ship - or at least the crew? And more importantly, can you survive?

-------------------------------------------

**SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:**  This session will use Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet&#39;s Community Code of Conduct: https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html

**RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:**  6/15/21, 3:30 p.m. CDT

**SET UP INFO:**  We will use Streamyard for the event. Since this game is being set up on short notice, players will receive an email confirming attendance and providing links to documents on the day before the session.

**BREAKS:**  2 breaks of 5-10 minutes.

**RECORDED:**  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.

**PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:**  No experience required, rules will be taught.

https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McBE3r02kOqeWxOFaMR</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 20:37:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Gauntlet Calendar</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stay-frosty-operation-black-nova-tuesday-6-22-21-at-1-p-m-central-time/7087.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Stay Frosty: Operation Black Nova, Tuesday, 6/22/21 at 1 p.m. Central Time</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Puckett]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/puckett">@Puckett</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h1>For the first 24 hours, please only RSVP if you are in the U.K./E.U.</h1>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF SESSIONS:</strong>  1</p>
<p><strong>DURATION:</strong>  3 hours</p>
<p><strong>NUMBER OF PLAYERS:</strong>  4 (a seat is being reserved for Will H.)</p>
<p><strong>CONTENT WARNING:</strong>  This game will include violence (graphic violence can be veiled) and PC death is on the table. It may include smoking/alcohol/drugs, body horror, religious zealotry, interrogations (torture can be veiled), and themes of murder/suicide/genocide/xenocide/extinction level events.</p>
<hr>
<p>“All right, you trigger-happy bulletheads, eyes forward, ears open! Some science vessel called the Null Spectrum sent a distress call 15 minutes ago because there’s a … let me see here … a gravitic anomaly near Tonantzin … you know, that planet where all the eggheads you bullied for being smart went? The one where they’re all rich and happy and go to sleep in nice, soft beds, while you drag your asses across the galaxy shooting plants and animals that want to eat you and eat cold slop and fight over the top bunk so Hadathen’s farts don’t drift down and smother you in your sleep? Anyway, command says it’s our turn to respond to the call. Apparently, this thing has already destroyed six ships. Stay frosty on this one … I don’t want us to be seventh  <em>or</em>  eighth.”</p>
<p>The Null Spectrum, a science vessel from Tonantzin, has sent a distress call due to a gravitic anomaly which has already destroyed six ships. The Null Spectrum’s force shields are the only thing protecting it, and they’re on the verge of failing. Can you save the ship - or at least the crew? And more importantly, can you survive?</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>SAFETY TOOLS IN USE:</strong>  This session will use Lines and Veils to facilitate an initial baseline for player safety. Players are absolutely encouraged to add more topics to the list for their own safety. This session will also use the N-Card, X-Card, and Script Change as necessary to adjust the game while it’s in progress to maintain player safety. Finally, the Open Door Policy is always in effect and players may leave the game at any time for any length of time for any reason. This session will also adhere to The Gauntlet’s Community Code of Conduct: <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/community-code-of-conduct.html</a></p>
<p><strong>RSVP OPEN ACCESS TIME:</strong>  6/15/21, 3:30 p.m. CDT</p>
<p><strong>SET UP INFO:</strong>  We will use Streamyard for the event. Since this game is being set up on short notice, players will receive an email confirming attendance and providing links to documents on the day before the session.</p>
<p><strong>BREAKS:</strong>  2 breaks of 5-10 minutes.</p>
<p><strong>RECORDED:</strong>  If all participants consent, it will be recorded and uploaded to YouTube.</p>
<p><strong>PRIOR EXPERIENCE REQUIRED:</strong>  No experience required, rules will be taught.</p>
<p><a href="https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McBE3r02kOqeWxOFaMR" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://gauntlet-hangouts.firebaseapp.com/event-detail/-McBE3r02kOqeWxOFaMR</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stay-frosty-operation-black-nova-tuesday-6-22-21-at-1-p-m-central-time/7087/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stay-frosty-operation-black-nova-tuesday-6-22-21-at-1-p-m-central-time/7087/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 20:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-7087-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/stay-frosty-operation-black-nova-tuesday-6-22-21-at-1-p-m-central-time/7087.rss">Stay Frosty: Operation Black Nova, Tuesday, 6/22/21 at 1 p.m. Central Time</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
