<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314</link>
    <description>Hello everyone! I just released some of the rules I had been working on for a variation of FATE Core based around allowing players and GMs to select “scenarios” to play out which are little mini-quests treated as actions in the game (deal damage to bigger bads, can bring new advantages into the game with mechanical effects, etc.). It really takes the idea of the FATE fractal to new heights, allowing you to treat much more as entities with stats in the game. You can look over the fairly extensive expansion of FATE I have so far here for free - https://integralmindgames.itch.io/guiding-fate-playtest

I have hit the point in the process where I need to strategize on what to focus on next. To do that, I would appreciate if I could get something of a read on how interested people are in such ideas and gameplay. 

For those interested, below is a brief summary of some of the mechanics.

Scenarios are basically like combat events in FATE Core, but in this game can be sneaking missions, investigations, combat, chasing, etc.

There are 4 ways to approach a scenario. 

Direct – Think through the problem in a scenario.
Skillful – Think around a problem in a scenario.
Reflexive – Think about how the problem became a problem.
Social – Think about how forces outside the current scenario can help.

Choosing an approach determines what type of scenarios you can use for a problem, (Combat, Chase, Social Persuasion, etc.) It also determines what bonuses you might receive to perform such a quest.

Scenarios are layered upon each other, so on one level of the story there might be Combat breaking out. Such as, two gang factions wandering about the city, trying to knock each other out. When the gangs encounter each other, they can make an attack action, which creates a new sub scenario to play out (one gang might be said to get the jump on a member and create a Chase scenario). The outcome of this sub-scenario can damage the gang faction which loses it. 

With that, what is your reaction? I was hoping your feedback might assist me in thinking about what to prioritize next. For instance, if you said it sounds a little involved, I might focus on sliming down the systems and complexity as best I can, if you thought it seemed a little abstract, I could focus on working the rules into a setting, or if you thought it all sounds interesting, I might work on refining and expanding what I have.

Please feel free to provide whatever comes to your mind!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 05:53:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Game Design</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ChristopherA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christophera">@ChristopherA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Don" data-post="3" data-topic="8314">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/user_avatar/forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/don/40/5908_2.png" class="avatar"> Don:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I am afraid the link you provided was not working for me, so I was not able to look closer at things.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I fixed it in my post, it should be: <a href="https://www.DyversHands.com/Tableau" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.DyversHands.com/Tableau</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 05:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8314-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314.rss">Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Don]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/don">@Don</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello Christopher! Thank you for the feedback and ideas!</p>
<p>I always find it an interesting exercise, trying to systematize the creation of narrative. There is the aspect of setting the scene and determining the problems to be faced as well as the aspect of determining the specific actions the characters can make. It sounds like you use setting story cards to allow players to create the larger context of a problem (what type of threat they are facing) and then the player use their character’s traits to determine how they go about trying to achieve their goals as well as how successful they might be.</p>
<p>I generally use 4 Approaches (Direct, Skillful, Reflective, and Social) which determine the actions of the characters best suited to achieve a goal and 4 types of end goals which the players can decide they are working towards (Defeating an obstacle, Capturing an element, Revealing some new aspect, or Influencing an agent’s loyalty). The players then combine these to generate more intriguing scenarios which make up the story.</p>
<p>Additionally, your technique of unveiling three cards to determine the different approaches which can be used in a situation as well as their difficulty is an interesting one. Like tarot cards, describing the possible fates of the characters. It presents some choices to the players, while also severing a “game” function of encouraging certain choices over others (such as an approach which works well for their character and against the threat). (I am afraid the link you provided was not working for me, so I was not able to look closer at things.)</p>
<p>I will mull over your thoughts a bit and see how they might fit in with my game.</p>
<p>– Donald Brett</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 02:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8314-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314.rss">Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ChristopherA]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/christophera">@ChristopherA</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Don,</p>
<p>I’ve also been thinking in similar territory, but with my new game system <a href="https://www.DyversHands.com/Tableau" rel="nofollow noopener">Tableau</a> which uses poker-sized cards.</p>
<p>I currently have 11 optional character traits as cards that are called “Approaches”, which are loosely inspired by FAE: brash, careful, charming, clever, eccentric, fast, forceful, handy, ruthless, shady, tenacious.</p>
<p>Unlike FAE, these are not skill-like with number, instead, they define how a character tends to makes decisions when solving problems, in particular under extraordinary conditions. If you have the character approach “fast” you tend to just go first; if “shady” you’ll look first for an indirect approach; if you are “brash” you’ll take a risky choice. Your character may not be good at it, but  their “approach” is their stereotypical first option (in psychology “satisficing”).</p>
<p>Unlike Fate and FAE, the default rules for Tableau are gmless, so each player also holds a story card that represents their authority over that element of the narrative.</p>
<p>So for instance, in my upcoming Lovecraft Country: ‘A Study in Madness’ playset, which is more adventure-oriented, there is a setting story card “Academic” that represents the mundane problems of living or working in higher-education. In a sense, these allow the player holding the Academic card the ability to trigger the “threats” of that setting.</p>
<p>I’ve been consider about pulling these character traits aside not for use by characters, but as an optional rule for how threats work. You’ll randomize a stack of all 11 traits, and the “approach” at the top will be the riskiest way to tackle that threat. So if “Brash” is on the top, being impulsive will likely fail you, but you’ll have to overcome it somehow, either by spending a token (using a karma drama rule card), or succeed in some extraordinary way (using a dice drama rule card). The next card revealed will have ordinary risk, say “handy”, which requires you to physically become involved in tinkering in some way. The third card will reveal the easy way for success, say “careful”, which requires just taking the time and not rushing.</p>
<p>As you are more Fate oriented, you might want to consider using the FAE approaches (careful, clever, flashy, forceful, quick, sneaky, or use one my <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1OYtvwFHVNA-RcDdnr8i9aop2N8cKBJBmA94g4KdzHXc/edit?usp=sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">Varieties of FAE approaches</a>) in a similar for your list of scenario aspects, write up each of those from overcoming threat point-of-view. Optionally you can have a GM draw a FAE card or a d6.</p>
<p>I’d be interested in knowing if this idea is useful for you.</p>
<p>– Christopher Allen</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 19:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8314-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314.rss">Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Don]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/don">@Don</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Hello everyone! I just released some of the rules I had been working on for a variation of FATE Core based around allowing players and GMs to select “scenarios” to play out which are little mini-quests treated as actions in the game (deal damage to bigger bads, can bring new advantages into the game with mechanical effects, etc.). It really takes the idea of the FATE fractal to new heights, allowing you to treat much more as entities with stats in the game. You can look over the fairly extensive expansion of FATE I have so far here for free - <a href="https://integralmindgames.itch.io/guiding-fate-playtest" rel="nofollow noopener">https://integralmindgames.itch.io/guiding-fate-playtest</a></p>
<p>I have hit the point in the process where I need to strategize on what to focus on next. To do that, I would appreciate if I could get something of a read on how interested people are in such ideas and gameplay.</p>
<p>For those interested, below is a brief summary of some of the mechanics.</p>
<p>Scenarios are basically like combat events in FATE Core, but in this game can be sneaking missions, investigations, combat, chasing, etc.</p>
<p>There are 4 ways to approach a scenario.</p>
<p>Direct – Think through the problem in a scenario.<br>
Skillful – Think around a problem in a scenario.<br>
Reflexive – Think about how the problem became a problem.<br>
Social – Think about how forces outside the current scenario can help.</p>
<p>Choosing an approach determines what type of scenarios you can use for a problem, (Combat, Chase, Social Persuasion, etc.) It also determines what bonuses you might receive to perform such a quest.</p>
<p>Scenarios are layered upon each other, so on one level of the story there might be Combat breaking out. Such as, two gang factions wandering about the city, trying to knock each other out. When the gangs encounter each other, they can make an attack action, which creates a new sub scenario to play out (one gang might be said to get the jump on a member and create a Chase scenario). The outcome of this sub-scenario can damage the gang faction which loses it.</p>
<p>With that, what is your reaction? I was hoping your feedback might assist me in thinking about what to prioritize next. For instance, if you said it sounds a little involved, I might focus on sliming down the systems and complexity as best I can, if you thought it seemed a little abstract, I could focus on working the rules into a setting, or if you thought it all sounds interesting, I might work on refining and expanding what I have.</p>
<p>Please feel free to provide whatever comes to your mind!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 03:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-8314-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/feedback-for-meta-game-ideas/8314.rss">Feedback for Meta-Game Ideas</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
